<?xml version="1.0"  ?><!DOCTYPE pmc-articleset PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD ARTICLE SET 2.0//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pmc/articleset/nlm-articleset-2.0.dtd"><pmc-articleset><article xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" xmlns:ali="http://www.niso.org/schemas/ali/1.0/" xml:lang="en" article-type="research-article" dtd-version="1.4"><processing-meta base-tagset="archiving" mathml-version="3.0" table-model="xhtml" tagset-family="jats"><restricted-by>pmc</restricted-by></processing-meta><front><journal-meta><journal-id journal-id-type="nlm-ta">Plast Reconstr Surg</journal-id><journal-id journal-id-type="iso-abbrev">Plast Reconstr Surg</journal-id><journal-id journal-id-type="pmc-domain-id">2035</journal-id><journal-id journal-id-type="pmc-domain">lwwopen</journal-id><journal-id journal-id-type="publisher-id">PRS</journal-id><journal-title-group><journal-title>Plastic and Reconstructive Surgery</journal-title></journal-title-group><issn pub-type="ppub">0032-1052</issn><issn pub-type="epub">1529-4242</issn><custom-meta-group><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-is-collection-domain</meta-name><meta-value>yes</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-collection-title</meta-name><meta-value>Lippincott Open Access</meta-value></custom-meta></custom-meta-group></journal-meta><article-meta><article-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC12184970</article-id><article-id pub-id-type="pmcid-ver">PMC12184970.1</article-id><article-id pub-id-type="pmcaid">12184970</article-id><article-id pub-id-type="pmcaiid">12184970</article-id><article-id pub-id-type="pmid">39808069</article-id><article-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1097/PRS.0000000000011957</article-id><article-id pub-id-type="publisher-id">PRS-D-24-00897</article-id><article-version-alternatives><article-version article-version-type="pmc-version">1</article-version><article-version vocab="JAV" vocab-identifier="http://www.niso.org/publications/rp/RP-8-2008.pdf" article-version-type="Version of Record">3</article-version></article-version-alternatives><article-categories><subj-group subj-group-type="heading"><subject>Cosmetic: Face: Original Articles</subject></subj-group></article-categories><title-group><article-title>Improvement in Temple Hollowing with VYC-20L Hyaluronic Acid Filler: A Multicenter Randomized Controlled Trial of Safety and Effectiveness</article-title></title-group><contrib-group><contrib contrib-type="author" corresp="yes"><name name-style="western"><surname>Montes</surname><given-names initials="JR">Jos&#233; Ra&#250;l</given-names></name><degrees>MD</degrees><xref rid="aff3" ref-type="aff">1</xref></contrib><contrib contrib-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Hooper</surname><given-names initials="D">Deirdre</given-names></name><degrees>MD</degrees><xref rid="aff4" ref-type="aff">2</xref></contrib><contrib contrib-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Jones</surname><given-names initials="D">Derek</given-names></name><degrees>MD</degrees><xref rid="aff5" ref-type="aff">3</xref></contrib><contrib contrib-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Biesman</surname><given-names initials="B">Brian</given-names></name><degrees>MD</degrees><xref rid="aff6" ref-type="aff">4</xref></contrib><contrib contrib-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Baumann</surname><given-names initials="L">Leslie</given-names></name><degrees>MD</degrees><xref rid="aff7" ref-type="aff">5</xref></contrib><contrib contrib-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Beer</surname><given-names initials="K">Kenneth</given-names></name><degrees>MD</degrees><xref rid="aff8" ref-type="aff">6</xref></contrib><contrib contrib-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Yoelin</surname><given-names initials="S">Steve</given-names></name><degrees>MD</degrees><xref rid="aff9" ref-type="aff">7</xref></contrib><contrib contrib-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Leung</surname><given-names initials="K">Kelly</given-names></name><degrees>PhD</degrees><xref rid="aff10" ref-type="aff">8</xref></contrib><contrib contrib-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Chawla</surname><given-names initials="S">Smita</given-names></name><degrees>PhD</degrees><xref rid="aff10" ref-type="aff">8</xref></contrib><aff>San Juan, Puerto Rico; New Orleans, LA; Los Angeles, Newport Beach, and Irvine, CA; Nashville, TN; and Miami and West Palm Beach, FL</aff><aff id="aff3">From <label>1</label>JRM Eyes &amp; Facial Rejuvenation and Department of Ophthalmology, University of Puerto Rico</aff><aff id="aff4"><label>2</label>Audubon Dermatology</aff><aff id="aff5"><label>3</label>Skin Care and Laser Physicians of Beverly Hills</aff><aff id="aff6"><label>4</label>Departments of Ophthalmology, Dermatology, and Otolaryngology, Vanderbilt University Medical Center</aff><aff id="aff7"><label>5</label>Baumann Cosmetic Dermatology</aff><aff id="aff8"><label>6</label>University of Miami</aff><aff id="aff9"><label>7</label>Medical Associates, Inc</aff><aff id="aff10"><label>8</label>Allergan Aesthetics, an AbbVie company.</aff></contrib-group><author-notes><corresp id="c1">Jos&#233; Ra&#250;l Montes, MD, Dr. Jos&#233; Ra&#250;l Montes Eyes &amp; Facial Rejuvenation, 813 Avenida Juan Ponce de Le&#243;n, San Juan 00917, Puerto Rico, <email xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xlink:href="jrmontes@jrmontes.com">jrmontes@jrmontes.com</email></corresp></author-notes><pub-date pub-type="epub"><day>14</day><month>1</month><year>2025</year></pub-date><pub-date pub-type="ppub"><month>7</month><year>2025</year></pub-date><volume>156</volume><issue>1</issue><issue-id pub-id-type="pmc-issue-id">491247</issue-id><fpage>25</fpage><lpage>36</lpage><history><date date-type="received"><day>10</day><month>4</month><year>2024</year></date><date date-type="accepted"><day>6</day><month>1</month><year>2025</year></date></history><pub-history><event event-type="pmc-release"><date><day>23</day><month>06</month><year>2025</year></date></event><event event-type="pmc-live"><date><day>24</day><month>06</month><year>2025</year></date></event><event event-type="pmc-last-change"><date iso-8601-date="2025-06-27 08:25:13.970"><day>27</day><month>06</month><year>2025</year></date></event></pub-history><permissions><copyright-statement>Copyright &#169; 2025 The Authors. Published by Wolters Kluwer Health, Inc. on behalf of the American Society of Plastic Surgeons.</copyright-statement><copyright-year>2025</copyright-year><license><ali:license_ref specific-use="textmining" content-type="ccbyncndlicense">https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/4.0/</ali:license_ref><license-p>This is an open-access article distributed under the terms of the <ext-link xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" ext-link-type="uri" xlink:href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/4.0/">Creative Commons Attribution-Non Commercial-No Derivatives License 4.0 (CCBY-NC-ND)</ext-link>, where it is permissible to download and share the work provided it is properly cited. The work cannot be changed in any way or used commercially without permission from the journal.</license-p></license></permissions><self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" content-type="pmc-pdf" xlink:href="prs-156-025e.pdf"/><self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xlink:href="prs-156-025e.pdf"/><abstract><sec><title>Background:</title><p>Temple hollowing is characterized by a reduction of volume in the temporal fossa, which can result in a skeletonized look and contribute to an aged appearance. This study aimed to evaluate the safety and effectiveness of VYC-20L injectable gel to improve temple hollowing.</p></sec><sec><title>Methods:</title><p>Adults with minimal, moderate, or severe temple hollows were randomized 2:1 to receive VYC-20L or no treatment. Participants were followed up for 13 months for safety and effectiveness assessments. Treatment effectiveness was assessed by blinded evaluating investigators using the validated Allergan Temple Hollowing Scale (ATHS) and the Global Aesthetic Improvement Scale (GAIS), and by participants using GAIS, FACE-Q scales, and patient satisfaction questionnaires. Adverse events and injection-site responses were monitored.</p></sec><sec><title>Results:</title><p>At month 3, 80.4% of the treatment group versus 13.5% of the untreated control group achieved a 1-grade improvement or greater in both temples on the ATHS (<italic toggle="yes">P</italic> &lt; 0.0001). The ATHS responder rate remained high throughout month 13. The GAIS responder rates at month 3 (responses of improved or much improved) were high in the treatment group, as assessed by the blinded evaluating investigator (83.8%) and participants (92.9%). Furthermore, satisfaction with facial appearance and temples on the FACE-Q questionnaires increased significantly from baseline (both <italic toggle="yes">P</italic> &lt; 0.0001). Adverse events and injection-site responses were mostly mild and consistent with the known safety profile of fillers.</p></sec><sec><title>Conclusions:</title><p>VYC-20L treatment showed favorable safety and effectiveness results in restoring temple volume, with significant aesthetic improvement and high participant satisfaction. Treatment effects lasted for more than a year.</p></sec><sec><title>CLINICAL QUESTION/LEVEL OF EVIDENCE:</title><p>Therapeutic, II.</p></sec></abstract><funding-group><award-group id="ID0EAXAG13177"><funding-source><institution-wrap><institution>Allergan Aesthetics</institution><institution-id institution-id-type="doi">10.13039/100020638</institution-id></institution-wrap></funding-source><principal-award-recipient>Not Applicable</principal-award-recipient></award-group></funding-group><custom-meta-group><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-status-qastatus</meta-name><meta-value>0</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-status-live</meta-name><meta-value>yes</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-status-embargo</meta-name><meta-value>no</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-status-released</meta-name><meta-value>yes</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-open-access</meta-name><meta-value>yes</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-olf</meta-name><meta-value>no</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-manuscript</meta-name><meta-value>no</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-legally-suppressed</meta-name><meta-value>no</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-has-pdf</meta-name><meta-value>yes</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-has-supplement</meta-name><meta-value>yes</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-pdf-only</meta-name><meta-value>no</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-suppress-copyright</meta-name><meta-value>no</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-is-real-version</meta-name><meta-value>no</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-is-scanned-article</meta-name><meta-value>no</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-preprint</meta-name><meta-value>no</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-in-epmc</meta-name><meta-value>yes</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>STATUS</meta-name><meta-value>ONLINE-ONLY</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>OPEN-ACCESS</meta-name><meta-value>TRUE</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>SDC</meta-name><meta-value>T</meta-value></custom-meta></custom-meta-group></article-meta></front><body><p>Temple hollowing refers to loss of volume in the temporalis muscle and temporal fat pad, resulting in the emergence of bony margins, leading to a gaunt and skeletonized appearance.<sup><xref rid="R1" ref-type="bibr">1</xref>&#8211;<xref rid="R4" ref-type="bibr">4</xref></sup> Temple hollowing is commonly associated with aging, but can also occur in thin or athletic individuals, in patients with human immunodeficiency virus and antiretroviral lipoatrophy, or as a consequence of a coronal incision.<sup><xref rid="R4" ref-type="bibr">4</xref>&#8211;<xref rid="R6" ref-type="bibr">6</xref></sup> Various treatments have been explored to address temple hollowing, including fat grafting, surgical implants, and soft-tissue fillers, such as hyaluronic acid (HA), poly-L-lactic acid, and calcium hydroxylapatite.<sup><xref rid="R1" ref-type="bibr">1</xref>,<xref rid="R7" ref-type="bibr">7</xref>,<xref rid="R8" ref-type="bibr">8</xref></sup> HA-based soft-tissue fillers have become an established treatment option because they provide immediate and natural results, and are considered safe.<sup><xref rid="R3" ref-type="bibr">3</xref>,<xref rid="R4" ref-type="bibr">4</xref>,<xref rid="R7" ref-type="bibr">7</xref></sup> In addition, their effects can be reversed by hyaluronidase.<sup><xref rid="R4" ref-type="bibr">4</xref>,<xref rid="R9" ref-type="bibr">9</xref></sup></p><p>VYC-20L (Juv&#233;derm Voluma XC; Allergan Aesthetics, an AbbVie company) is an HA soft-tissue filler with lidocaine that is well suited for volumizing and contouring in facial rejuvenation given its high viscosity and cohesivity.<sup><xref rid="R10" ref-type="bibr">10</xref></sup> Previous studies have demonstrated that VYC-20L is well tolerated and can effectively improve temple hollowing.<sup><xref rid="R11" ref-type="bibr">11</xref>&#8211;<xref rid="R15" ref-type="bibr">15</xref></sup> However, these studies had limitations, such as being uncontrolled, single-center, or open-label, or having small sample sizes. Further research with a more rigorous study design is required to establish the safety and effectiveness of VYC-20L for temple hollowing treatment. This multicenter, evaluator-blinded, randomized, controlled, parallel-design pivotal study was designed to assess the safety and effectiveness of VYC-20L in improving temple hollowing.</p><sec sec-type="methods"><title>PATIENTS AND METHODS</title><sec><title>Study Design</title><p>This study was conducted at 15 sites in the United States in accordance with all applicable international guidelines. It was reviewed and approved by an institutional review board, and all participants provided informed consent before study initiation.</p></sec><sec><title>Randomization and Treatment</title><p>Eligible participants were randomly assigned in a 2:1 ratio to VYC-20L or no treatment (control) based on a central randomization schedule. Participants in the treatment group received VYC-20L on day 1 and an optional touch-up treatment after 30 days, and were followed up at day 3, day 14, and months 1, 3, 6, 9, and 13 after the last treatment. Participants in the control group did not receive any treatment and were followed up for 3 months. At that time, they were given the option to exit the study or receive treatment (initial treatment and touch-up if necessary) with the same follow-up schedule as the treatment group. A subset of participants from the treatment group received repeated treatment after the month 13 visit and were followed up for 6 months.</p><p>VYC-20L was injected in bolus using 27-G half-inch or 25-G 1-inch needles in the supraperiosteal plane in the temples using the 1-up-and-1-over technique.<sup><xref rid="R16" ref-type="bibr">16</xref></sup> The injection location was approximately 1 cm inferolaterally to the temporal fusion line and 1 cm superolaterally to the lateral orbital rim (Fig. <xref rid="F1" ref-type="fig">1</xref>). The maximum permitted injection volume was 3 mL/temple for the combined initial and touch-up treatments, with a limit of 2 mL/temple per treatment session.</p><fig position="float" id="F1" orientation="portrait"><label>Fig. 1.</label><caption><p>Injection site. The injection site is situated at approximately 1 cm superior and 1 cm lateral to where the temporal fusion line meets the lateral orbital rim.</p></caption><graphic xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" position="float" orientation="portrait" xlink:href="prs-156-025e-g001.jpg"/></fig></sec><sec><title>Participants</title><p>Eligible male and female participants 22 years or older who exhibited minimal, moderate, or severe hollows in both temples were randomized. Participants with temple hollowing due to trauma, congenital malformations, or lipodystrophy; temporomandibular joint dysfunction or any other jaw issues; recurrent temporal headaches; active immune disease; or a history of allergy or anaphylaxis to lidocaine were excluded. In addition, participants who had undergone previous facial reconstructive surgery, face lift or brow lift, or surgery on the temple area (e.g., biopsy), or had received fat injections or permanent facial implants, semipermanent soft-tissue filler treatment in the temple or midface within 36 months before enrollment, temporary dermal filler treatment above the subnasale within 24 months before enrollment, or botulinum toxin injections, mesotherapy, or other cosmetic procedures above the subnasale within 6 months before study enrollment were deemed ineligible for the study.</p></sec><sec><title>Assessments</title><sec><title>Effectiveness</title><p>The primary end point was the Allergan Temple Hollowing Scale (ATHS) responder rate at month 3. A responder was defined as a participant with at least 1-grade improvement from their baseline ATHS score in both temples, based on the blinded evaluating investigator&#8217;s (EI) live assessment. The ATHS is a validated 5-point scale with substantial intrarater agreement (mean weighted kappa, 0.86) and interrater agreement (intraclass correlation coefficient, 0.81). A 1-point difference on the ATHS scale indicated a clinically significant change in temple volume deficit.<sup><xref rid="R17" ref-type="bibr">17</xref></sup></p><p>Secondary end points included the Global Aesthetic Improvement Scale (GAIS) responder rate at month 3, as assessed by both the blinded EI and the participant. The GAIS responder rate was defined as the proportion of participants with a rating of improved or much improved in overall temple area aesthetics compared with baseline images using the 5-point GAIS (2 = much improved; 1 = improved; 0 = no change; &#8722;1 = worse; &#8722;2 = much worse). Other secondary end points were the change from baseline on the FACE-Q Satisfaction with Facial Appearance questionnaire at month 3 and the change from baseline on the FACE-Q Satisfaction with Temples questionnaire at month 3. The 10-item FACE-Q Satisfaction with Facial Appearance questionnaire and multiple-item FACE-Q Satisfaction with Temples questionnaire are validated 4-point scales, where 1 = very dissatisfied and 4 = very satisfied.<sup><xref rid="R18" ref-type="bibr">18</xref>&#8211;<xref rid="R20" ref-type="bibr">20</xref></sup> Other effectiveness analysis included temple volume change using 3-dimensional image volumetric analysis and the participant&#8217;s satisfaction with treatment.</p></sec><sec><title>Safety</title><p>Safety assessments included analysis of adverse events (AEs) and vision (Snellen visual acuity, confrontational visual fields, and ocular motility), which were monitored by the treating investigator at all study visits. Participants rated procedural pain (during injection) immediately after the initial and touch-up treatments on an 11-point scale, with 0 indicating no pain and 10 the worst imaginable pain. Participants also recorded injection-site responses (ISRs) in an e-diary for 30 days after the initial treatment and 14 days after touch-up and repeated treatments. In addition, participants assessed their jaw function with the 20-item Jaw Functional Limitation Scale.</p></sec></sec><sec><title>Statistical Analysis</title><p>A total of 90 participants in the treatment group and 45 in the control group were estimated to provide 90% or greater power to detect a difference of 30% between groups for the primary end point responder rates. The analyzed populations included the modified intent-to-treat population, consisting of all randomized participants who had nonmissing ATHS assessment at baseline (<italic toggle="yes">n</italic> = 171), and the safety population, consisting of all randomized participants who had 1 or more study treatment interventions (<italic toggle="yes">n</italic> = 171).</p><p>For the primary end point, ATHS responder rates were compared between treatment and control groups using a 2-sided Fisher exact test. A <italic toggle="yes">P</italic> value less than 0.05 was considered statistically significant. The change from baseline to month 3 on the FACE-Q questionnaires was evaluated with a 2-sided paired <italic toggle="yes">t</italic> test at a significance level of 5%. The primary and secondary analysis at timepoints different from the primary timepoint (month 3) and all other variables were summarized descriptively, as were demographic and safety data. Statistical analyses were conducted using SAS version 9.4 (SAS Institute, Inc.).</p></sec></sec><sec sec-type="results"><title>RESULTS</title><sec><title>Participants</title><p>Of 205 participants screened, 171 were randomized to VYC-20L (<italic toggle="yes">n</italic> = 113) or no treatment control (<italic toggle="yes">n</italic> = 58). (<bold>See Table, Supplemental Digital Content 1</bold>, which summarizes the study participant disposition, <ext-link xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xlink:href="http://links.lww.com/PRS/H715" ext-link-type="uri">http://links.lww.com/PRS/H715</ext-link>.) Of the 171 participants randomized, 162 (94.7%) completed the primary end point visit and 140 (81.9%) completed the study. No participant withdrew because of AEs.</p><p>The study included participants ranging in age from 25 to 82 years, with a mean age of 54.9 years in the treatment group and 54.4 years in the untreated control group. Most participants were women (83.6%) and White (83.0%). The demographic and baseline characteristics of the 2 groups were balanced (Table <xref rid="T1" ref-type="table">1</xref>).</p><table-wrap position="float" id="T1" orientation="portrait"><label>Table 1.</label><caption><p>Demographic and Baseline Characteristics of Participants in the Modified Intent-to-Treat Population</p></caption><table frame="hsides" rules="groups"><thead><tr><th align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Characteristics</th><th align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Control (<italic toggle="yes">n</italic> = 58)</th><th align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">VYC-20L (<italic toggle="yes">n</italic> = 113)</th><th align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Total (<italic toggle="yes">n</italic> = 171)</th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Age, yrs, mean &#177; SD</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">54.4 &#177; 9.81</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">54.9 &#177; 9.97</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">54.7 &#177; 9.89</td></tr><tr><td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Sex, no. (%)</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1"/><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1"/><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1"/></tr><tr><td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">&#8195;Male</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">11 (19.0)</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">17 (15.0)</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">28 (16.4)</td></tr><tr><td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">&#8195;Female</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">47 (81.0)</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">96 (85.0)</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">143 (83.6)</td></tr><tr><td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Race, no. (%)</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1"/><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1"/><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1"/></tr><tr><td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">&#8195;American Indian or Alaskan Native</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">0 (0.0)</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">1 (0.9)</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">1 (0.6)</td></tr><tr><td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">&#8195;Asian</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">1 (1.7)</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">2 (1.8)</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">3 (1.8)</td></tr><tr><td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">&#8195;Black or African American</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">6 (10.3)</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">12 (10.6)</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">18 (10.5)</td></tr><tr><td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">&#8195;Native Hawaiian or Other Pacific Islander</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">0 (0.0)</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">0 (0.0)</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">0 (0.0)</td></tr><tr><td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">&#8195;White</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">48 (82.8)</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">94 (83.2)</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">142 (83.0)</td></tr><tr><td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">&#8195;Multiple<sup><xref rid="tab1fn1" ref-type="table-fn">a</xref></sup></td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">3 (5.2)</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">4 (3.5)</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">7 (4.1)</td></tr><tr><td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Ethnicity, no. (%)</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1"/><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1"/><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1"/></tr><tr><td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">&#8195;Hispanic</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">14 (24.1)</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">27 (23.9)</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">41 (24.0)</td></tr><tr><td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">&#8195;Not Hispanic</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">44 (75.9)</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">86 (76.1)</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">130 (76.0)</td></tr><tr><td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Fitzpatrick skin phototype, no. (%)</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1"/><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1"/><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1"/></tr><tr><td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">&#8195;1 or 2</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">20 (34.5)</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">39 (34.5)</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">59 (34.5)</td></tr><tr><td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">&#8195;3 or 4</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">34 (58.6)</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">60 (53.1)</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">94 (55.0)</td></tr><tr><td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">&#8195;5 or 6</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">4 (6.9)</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">14 (12.4)</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">18 (10.5)</td></tr></tbody></table><table-wrap-foot><fn fn-type="other" id="tab1fn1"><label>a</label><p>Black or African American and White.</p></fn></table-wrap-foot></table-wrap></sec><sec><title>Treatment Administration</title><p>Anesthesia (ice, topical, or local, or a combination) was administered to 43.8% of participants, with the majority (38.4%) receiving topical anesthesia. In the treatment group, 112 participants received initial treatment, 73 (65.2%) received an additional touch-up treatment, and 40 (35.7%) received a repeated treatment. The most common reason for participants not receiving repeated treatment was that full correction remained. The median total volume injected for both temples in the treatment group was 3.65 mL for initial and touch-up treatments combined and 2.0 mL for repeated treatment. All injections were administered in boluses into the supraperiosteal plane, and most were performed using a 27-G half-inch needle.</p></sec><sec><title>Effectiveness</title><sec><title>ATHS Responder Rate</title><p>Temple hollowing significantly improved at month 3 in the treatment group compared with the untreated control group according to EI assessment using the ATHS. The ATHS responder rate was 80.4% (95% CI, 72.7% to 88.1%) for the treatment group versus 13.5% (95% CI, 4.5% to 22.5%) for the untreated control group (<italic toggle="yes">P</italic> &lt; 0.0001) (Fig. <xref rid="F2" ref-type="fig">2</xref>).</p><fig position="float" id="F2" orientation="portrait"><label>Fig. 2.</label><caption><p>Proportion of responders (1 grade or greater improvement from baseline on the ATHS in both temples) over time based on blinded EI live assessment. <italic toggle="yes">Error bars</italic> indicate 95% confidence intervals. *<italic toggle="yes">P</italic> &lt; 0.0001 versus untreated control.</p></caption><graphic xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" position="float" orientation="portrait" xlink:href="prs-156-025e-g002.jpg"/></fig><p>VYC-20L effects were visible from month 1 and lasted for more than 1 year. At month 1, the percentage of ATHS responders was 81.7% (95% CI, 72.9% to 88.6%) in the VYC-20L group versus 23.6% (95% CI, 13.2% to 37.0%) in the untreated controls. The ATHS responder rate with VYC-20L was 73.3% (95% CI, 63.0% to 82.1%) at month 13. Images of participants before and after 3 and 13 months of VYC-20L treatment can be seen in Figure <xref rid="F3" ref-type="fig">3</xref>.</p><fig position="float" id="F3" orientation="portrait"><label>Fig. 3.</label><caption><p>Representative photographs of improved temple hollowing after VYC-20L treatment. A participant with a baseline ATHS score of 4 (<italic toggle="yes">severe</italic>) on both temples (<italic toggle="yes">above</italic>, <italic toggle="yes">left</italic>) received 1.0 mL/temple at initial treatment and 1.0 mL/temple at touch-up treatment, and had a score of 0 (<italic toggle="yes">convex</italic>) on both temples at month 3 (<italic toggle="yes">above</italic>, <italic toggle="yes">center</italic>) and maintained these results through month 13 (<italic toggle="yes">above</italic>, <italic toggle="yes">right</italic>). A participant who had a baseline ATHS score of 4 on both temples (<italic toggle="yes">center</italic>, <italic toggle="yes">left</italic>) received 1.0 mL/temple at initial treatment and 1.0 mL/temple at touch-up treatment, and had a 3-point ATHS improvement (from <italic toggle="yes">severe</italic> to <italic toggle="yes">flat</italic>) at month 3 (<italic toggle="yes">center</italic>) and reached a score of 2 (<italic toggle="yes">minimal</italic>) on both temples at month 13 (<italic toggle="yes">center</italic>, <italic toggle="yes">right</italic>). A participant with an ATHS score of 3 (<italic toggle="yes">moderate</italic>) on both temples (<italic toggle="yes">below</italic>, <italic toggle="yes">left</italic>) had a score of 2 on the left temple and 1 on the right temple at month 3 (<italic toggle="yes">below</italic>, <italic toggle="yes">center</italic>) and a score of 0 on the left temple and 1 on the right temple at month 13 (<italic toggle="yes">below</italic>, <italic toggle="yes">right</italic>). The initial treatment consisted of 1.0 mL/temple; during touch-up, the participant received 0.3 mL on the left temple and 0.6 mL on the right temple.</p></caption><graphic xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" position="float" orientation="portrait" xlink:href="prs-156-025e-g003.jpg"/></fig><p>For participants who received repeated treatment, 77.5% (95% CI, 61.5% to 89.2%) were ATHS responders at month 3 and 57.5% (95% CI, 40.9% to 73.0%) were responders at month 13. After repeated treatment, the responder rate increased to 82.9% (95% CI, 66.4% to 93.4%) and remained high up to 6 months later (71.4%; 95% CI, 53.7% to 85.4%).</p></sec><sec><title>Global Aesthetic Improvement</title><p>The EIs rated 83.8% of participants (95% CI, 75.3% to 90.3%) in the treatment group as improved or much improved on the GAIS at month 3 versus 10.7% in the untreated control group (95% CI, 4.0% to 21.9%) (Fig. <xref rid="F4" ref-type="fig">4</xref>). At month 13, 72.2% of participants (95% CI, 61.8% to 81.1%) continued to have improved or much improved global aesthetic appearance.</p><fig position="float" id="F4" orientation="portrait"><label>Fig. 4.</label><caption><p>Proportion of participants with an improved or much improved global aesthetic appearance, as assessed by the blinded EI and participants over time using GAIS. <italic toggle="yes">Error bars</italic> indicate 95% confidence intervals.</p></caption><graphic xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" position="float" orientation="portrait" xlink:href="prs-156-025e-g004.jpg"/></fig><p>According to the participants, the GAIS responder rate at month 3 for the treatment group was substantially better (92.9%; 95% CI, 86.0% to 97.1%) compared with the untreated control group (2.0%; 95% CI, 0.0% to 10.4%) (Fig. <xref rid="F4" ref-type="fig">4</xref>). By month 13, 78.9% (95% CI, 69.0% to 86.8%) of treated participants continued to report improved or much improved global aesthetic appearance on the GAIS.</p></sec><sec><title>Satisfaction with Facial Appearance and Temples (FACE-Q)</title><p>The FACE-Q Satisfaction with Facial Appearance overall Rasch-transformed mean score improved significantly by a mean of 24.2 points (95% CI, 19.7 to 28.6) from baseline to month 3 (<italic toggle="yes">P</italic> &lt; 0.0001) in the treatment group, whereas the untreated control group worsened by &#8722;6.6 points (95% CI, &#8722;9.1 to &#8722;4.1) (Fig. <xref rid="F5" ref-type="fig">5</xref>, <italic toggle="yes">above</italic>). The Rasch-transformed mean score remained high through month 13 compared with baseline (20.3; 95% CI, 15.8 to 24.7).</p><fig position="float" id="F5" orientation="portrait"><label>Fig. 5.</label><caption><p>FACE-Q Satisfaction with Facial Appearance questionnaire results. (<italic toggle="yes">Above</italic>) Overall Rasch-transformed mean score (100-point scale; higher scores indicate more favorable outcomes). (<italic toggle="yes">Below</italic>) Proportion of participants who reported being satisfied (somewhat satisfied to very satisfied) before and after treatment with VYC-20L in key individual items. Error bars indicate 95% confidence intervals. *<italic toggle="yes">P</italic> &lt; 0.0001 versus baseline.</p></caption><graphic xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" position="float" orientation="portrait" xlink:href="prs-156-025e-g005.jpg"/></fig><p>Improvements were also seen in individual FACE-Q Satisfaction with Facial Appearance questions. At month 3, participants in the treatment group showed increased satisfaction with facial symmetry and balance, with 89.0% and 88.0% expressing satisfaction (somewhat satisfied to very satisfied), respectively, compared with 54.0% and 49.6% at baseline. There was also a notable increase in satisfaction with fresh appearance, profile view, appearance in photographs, and appearance under bright light, with at least 40% more participants reporting satisfaction at month 3 compared with baseline. Even at month 13, 62% or more of participants remained satisfied with each of these aspects (Fig. <xref rid="F5" ref-type="fig">5</xref>, <italic toggle="yes">below</italic>).</p><p>The FACE-Q Satisfaction with Temples overall Rasch-transformed mean score improved significantly by a mean of 42.7 points (95% CI, 37.4 to 48.0) from baseline to month 3 (<italic toggle="yes">P</italic> &lt; 0.0001) in the treatment group; the untreated control worsened by &#8722;4.2 points (95% CI, &#8722;8.3 to &#8722;0.0) (Fig. <xref rid="F6" ref-type="fig">6</xref>, <italic toggle="yes">above</italic>). The Rasch-transformed mean score remained high through month 13 compared with baseline (34.1; 95% CI, 28.7 to 39.6).</p><fig position="float" id="F6" orientation="portrait"><label>Fig. 6.</label><caption><p>FACE-Q Satisfaction with Temples questionnaire results. (<italic toggle="yes">Above</italic>) Overall Rasch-transformed mean score (100-point scale, where higher scores indicate more favorable outcomes). (<italic toggle="yes">Below</italic>) Proportion of participants who reported being satisfied (somewhat satisfied to very satisfied) before and after treatment with VYC-20L in key individual items. Error bars indicate 95% confidence intervals. *<italic toggle="yes">P</italic> &lt; 0.0001 versus baseline.</p></caption><graphic xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" position="float" orientation="portrait" xlink:href="prs-156-025e-g006.jpg"/></fig><p>Individual responses to the FACE-Q Satisfaction with Temples questionnaire showed that at month 3, 83.7% of the treatment group were satisfied with the youthful appearance of their temples, compared with 13.5% at baseline. Satisfaction also increased in other areas, such as how well the temples fit with the rest of their face, with 85.7% expressing satisfaction at month 3 compared with 28.8% at baseline. In addition, there was an increase in satisfaction for other aspects of temple appearance, with at least 52% more of participants expressing satisfaction from baseline to month 3. More than 73% remained satisfied with these aspects at month 13 (Fig. <xref rid="F6" ref-type="fig">6</xref>, <italic toggle="yes">below</italic>).</p></sec><sec><title>Other Exploratory Outcomes</title><p>When examining volumetric changes, the treatment group exhibited a mean increase from baseline of 1.1 cc/temple and 0.8 cc/temple at months 1 and 6, respectively. At month 13, the mean volume increase from baseline was 0.8 cc in the right temple and 0.7 cc in the left temple. In addition, participants reported satisfaction with treatment. At month 3, 91.0% of treated participants reported being satisfied or very satisfied with the overall result of treatment, 89.0% with how natural the temple area looked, and 91.0% with how natural the temple area felt; 87.0% reported the treatment met expectations, 93.0% were likely to continue treatment, and 98.0% were willing to recommend treatment. Satisfaction remained high in the treatment group throughout month 13 (Fig. <xref rid="F7" ref-type="fig">7</xref>).</p><fig position="float" id="F7" orientation="portrait"><label>Fig. 7.</label><caption><p>Participant satisfaction with treatment.</p></caption><graphic xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" position="float" orientation="portrait" xlink:href="prs-156-025e-g007.jpg"/></fig></sec></sec><sec><title>Safety</title><p>Participants in the treatment group rated procedural pain as minimal, with mean scores of 1.3 for initial treatment and 1.0 for touch-up treatment. For ISRs, 95 participants (59.0%) reported at least 1 ISR after initial treatment, 46 (42.6%) after touch-up, and 17 (42.5%) after repeated treatment. The most frequently reported ISRs after initial treatment were pain after injection (50.9%), tenderness to touch (49.7%), and redness (41.0%) (Table <xref rid="T2" ref-type="table">2</xref>). Common ISRs were the same after repeated treatment with lower incidence rates. Most ISRs were mild or moderate in severity after all treatments (initial, touch-up, or repeated) and resolved within 1 week of injection.</p><table-wrap position="float" id="T2" orientation="portrait"><label>Table 2.</label><caption><p>ISRs after Initial Treatment Reported by More Than 5% of Treated Participants with Recorded Responses on the E-Diaries (<italic toggle="yes">n</italic> = 161)<sup><xref rid="tab2fn1" ref-type="table-fn">a</xref></sup></p></caption><table frame="hsides" rules="groups"><thead><tr><th align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Injection-Site Response</th><th align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Total Incidence</th><th align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Mild</th><th align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Moderate</th><th align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Severe</th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Any</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">95 (59.0)</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">67 (41.6)</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">25 (15.5)</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">3 (1.9)</td></tr><tr><td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Pain after injection</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">82 (50.9)</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">61 (37.9)</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">18 (11.2)</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">3 (1.9)</td></tr><tr><td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Tenderness to touch</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">80 (49.7)</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">69 (42.9)</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">9 (5.6)</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">2 (1.2)</td></tr><tr><td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Redness</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">66 (41.0)</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">55 (34.2)</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">9 (5.6)</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">2 (1.2)</td></tr><tr><td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Firmness</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">61 (37.9)</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">54 (33.5)</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">6 (3.7)</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">1 (0.6)</td></tr><tr><td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Swelling</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">49 (30.4)</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">42 (26.1)</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">7 (4.3)</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">0 (0.0)</td></tr><tr><td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Lumps or bumps</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">42 (26.1)</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">37 (23.0)</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">5 (3.1)</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">0 (0.0)</td></tr><tr><td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Bruising</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">26 (16.1)</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">24 (14.9)</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">2 (1.2)</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">0 (0.0)</td></tr><tr><td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Discoloration</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">11 (6.8)</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">9 (5.6)</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">2 (1.2)</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">0 (0.0)</td></tr></tbody></table><table-wrap-foot><fn fn-type="other" id="tab2fn1"><label>a</label><p>Data are presented as no. (%).</p></fn></table-wrap-foot></table-wrap><p>Treatment-related AEs occurred in 29 participants (17.6%), which were mostly mild. The most common AEs included jaw pain (6.1%) and headache (4.8%) (Table <xref rid="T3" ref-type="table">3</xref>). The majority of treatment-related AEs resolved within 1 week. Four participants experienced treatment-related AEs that resolved after 30 days: mild trismus (decrease in jaw function when yawning), which lasted for 42 days; mild injection site mass, which lasted for 56 days; mild injection site pain, which lasted for 32 days; and mild injection site mass, which lasted for 66 days. All resolved without intervention or sequalae. Of the 40 participants who received repeated treatment, 5 (12.5%) experienced treatment-related AEs. All these treatment-related AEs were mild and resolved without intervention or sequalae.</p><table-wrap position="float" id="T3" orientation="portrait"><label>Table 3.</label><caption><p>Treatment-Related AEs Occurring in More Than 1% of Treated Participants (<italic toggle="yes">n</italic> = 165)</p></caption><table frame="hsides" rules="groups"><thead><tr><th align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Treatment-Related AE</th><th align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Treated Participants, No. (%)</th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Pain in jaw</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">10 (6.1)</td></tr><tr><td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Headache</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">8 (4.8)</td></tr><tr><td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Injection site pain</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">3 (1.8)</td></tr><tr><td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Injection site discomfort</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">2 (1.2)</td></tr><tr><td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Injection site mass</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">2 (1.2)</td></tr><tr><td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Temporomandibular joint syndrome</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">2 (1.2)</td></tr><tr><td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Trismus</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">2 (1.2)</td></tr></tbody></table></table-wrap><p>There were no serious treatment-related AEs, late-onset AEs (AEs started over 4 weeks from treatment), AEs leading to study discontinuation, AEs related to vascular occlusion, or deaths.</p><sec><title>Other Safety Assessments</title><p>No significant changes were found in the Jaw Functional Limitation Scale overall score between baseline and all subsequent timepoints, including subscores for mastication, mobility, and verbal and nonverbal communication. Furthermore, the Snellen visual acuity test revealed no clinically meaningful changes in participants&#8217; vision after treatment, and there were no differences in confrontational visual fields or ocular motility after treatment.</p></sec></sec></sec><sec sec-type="discussion"><title>DISCUSSION</title><p>A wide range of soft-tissue fillers is available, each with distinct rheologic properties that make them appropriate for specific indications. VYC-20L uses a unique combination of high- and low-molecular-weight HA polymers, resulting in a filler with high viscosity and cohesivity. These properties confer VYC-20L with high lifting capacity, which is well suited for deeper injections, with minimal polymer volume changes after injection.<sup><xref rid="R10" ref-type="bibr">10</xref>,<xref rid="R21" ref-type="bibr">21</xref></sup> In addition, the tight HA network provides increased resistance to degradation, leading to longer-lasting results.<sup><xref rid="R22" ref-type="bibr">22</xref></sup></p><p>The effects of VYC-20L were observed as early as month 1 and persisted for more than a year. At the month 3 primary end point, the VYC-20L treatment group responder rate was 80.4% (<italic toggle="yes">P</italic> &lt; 0.0001 versus the untreated control group). The positive effects of VYC-20L were further corroborated by the secondary end points, which showed improvements in EI- and participant-assessed GAIS and FACE-Q scores. In addition, participants expressed satisfaction with treatment outcomes, including the natural appearance and feel of their temples. These results align with the medical literature on VYC-20L for temple volume restoration and demonstrate the effectiveness of the treatment in improving temple hollowing.<sup><xref rid="R11" ref-type="bibr">11</xref>,<xref rid="R13" ref-type="bibr">13</xref></sup> This study strengthens the existing research by incorporating a control group, larger sample size, validated severity scales, and patient-reported outcomes specifically designed for the temple area.</p><p>In the study, VYC-20L was injected deep into the supraperiosteal plane 1 cm superior and 1 cm lateral to where the temporal fusion line meets the lateral orbital rim. Most injections were performed with a 27-G half-inch needle. When injecting into the temple, it is crucial to exercise caution to prevent any damage to the superficial temporal artery and vessels, as well as the middle temporal vein, medial zygomaticotemporal vein, and deep temporal arteries.<sup><xref rid="R1" ref-type="bibr">1</xref>,<xref rid="R23" ref-type="bibr">23</xref>&#8211;<xref rid="R27" ref-type="bibr">27</xref></sup> A comprehensive understanding of the anatomy of the temple area, including awareness of the substantial variation in facial arterial vasculature among individuals,<sup><xref rid="R28" ref-type="bibr">28</xref></sup> is essential. A deep supraperiosteal injection may reduce the risk of intravascular injection and minimize the potential for nerve or blood vessel injury, as these structures are more superficial in the temporal fossa. By using the injection window described here, the middle temporal vein, which has been linked to vision complications, can be avoided.<sup><xref rid="R1" ref-type="bibr">1</xref></sup> Although other injection techniques have been proposed,<sup><xref rid="R29" ref-type="bibr">29</xref>&#8211;<xref rid="R32" ref-type="bibr">32</xref></sup> this injection method has been endorsed by field experts and the American Society for Dermatologic Surgery.<sup><xref rid="R1" ref-type="bibr">1</xref>,<xref rid="R16" ref-type="bibr">16</xref>,<xref rid="R23" ref-type="bibr">23</xref>,<xref rid="R24" ref-type="bibr">24</xref>,<xref rid="R33" ref-type="bibr">33</xref></sup> A diagram of the safe temple injection zone, highlighting critical vasculature, can be found in Carruthers et al.<sup><xref rid="R23" ref-type="bibr">23</xref></sup> Before injection, palpation and visual inspection of the superficial temporal artery and its branches are recommended to further enhance the safety and precision of temple volumization.<sup><xref rid="R1" ref-type="bibr">1</xref></sup> Administering the product slowly and steadily is also key to avoid complications.<sup><xref rid="R1" ref-type="bibr">1</xref></sup></p><p>This deeper injection may require a larger filler volume compared with a shallower injection. Cotofana et al.<sup><xref rid="R34" ref-type="bibr">34</xref></sup> observed that when injecting 0.5 mL of soft-tissue filler into the sub&#8211;orbicularis oculi fat compartment, 94% of the volume resulted in skin projection. However, when injecting the same amount in the deep temporal fat pad, only 53% led to visible changes. The median volume used in the study was 3.65 mL for both temples for the initial (and touch-up) treatment and 2.0 mL for repeated treatment.</p><p>The safety profile of VYC-20L for this indication was consistent with previous studies of VYC-20L and other HA fillers in temple hollowing.<sup><xref rid="R6" ref-type="bibr">6</xref>,<xref rid="R11" ref-type="bibr">11</xref>,<xref rid="R15" ref-type="bibr">15</xref>,<xref rid="R35" ref-type="bibr">35</xref>,<xref rid="R36" ref-type="bibr">36</xref></sup> Procedural pain was rated as minimal. Most ISRs were mild or moderate and resolved within a week. The most common treatment-related AEs after initial or touch-up treatment were headache and jaw pain, which resolved within 5 days. Filler injections in the temples can exert pressure on muscles associated with jaw function, such as the temporalis and masseter, which run through or connect at this region. This may result in jaw pain or discomfort while chewing, which generally resolves within a few days.<sup><xref rid="R11" ref-type="bibr">11</xref>,<xref rid="R35" ref-type="bibr">35</xref>,<xref rid="R37" ref-type="bibr">37</xref></sup></p><p>The effects of VYC-20L remained 13 months after the initial treatment. However, longer-term studies are needed to evaluate the sustained efficacy and safety of VYC-20L for improvement of temple hollowing. Our study mainly included White female participants, but the diversity in our sample is consistent with the demographic representation of patients who typically receive temple treatment in clinical practice. According to the 2020 Plastic Surgery Statistics Report from the American Society of Plastic Surgeons, 4%, 5%, and 10% of all soft-tissue filler injections in the United States were performed on male, Black, or Hispanic patients, respectively.<sup><xref rid="R38" ref-type="bibr">38</xref></sup> In addition, an AbbVie-sponsored online survey conducted from December of 2022 to January of 2023 in the United States involving 200 health care professionals who had a minimum of 2 years of dermal filler injection experience showed that 17%, 9%, and 10% of temple filler injections were performed on male, Black, or Hispanic patients, respectively (unpublished data). Another limitation of the study is the lack of 2-dimensional photographs. During the rendition from 3-dimensional to 2-dimensional images, areas such as hair and ears were cropped, and dimensional data were reduced. Nevertheless, the rendered images reflect the findings of the study accurately.</p></sec><sec sec-type="conclusions"><title>CONCLUSIONS</title><p>VYC-20L was found to be safe and effective in improving temple hollowing, with immediate and long-lasting results, which persisted for more than a year. Repeated treatment resulted in comparable outcomes with approximately half of the injection volume. Participants treated with VYC-20L were highly satisfied with the treatment outcome and would recommend the treatment to a friend more than 1 year after treatment.</p></sec><sec sec-type="COI-statement"><title>DISCLOSURE</title><p>Dr. Montes and Dr. Yoelin are consultants, investigators, speakers, and trainers for Allergan Aesthetics, an AbbVie company. Dr. Hooper and Dr. Biesman are investigators, consultants, and advisory board members for Allergan Aesthetics, an AbbVie company. Dr. Jones is an investigator, consultant, or advisory board member for Allergan Aesthetics, an AbbVie company, and Galderma. Dr. Baumann is an investigator for Allergan Aesthetics, an AbbVie company, Teoxane, and Galderma, and a consultant for AbbVie. Dr. Beer is an investigator and consultant for AbbVie. Drs. Leung and Chawla are employees of Allergan Aesthetics, an AbbVie company, and may own AbbVie stock.</p></sec><sec><title>ACKNOWLEDGMENTS</title><p>Allergan Aesthetics, an AbbVie company, and the authors thank the study and site investigators, coordinating staff, and participants involved in this trial. Allergan Aesthetics, an AbbVie company, funded this study and participated in the study design, research, analysis, data collection, interpretation of data, review, and approval of the publication. All authors had access to relevant data and participated in the drafting, review, and approval of this publication. No honoraria or payments were made for authorship. Medical writing support was provided by Ana Vicente-Sanchez, PhD, of AbbVie Inc., and editorial support was provided by Angela T. Hadsell of AbbVie Inc.; both were funded by AbbVie Inc.</p></sec><sec><title>DATA SHARING STATEMENT</title><p>AbbVie is committed to responsible data sharing regarding the clinical trials we sponsor. This includes access to anonymized, individual, and trial-level data (analysis data sets), as well as other information (eg, protocols, clinical study reports, or analysis plans), as long as the trials are not part of an ongoing or planned regulatory submission. This includes requests for clinical trial data for unlicensed products and indications. The clinical trial data can be requested by qualified researchers who engage in rigorous, independent scientific research, and will be provided following review and approval of a research proposal and statistical analysis plan and execution of a data sharing agreement. Data requests can be submitted at any time after approval in the United States and Europe. The data will be accessible for 12 months, with possible extensions considered. For more information on the process or to submit a request, visit <ext-link xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xlink:href="https://vivli.org/ourmember/abbvie" ext-link-type="uri">https://vivli.org/ourmember/abbvie</ext-link> and select &#8220;Home.&#8221;</p></sec><sec sec-type="supplementary-material"><title>Supplementary Material</title><supplementary-material id="SD1" position="float" content-type="local-data" orientation="portrait"><media xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" id="s1" content-type="document" xlink:href="prs-156-025e-s001.pdf" position="anchor" orientation="portrait"/></supplementary-material></sec></body><back><fn-group><fn fn-type="other"><p>This trial is registered under the name &#8220;A Study Evaluating Juv&#233;derm Voluma&#174; XC Injectable Gel for Correction of Temple Hollowing in Adult Participants Over 22 Years Old,&#8221; Clinical Trials.gov identification no. <ext-link xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" ext-link-type="pmc:clinical-trial" xlink:href="NCT04414397">NCT04414397</ext-link> (<ext-link xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xlink:href="https://www.clinicaltrials.gov/study/NCT04414397" ext-link-type="uri">https://www.clinicaltrials.gov/study/NCT04414397</ext-link>).</p></fn><fn fn-type="presented-at"><p>Presented at the 2024 American Academy of Dermatology Annual Meeting, in San Diego, California, March 8 through 12, 2024; the Tennessee Society for Laser Medicine and Surgery Symposium for Cosmetic Advances &amp; Laser Education (SCALE 2024), in Nashville, Tennessee, May 15 through 19, 2024; Cosmetic Bootcamp&#8211;2024 Annual Summer Meeting, in Aspen, Colorado, June 20 through 23, 2024; and the American Society for Dermatologic Surgery 2024 Annual Meeting, in Orlando, Florida, October 17 through 20, 2024.</p></fn><fn fn-type="financial-disclosure"><p>Disclosure statements are at the end of this article, following the correspondence information.</p></fn><fn fn-type="other"><p>Related digital media are available in the full-text version of the article on <ext-link xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xlink:href="www.PRSJournal.com" ext-link-type="uri">www.PRSJournal.com</ext-link>.</p></fn><fn fn-type="other"><p>Read classic pairings, listen to the podcast, and join a live Q&amp;A to round out your Journal Club Discussion. Click on the Journal Club icon on <ext-link xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xlink:href="www.PRSJournal.com" ext-link-type="uri">PRSJournal.com</ext-link> to join the #PRSJournalClub.</p></fn></fn-group><ref-list><title>REFERENCES</title><ref id="R1"><label>1.</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Breithaupt</surname><given-names>AD</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Jones</surname><given-names>DH</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Braz</surname><given-names>A</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Narins</surname><given-names>R</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Weinkle</surname><given-names>S</given-names></name></person-group>. <article-title>Anatomical basis for safe and effective volumization of the temple.</article-title><source>Dermatol Surg</source>. <year>2015</year>;<volume>41</volume>:<fpage>S278</fpage>&#8211;<lpage>S283</lpage>.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">26618454</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1097/DSS.0000000000000539</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="R2"><label>2.</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Juhasz</surname><given-names>ML</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Marmur</surname><given-names>ES</given-names></name></person-group>. <article-title>Temporal fossa defects: techniques for injecting hyaluronic acid filler and complications after hyaluronic acid filler injection.</article-title><source>J Cosmet Dermatol</source>. <year>2015</year>;<volume>14</volume>:<fpage>254</fpage>&#8211;<lpage>259</lpage>.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">26311237</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1111/jocd.12155</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="R3"><label>3.</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Moradi</surname><given-names>A</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Shirazi</surname><given-names>A</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Perez</surname><given-names>V</given-names></name></person-group>. <article-title>A guide to temporal fossa augmentation with small gel particle hyaluronic acid dermal filler.</article-title><source>J Drugs Dermatol</source>. <year>2011</year>;<volume>10</volume>:<fpage>673</fpage>&#8211;<lpage>676</lpage>.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">21637909</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="R4"><label>4.</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Rose</surname><given-names>AE</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Day</surname><given-names>D</given-names></name></person-group>. <article-title>Esthetic rejuvenation of the temple.</article-title><source>Clin Plast Surg</source>. <year>2013</year>;<volume>40</volume>:<fpage>77</fpage>&#8211;<lpage>89</lpage>.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">23186757</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1016/j.cps.2012.09.001</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="R5"><label>5.</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Kim</surname><given-names>S</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Matic</surname><given-names>DB</given-names></name></person-group>. <article-title>The anatomy of temporal hollowing: the superficial temporal fat pad.</article-title><source>J Craniofac Surg</source>. <year>2005</year>;<volume>16</volume>:<fpage>760</fpage>&#8211;<lpage>763</lpage>.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">16192853</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1097/01.scs.0000180010.83480.10</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="R6"><label>6.</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Ross</surname><given-names>JJ</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Malhotra</surname><given-names>R</given-names></name></person-group>. <article-title>Orbitofacial rejuvenation of temple hollowing with Perlane injectable filler.</article-title><source>Aesthet Surg J</source>. <year>2010</year>;<volume>30</volume>:<fpage>428</fpage>&#8211;<lpage>433</lpage>.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">20601570</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1177/1090820X10374099</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="R7"><label>7.</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Raspaldo</surname><given-names>H</given-names></name></person-group>. <article-title>Temporal rejuvenation with fillers: global faceculpture approach.</article-title><source>Dermatol Surg</source>. <year>2012</year>;<volume>38</volume>:<fpage>261</fpage>&#8211;<lpage>265</lpage>.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">22122524</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1111/j.1524-4725.2011.02218.x</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="R8"><label>8.</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Rihani</surname><given-names>J</given-names></name></person-group>. <article-title>Aesthetics and rejuvenation of the temple.</article-title><source>Facial Plast Surg</source>. <year>2018</year>;<volume>34</volume>:<fpage>159</fpage>&#8211;<lpage>163</lpage>.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">29631286</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1055/s-0038-1636921</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="R9"><label>9.</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Cavallini</surname><given-names>M</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Gazzola</surname><given-names>R</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Metalla</surname><given-names>M</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Vaienti</surname><given-names>L</given-names></name></person-group>. <article-title>The role of hyaluronidase in the treatment of complications from hyaluronic acid dermal fillers.</article-title><source>Aesthet Surg J</source>. <year>2013</year>;<volume>33</volume>:<fpage>1167</fpage>&#8211;<lpage>1174</lpage>.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">24197934</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1177/1090820X13511970</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="R10"><label>10.</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Carruthers</surname><given-names>J</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Carruthers</surname><given-names>A</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Tezel</surname><given-names>A</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Kraemer</surname><given-names>J</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Craik</surname><given-names>L</given-names></name></person-group>. <article-title>Volumizing with a 20-mg/mL smooth, highly cohesive, viscous hyaluronic acid filler and its role in facial rejuvenation therapy.</article-title><source>Dermatol Surg</source>. <year>2010</year>;<volume>36</volume>:<fpage>1886</fpage>&#8211;<lpage>1892</lpage>.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">20969666</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1111/j.1524-4725.2010.01778.x</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="R11"><label>11.</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Baumann</surname><given-names>LS</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Weisberg</surname><given-names>EM</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Mayans</surname><given-names>M</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Arcuri</surname><given-names>E</given-names></name></person-group>. <article-title>Open label study evaluating efficacy, safety, and effects on perception of age after injectable 20 mg/mL hyaluronic acid gel for volumization of facial temples.</article-title><source>J Drugs Dermatol</source>. <year>2019</year>;<volume>18</volume>:<fpage>67</fpage>&#8211;<lpage>74</lpage>.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">30681799</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="R12"><label>12.</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Bertossi</surname></name></person-group>. <article-title>Non surgical facial reshaping using MD codes.</article-title><source>J Cosmet Dermatol</source>. <year>2020</year>;<volume>19</volume>:<fpage>3456</fpage>&#8211;<lpage>3456</lpage>.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">32623790</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1111/jocd.13596</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="R13"><label>13.</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Casabona</surname><given-names>G</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Frank</surname><given-names>K</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Moellhoff</surname><given-names>N</given-names></name><etal/></person-group>. <article-title>Full-face effects of temporal volumizing and temporal lifting techniques.</article-title><source>J Cosmet Dermatol</source>. <year>2020</year>;<volume>19</volume>:<fpage>2830</fpage>&#8211;<lpage>2837</lpage>.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">32946624</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1111/jocd.13728</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="R14"><label>14.</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Ho</surname><given-names>D</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Jagdeo</surname><given-names>J</given-names></name></person-group>. <article-title>Safety and efficacy of a volumizing hyaluronic acid filler for treatment of HIV-associated facial lipoatrophy.</article-title><source>JAMA Dermatol</source>. <year>2017</year>;<volume>153</volume>:<fpage>61</fpage>&#8211;<lpage>65</lpage>.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">27806168</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1001/jamadermatol.2016.3827</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="R15"><label>15.</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Ueland</surname><given-names>HO</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Nilsen</surname><given-names>RM</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Rodahl</surname><given-names>E</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Jensen</surname><given-names>SA</given-names></name></person-group>. <article-title>Hyaluronic acid is superior to autologous fat for treatment of temporal hollowing after lateral orbital wall decompression: a prospective interventional trial.</article-title><source>J Plast Reconstr Aesthet Surg</source>. <year>2019</year>;<volume>72</volume>:<fpage>973</fpage>&#8211;<lpage>981</lpage>.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">30679116</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1016/j.bjps.2018.12.031</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="R16"><label>16.</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Sykes</surname><given-names>JM</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Cotofana</surname><given-names>S</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Trevidic</surname><given-names>P</given-names></name><etal/></person-group>. <article-title>Upper face: clinical anatomy and regional approaches with injectable fillers.</article-title><source>Plast Reconstr Surg</source>. <year>2015</year>;<volume>136</volume>:<fpage>204S</fpage>&#8211;<lpage>218S</lpage>.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">26441101</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1097/PRS.0000000000001830</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="R17"><label>17.</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Carruthers</surname><given-names>J</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Jones</surname><given-names>D</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Hardas</surname><given-names>B</given-names></name><etal/></person-group>. <article-title>Development and validation of a photonumeric scale for evaluation of volume deficit of the temple.</article-title><source>Dermatol Surg</source>. <year>2016</year>;<volume>42</volume>:<fpage>S203</fpage>&#8211;<lpage>S210</lpage>.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">27661742</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1097/DSS.0000000000000848</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC5671790</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="R18"><label>18.</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Kaur</surname><given-names>MN</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Baradaran</surname><given-names>S</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Patel</surname><given-names>V</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Klassen</surname><given-names>AF</given-names></name></person-group>. <article-title>Measuring outcomes for temple hollowing treatment: content validity of new and existing FACE-Q scales.</article-title><source>J Cosmet Dermatol</source>. <year>2022</year>;<volume>21</volume>:<fpage>167</fpage>&#8211;<lpage>175</lpage>.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">34855266</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1111/jocd.14646</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="R19"><label>19.</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Pusic</surname><given-names>AL</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Klassen</surname><given-names>AF</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Scott</surname><given-names>AM</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Cano</surname><given-names>SJ</given-names></name></person-group>. <article-title>Development and psychometric evaluation of the FACE-Q satisfaction with appearance scale: a new patient-reported outcome instrument for facial aesthetics patients.</article-title><source>Clin Plast Surg</source>. <year>2013</year>;<volume>40</volume>:<fpage>249</fpage>&#8211;<lpage>260</lpage>.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">23506765</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1016/j.cps.2012.12.001</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="R20"><label>20.</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Kaur</surname><given-names>MN</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Patel</surname><given-names>VD</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Leung</surname><given-names>KX</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Klassen</surname><given-names>AF</given-names></name></person-group>. <article-title>Psychometric validation of the FACE-Q Aesthetics Satisfaction with Temples scale in individuals seeking minimally invasive treatment to improve temple hollowing.</article-title><source>J Cosmet Dermatol</source>. <year>2024</year>;<volume>23</volume>:<fpage>3517</fpage>&#8211;<lpage>3524</lpage>.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">39101674</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1111/jocd.16450</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="R21"><label>21.</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Goodman</surname><given-names>GJ</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Swift</surname><given-names>A</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Remington</surname><given-names>BK</given-names></name></person-group>. <article-title>Current concepts in the use of Voluma, Volift, and Volbella.</article-title><source>Plast Reconstr Surg</source>. <year>2015</year>;<volume>136</volume>:<fpage>139S</fpage>&#8211;<lpage>148S</lpage>.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">26441094</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1097/PRS.0000000000001734</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="R22"><label>22.</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Jones</surname><given-names>D</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Murphy</surname><given-names>DK</given-names></name></person-group>. <article-title>Volumizing hyaluronic acid filler for midface volume deficit: 2-year results from a pivotal single-blind randomized controlled study.</article-title><source>Dermatol Surg</source>. <year>2013</year>;<volume>39</volume>:<fpage>1602</fpage>&#8211;<lpage>1612</lpage>.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">24093664</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1111/dsu.12343</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="R23"><label>23.</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Carruthers</surname><given-names>J</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Humphrey</surname><given-names>S</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Beleznay</surname><given-names>K</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Carruthers</surname><given-names>A</given-names></name></person-group>. <article-title>Suggested injection zone for soft tissue fillers in the temple?</article-title><source>Dermatol Surg</source>. <year>2017</year>;<volume>43</volume>:<fpage>756</fpage>&#8211;<lpage>757</lpage>.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">28441304</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1097/DSS.0000000000001057</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="R24"><label>24.</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>de Maio</surname><given-names>M</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Swift</surname><given-names>A</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Signorini</surname><given-names>M</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Fagien</surname><given-names>S</given-names></name></person-group>; <collab>Aesthetic Leaders in Facial Aesthetics Consensus Committee</collab>. <article-title>Facial assessment and injection guide for botulinum toxin and injectable hyaluronic acid fillers: focus on the upper face.</article-title><source>Plast Reconstr Surg</source>. <year>2017</year>;<volume>140</volume>:<fpage>265e</fpage>&#8211;<lpage>276e</lpage>.<pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1097/PRS.0000000000003544</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">28746271</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="R25"><label>25.</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Lee</surname><given-names>JG</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Yang</surname><given-names>HM</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Hu</surname><given-names>KS</given-names></name><etal/></person-group>. <article-title>Frontal branch of the superficial temporal artery: anatomical study and clinical implications regarding injectable treatments.</article-title><source>Surg Radiol Anat</source>. <year>2015</year>;<volume>37</volume>:<fpage>61</fpage>&#8211;<lpage>68</lpage>.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">24841991</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1007/s00276-014-1306-6</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="R26"><label>26.</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Yang</surname><given-names>HM</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Jung</surname><given-names>W</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Won</surname><given-names>SY</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Youn</surname><given-names>KH</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Hu</surname><given-names>KS</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Kim</surname><given-names>HJ</given-names></name></person-group>. <article-title>Anatomical study of medial zygomaticotemporal vein and its clinical implication regarding the injectable treatments.</article-title><source>Surg Radiol Anat</source>. <year>2015</year>;<volume>37</volume>:<fpage>175</fpage>&#8211;<lpage>180</lpage>.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">24996533</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1007/s00276-014-1337-z</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="R27"><label>27.</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Bae</surname><given-names>H</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Choi</surname><given-names>YJ</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Lee</surname><given-names>KL</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Gil</surname><given-names>YC</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Hu</surname><given-names>KS</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Kim</surname><given-names>HJ</given-names></name></person-group>. <article-title>The deep temporal arteries: anatomical study with application to augmentations procedures of the temple.</article-title><source>Clin Anat</source>. <year>2023</year>;<volume>36</volume>:<fpage>386</fpage>&#8211;<lpage>392</lpage>.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">36136301</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1002/ca.23952</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="R28"><label>28.</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Cotofana</surname><given-names>S</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Lachman</surname><given-names>N</given-names></name></person-group>. <article-title>Arteries of the face and their relevance for minimally invasive facial procedures: an anatomical review.</article-title><source>Plast Reconstr Surg</source>. <year>2019</year>;<volume>143</volume>:<fpage>416</fpage>&#8211;<lpage>426</lpage>.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">30688884</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1097/PRS.0000000000005201</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="R29"><label>29.</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Faria</surname><given-names>GEL</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Bastos</surname><given-names>AQ</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Vilela</surname><given-names>CL</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Zattar</surname><given-names>L</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Boggio</surname><given-names>RF</given-names></name></person-group>. <article-title>Safety of the inferolateral orbital access for filling the temporal region with the fanning technique.</article-title><source>J Cosmet Dermatol</source>. <year>2022</year>;<volume>21</volume>:<fpage>5569</fpage>&#8211;<lpage>5575</lpage>.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">35673959</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1111/jocd.15146</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="R30"><label>30.</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Lee</surname><given-names>W</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Park</surname><given-names>JW</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Yang</surname><given-names>EJ</given-names></name></person-group>. <article-title>Temple augmentation by injecting a hyaluronic acid filler between the superficial and deep temporal fasciae.</article-title><source>J Cosmet Dermatol</source>. <year>2022</year>;<volume>21</volume>:<fpage>4313</fpage>&#8211;<lpage>4318</lpage>.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">35435310</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1111/jocd.15004</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="R31"><label>31.</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Moradi</surname><given-names>A</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Watson</surname><given-names>J</given-names></name></person-group>. <article-title>Current concepts in filler injection.</article-title><source>Facial Plast Surg Clin North Am</source>. <year>2015</year>;<volume>23</volume>:<fpage>489</fpage>&#8211;<lpage>494</lpage>.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">26505545</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1016/j.fsc.2015.07.005</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="R32"><label>32.</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Surek</surname><given-names>CC</given-names></name></person-group>. <article-title>A new target for temple volumization? An anatomical and ultrasound-guided study of the intermediate temporal fat pad.</article-title><source>Aesthet Surg J</source>. <year>2021</year>;<volume>41</volume>:<fpage>1339</fpage>&#8211;<lpage>1343</lpage>.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">33630064</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1093/asj/sjaa425</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="R33"><label>33.</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Jones</surname><given-names>DH</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Fitzgerald</surname><given-names>R</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Cox</surname><given-names>SE</given-names></name><etal/></person-group>. <article-title>Preventing and treating adverse events of injectable fillers: evidence-based recommendations from the American Society for Dermatologic Surgery Multidisciplinary Task Force.</article-title><source>Dermatol Surg</source>. <year>2021</year>;<volume>47</volume>:<fpage>214</fpage>&#8211;<lpage>226</lpage>.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">33543879</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1097/DSS.0000000000002921</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="R34"><label>34.</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Cotofana</surname><given-names>S</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Koban</surname><given-names>KC</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Konstantin</surname><given-names>F</given-names></name><etal/></person-group>. <article-title>The surface-volume coefficient of the superficial and deep facial fat compartments: a cadaveric three-dimensional volumetric analysis.</article-title><source>Plast Reconstr Surg</source>. <year>2019</year>;<volume>143</volume>:<fpage>1605</fpage>&#8211;<lpage>1613</lpage>.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">30907804</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1097/PRS.0000000000005524</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="R35"><label>35.</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Moradi</surname><given-names>A</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Shirazi</surname><given-names>A</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Moradi</surname><given-names>J</given-names></name></person-group>. <article-title>A 12-month, prospective, evaluator-blinded study of small gel particle hyaluronic acid filler in the correction of temporal fossa volume loss.</article-title><source>J Drugs Dermatol</source>. <year>2013</year>;<volume>12</volume>:<fpage>470</fpage>&#8211;<lpage>475</lpage>.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">23652897</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="R36"><label>36.</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Pavicic</surname><given-names>T</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Sattler</surname><given-names>G</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Prager</surname><given-names>W</given-names></name><etal/></person-group>. <article-title>Safety of cohesive polydensified matrix cross-linked hyaluronic acid volumizing gel in temporal hollows and cheeks: a prospective, open-label, postmarket study.</article-title><source>Dermatol Surg</source>. <year>2021</year>;<volume>47</volume>:<fpage>1359</fpage>&#8211;<lpage>1364</lpage>.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">34417392</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1097/DSS.0000000000003176</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="R37"><label>37.</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Juhasz</surname><given-names>MLW</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Levin</surname><given-names>MK</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Marmur</surname><given-names>ES</given-names></name></person-group>. <article-title>Pilot study examining the safety and efficacy of calcium hydroxylapatite filler with integral lidocaine over a 12-month period to correct temporal fossa volume loss.</article-title><source>Dermatol Surg</source>. <year>2018</year>;<volume>44</volume>:<fpage>93</fpage>&#8211;<lpage>100</lpage>.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">28858938</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1097/DSS.0000000000001268</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="R38"><label>38.</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><collab>American Society of Plastic Surgeons</collab>. <article-title>Plastic surgery statistics report.</article-title> Published <year>2020</year>. <comment>Available at: <ext-link xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xlink:href="https://www.plasticsurgery.org/documents/news/statistics/2020/plastic-surgery-statistics-full-report-2020.pdf" ext-link-type="uri">https://www.plasticsurgery.org/documents/news/statistics/2020/plastic-surgery-statistics-full-report-2020.pdf</ext-link>. Accessed August 16, 2024.</comment></mixed-citation></ref></ref-list></back></article></pmc-articleset>