<?xml version="1.0"  ?><!DOCTYPE pmc-articleset PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD ARTICLE SET 2.0//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pmc/articleset/nlm-articleset-2.0.dtd"><pmc-articleset><article xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" xmlns:ali="http://www.niso.org/schemas/ali/1.0/" xml:lang="en" article-type="research-article" dtd-version="1.4"><processing-meta base-tagset="archiving" mathml-version="3.0" table-model="xhtml" tagset-family="jats"><restricted-by>pmc</restricted-by></processing-meta><front><journal-meta><journal-id journal-id-type="nlm-ta">Aesthet Surg J Open Forum</journal-id><journal-id journal-id-type="iso-abbrev">Aesthet Surg J Open Forum</journal-id><journal-id journal-id-type="pmc-domain-id">3943</journal-id><journal-id journal-id-type="pmc-domain">asjopen</journal-id><journal-id journal-id-type="publisher-id">asjopenforum</journal-id><journal-title-group><journal-title>Aesthetic Surgery Journal. Open Forum</journal-title></journal-title-group><issn pub-type="epub">2631-4797</issn><publisher><publisher-name>Oxford University Press</publisher-name></publisher></journal-meta><article-meta><article-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC12254949</article-id><article-id pub-id-type="pmcid-ver">PMC12254949.1</article-id><article-id pub-id-type="pmcaid">12254949</article-id><article-id pub-id-type="pmcaiid">12254949</article-id><article-id pub-id-type="pmid">40657559</article-id><article-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1093/asjof/ojaf061</article-id><article-id pub-id-type="publisher-id">ojaf061</article-id><article-version article-version-type="pmc-version">1</article-version><article-categories><subj-group subj-group-type="heading"><subject>Original Article</subject></subj-group><subj-group subj-group-type="category-taxonomy-collection"><subject>AcademicSubjects/MED00987</subject></subj-group><subj-group subj-group-type="category-taxonomy-collection"><subject>Asj/1</subject></subj-group></article-categories><title-group><article-title>A New Time-Saving Technique for Ultrasound-Guided Filler Injection: A 3-Year Retrospective Study</article-title></title-group><contrib-group><contrib contrib-type="author" corresp="yes"><contrib-id contrib-id-type="orcid" authenticated="false">https://orcid.org/0000-0001-7629-7777</contrib-id><name name-style="western"><surname>Teixeira</surname><given-names initials="DA">Danilo Augusto</given-names></name><degrees>MD, MSc</degrees><xref rid="FM1" ref-type="author-notes"/><xref rid="ojaf061-cor1" ref-type="corresp"/></contrib></contrib-group><author-notes><fn id="FM1"><p>Dr Teixeira is a dermatologist in private practice, Clinica P&#233;li, Goi&#226;nia, Goi&#225;s, Brazil.</p></fn><corresp id="ojaf061-cor1"><bold>Corresponding Author:</bold> Dr Danilo Augusto Teixeira, Alameda do Bosque, quadra 4, lote 8, Jardins Munique, Goiania, Goi&#225;s 74886075, Brazil. E-mail: <email>danilodermato@yahoo.com.br</email>; Instagram: <ext-link xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xlink:href="https://instagram.com/drdanilodermato" ext-link-type="uri">@drdanilodermato</ext-link></corresp></author-notes><pub-date pub-type="collection"><year>2025</year></pub-date><pub-date pub-type="epub" iso-8601-date="2025-06-16"><day>16</day><month>6</month><year>2025</year></pub-date><volume>7</volume><issue-id pub-id-type="pmc-issue-id">478988</issue-id><elocation-id>ojaf061</elocation-id><history><date date-type="editorial-decision"><day>29</day><month>5</month><year>2025</year></date><date date-type="corrected-typeset"><day>12</day><month>7</month><year>2025</year></date></history><pub-history><event event-type="pmc-release"><date><day>16</day><month>06</month><year>2025</year></date></event><event event-type="pmc-live"><date><day>12</day><month>07</month><year>2025</year></date></event><event event-type="pmc-last-change"><date iso-8601-date="2025-07-14 15:25:24.943"><day>14</day><month>07</month><year>2025</year></date></event></pub-history><permissions><copyright-statement>&#169; The Author(s) 2025. Published by Oxford University Press on behalf of The Aesthetic Society.</copyright-statement><copyright-year>2025</copyright-year><license><ali:license_ref specific-use="textmining" content-type="ccbynclicense">https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/</ali:license_ref><license-p>This is an Open Access article distributed under the terms of the Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial License (<ext-link xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" ext-link-type="uri" xlink:href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/">https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/</ext-link>), which permits non-commercial re-use, distribution, and reproduction in any medium, provided the original work is properly cited. For commercial re-use, please contact reprints@oup.com for reprints and translation rights for reprints. All other permissions can be obtained through our RightsLink service via the Permissions link on the article page on our site&#8212;for further information please contact journals.permissions@oup.com.</license-p></license></permissions><self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" content-type="pmc-pdf" xlink:href="ojaf061.pdf"/><self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xlink:href="ojaf061.pdf"/><abstract><title>Abstract</title><sec id="s1"><title>Background</title><p>The use of hyaluronic acid (HA) for facial rejuvenation is increasing every year. However, complications can be disastrous because they can cause necrosis, blindness, and stroke. In 2021, the author described a 3-step technique to prevent intravascular injections, but it is time-consuming and difficult to implement.</p></sec><sec id="s2"><title>Objectives</title><p>The aim of the authors of this article is to propose a quicker and simpler ultrasound-guided filling technique using high-frequency ultrasound to avoid intravascular injections.</p></sec><sec id="s3"><title>Methods</title><p>The investigator introduced a vascular mapping technique that takes &lt;3&#8197;min to identify the position of the arteries to introduce the cannula or needle in a different plane. The investigator retrospectively reviewed 503 patients who were injected with 1109&#8197;cc of HA utilizing vascular mapping in different areas of the face to evaluate vascular complications.</p></sec><sec id="s4"><title>Results</title><p>The most common injection sites were the nasolabial fold (324 cases), marionette lines (157), and lips (106). The chin was injected in 48 patients, the temple in 34, the nose in 26, and the glabella in 23. In 34.7%, 13.2%, and 2.9% of the glabella, nasolabial folds, and temple, respectively, arteries with significant diameters (&gt;0.8&#8197;mm) were present at the injection sites. There were no cases of vascular complications.</p></sec><sec id="s5"><title>Conclusions</title><p>Except for the glabella, only a small percentage of patients have arteries with larger calibers in the injection area. These arteries can be identified before the procedure using quick Doppler ultrasonography (DUS). The use of DUS to map the site of filler injection can help physicians reduce the risk of intravascular injection.</p></sec><sec id="s6"><title>Level of Evidence: 4 (Therapeutic)</title><p>
<inline-graphic xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xlink:href="ojaf061il1.jpg"/>
</p></sec></abstract><counts><page-count count="6"/></counts><custom-meta-group><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-status-qastatus</meta-name><meta-value>0</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-status-live</meta-name><meta-value>yes</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-status-embargo</meta-name><meta-value>no</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-status-released</meta-name><meta-value>yes</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-open-access</meta-name><meta-value>yes</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-olf</meta-name><meta-value>no</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-manuscript</meta-name><meta-value>no</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-legally-suppressed</meta-name><meta-value>no</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-has-pdf</meta-name><meta-value>yes</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-has-supplement</meta-name><meta-value>no</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-pdf-only</meta-name><meta-value>no</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-suppress-copyright</meta-name><meta-value>no</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-is-real-version</meta-name><meta-value>no</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-is-scanned-article</meta-name><meta-value>no</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-preprint</meta-name><meta-value>no</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-in-epmc</meta-name><meta-value>yes</meta-value></custom-meta></custom-meta-group></article-meta></front><body><p>The use of soft tissue fillers for facial rejuvenation continues to increase every year. The global market for dermal fillers is projected to reach $10.16 billion by 2032.<sup><xref rid="ojaf061-B1" ref-type="bibr">1</xref></sup> Although filler injections are relatively easy to perform, they carry risks and can lead to severe complications. Vascular complications, such as skin necrosis, blindness, and stroke, are among the most serious risks associated with filler injections.<sup><xref rid="ojaf061-B2" ref-type="bibr">2</xref>,<xref rid="ojaf061-B3" ref-type="bibr">3</xref></sup> A recent review reported 365 new cases of ocular complications secondary to fillers.<sup><xref rid="ojaf061-B1" ref-type="bibr">1</xref></sup></p><p>Even with a strong understanding of facial anatomy, professionals still face the risk of causing vascular complications because of anatomical variations. The probable cause of these complications is the intravascular injection of filler, which can lead to vascular obstruction, subsequent necrosis, and, in some cases, retrograde flow to the arteries supplying the retina or the brain, resulting in blindness or stroke.<sup><xref rid="ojaf061-B4" ref-type="bibr">4</xref></sup></p><p>Doppler ultrasonography (DUS) can be utilized to visualize facial vessels without side effects and can help minimize the risks associated with intravascular injection of facial fillers.<sup><xref rid="ojaf061-B3" ref-type="bibr">3</xref></sup></p><p>The main named arteries of the face have a diameter &gt;0.8&#8197;mm, whereas the most commonly utilized cannulas in dermatological procedures are 22&#8197;G (0.64&#8197;mm) and 25&#8197;G (0.57&#8197;mm). It is important to utilize a high-frequency ultrasound transducer to visualize vessels of this caliber.</p><p>Our group previously reported a 3-step technique for hyaluronic acid (HA) filler injection guided by DUS, which increases safety against vascular occlusion.<sup><xref rid="ojaf061-B5" ref-type="bibr">5</xref></sup> This technique involved previous arterial mapping, real-time ultrasound-guided filling, and postinjection assessment of perfusion. This technique took 5 to 20&#8197;min for real-time visualization and 1 to 3&#8197;min for perfusion assessment.<sup><xref rid="ojaf061-B5" ref-type="bibr">5</xref></sup></p><p>The main challenges of this method are the time required to perform the technique, the difficulty in learning it, and the need to simultaneously handle the transducer and the syringe. To save time and maintain safety with a simpler method, the investigator proposes a new filling technique to avoid intravascular injections with just DUS mapping at the site of filling.</p><sec sec-type="methods" id="ojaf061-s1"><title>METHODS</title><p>This study is a case series that retrospectively reviewed the medical records of consecutive patients who were injected with HA in the face at a private clinic from January 2022 to December 2024 by a single dermatologist. Informed consent for the procedure was obtained from all participating patients before the procedures. The study was conducted in accordance with the principles outlined in the Declaration of Helsinki.</p><p>Cross-linked HA gels (Rennova Ultra Volume-Lido; Rennova Deep Line-Lido [Humedix Co., Seoul, South Korea]; Restylane Lyft Lidocaine [Q-Med AB, Uppsala, Sweden]) were utilized for injection. The author utilized the Clarius L20 (Clarius Mobile Health Corp., Vancouver, Canada&#8212;20&#8197;MHz handheld transducer; dimensions: 147 &#215; 76 &#215; 32&#8197;mm, weight: 290&#8197;g) ultrasound to perform the examinations before injection.</p><p>Patients aged 18 or older with a desire to improve the cosmetic appearance of their face were included.</p><p>Exclusion criteria applied to those with classical clinical contraindications for the use of HA, including autoimmune diseases, use of immunosuppressive drugs, skin infections, active local inflammation at the injection site, pregnancy, breastfeeding, or known allergy to HA.</p><p>The following data were collected: age, sex, anatomical injection sites, volume injected, and technique utilized (needle vs cannula).</p><sec id="ojaf061-s1.1"><title>Technique</title><p>The investigator presents a DUS HA filling technique, consistently utilized on every consecutive patient who visited the clinic (503 patients) over the past 3 years, employing a 20&#8197;MHz handheld transducer and implemented through a 2-step process.</p><list list-type="order"><list-item><p>Arterial mapping before injection (focused on the site to be injected): The goal was to map the target area, identifying the trajectory of vessels and their depth. The transducer was positioned specifically over the area intended for filler injection, focusing on identifying whether there was any artery in that location rather than scanning the entire face. No marks with pens were used to identify the path of the vessels or the entry point of the cannula or needle. It usually took 1 to 3&#8197;min depending on the number of injected areas.</p></list-item><list-item><p>Filler injection (without the transducer): After removing the gel, guide holes were made using a 21&#8197;G needle at lateral safe entry points, depending on the injection site. The author's preference was to inject in the subdermal plane or as superficially as possible. The injection was performed according to the author's technique but adjusted based on vessel depth. If the vessel lay in a superficial plane, a 22&#8197;G cannula was inserted deeper into the subcutaneous plane. If the vessel was in a deeper plane, the cannula was placed more superficially. An exception was the glabella, where a 27&#8197;G needle was utilized.</p></list-item></list><p>When an artery with a large diameter (&gt;0.8&#8197;mm) was found in the plane of injection (usually the subcutaneous plane), a picture of the DUS was taken, or the diameter of the artery was recorded. In other cases, no pictures were taken because the intention of the technique was to increase safety, not to perform a DUS examination. If the artery was found in deeper planes, the supraperiosteal plane or intrafascial plane (in the case of the temple), the author did not consider it a high-risk case because the preferred plane of injection was subdermal.</p><p>All the patients were contacted by phone the next day and were evaluated 14 days later.</p><p>The DUS utilized visualizes vessels with a diameter of 0.1&#8197;mm or greater.<sup><xref rid="ojaf061-B5" ref-type="bibr">5</xref></sup> The 22&#8197;G cannula has a diameter of 0.64&#8197;mm, and the 27&#8197;G needle measures 0.35&#8197;mm. This means that all the vessels that could be intravascularly injected were identified before the procedure.</p></sec></sec><sec sec-type="results" id="ojaf061-s2"><title>RESULTS</title><p>Between January 2022 and December 2024, 503 patients (447 females, 56 males) between 18 and 76 years old (mean: 47.49 years) were injected with 1109&#8197;mL of HA in different areas of the face by the author, using the described technique. The mean volume utilized for each procedure was 2.20&#8197;mL for women and 2.44&#8197;mL for men (1&#8197;mL minimum and 10&#8197;mL maximum; <xref rid="ojaf061-T1" ref-type="table">Table 1</xref>).</p><table-wrap position="float" id="ojaf061-T1" orientation="portrait"><label>Table 1.</label><caption><p>Patients Characteristics</p></caption><table frame="hsides" rules="groups"><colgroup span="1"><col align="left" span="1"/><col align="left" span="1"/></colgroup><thead><tr><th align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Variable</th><th align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Description</th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Age (years)</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Range: 18-76 years, mean: 47.49, median: 48, SD: 12.89</td></tr><tr><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Sex</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">447 females (88.87%), 56 males (11.13%)</td></tr><tr><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Injection technique</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Needle: 4.57%, cannula: 95.43%</td></tr><tr><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Average volume of hyaluronic acid</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Female: 2.2&#8197;mL (1-8&#8197;mL), male: 2.44&#8197;mL (1-10&#8197;mL)</td></tr></tbody></table><table-wrap-foot><fn id="tblfn1"><p>SD, standard deviation.</p></fn></table-wrap-foot></table-wrap><p>The most common sites of injection were the nasolabial fold (324 cases), marionette lines (157), and lips (106). The chin was injected in 48 patients, the temple in 34, the nose in 26, and the glabella in 23 (<xref rid="ojaf061-F1" ref-type="fig">Figures 1</xref>, <xref rid="ojaf061-F2" ref-type="fig">2</xref>).</p><fig position="float" id="ojaf061-F1" fig-type="figure" orientation="portrait"><label>Figure 1.</label><caption><p>Number of patients injected in each region.</p></caption><graphic xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" position="float" orientation="portrait" xlink:href="ojaf061f1.jpg"/></fig><fig position="float" id="ojaf061-F2" fig-type="figure" orientation="portrait"><label>Figure 2.</label><caption><p>Injection sites by percentage of patients.</p></caption><graphic xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" position="float" orientation="portrait" xlink:href="ojaf061f2.jpg"/></fig><p>The glabella was the only site injected with a 27&#8197;G needle; all other sites were injected with a 22&#8197;G cannula.</p><p>Filling was not contraindicated in any patient because of ultrasound findings.</p><p>In 43 cases (13.2%) of nasolabial folds, the investigator found the facial artery with a significant diameter (0.8-1.8&#8197;mm; mean 1.2&#8197;mm) at the injection site. The diameter varied significantly, and sometimes the long axis of the facial artery aligned with the nasolabial fold (<xref rid="ojaf061-F3" ref-type="fig">Figures 3</xref>, <xref rid="ojaf061-F4" ref-type="fig">4</xref>). Two patients had experienced intravascular injections with other physicians before (<xref rid="ojaf061-F5" ref-type="fig">Figures 5</xref>, <xref rid="ojaf061-F6" ref-type="fig">6</xref>). In these cases, the arteries had diameters &gt;0.8&#8197;mm, and the investigator injected in the subdermal plane with a 22&#8197;G cannula. These patients showed no signs of bruising or hematomas.</p><fig position="float" id="ojaf061-F3" fig-type="figure" orientation="portrait"><label>Figure 3.</label><caption><p>Patient 1, female, 42 years old&#8212;Doppler ultrasound of the right nasolabial fold (transducer along the sulcus)&#8212;facial artery transverse to the nasolabial fold (0.9&#8197;mm in diameter). Injection in the subdermal plane, above the artery, with a 22&#8197;G cannula.</p></caption><graphic xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" position="float" orientation="portrait" xlink:href="ojaf061f3.jpg"/></fig><fig position="float" id="ojaf061-F4" fig-type="figure" orientation="portrait"><label>Figure 4.</label><caption><p>Patient 2, female, 35 years old&#8212;Doppler ultrasound of the right nasolabial fold (transducer along the sulcus)&#8212;facial artery along the nasolabial fold (1&#8197;mm in diameter). Injection in the subcutaneous plane, below the artery, with a 22&#8197;G cannula.</p></caption><graphic xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" position="float" orientation="portrait" xlink:href="ojaf061f4.jpg"/></fig><fig position="float" id="ojaf061-F5" fig-type="figure" orientation="portrait"><label>Figure 5.</label><caption><p>Patient 3, female, 46 years old&#8212;Doppler ultrasound of the left nasolabial fold (transducer along the sulcus)&#8212;facial artery in the supraperiosteal plane (0.8&#8197;mm in diameter). This patient had experienced an intravascular injection with another doctor before. Injection in the subdermal plane, above the artery.</p></caption><graphic xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" position="float" orientation="portrait" xlink:href="ojaf061f5.jpg"/></fig><fig position="float" id="ojaf061-F6" fig-type="figure" orientation="portrait"><label>Figure 6.</label><caption><p>Patient 4, female, 37 years old&#8212;Doppler ultrasound of the left nasolabial fold (transducer along the sulcus)&#8212;facial artery along the nasolabial fold (1.4&#8197;mm in diameter). This patient had experienced an intravascular injection with another doctor before. Injection in the subcutaneous plane, below the artery, with a 22&#8197;G cannula.</p></caption><graphic xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" position="float" orientation="portrait" xlink:href="ojaf061f6.jpg"/></fig><p>For the temple, in only 1 case (2.9%), the investigator found a branch of the superficial temporal artery in the subcutaneous plane. All 34 patients were injected in the subcutaneous plane, and the superficial temporal artery was observed in the superficial temporal fascia (below the subcutaneous plane) with varying diameters in all of them (<xref rid="ojaf061-F7" ref-type="fig">Figures 7</xref>, <xref rid="ojaf061-F8" ref-type="fig">8</xref>).</p><fig position="float" id="ojaf061-F7" fig-type="figure" orientation="portrait"><label>Figure 7.</label><caption><p>Patient 5, female, 49 years old&#8212;Doppler ultrasound of the left temple&#8212;a branch of the superficial temporal artery (0.9&#8197;mm in diameter) in the subcutaneous plane and the main artery under the superficial temporal fascia (1.1&#8197;mm in diameter). Injection in the subdermal plane, above the artery, with a 22&#8197;G cannula.</p></caption><graphic xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" position="float" orientation="portrait" xlink:href="ojaf061f7.jpg"/></fig><fig position="float" id="ojaf061-F8" fig-type="figure" orientation="portrait"><label>Figure 8.</label><caption><p>Patient 6, female, 45 years old&#8212;Doppler ultrasound of the left temple&#8212;superficial temporal artery in the superficial temporal fascia (1.8&#8197;mm in diameter). Injection in the subdermal plane, above the artery, with a 22&#8197;G cannula.</p></caption><graphic xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" position="float" orientation="portrait" xlink:href="ojaf061f8.jpg"/></fig><p>In the glabella, arteries of different calibers (starting from 0.1&#8197;mm, branches of the supratrochlear artery) were observed in the wrinkles, with 8 cases (34.7%) showing the supratrochlear artery measuring &gt;0.8&#8197;mm (0.8-1.6&#8197;mm; mean: 1.08&#8197;mm; <xref rid="ojaf061-F9" ref-type="fig">Figure 9</xref>).</p><fig position="float" id="ojaf061-F9" fig-type="figure" orientation="portrait"><label>Figure 9.</label><caption><p>Patient 7, male, 52 years old&#8212;Doppler ultrasound of the glabella&#8212;supratrochlear artery measuring 1&#8197;mm in the left glabellar wrinkle. Injection in the subdermal plane, above the artery, with a 27&#8197;G needle.</p></caption><graphic xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" position="float" orientation="portrait" xlink:href="ojaf061f9.jpg"/></fig><p>In other regions, the proportion of arteries &gt;0.8&#8197;mm in the site and plane of injection were marionette lines (3.18%), tear trough (7.5%), nose (19.2%), malar (0%), mandible (0%&#8212;the facial artery was found in the supraperiosteal plane, and the author injected in the subdermal plane), supralabial (0%), and chin (8.3%).</p><p>There were no cases of intravascular injection or vascular compression following these 1109&#8197;cc of injections.</p></sec><sec sec-type="discussion" id="ojaf061-s3"><title>DISCUSSION</title><p>The use of DUS to guide filler injections has been increasing in recent years. Conventional ultrasound-guided techniques involve positioning the needle or cannula tip at the desired location and holding it steady to administer a bolus of medication.<sup><xref rid="ojaf061-B6" ref-type="bibr">6</xref></sup></p><p>This group had already published a 3-step HA filling technique to prevent vascular events in 2021.<sup><xref rid="ojaf061-B5" ref-type="bibr">5</xref></sup> The steps consisted of previous mapping, real-time ultrasound-guided filling, and perfusion assessment. The second step of this method&#8212;real-time ultrasound-guided filling&#8212;involved the injector inserting the cannula, placing the transducer above it, and locating the image of the cannula and the artery. This was the most challenging step to perform and typically took 5 to 20&#8197;min, depending on the number of areas injected. Following this, in some cases, the injector would evaluate arterial perfusion to rule out the possibility of vascular compression. This additional step usually required 1 to 3&#8197;min.<sup><xref rid="ojaf061-B5" ref-type="bibr">5</xref></sup> Therefore, the time-consuming nature of the 3-step technique and the challenges in executing it restricted its use in daily practice.</p><p>During the 3 years that the investigator performed the 3-step technique with real-time visualization using DUS, the cannula placement inside the artery proved very difficult, even in arteries with larger diameters and when the cannula inadvertently touched the artery wall (<xref rid="ojaf061-F10" ref-type="fig">Figure 10</xref>). Also, the investigator learned how to insert the cannula at a different plane from the artery, without the need for visualization and measuring with DUS.</p><fig position="float" id="ojaf061-F10" fig-type="figure" orientation="portrait"><label>Figure 10.</label><caption><p>Patient 8, female, 44 years old&#8212;Doppler ultrasound of the right nasolabial fold&#8212;cannula touching the wall of a 1.2&#8197;mm facial artery. In this case, the artery was not perforated and there was no hematoma or bruise.</p></caption><graphic xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" position="float" orientation="portrait" xlink:href="ojaf061f10.jpg"/></fig><p>Another discovery was the absence of vascular compression even when the HA was all around the artery. This finding was presented in the authors&#8217; first publication in 2021.<sup><xref rid="ojaf061-B5" ref-type="bibr">5</xref></sup></p><p>These discoveries led the investigator to question the need for Steps 2 and 3 in the investigator's previous technique. As a result, the investigator began only mapping the area before injecting to determine the correct plane for placing the cannula or needle, the actual technique. This modification saved the investigator approximately&#8764;6 to 23&#8197;min.</p><p>Analyzing the complications, in a 2022 publication, the nose (36.5%), glabella (27%), forehead (20.2%), and nasolabial fold (7.3%) were the most common sites associated with visual loss.<sup><xref rid="ojaf061-B2" ref-type="bibr">2</xref></sup> In cases of facial skin necrosis, the facial artery was involved in 58% of the cases.<sup><xref rid="ojaf061-B7" ref-type="bibr">7</xref></sup> Other publications showed that the highest-risk injection sites for skin necrosis included the nasal region (50.4%), temple (13.9%), and forehead (9.6%).<sup><xref rid="ojaf061-B8" ref-type="bibr">8</xref></sup> These intravascular injection cases involved named arteries (supratrochlear, facial, superficial temporal, labial, and dorsal nasal arteries), which, according to the literature, have larger diameters, usually &gt;0.8&#8197;mm.<sup><xref rid="ojaf061-B9" ref-type="bibr">9-11</xref></sup></p><p>Clinicians typically rely on their anatomical knowledge and preinjection aspiration to prevent intravascular injections. The effectiveness of preinjection aspiration depends on the viscosity of the filler and the injection site, but it is unlikely to completely eliminate the risk of embolization.<sup><xref rid="ojaf061-B12" ref-type="bibr">12</xref></sup></p><p>Another perspective is that the cannula is considered safer and may reduce the risk of vascular complications. It has been reported that using a cannula is generally safer than needle injections.<sup><xref rid="ojaf061-B13" ref-type="bibr">13</xref></sup> However, Zhang et al found that the safety of the cannula depends on the injection site. They highlight that the cannula might carry a greater risk of vision loss compared with the needle, particularly when used in the nasal area. According to their data, the nasal region is more dangerous for filler injections, and notably, 10 out of 16 cases of vision loss caused by nasal injections involved the use of a cannula.<sup><xref rid="ojaf061-B8" ref-type="bibr">8</xref></sup> The article did not inform the caliber of the cannulas used. A 22&#8197;G cannula poses less risk than 25 or 27&#8197;G, which can carry risks similar to needles. The increased risk with the cannula could be linked to the filler being injected in alignment with the flow of nasal blood vessels, which leads to the ophthalmic artery system when the cannula is inserted at the nasal tip and advanced along the dorsum.<sup><xref rid="ojaf061-B14" ref-type="bibr">14</xref></sup></p><p>Except for the glabella, only a small percentage of patients have larger vessels (facial artery, 1.7-3.6&#8197;mm; labial artery, 1.1&#8197;mm; supratrochlear artery, 0.8&#8197;mm) at the injection site, and in a large proportion of patients, the investigator did not visualize any artery at the injection site (the only exception was the glabella).<sup><xref rid="ojaf061-B9" ref-type="bibr">9-11</xref></sup> You must apply more pressure and be at the exact plane to penetrate the artery.<sup><xref rid="ojaf061-B15" ref-type="bibr">15</xref></sup> These cases of arteries with a larger caliber are the real risk of intravascular injections, not the small perforators (&lt;0.1&#8197;mm) not visible by DUS, and you will be aware of them before performing the procedure. With this method, you can visualize the plane of the artery before injecting and plan more accurately how you should inject to ensure greater safety. This was the exact technique that the author used on the 2 patients who had previously experienced intravascular injections in the nasolabial fold with other clinicians.</p><p>This new method consumes less time, does not require sterilized gel, and is easier to perform compared with the previous 3-step technique.</p><p>One limitation of this study is that the most dangerous areas for visual loss were less frequently injected in this case series. Although there is only 1 article where the authors describe glabellar wrinkle correction using Doppler ultrasound before injection with more patients (42 patients) than this one (23 patients).<sup><xref rid="ojaf061-B16" ref-type="bibr">16</xref></sup> In the nose, there is 1 study published with only 12 cases of Doppler ultrasound-guided filler, and in this case series, there are 26 patients.<sup><xref rid="ojaf061-B17" ref-type="bibr">17</xref></sup> Lastly, there are 2 papers about ultrasound scanning of the temple with 1 and 30 patients, and in this paper, there are 34 cases.<sup><xref rid="ojaf061-B6" ref-type="bibr">6</xref>,<xref rid="ojaf061-B18" ref-type="bibr">18</xref></sup></p><p>Another disadvantage is the need for specialized equipment and experience with ultrasound use. The cost of acquiring the DUS machine could be an obstacle to injectors, although new handheld equipment is emerging with affordable prices. Different pressures applied during ultrasound scanning can influence the visualization of vascular structures. Excessive pressure may compress vessels, and insufficient pressure may result in inadequate contact between the transducer and the skin, leading to difficulty in identifying vascular structures.<sup><xref rid="ojaf061-B17" ref-type="bibr">17</xref></sup> The sensitivity of the Clarius L20 could be a limitation in visualizing all the arteries, although it proved to be safe during &gt;1000 injections.</p><p>Other limitations are the total number of patients (503) and the fact that this is a single injector's experience.</p><p>It is important to emphasize that the author is a dermatologist with no residency in radiology or ultrasound. Daily practice on every patient, as well as the constant study required for good practice in any medical specialty, was the only training that the author utilized to implement the technique. The learning curve is not easy, but it is feasible for injectors to master.</p><p>Further validation of the author&#8217;s findings could be achieved through additional multicenter studies involving diverse populations and injectors.</p></sec><sec sec-type="conclusions" id="ojaf061-s4"><title>CONCLUSIONS</title><p>The use of DUS is becoming more common in injectors&#8217; offices. Except for the glabella, only a small percentage of patients have arteries with larger calibers in the injection area. These arteries can be identified before the procedure using quick DUS. The investigator believes that using DUS to map the site of filler injections helps reduce the risk of intravascular injection when correct technique is utilized, and it is possible for injectors to perform effectively with daily practice.</p></sec></body><back><sec id="ojaf061-s5"><title>Disclosures</title><p>The authors declared no potential conflicts of interest with respect to the research, authorship, and publication of this article.</p></sec><sec id="ojaf061-s6"><title>Funding</title><p>The authors received no financial support for the research, authorship, and publication of this article.</p></sec><ref-list id="ref1"><title>REFERENCES</title><ref id="ojaf061-B1"><label>1</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><string-name name-style="western"><surname>Doyon</surname> &#160;<given-names>VC</given-names></string-name>, <string-name name-style="western"><surname>Liu</surname> &#160;<given-names>C</given-names></string-name>, <string-name name-style="western"><surname>Fitzgerald</surname> &#160;<given-names>R</given-names></string-name>, <etal>et al</etal></person-group> &#160;<article-title>Update on blindness from filler: review of prognostic factors, management approaches, and a century of published cases</article-title>. <source>Aesthet Surg J</source>. <year>2024</year>;<volume>44</volume>:<fpage>1091</fpage>&#8211;<lpage>1104</lpage>. doi: <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1093/asj/sjae091</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">38630871</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="ojaf061-B2"><label>2</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><string-name name-style="western"><surname>Kato</surname> &#160;<given-names>JM</given-names></string-name>, <string-name name-style="western"><surname>Matayoshi</surname> &#160;<given-names>S</given-names></string-name></person-group>. <article-title>Visual loss after aesthetic facial filler injection: a literature review on an ophthalmologic issue</article-title>. <source>Arq Bras Oftalmol</source>. <year>2022</year>;<volume>85</volume>:<fpage>309</fpage>&#8211;<lpage>319</lpage>. doi: <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.5935/0004-2749.20220048</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">34852044</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC11826751</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="ojaf061-B3"><label>3</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><string-name name-style="western"><surname>Lee</surname> &#160;<given-names>W</given-names></string-name></person-group>. <article-title>Hyaluronic acid filler injection guided by Doppler ultrasound</article-title>. <source>Arch Plast Surg</source>. <year>2023</year>;<volume>50</volume>:<fpage>348</fpage>&#8211;<lpage>353</lpage>. doi: <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1055/s-0043-1770078</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">37564711</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC10411166</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="ojaf061-B4"><label>4</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><string-name name-style="western"><surname>Beleznay</surname> &#160;<given-names>K</given-names></string-name>, <string-name name-style="western"><surname>Carruthers</surname> &#160;<given-names>JDA</given-names></string-name>, <string-name name-style="western"><surname>Humphrey</surname> &#160;<given-names>S</given-names></string-name>, <string-name name-style="western"><surname>Carruthers</surname> &#160;<given-names>A</given-names></string-name>, <string-name name-style="western"><surname>Jones</surname> &#160;<given-names>D</given-names></string-name></person-group>. <article-title>Update on avoiding and treating blindness from fillers: a recent review of the world literature</article-title>. <source>Aesthet Surg J</source>. <year>2019</year>;<volume>39</volume>:<fpage>662</fpage>&#8211;<lpage>674</lpage>. doi: <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1093/asj/sjz053</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">30805636</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="ojaf061-B5"><label>5</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><string-name name-style="western"><surname>Rocha</surname> &#160;<given-names>PS</given-names></string-name>, <string-name name-style="western"><surname>Guerra</surname> &#160;<given-names>TA</given-names></string-name>, <string-name name-style="western"><surname>Teixeira</surname> &#160;<given-names>DA</given-names></string-name></person-group>. <article-title>Description of a safe Doppler ultrasound-guided technique for hyaluronic acid filler in the face&#8212;a method to avoid adverse vascular events</article-title>. <source>J Cosmet Dermatol</source>. <year>2022</year>;<volume>21</volume>:<fpage>2783</fpage>&#8211;<lpage>2787</lpage>. doi: <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1111/jocd.14492</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">34587360</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="ojaf061-B6"><label>6</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><string-name name-style="western"><surname>Desyatnikova</surname> &#160;<given-names>S</given-names></string-name></person-group>. <article-title>Ultrasound-guided temple filler injection</article-title>. <source>Facial Plast Surg Aesthet Med</source>. <year>2022</year>;<volume>24</volume>:<fpage>501</fpage>&#8211;<lpage>503</lpage>. doi: <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1089/fpsam.2022.0176</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">36351192</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC9700375</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="ojaf061-B7"><label>7</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><string-name name-style="western"><surname>Soares</surname> &#160;<given-names>DJ</given-names></string-name>, <string-name name-style="western"><surname>Bowhay</surname> &#160;<given-names>A</given-names></string-name>, <string-name name-style="western"><surname>Blevins</surname> &#160;<given-names>LW</given-names></string-name>, <string-name name-style="western"><surname>Patel</surname> &#160;<given-names>SM</given-names></string-name>, <string-name name-style="western"><surname>Zuliani</surname> &#160;<given-names>GF</given-names></string-name></person-group>. <article-title>Patterns of filler-induced facial skin ischemia: a systematic review of 243 cases and introduction of the FOEM scoring system and grading scale</article-title>. <source>Plast Reconstr Surg</source>. <year>2023</year>;<volume>151</volume>:<fpage>592e</fpage>&#8211;<lpage>608e</lpage>. doi: <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1097/PRS.0000000000009991</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">36477154</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="ojaf061-B8"><label>8</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><string-name name-style="western"><surname>Zhang</surname> &#160;<given-names>YL</given-names></string-name>, <string-name name-style="western"><surname>Chen</surname> &#160;<given-names>Y</given-names></string-name>, <string-name name-style="western"><surname>Sun</surname> &#160;<given-names>ZS</given-names></string-name>, <string-name name-style="western"><surname>Luo</surname> &#160;<given-names>SK</given-names></string-name></person-group>. <article-title>Retrospective study of vascular complications caused by hyaluronic acid injection</article-title>. <source>Aesthetic Plast Surg</source>. <year>2023</year>;<volume>47</volume>:<fpage>2745</fpage>&#8211;<lpage>2753</lpage>. doi: <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1007/s00266-023-03522-9</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">37580566</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="ojaf061-B9"><label>9</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><string-name name-style="western"><surname>Tansatit</surname> &#160;<given-names>T</given-names></string-name>, <string-name name-style="western"><surname>Phumyoo</surname> &#160;<given-names>T</given-names></string-name>, <string-name name-style="western"><surname>Jitaree</surname> &#160;<given-names>B</given-names></string-name>, <etal>et al</etal></person-group> &#160;<article-title>Ultrasound evaluation of arterial anastomosis of the forehead</article-title>. <source>J Cosmet Dermatol</source>. <year>2018</year>;<volume>17</volume>:<fpage>1031</fpage>&#8211;<lpage>1036</lpage>. doi: <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1111/jocd.12755</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">30146687</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="ojaf061-B10"><label>10</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><string-name name-style="western"><surname>Tansatit</surname> &#160;<given-names>T</given-names></string-name>, <string-name name-style="western"><surname>Phumyoo</surname> &#160;<given-names>T</given-names></string-name>, <string-name name-style="western"><surname>MCCabe</surname> &#160;<given-names>H</given-names></string-name>, <string-name name-style="western"><surname>Jitaree</surname> &#160;<given-names>B</given-names></string-name></person-group>. <article-title>Translucent and ultrasonographic studies of the inferior labial artery for improvement of filler injection techniques</article-title>. <source>Plast Reconstr Surg Glob Open</source>. <year>2019</year>;<volume>7</volume>:<fpage>e2399</fpage>. doi: <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1097/GOX.0000000000002399</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">31942380</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC6908380</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="ojaf061-B11"><label>11</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><string-name name-style="western"><surname>Lee</surname> &#160;<given-names>W</given-names></string-name>, <string-name name-style="western"><surname>Kim</surname> &#160;<given-names>JS</given-names></string-name>, <string-name name-style="western"><surname>Moon</surname> &#160;<given-names>HJ</given-names></string-name>, <string-name name-style="western"><surname>Yang</surname> &#160;<given-names>EJ</given-names></string-name></person-group>. <article-title>A safe Doppler ultrasound-guided method for nasolabial fold correction with hyaluronic acid filler</article-title>. <source>Aesthet Surg J</source>. <year>2021</year>;<volume>41</volume>:<fpage>NP486</fpage>&#8211;<lpage>NP492</lpage>. doi: <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1093/asj/sjaa153</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">32505134</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="ojaf061-B12"><label>12</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><string-name name-style="western"><surname>Tseng</surname> &#160;<given-names>FW</given-names></string-name>, <string-name name-style="western"><surname>Bommareddy</surname> &#160;<given-names>K</given-names></string-name>, <string-name name-style="western"><surname>Frank</surname> &#160;<given-names>K</given-names></string-name>, <etal>et al</etal></person-group> &#160;<article-title>Descriptive analysis of 213 positive blood aspiration cases when injecting facial soft tissue fillers</article-title>. <source>Aesthet Surg J</source>. <year>2021</year>;<volume>41</volume>:<fpage>616</fpage>&#8211;<lpage>624</lpage>. doi: <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1093/asj/sjaa075</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">32504468</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="ojaf061-B13"><label>13</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><string-name name-style="western"><surname>Alam</surname> &#160;<given-names>M</given-names></string-name>, <string-name name-style="western"><surname>Kakar</surname> &#160;<given-names>R</given-names></string-name>, <string-name name-style="western"><surname>Dover</surname> &#160;<given-names>JS</given-names></string-name>, <etal>et al</etal></person-group> &#160;<article-title>Rates of vascular occlusion associated with using needles vs cannulas for filler injection</article-title>. <source>JAMA Dermatol</source>. <year>2021</year>;<volume>157</volume>:<fpage>174180</fpage>. doi: <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1001/jamadermatol.2020.5102</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC7774041</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">33377939</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="ojaf061-B14"><label>14</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><string-name name-style="western"><surname>Cai</surname> &#160;<given-names>B</given-names></string-name>, <string-name name-style="western"><surname>Yuan</surname> &#160;<given-names>R</given-names></string-name>, <string-name name-style="western"><surname>Zhu</surname> &#160;<given-names>GZ</given-names></string-name>, <etal>et al</etal></person-group> &#160;<article-title>Deployment of the ophthalmic and facial angiosomes in the upper nose overlaying the nasal bones</article-title>. <source>Aesthet Surg J</source>. <year>2021</year>;<volume>41</volume>:<fpage>NP1975</fpage>&#8211;<lpage>NP1985</lpage>. doi: <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1093/asj/sjab003</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">33421060</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="ojaf061-B15"><label>15</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><string-name name-style="western"><surname>Pavicic</surname> &#160;<given-names>T</given-names></string-name>, <string-name name-style="western"><surname>Webb</surname> &#160;<given-names>KL</given-names></string-name>, <string-name name-style="western"><surname>Frank</surname> &#160;<given-names>K</given-names></string-name>, <string-name name-style="western"><surname>Gotkin</surname> &#160;<given-names>RH</given-names></string-name>, <string-name name-style="western"><surname>Tamura</surname> &#160;<given-names>B</given-names></string-name>, <string-name name-style="western"><surname>Cotofana</surname> &#160;<given-names>S</given-names></string-name></person-group>. <article-title>Arterial wall penetration forces in needles versus cannulas</article-title>. <source>Plast Reconstr Surg</source>. <year>2019</year>;<volume>143</volume>:<fpage>504e</fpage>&#8211;<lpage>512e</lpage>. doi: <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1097/PRS.0000000000005321</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">30589824</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="ojaf061-B16"><label>16</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><string-name name-style="western"><surname>Lee</surname> &#160;<given-names>W</given-names></string-name>, <string-name name-style="western"><surname>Moon</surname> &#160;<given-names>HJ</given-names></string-name>, <string-name name-style="western"><surname>Kim</surname> &#160;<given-names>JS</given-names></string-name>, <string-name name-style="western"><surname>Yang</surname> &#160;<given-names>EJ</given-names></string-name></person-group>. <article-title>Safe glabellar wrinkle correction with soft tissue filler using Doppler ultrasound</article-title>. <source>Aesthet Surg J</source>. <year>2021</year>;<volume>41</volume>:<fpage>1081</fpage>&#8211;<lpage>1089</lpage>. doi: <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1093/asj/sjaa197</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">32644130</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="ojaf061-B17"><label>17</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><string-name name-style="western"><surname>Bravo</surname> &#160;<given-names>BSF</given-names></string-name>, <string-name name-style="western"><surname>Carvalho</surname> &#160;<given-names>RM</given-names></string-name>, <string-name name-style="western"><surname>Elias</surname> &#160;<given-names>MC</given-names></string-name>, <etal>et al</etal></person-group> &#160;<article-title>Nasal filling guided by high frequency ultrasound: reducing risks</article-title>. <source>J Cosmet Dermatol</source>. <year>2024</year>;<volume>23</volume>:<fpage>3256</fpage>&#8211;<lpage>3262</lpage>. doi: <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1111/jocd.16430</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">38958454</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="ojaf061-B18"><label>18</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><string-name name-style="western"><surname>Lee</surname> &#160;<given-names>W</given-names></string-name>, <string-name name-style="western"><surname>Moon</surname> &#160;<given-names>HJ</given-names></string-name>, <string-name name-style="western"><surname>Kim</surname> &#160;<given-names>MS</given-names></string-name>, <string-name name-style="western"><surname>Cheon</surname> &#160;<given-names>GW</given-names></string-name>, <string-name name-style="western"><surname>Yang</surname> &#160;<given-names>EJ</given-names></string-name></person-group>. <article-title>Pre-injection ultrasound scanning for treating temporal hollowing</article-title>. <source>J Cosmet Dermatol</source>. <year>2022</year>;<volume>21</volume>:<fpage>2420</fpage>&#8211;<lpage>2425</lpage>. doi: <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1111/jocd.14471</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">34559940</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref></ref-list></back></article></pmc-articleset>