<?xml version="1.0"  ?><!DOCTYPE pmc-articleset PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD ARTICLE SET 2.0//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pmc/articleset/nlm-articleset-2.0.dtd"><pmc-articleset><article xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" xmlns:ali="http://www.niso.org/schemas/ali/1.0/" xml:lang="en" article-type="review-article" dtd-version="1.4"><processing-meta base-tagset="archiving" mathml-version="3.0" table-model="xhtml" tagset-family="jats"><restricted-by>pmc</restricted-by></processing-meta><front><journal-meta><journal-id journal-id-type="nlm-ta">Cureus</journal-id><journal-id journal-id-type="iso-abbrev">Cureus</journal-id><journal-id journal-id-type="pmc-domain-id">2757</journal-id><journal-id journal-id-type="pmc-domain">cureus</journal-id><journal-title-group><journal-title>Cureus</journal-title></journal-title-group><issn pub-type="epub">2168-8184</issn><publisher><publisher-name>Cureus Inc.</publisher-name></publisher></journal-meta><article-meta><article-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC12097758</article-id><article-id pub-id-type="pmcid-ver">PMC12097758.1</article-id><article-id pub-id-type="pmcaid">12097758</article-id><article-id pub-id-type="pmcaiid">12097758</article-id><article-id pub-id-type="pmid">40406769</article-id><article-id pub-id-type="doi">10.7759/cureus.82800</article-id><article-version article-version-type="pmc-version">1</article-version><article-categories><subj-group subj-group-type="heading"><subject>Dermatology</subject></subj-group><subj-group><subject>Medical Education</subject></subj-group></article-categories><title-group><article-title>Risk Factor Analysis for Vascular Occlusions After Dermal Filler Injections: A Systematic Review and Meta-Analysis</article-title></title-group><contrib-group><contrib contrib-type="editor"><name name-style="western"><surname>Muacevic</surname><given-names initials="A">Alexander</given-names></name></contrib><contrib contrib-type="editor"><name name-style="western"><surname>Adler</surname><given-names initials="JR">John R</given-names></name></contrib></contrib-group><contrib-group><contrib contrib-type="author" corresp="yes"><name name-style="western"><surname>Chakhachiro</surname><given-names initials="A">Adham</given-names></name><xref rid="aff-1" ref-type="aff">1</xref><xref rid="aff-2" ref-type="aff">2</xref></contrib><contrib contrib-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Waseem</surname><given-names initials="M">Maaz</given-names></name><xref rid="aff-3" ref-type="aff">3</xref></contrib></contrib-group><aff id="aff-1">
<label>1</label>
Dermatology, Clinic Platina, London, GBR </aff><aff id="aff-2">
<label>2</label>
Internal Medicine, St. Peter's Hospital, Chertsey, GBR </aff><aff id="aff-3">
<label>3</label>
Biological Sciences, Atta-Ur-Rehman School of Applied Biosciences, National University of Sciences and Technology (NUST), Islamabad, PAK </aff><author-notes><corresp id="cor1">
Adham Chakhachiro <email>adham.chakhachiro@outlook.com</email></corresp></author-notes><pub-date date-type="pub" publication-format="electronic"><day>22</day><month>4</month><year>2025</year></pub-date><pub-date date-type="collection" publication-format="electronic"><month>4</month><year>2025</year></pub-date><volume>17</volume><issue>4</issue><issue-id pub-id-type="pmc-issue-id">485740</issue-id><elocation-id>e82800</elocation-id><history><date date-type="accepted"><day>22</day><month>4</month><year>2025</year></date></history><pub-history><event event-type="pmc-release"><date><day>22</day><month>04</month><year>2025</year></date></event><event event-type="pmc-live"><date><day>22</day><month>05</month><year>2025</year></date></event><event event-type="pmc-last-change"><date iso-8601-date="2025-05-23 16:26:47.797"><day>23</day><month>05</month><year>2025</year></date></event></pub-history><permissions><copyright-statement>Copyright &#169; 2025, Chakhachiro et al.</copyright-statement><copyright-year>2025</copyright-year><copyright-holder>Chakhachiro et al.</copyright-holder><license><ali:license_ref specific-use="textmining" content-type="ccbylicense">https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</ali:license_ref><license-p>This is an open access article distributed under the terms of the Creative Commons Attribution License CC-BY 4.0., which permits unrestricted use, distribution, and reproduction in any medium, provided the original author and source are credited.</license-p></license></permissions><self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" content-type="pmc-pdf" xlink:href="cureus-0017-00000082800.pdf"/><self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xlink:href="https://www.cureus.com/articles/348371-risk-factor-analysis-for-vascular-occlusions-after-dermal-filler-injections-a-systematic-review-and-meta-analysis">This article is available from https://www.cureus.com/articles/348371-risk-factor-analysis-for-vascular-occlusions-after-dermal-filler-injections-a-systematic-review-and-meta-analysis</self-uri><abstract><p>This systematic review and meta-analysis investigate the risk factors associated with vascular occlusions following dermal filler injections, a rare but serious complication in aesthetic medicine. Fourteen studies involving various filler materials and injection sites were analyzed to identify patient and procedural variables influencing clinical outcomes. The most frequently used filler was hyaluronic acid (HA) (61.3%), and most complications occurred in female patients (71%). Anatomical regions with complex vasculature, such as the glabella, nose, and nasolabial folds, were most commonly implicated. Recovery outcomes were significantly influenced by the specific vessels involved, with occlusions in smaller arteries showing a better prognosis. Timely recognition and intervention were associated with improved recovery, with delays beyond five days correlating with permanent deficits. Hyaluronidase use in HA-related occlusions yielded high partial or total recovery rates with an 84.2% success rate, reaffirming its role as a first-line treatment. Based on the analysis, a morbidity risk assessment tool was developed to stratify patients into low-, moderate-, and high-risk categories, offering practical value for clinical decision-making. The findings underscore the importance of anatomical precision, prompt intervention, and standardized treatment protocols.&#160;</p></abstract><kwd-group kwd-group-type="author"><kwd>hyaluronic acid fillers</kwd><kwd>hyaluronidase</kwd><kwd>meta-analysis</kwd><kwd>reconstructive dentistry</kwd><kwd>retinal vascular occlusions</kwd></kwd-group><custom-meta-group><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-status-qastatus</meta-name><meta-value>0</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-status-live</meta-name><meta-value>yes</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-status-embargo</meta-name><meta-value>no</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-status-released</meta-name><meta-value>yes</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-open-access</meta-name><meta-value>yes</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-olf</meta-name><meta-value>no</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-manuscript</meta-name><meta-value>no</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-legally-suppressed</meta-name><meta-value>no</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-has-pdf</meta-name><meta-value>yes</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-has-supplement</meta-name><meta-value>no</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-pdf-only</meta-name><meta-value>no</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-suppress-copyright</meta-name><meta-value>no</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-is-real-version</meta-name><meta-value>no</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-is-scanned-article</meta-name><meta-value>no</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-preprint</meta-name><meta-value>no</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-in-epmc</meta-name><meta-value>yes</meta-value></custom-meta></custom-meta-group></article-meta></front><body><sec sec-type="intro"><title>Introduction and background</title><p>Dermal filler injections have become one of the most widely sought-after aesthetic procedures globally in the field of cosmetic dermatology in recent years [<xref rid="REF1" ref-type="bibr">1</xref>]. With their ability to restore volume, enhance facial contours, and diminish the appearance of wrinkles, these minimally invasive treatments have gained immense popularity [<xref rid="REF2" ref-type="bibr">2</xref>]. Various filler materials, including hyaluronic acid (HA), calcium hydroxylapatite (CaHa), and poly-L-lactic acid (PLLA), offer tailored solutions to meet the specific needs of diverse patient populations [<xref rid="REF3" ref-type="bibr">3</xref>]. Despite their widespread acceptance and generally favorable safety profile, dermal fillers are not without risks. Among the most serious complications is vascular occlusion, a rare (0.05-0.01% incidence) but potentially devastating event that can lead to tissue ischemia, necrosis, or even permanent vision loss and stroke [<xref rid="REF4" ref-type="bibr">4</xref>].</p><p>Understanding the risk factors contributing to vascular occlusion is crucial for mitigating this complication and improving patient outcomes [<xref rid="REF5" ref-type="bibr">5</xref>]. Vascular occlusion occurs when the filler inadvertently enters a blood vessel or exerts external pressure on it, impeding blood flow or causing vasospasm&#160;[<xref rid="REF6" ref-type="bibr">6</xref>]. The consequences range from mild to severe, depending on the site and extent of occlusion. Key risk factors hypothesized in existing literature include the injection technique, the anatomical site of administration, the type of filler used, and the patient's vascular anatomy [<xref rid="REF7" ref-type="bibr">7</xref>]. However, much of this evidence remains anecdotal or derived from small-scale case studies, leaving significant gaps in our understanding.</p><p>According to market trends, the demand for dermal fillers has steadily increased, driven by advancements in techniques, rising aesthetic awareness, and a broader acceptance of cosmetic interventions across various demographic groups [<xref rid="REF8" ref-type="bibr">8</xref>]. This surge also shows the importance of proper practitioner training and patient education. A deeper understanding of the risk factors associated with vascular occlusions can provide valuable insights into optimizing procedural protocols and refining injection techniques [<xref rid="REF9" ref-type="bibr">9</xref>].</p><p>Previous studies exploring vascular occlusions have predominantly focused on case reports or case series, offering limited generalizability due to small sample sizes and inconsistent methodologies [<xref rid="REF10" ref-type="bibr">10</xref>]. While these reports have provided valuable initial observations, the lack of robust, aggregated data limits their applicability to clinical practice. Systematic reviews and meta-analyses can address these limitations by synthesizing evidence across multiple studies, offering a comprehensive and statistically robust assessment of risk factors.</p><p>This study aims to systematically review and analyze the existing literature on vascular occlusions resulting from all types of dermal filler injections. Specifically, it seeks to identify and quantify the risk factors associated with this complication, focusing on patient demographics, anatomical sites of injection, injection techniques, filler materials, and vessel involvement. By pooling data from a diverse range of studies, this research intends to generate actionable insights that can guide clinical decision-making, enhance procedural safety, and improve patient outcomes. The importance of this study extends beyond its clinical implications. As the cosmetic industry continues to evolve, regulatory agencies and professional organizations are increasingly emphasizing the need for evidence-based practices. By elucidating the risk factors for vascular occlusion, this systematic review and meta-analysis will contribute to the growing body of literature aimed at standardizing safety protocols and setting benchmarks for best practices in aesthetic medicine.</p></sec><sec sec-type="review"><title>Review</title><p>Methods</p><p>Eligibility Criteria</p><p>Studies were included if they reported confirmed cases of vascular occlusions following dermal filler injections, provided data on patient demographics, anatomical injection sites, injection techniques, and filler types, and used clear diagnostic criteria for vascular occlusions. Case-control studies, cohort studies, and case series with detailed patient and procedural data were considered eligible. Studies were excluded if they were non-English without translation, lacked sufficient data on variables of interest, or focused on unrelated complications.</p><p>Search Strategy</p><p>A comprehensive literature search was conducted in PubMed, Embase, and the Cochrane Library using keywords such as &#8220;vascular occlusion,&#8221; &#8220;dermal fillers,&#8221; &#8220;risk factors,&#8221; and &#8220;injectable complications.&#8221; Boolean operators and database-specific filters were applied to ensure thorough coverage. The search strategy was tailored to capture relevant case-control studies, cohort studies, and case series, ensuring retrospective and prospective data inclusion. The proper Boolean search strings are shown in Table <xref rid="TAB7" ref-type="table">7</xref> of Appendices.</p><p>Study Selection</p><p>After removing duplicates, studies were screened in two stages: title/abstract screening and full-text review. Two independent reviewers assessed each study against the inclusion and exclusion criteria. Discrepancies were resolved through discussion or consultation with a third reviewer. Selected studies underwent data extraction and quality assessment to ensure reliability and relevance for the meta-analysis.</p><p>Risk of Bias Assessment</p><p>The risk of bias and overall quality of the included studies were evaluated using the Joanna Briggs Institute Checklist for Case Reports [<xref rid="REF11" ref-type="bibr">11</xref>] and summarized. PRISMA guidelines were adhered to throughout the review process to ensure transparency and rigor.</p><p>Data Extraction</p><p>Data for the meta-analysis, pertaining to study outcomes with relevant study characteristics, were extracted and entered into Microsoft Excel&#174;&#160;(Microsoft, Redmond, WA). The recorded data included study authors, patient demographics, age, gender, filler material, as well as injection site, along with relevant medical histories, vessels involved, and status of recovery. The outcome for recovery was categorized into &#8220;no improvement&#8221; or &#8220;partial/total improvement.&#8221;</p><p>Outcomes and Analysis</p><p>Descriptive statistics were employed for all variables. The primary outcome was the status of recovery and the association of various factors with it. The odds ratio (OR) was calculated using Fisher&#8217;s exact test, along with associated pooled effects. Significance testing was two-sided, and p&lt;0.05 was considered significant. The analysis was carried out using R Programming Language&#174; with its &#8220;metafor&#8221; package (ref.) and SPSS version 27&#174; (IBM&#160;SPSS Statistics, Armonk, NY).</p><p>Results</p><p>Study Characteristics</p><p>Fourteen studies were included in the analysis. The studies were published between 2009 and 2022, with their selection summarized in Figure <xref rid="FIG1" ref-type="fig">1</xref>. They were mostly from the USA (57.1%). The mean age of the patients was 42.58&#177;15.12. 71% of the patients were female, with the majority receiving a hyaluronic acid (HA) filler injection (61.3%).&#160;The general study data is shown in Table <xref rid="TAB1" ref-type="table">1</xref>.</p><fig position="anchor" fig-type="figure" id="FIG1" orientation="portrait"><label>Figure 1</label><caption><title>PRISMA flowchart</title></caption><graphic xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" position="float" orientation="portrait" xlink:href="cureus-0017-00000082800-i01.jpg"/></fig><table-wrap position="float" id="TAB1" orientation="portrait"><label>Table 1</label><caption><title>General study data</title><p>HA, hyaluronic acid; AF, autologous fat; CaHa, calcium hydroxyapatite; PLLA, poly-L-lactic acid</p></caption><table frame="hsides" rules="groups"><tbody><tr style="background-color:#ccc"><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Study</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Region</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Gender</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Injected Substance</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Management of Vascular Occlusion</td></tr><tr><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Ansari et al., 2019 [<xref rid="REF12" ref-type="bibr">12</xref>]</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">USA</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">1 Female</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">HA</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Aspirin and prednisolone</td></tr><tr style="background-color:#ccc"><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Jolly et al., 2021 [<xref rid="REF13" ref-type="bibr">13</xref>]</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">UK</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">1 Female</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">HA</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Iopidine 1%, Hyaluronidase 1500 IU</td></tr><tr><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Carle et al., 2014 [<xref rid="REF14" ref-type="bibr">14</xref>]</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">USA</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">1 Male, 2 Females</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">HA, AF, Collagen</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">AC paracentesis</td></tr><tr style="background-color:#ccc"><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Chou et al., 2015 [<xref rid="REF15" ref-type="bibr">15</xref>]</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">China</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">1 Female</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">CaHA</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Alprostadil, Dextran, and high-pressure oxygen</td></tr><tr><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Soares et al., 2023 [<xref rid="REF7" ref-type="bibr">7</xref>]</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">USA</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">1 Female</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">CaHa</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Morphine, Dexamethasone, Ketorolac</td></tr><tr style="background-color:#ccc"><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Georgescu et al., 2009 [<xref rid="REF16" ref-type="bibr">16</xref>]</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">USA</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">1 Male, 1 Female</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">CaHa</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Medrol DosePak, Nitroglycerin, and microdermabrasion</td></tr><tr><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Sung et al., 2010 [<xref rid="REF17" ref-type="bibr">17</xref>]</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">USA</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">1 Male</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">CaHa</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Corticosteroids</td></tr><tr style="background-color:#ccc"><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Roberts et al., 2012 [<xref rid="REF18" ref-type="bibr">18</xref>]</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">USA</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">1 Male</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">PLLA</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Not mentioned</td></tr><tr><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Kassir et al., 2011 [<xref rid="REF19" ref-type="bibr">19</xref>]</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">USA</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">1 Male</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">HA</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Massage, Mupirocin, Clindamycin, and Rocephin with silicone gel sheeting</td></tr><tr style="background-color:#ccc"><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Grunebaum et al., 2009 [<xref rid="REF20" ref-type="bibr">20</xref>]</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">USA</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">1 Male, 2 Females</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">HA</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Bacitracin, Debridement, Nitropaste, Hyaluronidase, Triamcinolone, and oral antibiotics</td></tr><tr><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Pan et al., 2021 [<xref rid="REF21" ref-type="bibr">21</xref>]</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">China</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">1 Female</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">HA</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Massage, Hyaluronidase, and hyperbaric oxygen therapy</td></tr><tr style="background-color:#ccc"><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Beleznay et al., 2014 [<xref rid="REF22" ref-type="bibr">22</xref>]</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Canada</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">2 Males, 6 Females</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">CaHa, HA</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Massage, warm compresses, nitroglycerin paste, hyaluronidase, prednisone, and aspirin</td></tr><tr><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Thanasarnaksorn et al., 2018 [<xref rid="REF10" ref-type="bibr">10</xref>]</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Thailand</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">1 Male, 5 Females</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">HA</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Carbogen, nitroglycerin, massage and Hyaluronidase with hyperbaric oxygen therapy</td></tr><tr style="background-color:#ccc"><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Cassiano et al., 2020 [<xref rid="REF23" ref-type="bibr">23</xref>]</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Brazil</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">1 Female</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">HA</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Hyaluronidase and Prednisolone</td></tr></tbody></table></table-wrap><p>The risk of bias assessment was done using the Joanna Briggs Institute Checklist for Case Reports [<xref rid="REF11" ref-type="bibr">11</xref>] and is summarized in Table <xref rid="TAB2" ref-type="table">2</xref>. Eight questions ranging from patient demographics to takeaway lessons assess the robustness, generalizability, and overall applicability of case reports in this critical appraisal tool.</p><table-wrap position="float" id="TAB2" orientation="portrait"><label>Table 2</label><caption><title>Critical appraisal of case reports using the Joanna Briggs Checklist</title></caption><table frame="hsides" rules="groups"><tbody><tr style="background-color:#ccc"><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Study</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Q1</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Q2</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Q3</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Q4</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Q5</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Q6</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Q7</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Q8</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Overall Appraisal</td></tr><tr><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Ansari et al., 2019 [<xref rid="REF12" ref-type="bibr">12</xref>]</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Yes</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Yes</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Yes</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Yes</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Yes</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Yes</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Yes</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Unclear</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Include</td></tr><tr style="background-color:#ccc"><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Jolly et al., 2021 [<xref rid="REF13" ref-type="bibr">13</xref>]</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Yes</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Yes</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Yes</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Unclear</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Yes</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Yes</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Yes</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">No</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Include</td></tr><tr><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Carle et al., 2014 [<xref rid="REF14" ref-type="bibr">14</xref>]</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Yes</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Yes</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Yes</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Yes</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Yes</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Yes</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Yes</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Unclear</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Include</td></tr><tr style="background-color:#ccc"><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Chou et al., 2015 [<xref rid="REF15" ref-type="bibr">15</xref>]</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Yes</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Yes</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Yes</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Yes</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Yes</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Yes</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Yes</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Unclear</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Include</td></tr><tr><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Soares et al., 2023 [<xref rid="REF7" ref-type="bibr">7</xref>]</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Yes</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Yes</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Yes</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Yes</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Yes</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Yes</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Yes</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Yes</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Include</td></tr><tr style="background-color:#ccc"><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Georgescu et al., 2009 [<xref rid="REF16" ref-type="bibr">16</xref>]</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Yes</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Yes</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Yes</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">No</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Yes</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Yes</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Yes</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Unclear</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Include</td></tr><tr><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Sung et al., 2010 [<xref rid="REF17" ref-type="bibr">17</xref>]</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Yes</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Yes</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Yes</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Yes</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Yes</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Yes</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Yes</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">No</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Include</td></tr><tr style="background-color:#ccc"><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Roberts et al., 2012 [<xref rid="REF18" ref-type="bibr">18</xref>]</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Yes</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Yes</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">No</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Yes</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Yes</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Yes</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Yes</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Unclear</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Include</td></tr><tr><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Kassir et al., 2011 [<xref rid="REF19" ref-type="bibr">19</xref>]</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Yes</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Yes</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">No</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Yes</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Yes</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Yes</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Yes</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Yes</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Include</td></tr><tr style="background-color:#ccc"><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Grunebaum et al., 2009 [<xref rid="REF20" ref-type="bibr">20</xref>]</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Yes</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Yes</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Yes</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">No</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Yes</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Yes</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Yes</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Unclear</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Include</td></tr><tr><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Pan et al., 2021 [<xref rid="REF21" ref-type="bibr">21</xref>]</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Yes</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">No</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Yes</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Yes</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Yes</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Yes</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Yes</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Yes</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Include</td></tr><tr style="background-color:#ccc"><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Beleznay et al., 2014 [<xref rid="REF22" ref-type="bibr">22</xref>]</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Yes</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Yes</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Yes</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">No</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Yes</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Yes</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Yes</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Yes</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Include</td></tr><tr><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Thanasarnaksorn et al., 2018 [<xref rid="REF10" ref-type="bibr">10</xref>]</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Yes</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">No</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Yes</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Yes</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Yes</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Yes</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Yes</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Yes</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Include</td></tr><tr style="background-color:#ccc"><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Cassiano et al., 2020 [<xref rid="REF23" ref-type="bibr">23</xref>]</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Yes</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Yes</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Yes</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Yes</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Yes</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Yes</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Yes</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Yes</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Include</td></tr></tbody></table></table-wrap><p>The heterogeneity of the dataset further impacts the generalizability of findings. Variability in study methodologies, patient demographics, filler types, and management protocols complicates the interpretation of pooled data. For instance, the inconsistency in defining vascular occlusions and reporting recovery outcomes hampers cross-study comparisons. There is a clear need for standardized diagnostic criteria and reporting frameworks to improve data reliability and facilitate more comprehensive analyses in future research. Future research should focus on large-scale, prospective studies to validate these findings and refine management protocols. Additionally, developing a universally accepted risk stratification tool, such as the proposed morbidity risk assessment scale, could guide clinical decision-making and improve patient outcomes.</p><p>Risk Factor Analysis</p><p>Various risk factors for recovery status were accumulated after a thorough literature review. These included gender, injected substance, injection site, vessel involved, and time to presentation. The distribution of cases over these variables is shown in Table <xref rid="TAB3" ref-type="table">3</xref>.</p><table-wrap position="float" id="TAB3" orientation="portrait"><label>Table 3</label><caption><title>Risk factor analysis with pooled OR</title><p>HA, hyaluronic acid; AF, autologous fat; CaHa, calcium hydroxyapatite; PLLA, poly-L-lactic acid; OR, odds ratio</p></caption><table frame="hsides" rules="groups"><tbody><tr style="background-color:#ccc"><td colspan="2" rowspan="1">Variable</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">No Improvement (n=4)</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Partial/Total Recovery (n=27)</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">OR (p-value)</td></tr><tr><td rowspan="2" colspan="1">Gender</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Male</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">1</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">8</td><td rowspan="2" colspan="1">0.036 (0.8)</td></tr><tr style="background-color:#ccc"><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Female</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">3</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">19</td></tr><tr><td rowspan="3" colspan="1">Injected substance</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">HA</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">3</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">16</td><td rowspan="3" colspan="1">6.64 (0.21)</td></tr><tr style="background-color:#ccc"><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">CaHa</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">0</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">9</td></tr><tr><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Others</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">1</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">2</td></tr><tr style="background-color:#ccc"><td rowspan="6" colspan="1">Injection site</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Glabella</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">1</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">3</td><td rowspan="6" colspan="1">1.48 (0.24)</td></tr><tr><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Forehead</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">2</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">5</td></tr><tr style="background-color:#ccc"><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Nose</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">0</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">7</td></tr><tr><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Periorbital</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">0</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">2</td></tr><tr style="background-color:#ccc"><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Cheek</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">1</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">3</td></tr><tr><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Nasolabial fold</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">0</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">7</td></tr><tr style="background-color:#ccc"><td rowspan="7" colspan="1">Vessel involved</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Ophthalmic artery</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">1</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">4</td><td rowspan="7" colspan="1">9.67 (0.02)</td></tr><tr><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Central retinal artery</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">0</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">6</td></tr><tr style="background-color:#ccc"><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Branch retinal artery</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">2</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">0</td></tr><tr><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Facial artery</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">0</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">6</td></tr><tr style="background-color:#ccc"><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Angular artery</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">0</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">2</td></tr><tr><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Multiple facial vessels</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">0</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">4</td></tr><tr style="background-color:#ccc"><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Others</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">1</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">5</td></tr><tr><td rowspan="4" colspan="1">Time to onset/presentation</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Immediately</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">2</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">11</td><td rowspan="4" colspan="1">3.13 (0.42)</td></tr><tr style="background-color:#ccc"><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Less than 1 day</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">0</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">6</td></tr><tr><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">1 to 5 days</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">1</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">9</td></tr><tr style="background-color:#ccc"><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">More than 5 days</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">1</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">1</td></tr></tbody></table></table-wrap><p>Eighteen cases (58.06%) showed complete recovery of functional impairment in the form of visual loss, ophthalmoplegia, or pain. Four cases (12.9%) showed no recovery after extensive therapy and remained permanently impaired in the form of non-aesthetic scar, permanent vision loss, or ptosis, among others. The primary association observed for partial or complete recovery was with the vessels involved; lesions affecting minor arteries (categorized as "others"), such as the supraorbital, supratrochlear, or infraorbital branch of the maxillary artery, demonstrated marginally better recovery outcomes than those involving other vessels (OR 9.67, p=0.02). Hyaluronidase was administered in all cases where complications arose due to HA fillers and was associated with an 84.2% rate of partial or total recovery.</p><p>Vascular Occlusion Morbidity Risk Assessment Tool</p><p>Weighted points were assigned to each risk factor based on the pooled ORs, forming an assessment scale described here. With a maximum total score of 14, a score greater than 9 indicated severe morbidity, often refractory to treatment. Risk categories were defined as follows: low-risk patients had a score of less than four, moderate-risk patients scored between four and nine, and high-risk patients had a score greater than nine (Table <xref rid="TAB4" ref-type="table">4</xref>).</p><table-wrap position="float" id="TAB4" orientation="portrait"><label>Table 4</label><caption><title>Morbidity risk assessment tool</title><p>HA, hyaluronic acid; AF, autologous fat; CaHa, calcium hydroxyapatite</p></caption><table frame="hsides" rules="groups"><tbody><tr style="background-color:#ccc"><td colspan="2" rowspan="1">Risk Factor</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Point(s)</td></tr><tr><td rowspan="2" colspan="1">Gender</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Female</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">2</td></tr><tr style="background-color:#ccc"><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Male</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">1</td></tr><tr><td rowspan="3" colspan="1">Injected substance</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">HA</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">3</td></tr><tr style="background-color:#ccc"><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">CaHa</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">2</td></tr><tr><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Others</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">1</td></tr><tr style="background-color:#ccc"><td rowspan="4" colspan="1">Injection site</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Glabella/periorbital</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">3</td></tr><tr><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Forehead/nose</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">2</td></tr><tr style="background-color:#ccc"><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Cheek</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">1</td></tr><tr><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Nasolabial fold</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">0</td></tr><tr style="background-color:#ccc"><td rowspan="5" colspan="1">Vessel involved</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Ophthalmic artery</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">4</td></tr><tr><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Central retinal artery</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">3</td></tr><tr style="background-color:#ccc"><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Branch retinal artery</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">2</td></tr><tr><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Facial/angular artery</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">1</td></tr><tr style="background-color:#ccc"><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Others</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">0</td></tr><tr><td rowspan="3" colspan="1">Time to onset/presentation</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">More than 5 days</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">2</td></tr><tr style="background-color:#ccc"><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Less than 5 days</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">1</td></tr><tr><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Immediately</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">0</td></tr></tbody></table></table-wrap><p>Clinical Implication</p><p>This tool offers significant clinical implications, promoting individualized patient care by identifying those requiring meticulous procedural adjustments or close post-procedural monitoring. For high-risk patients, practitioners can implement advanced injection techniques, such as using cannulas in high-risk areas or opting for safer filler types. Furthermore, it encourages early recognition of vascular compromise, facilitating timely interventions to prevent long-term complications. Integrating this tool into routine practice enhances safety and decision-making in aesthetic medicine, especially in high-stakes scenarios.&#160;The results of applying the morbidity risk assessment tool to our patient population are presented in Table <xref rid="TAB5" ref-type="table">5</xref>.</p><table-wrap position="float" id="TAB5" orientation="portrait"><label>Table 5</label><caption><title>Risk assessment of the patient population</title></caption><table frame="hsides" rules="groups"><tbody><tr style="background-color:#ccc"><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Case</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Gender</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Substance</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Injection Site</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Vessel</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Onset</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Total Points</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Risk Category</td></tr><tr><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Grunebaum et al., 2009&#160;[<xref rid="REF20" ref-type="bibr">20</xref>]</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Female (2)</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">HA (3)</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Nose (2)</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Facial artery (1)</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Immediately (0)</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">8</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Moderate risk</td></tr><tr style="background-color:#ccc"><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Grunebaum et al., 2009&#160;[<xref rid="REF20" ref-type="bibr">20</xref>]</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Male (1)</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">HA (3)</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Nasolabial fold (0)</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Facial artery (1)</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">&lt;5 days (1)</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">6</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Moderate risk</td></tr><tr><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Pan et al., 2021&#160;[<xref rid="REF21" ref-type="bibr">21</xref>]</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Female (2)</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">HA (3)</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Forehead (2)</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Central retinal artery (3)</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">&lt;5 days (1)</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">11</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">High risk</td></tr><tr style="background-color:#ccc"><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Beleznay et al., 2014&#160;[<xref rid="REF22" ref-type="bibr">22</xref>]</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Female (2)</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">CaHa (2)</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Nasolabial fold (0)</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Multiple facial vessels (1)</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">&gt;5 days (2)</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">7</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Moderate risk</td></tr><tr><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Beleznay et al., 2014&#160;[<xref rid="REF22" ref-type="bibr">22</xref>]</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Male (1)</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">HA (3)</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Cheek (1)</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Multiple facial vessels (1)</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">&lt;5 days (1)</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">7</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Moderate risk</td></tr><tr style="background-color:#ccc"><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Beleznay et al., 2014&#160;[<xref rid="REF22" ref-type="bibr">22</xref>]</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Female (2)</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">CaHa (2)</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Nose (2)</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Angular artery (1)</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">&lt;5 days (1)</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">8</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Moderate risk</td></tr><tr><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Beleznay et al., 2014&#160;[<xref rid="REF22" ref-type="bibr">22</xref>]</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Female (2)</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">HA (3)</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Nasolabial fold (0)</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Facial artery (1)</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">&lt;5 days (1)</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">7</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Moderate risk</td></tr><tr style="background-color:#ccc"><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Beleznay et al., 2014&#160;[<xref rid="REF22" ref-type="bibr">22</xref>]</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Female (2)</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">HA (3)</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Nose (2)</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Multiple facial vessels (1)</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">&gt;5 days (2)</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">10</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">High risk</td></tr><tr><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Beleznay et al., 2014&#160;[<xref rid="REF22" ref-type="bibr">22</xref>]</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Female (2)</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">HA (3)</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Nasolabial fold (0)</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Facial artery (1)</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">&lt;5 days (1)</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">7</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Moderate risk</td></tr><tr style="background-color:#ccc"><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Beleznay et al., 2014&#160;[<xref rid="REF22" ref-type="bibr">22</xref>]</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Male (1)</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">CaHa (2)</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Glabella (3)</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Supraorbital artery (1)</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">&lt;5 days (1)</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">8</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Moderate risk</td></tr><tr><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Beleznay et al., 2014&#160;[<xref rid="REF22" ref-type="bibr">22</xref>]</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Female (2)</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">CaHa (2)</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Nasolabial fold (0)</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Facial artery (1)</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Immediately (0)</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">5</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Moderate risk</td></tr><tr style="background-color:#ccc"><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Thanasarnaksorn et al., 2018&#160;[<xref rid="REF10" ref-type="bibr">10</xref>]</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Female (2)</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">HA (3)</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Cheek (1)</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Ophthalmic artery (4)</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Immediately (0)</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">10</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">High risk</td></tr><tr><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Thanasarnaksorn et al., 2018&#160;[<xref rid="REF10" ref-type="bibr">10</xref>]</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Female (2)</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">HA (3)</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Nose (2)</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Central retinal artery (3)</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Immediately (0)</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">10</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">High risk</td></tr><tr style="background-color:#ccc"><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Thanasarnaksorn et al., 2018&#160;[<xref rid="REF10" ref-type="bibr">10</xref>]</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Female (2)</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">HA (3)</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Nose (2)</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Central retinal artery (3)</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Immediately (0)</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">10</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">High risk</td></tr><tr><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Thanasarnaksorn et al., 2018&#160;[<xref rid="REF10" ref-type="bibr">10</xref>]</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Male (1)</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">HA (3)</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Nose (2)</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Central retinal artery (3)</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Immediately (0)</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">9</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Moderate risk</td></tr><tr style="background-color:#ccc"><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Thanasarnaksorn et al., 2018&#160;[<xref rid="REF10" ref-type="bibr">10</xref>]</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Female (2)</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">HA (3)</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Forehead (2)</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Ophthalmic artery (4)</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Immediately (0)</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">11</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">High risk</td></tr><tr><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Thanasarnaksorn et al., 2018&#160;[<xref rid="REF10" ref-type="bibr">10</xref>]</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Female (2)</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">HA (3)</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Temporal area (1)</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Central retinal artery (3)</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Immediately (0)</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">9</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Moderate risk</td></tr><tr style="background-color:#ccc"><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Cassiano et al., 2020&#160;[<xref rid="REF23" ref-type="bibr">23</xref>]</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Female (2)</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">HA (3)</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Forehead (2)</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Supratrochlear artery (1)</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">&lt;5 days (1)</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">9</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Moderate risk</td></tr></tbody></table></table-wrap><p>Discussion</p><p>This study looked into the vascular occlusions related to using any aesthetic filler injection while addressing possible risk factors, management, and clinical outcomes (a graphical abstract of the study is shown in Figure <xref rid="FIG2" ref-type="fig">2</xref>). Its results recommend that a customized approach toward aesthetic medicine would enhance patient safety and give an optimized effect in the treatments offered [<xref rid="REF24" ref-type="bibr">24</xref>]. The predominance of vascular occlusions in the female population studied was 71%, corresponding with the demographic trend that most patients who undergo cosmetic procedures in facial enhancement are women [<xref rid="REF25" ref-type="bibr">25</xref>].&#160;This gender disparity, however, might also reflect anatomical blockages or physiological differences that predispose female patients to such complications. HA has been implicated as a filler in almost 61.3 percent of the cases analyzed. This may well be attributed to the general inclination of individuals for the use of such fillers, given that they are biocompatible as well as reversible by hyaluronidase, and not due to a tendency to be more naturally occlusive with blood vessels in comparison with other fillers such as CaHa&#160;or PLLA.</p><p>The location in which the filler is injected is regarded as the most critical parameter for assessing vascular risk. The occlusive events have occurred most frequently in high-risk anatomic zones such as the glabella, nose, and nasolabial folds. Rich vascular networks, such as the ophthalmic and angular arteries, have direct connections to the retinal circulation, making these areas particularly susceptible to occlusions and increasing the severity of resulting complications, such as blindness and extensive tissue necrosis [<xref rid="REF26" ref-type="bibr">26</xref>]. Comparatively, higher site areas like the lateral cheek and jawline have been noted to significantly decrease occlusion incidences, indicating that risk evaluation should form part of a procedure's site-specific component. Occlusions involving minor arteries, such as the supraorbital, supratrochlear, and infraorbital branches, demonstrated better recovery odds (OR 9.67, p=0.02), likely due to their smaller caliber and limited vascular territory. This is why there is a need for anatomical precision during injections, particularly in high-risk zones.</p><p>The time taken to present is critical to the clinical outcome of the patient. Immediate recognition of vascular compromise within hours of injection is associated with very good recovery, while recognition of such events much later (greater than five days) is associated with poor prognosis with irreversible tissue loss and possible vision loss. It emphasizes the need for better awareness among both the practitioners and patients regarding the early signs of vascular occlusion (blanching, pain, and livedo reticularis) as warning signals. The monitoring of patients in these intervention procedures should be in real-time because it is important to document early signs of intravascular injection, including resistance to injection and immediate blanching. Such events require immediate cessation and corrective action.</p><p>Managing vascular occlusions was primarily dependent on hyaluronidase treatment, typically indicated for cases involving HA fillers. Administration of targeted high-dose hyaluronidase injections was established to yield an 84.2% chance of partial or complete recovery, reaffirming it as the first-line treatment. Augmentative treatment options such as nitroglycerin paste, aspirin, corticosteroids, and hyperbaric oxygen therapy had, however, complemented recovery in some cases.</p><p>The inconsistency across studies throws a glaring light on an urgent need to develop treatment protocols and guidelines for filler-induced vascular events [<xref rid="REF27" ref-type="bibr">27</xref>,<xref rid="REF28" ref-type="bibr">28</xref>].</p><p>The expertise of the practitioner was another significant factor in avoiding complications owing to the possibility of high incidence of vascular occlusions caused by faulty techniques used. The safest measures hence recommended included the use of blunt-tipped cannulae rather than sharp needles in injection high-risk areas, slow retrograde injections, and repeated aspiration before injection to prevent intravascular placements. Similarly, before any procedure, vascular mapping using imaging modalities such as ultrasound can also give a proactive approach to high-risk anatomical variations and reduce complication rates. Such practice of case selection will continue being competent in risk mitigation and at promoting individual evaluations for detection of candidates at an even higher risk of developing vascular occlusions. Besides the anatomy, preexisting vascular conditions, history of thromboembolic events, and previous adverse reactions to dermal fillers should inform decision-making. This suggested tool for vascular occlusion morbidity-risk assessment could become a promising framework that one will use in stratifying low, moderate, and high-risk patients so that they can have their own adjusted and personalized procedural and post-treatment monitoring.</p><p>There is a clear need for standardized diagnostic criteria and reporting frameworks to improve data reliability and facilitate more comprehensive analyses in future research. Future research should focus its efforts on large-scale, prospective studies, which will prove to be strategic in validating these observations and refining evidence-based management protocols. The standardization of risk stratification tools and the consensus-derived treatment algorithms would go a long way toward&#160;standardizing safety measures and thereby enhancing patient outcomes in aesthetic medicine.</p><p>Developing and adhering to evidence-based guidelines for managing vascular occlusions can reduce variability in outcomes. A unified protocol that incorporates hyaluronidase dosing, timing, and adjunctive therapies would be particularly beneficial. This study reinforces that prompt recognition and intervention are critical for favorable outcomes. Occlusions presenting within one day were associated with higher recovery rates, while delays beyond five days correlated with poor outcomes. Standardized treatment protocols, including immediate administration of hyaluronidase for HA fillers and adjunctive therapies, should be widely adopted to ensure consistency in managing complications.</p><p>This study looks into the multifaceted nature of vascular occlusion and takes into consideration the anatomical risk factors, procedural techniques, and timely interventions. These findings highlight the importance of practitioner training in specific assessments of individual patient risk, along with the management protocol for trying to reduce the occurrence of complications. The use of hyaluronidase remains a cornerstone in treating occlusions with HA, but an integrated approach employing different adjunct therapies and different procedural safeguards will ensure maximum healing. While aesthetic medicine is constantly evolving, research and clinical compliance will remain important to the safety and efficacy of dermal filler procedures.</p><p>However, while this study presents valuable findings (Table <xref rid="TAB6" ref-type="table">6</xref>), there are limitations to its interpretation. The dependence on case reports and retrospective data brings with it all of the biases inherent in such studies, including variability in reporting standards and a disproportionate emphasis placed on severe or otherwise atypical events. This will therefore lead to an underreporting of milder or transient vascular occlusions, although the general trend may be skewed toward more dramatic presentations. In addition, the variability in the methodology used in determining the studies, the patients uninvolved, and the different filler types used complicate comparison across studies and render the findings less generalized. The heterogeneity of the dataset further impacts the generalizability of findings. Variability in study methodologies, patient demographics, filler types, and management protocols complicates the interpretation of pooled data. For instance, the inconsistency in defining vascular occlusions and reporting recovery outcomes hampers cross-study comparisons.</p><table-wrap position="float" id="TAB6" orientation="portrait"><label>Table 6</label><caption><title>Summary of findings</title><p>HA, hyaluronic acid</p></caption><table frame="hsides" rules="groups"><tbody><tr style="background-color:#ccc"><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Finding Area</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Summary</td></tr><tr><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Most common filler material</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">HA (61.3%) was most commonly implicated</td></tr><tr style="background-color:#ccc"><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Recovery with hyaluronidase</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">84.2% of HA-related occlusions showed partial or complete recovery with hyaluronidase</td></tr><tr><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Vessel involvement and prognosis</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Minor artery involvement showed better recovery (OR 9.67, p=0.02)</td></tr><tr style="background-color:#ccc"><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">High-risk injection sites</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Glabella, nose, and nasolabial folds were most associated with severe complications</td></tr><tr><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Gender distribution</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">71% of affected patients were female</td></tr><tr style="background-color:#ccc"><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Impact of time to presentation</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Early presentation (immediate or &lt;1 day) correlated with better recovery</td></tr><tr><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Overall recovery outcomes</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">58% full recovery; 12.9% showed no recovery and had permanent deficits</td></tr><tr style="background-color:#ccc"><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Risk stratification tool</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Tool developed to stratify patients into low, moderate, and high-risk groups</td></tr></tbody></table></table-wrap></sec><sec sec-type="conclusions"><title>Conclusions</title><p>This meta-analysis identifies key procedural and anatomical risk factors contributing to vascular occlusion following dermal filler injections. Findings underscore the importance of proper injection technique, detailed anatomical knowledge, and prompt recognition of vascular compromise to reduce the risk of serious complications such as tissue necrosis or vision loss. High-risk facial regions, particularly the glabella, nose, and nasolabial folds, were most commonly associated with adverse outcomes, reinforcing the need for advanced practitioner training and refined injection approaches. The study also highlights the vital role of hyaluronidase in treating complications related to HA fillers, with a high proportion of cases showing partial or complete recovery following timely administration.</p><p>Nonetheless, the conclusions drawn are limited by the retrospective nature of the data, variability in case reporting, and a lack of uniform diagnostic criteria across studies. The small sample size and inconsistency in methodology prevented detailed subgroup analyses on the impact of factors like demographics, comorbidities, and specific injection techniques. These limitations highlight the urgent need for standardized definitions, reporting frameworks, and clinical protocols to ensure consistency in both research and practice. Future research should prioritize multicenter, prospective studies with larger and more diverse patient populations to validate these findings and refine best practices. The development of comprehensive, evidence-based guidelines for procedural safety, anatomical risk mapping, and emergency intervention protocols is essential. Moreover, incorporating patient-specific factors, such as individual vascular anatomy and medical history, into pre-procedural planning can further personalize care and improve outcomes. These efforts will be instrumental in enhancing safety standards and advancing the quality of care in aesthetic medicine.</p></sec></body><back><fn-group content-type="conflict"><title>Disclosures</title><fn fn-type="COI-statement"><p><bold>Conflicts of interest:</bold> In compliance with the ICMJE uniform disclosure form, all authors declare the following:</p><p><bold>Payment/services info:</bold> All authors have declared that no financial support was received from any organization for the submitted work.</p><p><bold>Financial relationships:</bold> All authors have declared that they have no financial relationships at present or within the previous three years with any organizations that might have an interest in the submitted work.</p><p><bold>Other relationships:</bold> All authors have declared that there are no other relationships or activities that could appear to have influenced the submitted work.</p></fn></fn-group><fn-group content-type="other"><title>Author Contributions</title><fn fn-type="other"><p><bold>Concept and design:</bold>&#160; Adham Chakhachiro </p><p><bold>Acquisition, analysis, or interpretation of data:</bold>&#160; Adham Chakhachiro , Maaz Waseem</p><p><bold>Drafting of the manuscript:</bold>&#160; Adham Chakhachiro , Maaz Waseem</p><p><bold>Supervision:</bold>&#160; Adham Chakhachiro </p><p><bold>Critical review of the manuscript for important intellectual content:</bold>&#160; Maaz Waseem</p></fn></fn-group><app-group><app><title>Appendices</title><fig position="anchor" fig-type="figure" id="FIG2" orientation="portrait"><label>Figure 2</label><caption><title>Graphical abstract of the study</title><p>Image credits: Authors</p></caption><graphic xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" position="float" orientation="portrait" xlink:href="cureus-0017-00000082800-i02.jpg"/></fig><table-wrap position="anchor" id="TAB7" orientation="portrait"><label>Table 7</label><caption><title>Databases</title></caption><table frame="hsides" rules="groups"><tbody><tr style="background-color:#ccc"><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">
Database
</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">
Search Strategy
</td></tr><tr><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">
PubMed
</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">
("vascular occlusion"[MeSH Terms] OR "vascular occlusion"[Title/Abstract] OR "arterial occlusion"[Title/Abstract] OR "venous occlusion"[Title/Abstract])
AND
("dermal fillers"[MeSH Terms] OR "dermal fillers"[Title/Abstract] OR "injectable fillers"[Title/Abstract] OR "soft tissue augmentation"[Title/Abstract])
AND
("risk factors"[MeSH Terms] OR "risk factors"[Title/Abstract] OR "complications"[Title/Abstract] OR "adverse events"[Title/Abstract])
AND
("case-control studies"[MeSH Terms] OR "case-control"[Title/Abstract] OR "cohort studies"[MeSH Terms] OR "cohort"[Title/Abstract] OR "case series"[Title/Abstract] OR "retrospective"[Title/Abstract] OR "prospective"[Title/Abstract])
</td></tr><tr style="background-color:#ccc"><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">
Google Scholar
</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">
"vascular occlusion" OR "arterial occlusion" OR "venous occlusion" AND "dermal fillers" OR "injectable fillers" OR "soft tissue augmentation" AND "risk factors" OR "complications" OR "adverse events" AND ("case-control" OR "cohort" OR "case series" OR "retrospective" OR "prospective")
</td></tr><tr><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">
Cochrane
</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">
("vascular occlusion" OR "arterial occlusion" OR "venous occlusion") AND ("dermal fillers" OR "injectable fillers" OR "soft tissue augmentation") AND ("risk factors" OR "complications" OR "adverse events") AND ("case-control" OR "cohort" OR "case series" OR "retrospective" OR "prospective")
</td></tr></tbody></table></table-wrap></app></app-group><ref-list><title>References</title><ref id="REF1"><label>1</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><article-title>The research trend of soft tissue filler injection from 2000 to 2022: a bibliometric and visualized analysis</article-title><source>Plast Reconstr Surg Glob Open</source><person-group><name name-style="western"><surname>Liao</surname><given-names>ZF</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Cong</surname><given-names>LY</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Li</surname><given-names>FW</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Wang</surname><given-names>SW</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Liu</surname><given-names>FC</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Wang</surname><given-names>HB</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Luo</surname><given-names>SK</given-names></name></person-group><fpage>0</fpage><volume>12</volume><year>2024</year><pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1097/GOX.0000000000005579</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC10836874</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">38313594</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="REF2"><label>2</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><article-title>Comprehensive assessment of intradermal responses to hyaluronic acid-based skin injection fillers through multi-pathway dynamic synergies</article-title><source>Colloids Surf B Biointerfaces</source><person-group><name name-style="western"><surname>Zhong</surname><given-names>M</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>He</surname><given-names>H</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Wang</surname><given-names>L</given-names></name><etal/></person-group><fpage>114378</fpage><volume>246</volume><year>2025</year><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">39551036</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1016/j.colsurfb.2024.114378</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="REF3"><label>3</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><article-title>The gold protocol: a combined treatment approach for neck rejuvenation with calcium hydroxyapatite, botulinum toxin, and hyaluronic acid in the same session</article-title><source>J Cosmet Dermatol</source><person-group><name name-style="western"><surname>de Sanctis Pecora</surname><given-names>C</given-names></name></person-group><fpage>2392</fpage><lpage>2400</lpage><volume>23</volume><year>2024</year><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">38566435</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1111/jocd.16296</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="REF4"><label>4</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><article-title>A histopathologic diagnosis of vascular occlusion after injection of hyaluronic acid filler: findings of intravascular foreign body and skin necrosis</article-title><source>Aesthet Surg J</source><person-group><name name-style="western"><surname>Maruyama</surname><given-names>S</given-names></name></person-group><fpage>0</fpage><lpage>8</lpage><volume>37</volume><year>2017</year><pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1093/asj/sjx085</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">29025226</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="REF5"><label>5</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><article-title>Complications of injectables</article-title><source>Atlas Oral Maxillofac Surg Clin North Am</source><person-group><name name-style="western"><surname>Quach</surname><given-names>B</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Clevens</surname><given-names>RA</given-names></name></person-group><fpage>57</fpage><lpage>63</lpage><volume>32</volume><year>2024</year><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">38307636</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1016/j.cxom.2023.10.005</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="REF6"><label>6</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><article-title>Hyaluronic acid filler-induced vascular occlusion-three case reports and overview of prevention and treatment</article-title><source>J Cosmet Dermatol</source><person-group><name name-style="western"><surname>Wang</surname><given-names>R</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Li</surname><given-names>Y</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Li</surname><given-names>Z</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Yao</surname><given-names>H</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Zhai</surname><given-names>Z</given-names></name></person-group><fpage>1217</fpage><lpage>1223</lpage><volume>23</volume><year>2024</year><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">38131127</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1111/jocd.16147</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="REF7"><label>7</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><article-title>Patterns of filler-induced facial skin ischemia: a systematic review of 243 cases and introduction of the FOEM scoring system and grading scale</article-title><source>Plast Reconstr Surg</source><person-group><name name-style="western"><surname>Soares</surname><given-names>DJ</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Bowhay</surname><given-names>A</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Blevins</surname><given-names>LW</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Patel</surname><given-names>SM</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Zuliani</surname><given-names>GF</given-names></name></person-group><fpage>592</fpage><lpage>608</lpage><volume>151</volume><year>2023</year><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">36477154</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1097/PRS.0000000000009991</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="REF8"><label>8</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><article-title>Male rejuvenation: injectables</article-title><source>Facial Plast Surg Clin North Am</source><person-group><name name-style="western"><surname>Hall</surname><given-names>DB</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Kim</surname><given-names>LR</given-names></name></person-group><fpage>425</fpage><lpage>435</lpage><volume>32</volume><year>2024</year><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">38937000</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1016/j.fsc.2024.02.007</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="REF9"><label>9</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><article-title>Management of vascular complications following facial hyaluronic acid injection: high-dose hyaluronidase protocol: a technical note</article-title><source>J Stomatol Oral Maxillofac Surg</source><person-group><name name-style="western"><surname>Rouanet</surname><given-names>C</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Kestemont</surname><given-names>P</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Winter</surname><given-names>C</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Lerhe</surname><given-names>B</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Savoldelli</surname><given-names>C</given-names></name></person-group><fpage>262</fpage><lpage>265</lpage><volume>123</volume><year>2022</year><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">34157447</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1016/j.jormas.2021.05.014</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="REF10"><label>10</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><article-title>Severe vision loss caused by cosmetic filler augmentation: case series with review of cause and therapy</article-title><source>J Cosmet Dermatol</source><person-group><name name-style="western"><surname>Thanasarnaksorn</surname><given-names>W</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Cotofana</surname><given-names>S</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Rudolph</surname><given-names>C</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Kraisak</surname><given-names>P</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Chanasumon</surname><given-names>N</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Suwanchinda</surname><given-names>A</given-names></name></person-group><fpage>712</fpage><lpage>718</lpage><volume>17</volume><year>2018</year><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">30006992</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1111/jocd.12705</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="REF11"><label>11</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><article-title>The CARE guidelines: consensus-based clinical case reporting guideline development</article-title><source>Headache</source><person-group><name name-style="western"><surname>Gagnier</surname><given-names>JJ</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Kienle</surname><given-names>G</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Altman</surname><given-names>DG</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Moher</surname><given-names>D</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Sox</surname><given-names>H</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Riley</surname><given-names>D</given-names></name></person-group><fpage>1541</fpage><lpage>1547</lpage><volume>53</volume><year>2013</year><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">24266334</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1111/head.12246</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="REF12"><label>12</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><article-title>Ocular and cerebral infarction from periocular filler injection</article-title><source>Orbit</source><person-group><name name-style="western"><surname>Ansari</surname><given-names>ZA</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Choi</surname><given-names>CJ</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Rong</surname><given-names>AJ</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Erickson</surname><given-names>BP</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Tse</surname><given-names>DT</given-names></name></person-group><fpage>322</fpage><lpage>324</lpage><volume>38</volume><year>2019</year><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">30376386</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1080/01676830.2018.1537287</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="REF13"><label>13</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><article-title>Visual loss from dermal fillers</article-title><source>Eur J Ophthalmol</source><person-group><name name-style="western"><surname>Jolly</surname><given-names>R</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Bhalla</surname><given-names>M</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Zakir</surname><given-names>R</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Joshi</surname><given-names>N</given-names></name></person-group><fpage>0</fpage><lpage>5</lpage><volume>31</volume><year>2021</year><pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1177/1120672119855856</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">31187644</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="REF14"><label>14</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><article-title>Cosmetic facial fillers and severe vision loss</article-title><source>JAMA Ophthalmol</source><person-group><name name-style="western"><surname>Carle</surname><given-names>MV</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Roe</surname><given-names>R</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Novack</surname><given-names>R</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Boyer</surname><given-names>DS</given-names></name></person-group><fpage>637</fpage><lpage>639</lpage><volume>132</volume><year>2014</year><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">24604287</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1001/jamaophthalmol.2014.498</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="REF15"><label>15</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><article-title>Choroid vascular occlusion and ischemic optic neuropathy after facial calcium hydroxyapatite injection - a case report</article-title><source>BMC Surg</source><person-group><name name-style="western"><surname>Chou</surname><given-names>CC</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Chen</surname><given-names>HH</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Tsai</surname><given-names>YY</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Li</surname><given-names>YL</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Lin</surname><given-names>HJ</given-names></name></person-group><fpage>21</fpage><volume>15</volume><year>2015</year><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">25884651</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1186/s12893-015-0007-3</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC4359764</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="REF16"><label>16</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><article-title>Skin necrosis after calcium hydroxylapatite injection into the glabellar and nasolabial folds</article-title><source>Ophthalmic Plast Reconstr Surg</source><person-group><name name-style="western"><surname>Georgescu</surname><given-names>D</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Jones</surname><given-names>Y</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>McCann</surname><given-names>JD</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Anderson</surname><given-names>RL</given-names></name></person-group><fpage>498</fpage><lpage>499</lpage><volume>25</volume><year>2009</year><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">19935263</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1097/IOP.0b013e3181b81082</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="REF17"><label>17</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><article-title>Ocular ischemia and ischemic oculomotor nerve palsy after vascular embolization of injectable calcium hydroxylapatite filler</article-title><source>Ophthalmic Plast Reconstr Surg</source><person-group><name name-style="western"><surname>Sung</surname><given-names>MS</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Kim</surname><given-names>HG</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Woo</surname><given-names>KI</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Kim</surname><given-names>YD</given-names></name></person-group><fpage>289</fpage><lpage>291</lpage><volume>26</volume><year>2010</year><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">20523258</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1097/IOP.0b013e3181bd4341</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="REF18"><label>18</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><article-title>Severe visual loss and orbital infarction following periorbital aesthetic poly-(L)-lactic acid (PLLA) injection</article-title><source>Ophthalmic Plast Reconstr Surg</source><person-group><name name-style="western"><surname>Roberts</surname><given-names>SA</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Arthurs</surname><given-names>BP</given-names></name></person-group><fpage>0</fpage><lpage>70</lpage><volume>28</volume><year>2012</year><uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xlink:href="https://journals.lww.com/op-rs/fulltext/2012/05000/Severe_Visual_Loss_and_Orbital_Infarction.34.aspx">https://journals.lww.com/op-rs/fulltext/2012/05000/Severe_Visual_Loss_and_Orbital_Infarction.34.aspx</uri><pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1097/IOP.0b013e3182288e4d</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">21862947</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="REF19"><label>19</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><article-title>Extensive necrosis after injection of hyaluronic acid filler: case report and review of the literature</article-title><source>J Cosmet Dermatol</source><person-group><name name-style="western"><surname>Kassir</surname><given-names>R</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Kolluru</surname><given-names>A</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Kassir</surname><given-names>M</given-names></name></person-group><fpage>224</fpage><lpage>231</lpage><volume>10</volume><year>2011</year><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">21896135</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1111/j.1473-2165.2011.00562.x</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="REF20"><label>20</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><article-title>The risk of alar necrosis associated with dermal filler injection</article-title><source>Dermatol Surg</source><person-group><name name-style="western"><surname>Grunebaum</surname><given-names>LD</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Bogdan Allemann</surname><given-names>I</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Dayan</surname><given-names>S</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Mandy</surname><given-names>S</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Baumann</surname><given-names>L</given-names></name></person-group><fpage>1635</fpage><lpage>1640</lpage><volume>35 Suppl 2</volume><year>2009</year><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">19807758</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1111/j.1524-4725.2009.01342.x</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="REF21"><label>21</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><article-title>Injectable soft tissue nano/micro fillers for facial reconstruction</article-title><source>J Biomed Nanotechnol</source><person-group><name name-style="western"><surname>Pan</surname><given-names>Y</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Hao</surname><given-names>Y</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Xiao</surname><given-names>Y</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Shi</surname><given-names>K</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Qu</surname><given-names>Y</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Qian</surname><given-names>Z</given-names></name></person-group><fpage>1</fpage><lpage>17</lpage><volume>17</volume><year>2021</year><uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xlink:href="https://www.ingentaconnect.com/contentone/asp/jbn/2021/00000017/00000001/art00001">https://www.ingentaconnect.com/contentone/asp/jbn/2021/00000017/00000001/art00001</uri><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">33653493</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1166/jbn.2021.3011</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="REF22"><label>22</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><article-title>Vascular compromise from soft tissue augmentation: experience with 12 cases and recommendations for optimal outcomes</article-title><source>J Clin Aesthet Dermatol</source><person-group><name name-style="western"><surname>Beleznay</surname><given-names>K</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Humphrey</surname><given-names>S</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Carruthers</surname><given-names>JD</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Carruthers</surname><given-names>A</given-names></name></person-group><fpage>37</fpage><lpage>43</lpage><volume>7</volume><year>2014</year><uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xlink:href="https://jcadonline.com/vascular-compromise-from-soft-tissue-augmentation/">https://jcadonline.com/vascular-compromise-from-soft-tissue-augmentation/</uri><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC4174919</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">25276276</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="REF23"><label>23</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><article-title>Delayed skin necrosis following hyaluronic acid filler injection: a case report</article-title><source>J Cosmet Dermatol</source><person-group><name name-style="western"><surname>Cassiano</surname><given-names>D</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Miyuki Iida</surname><given-names>T</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>L&#250;cia Recio</surname><given-names>A</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Yarak</surname><given-names>S</given-names></name></person-group><fpage>582</fpage><lpage>584</lpage><volume>19</volume><year>2020</year><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">31925876</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1111/jocd.13287</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="REF24"><label>24</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><article-title>Aesthetic surgical pathway in permanent facial filler removal</article-title><source>Facial Plast Surg</source><person-group><name name-style="western"><surname>Pascali</surname><given-names>M</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Chirico</surname><given-names>F</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Rugge</surname><given-names>L</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Rauso</surname><given-names>R</given-names></name></person-group><fpage>19</fpage><lpage>30</lpage><volume>40</volume><year>2024</year><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">36696919</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1055/a-2019-5131</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="REF25"><label>25</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><article-title>In vivo models for the study of hyaluronic acid fillers: a review</article-title><source>Aesthetic Plast Surg</source><person-group><name name-style="western"><surname>Salinas-Alvarez</surname><given-names>Y</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Quiroga-Garza</surname><given-names>A</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Soto-Dominguez</surname><given-names>A</given-names></name><etal/></person-group><fpage>1185</fpage><lpage>1191</lpage><volume>47</volume><year>2023</year><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">36595036</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1007/s00266-022-03212-y</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="REF26"><label>26</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><article-title>Causes and management of sight threatening complications of dermal filler injections: a review</article-title><source>Clin Exp Ophthalmol</source><person-group><name name-style="western"><surname>Botha</surname><given-names>VE</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Insull</surname><given-names>EA</given-names></name></person-group><fpage>365</fpage><lpage>373</lpage><volume>52</volume><year>2024</year><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">38380782</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1111/ceo.14362</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="REF27"><label>27</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><article-title>Optimal practices in the delivery of aesthetic medical care to patients on immunosuppressants and immunomodulators: a systematic review of the literature</article-title><source>Aesthet Surg J</source><person-group><name name-style="western"><surname>Cattelan</surname><given-names>L</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Dayan</surname><given-names>S</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Fabi</surname><given-names>SG</given-names></name></person-group><fpage>0</fpage><lpage>28</lpage><volume>44</volume><year>2024</year><pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1093/asj/sjae141</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">38967686</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="REF28"><label>28</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><article-title>The use of hyaluronidase in aesthetic practice: a comparative study of practitioner usage in elective and emergency situations</article-title><source>Aesthet Surg J</source><person-group><name name-style="western"><surname>Currie</surname><given-names>E</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Granata</surname><given-names>B</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Goodman</surname><given-names>G</given-names></name><etal/></person-group><fpage>647</fpage><lpage>657</lpage><volume>44</volume><year>2024</year><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">38262634</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1093/asj/sjae009</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC11093658</pub-id></element-citation></ref></ref-list></back></article></pmc-articleset>