<?xml version="1.0"  ?><!DOCTYPE pmc-articleset PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD ARTICLE SET 2.0//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pmc/articleset/nlm-articleset-2.0.dtd"><pmc-articleset><article xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" xmlns:ali="http://www.niso.org/schemas/ali/1.0/" article-type="review-article" xml:lang="en" dtd-version="1.4"><processing-meta base-tagset="archiving" mathml-version="3.0" table-model="xhtml" tagset-family="jats"><restricted-by>pmc</restricted-by></processing-meta><front><journal-meta><journal-id journal-id-type="nlm-ta">Aesthetic Plast Surg</journal-id><journal-id journal-id-type="iso-abbrev">Aesthetic Plast Surg</journal-id><journal-id journal-id-type="pmc-domain-id">365</journal-id><journal-id journal-id-type="pmc-domain">springeropen</journal-id><journal-title-group><journal-title>Aesthetic Plastic Surgery</journal-title></journal-title-group><issn pub-type="ppub">0364-216X</issn><issn pub-type="epub">1432-5241</issn><custom-meta-group><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-is-collection-domain</meta-name><meta-value>yes</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-collection-title</meta-name><meta-value>Springer</meta-value></custom-meta></custom-meta-group></journal-meta><article-meta><article-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC10999391</article-id><article-id pub-id-type="pmcid-ver">PMC10999391.1</article-id><article-id pub-id-type="pmcaid">10999391</article-id><article-id pub-id-type="pmcaiid">10999391</article-id><article-id pub-id-type="pmid">36536092</article-id><article-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1007/s00266-022-03207-9</article-id><article-id pub-id-type="publisher-id">3207</article-id><article-version article-version-type="pmc-version">1</article-version><article-categories><subj-group subj-group-type="heading"><subject>Review</subject></subj-group></article-categories><title-group><article-title>A Scoping Review of Hyaluronidase Use in Managing the Complications of Aesthetic Interventions</article-title></title-group><contrib-group><contrib contrib-type="author" corresp="yes"><contrib-id contrib-id-type="orcid" authenticated="false">http://orcid.org/0000-0002-3729-2348</contrib-id><name name-style="western"><surname>Borzabadi-Farahani</surname><given-names initials="A">Ali</given-names></name><address><email>faraortho@yahoo.com</email></address><xref ref-type="aff" rid="Aff1">1</xref><xref ref-type="aff" rid="Aff2">2</xref></contrib><contrib contrib-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Mosahebi</surname><given-names initials="A">Afshin</given-names></name><xref ref-type="aff" rid="Aff3">3</xref></contrib><contrib contrib-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Zargaran</surname><given-names initials="D">David</given-names></name><xref ref-type="aff" rid="Aff3">3</xref></contrib><aff id="Aff1"><label>1</label><institution-wrap><institution-id institution-id-type="ROR">https://ror.org/02jx3x895</institution-id><institution-id institution-id-type="GRID">grid.83440.3b</institution-id><institution-id institution-id-type="ISNI">0000 0001 2190 1201</institution-id><institution>Division of Surgery &amp; Interventional Science (Minimally Invasive Aesthetics), </institution><institution>University College London (UCL), </institution></institution-wrap>London, WC1E 6BT UK </aff><aff id="Aff2"><label>2</label>Crouch End Orthodontics, 72 Crouch End Hill, London, N8 8AG England UK </aff><aff id="Aff3"><label>3</label><institution-wrap><institution-id institution-id-type="GRID">grid.83440.3b</institution-id><institution-id institution-id-type="ISNI">0000000121901201</institution-id><institution>Department of Plastic Surgery, </institution><institution>Royal Free Hospital, University College London, </institution></institution-wrap>London, UK </aff></contrib-group><pub-date pub-type="epub"><day>19</day><month>12</month><year>2022</year></pub-date><pub-date pub-type="ppub"><year>2024</year></pub-date><volume>48</volume><issue>6</issue><issue-id pub-id-type="pmc-issue-id">459571</issue-id><fpage>1193</fpage><lpage>1209</lpage><history><date date-type="received"><day>22</day><month>7</month><year>2022</year></date><date date-type="accepted"><day>19</day><month>11</month><year>2022</year></date></history><pub-history><event event-type="pmc-release"><date><day>19</day><month>12</month><year>2022</year></date></event><event event-type="pmc-live"><date><day>09</day><month>04</month><year>2024</year></date></event><event event-type="pmc-last-change"><date iso-8601-date="2024-04-09 00:25:13.160"><day>09</day><month>04</month><year>2024</year></date></event></pub-history><permissions><copyright-statement>&#169; The Author(s) 2022</copyright-statement><license><ali:license_ref specific-use="textmining" content-type="ccbylicense">https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</ali:license_ref><license-p><bold>Open Access</bold>This article is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution 4.0 International License, which permits use, sharing, adaptation, distribution and reproduction in any medium or format, as long as you give appropriate credit to the original author(s) and the source, provide a link to the Creative Commons licence, and indicate if changes were made. The images or other third party material in this article are included in the article's Creative Commons licence, unless indicated otherwise in a credit line to the material. If material is not included in the article's Creative Commons licence and your intended use is not permitted by statutory regulation or exceeds the permitted use, you will need to obtain permission directly from the copyright holder. To view a copy of this licence, visit <ext-link xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" ext-link-type="uri" xlink:href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/">http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</ext-link>.</license-p></license></permissions><self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" content-type="pmc-pdf" xlink:href="266_2022_Article_3207.pdf"/><abstract id="Abs1"><sec><title>Background</title><p id="Par1">Hyaluronidase is used as an adjunct or main treatment to manage complications associated with cosmetic hyaluronic acid (HA) filler injections such as necrosis, blindness, hypersensitivity, delayed nodules, and poor aesthetic outcomes.</p></sec><sec><title>Objective</title><p id="Par2">To systematically map the available evidence and identify the gaps in knowledge on the effectiveness of hyaluronidase use in managing the aesthetic complications associated with HA injections (vascular occlusion, blindness, nodules, delayed hypersensivity, granuloma, poor aesthetic outcome).</p></sec><sec><title>Methods</title><p id="Par3">PubMed, Medline, Embase and Cochrane databases were used up to May 2022, to look for randomized clinical trials (RCTs), clinical trials, and retrospective case-control studies reporting on the use of hyaluronidase for managing the HA filler injection complications.</p></sec><sec><title>Results</title><p id="Par4">The database search yielded 395 studies; of those 5 RCTs (all carried out in the USA) were selected (53 subjects), indicating the effectiveness of hyaluronidase for removal of un-complicated injected HA nodules (forearm, upper arm, or back skin). The follow-ups ranged from 14 days to 4 years. The amount of HA filler injected into each site varied from 0.2 to 0.4 mL. A dose dependent response was observed for most HA fillers. No major adverse reactions were reported. Overall, for removal of every 0.1 mL of HA filler they injected 1.25&#8211;37.5 units of hyaluronidase (single injections). When 3 consecutive weekly hyaluronidase injection was used much lower doses of 0.375&#8211;2.25 unit was utilised. There was no evidence in a form of RCTs, clinical trials, and retrospective case-control studies on the removal/reversal of HA injections in the facial skin, or management of over-corrections, inflammatory nodules, or tissue ischemia/necrosis associated with HA filler injection.</p></sec><sec><title>Conclusion</title><p id="Par5">Based on studies on the forearm, upper arm and back skin, hyaluronidase can be used for the reversal of uncomplicated HA filler injection nodule. However, further adequately powered studies are warranted to establish the ideal treatment protocol/dose of hyaluronidase for reversal of HA filler injections in the facial region or management of complications associated with aesthetic HA injection.</p></sec><sec><title>Level of Evidence III</title><p id="Par6">This journal requires that authors assign a level of evidence to each article. For a full description of these Evidence-Based Medicine ratings, please refer to the Table of Contents or the online Instructions to Authors <ext-link xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" ext-link-type="uri" xlink:href="http://www.springer.com/00266">www.springer.com/00266</ext-link>.</p></sec></abstract><kwd-group xml:lang="en"><title>Keywords</title><kwd>Hyaluronidase</kwd><kwd>Hyaluronic acid</kwd><kwd>HA filler</kwd><kwd>Aesthetic medicine</kwd></kwd-group><custom-meta-group><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-status-qastatus</meta-name><meta-value>0</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-status-live</meta-name><meta-value>yes</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-status-embargo</meta-name><meta-value>no</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-status-released</meta-name><meta-value>yes</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-open-access</meta-name><meta-value>yes</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-olf</meta-name><meta-value>no</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-manuscript</meta-name><meta-value>no</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-legally-suppressed</meta-name><meta-value>no</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-has-pdf</meta-name><meta-value>yes</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-has-supplement</meta-name><meta-value>no</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-pdf-only</meta-name><meta-value>no</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-suppress-copyright</meta-name><meta-value>no</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-is-real-version</meta-name><meta-value>no</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-is-scanned-article</meta-name><meta-value>no</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-preprint</meta-name><meta-value>no</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-in-epmc</meta-name><meta-value>yes</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-license-ref</meta-name><meta-value>CC BY</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>issue-copyright-statement</meta-name><meta-value>&#169; Springer Science+Business Media, LLC, part of Springer Nature and International Society of Aesthetic Plastic Surgery 2024</meta-value></custom-meta></custom-meta-group></article-meta></front><body><sec id="Sec1"><title>Introduction</title><p id="Par7">Cross-linked hyaluronic acid (hyaluronan, HA) is a polysaccharide; the most used reversible filler in aesthetic medicine [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR1">1</xref>, <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR2">2</xref>]. HA is a highly hydrophilic molecule and an essential part of the extracellular matrix; it attracts water molecules and creates a gel-like substance even at low HA concentrations contributing to the viscoelastic properties of the skin [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR1">1</xref>, <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR2">2</xref>]. HA is a polysaccharide consisting of the repeating disaccharide D-glucuronic acid and N-Acetyl-D-glucosamine units. Each disaccharide unit can bind up to 15 molecules of water, allowing 1&#160;g of hyaluronan to bind about 16&#160;l of water [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR2">2</xref>]. A high HA concentration, larger HA particle size, and increased number of cross-links all contribute to the increased durability of injectable HA fillers [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR1">1</xref>, <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR2">2</xref>]. Literature suggests that a high-molecular-weight HA has an anti-inflammatory behaviour, but a low-molecular-weight HA is pro-inflammatory [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR1">1</xref>&#8211;<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR4">4</xref>].</p><p id="Par8">Although HA injection is relatively safe [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR3">3</xref>, <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR4">4</xref>] for aesthetic procedures, complications can occur after HA injections, such as over-correction, or the Tyndall-effect (bluish discolouration caused by superficial injection of HA) [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR2">2</xref>], chronic oedema, inflammatory reaction, granuloma, vascular occlusion/compression, and tissue necrosis, to name a few. Early onset complications (&lt;14 days post-injection) such as bruising, swelling, lumps, vascular occlusion, or tissue necrosis are mainly related to superficial placement, rapid injection/flow rates, or higher injection volumes [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR4">4</xref>&#8211;<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR7">7</xref>].</p><p id="Par9">Early signs of HA induced vascular occlusion can be immediate with severe pain, or temporary blanching that often lasts for a few seconds due to disruption of blood flow primarily beyond the injection site. Subsequently, pain can increase followed by bluish-red skin discolourations, and finally if left untreated, progression to tissue necrosis is inevitable [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR8">8</xref>, <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR9">9</xref>].</p><sec id="Sec2"><title>Hyaluronidases</title><p id="Par10">Hyaluronidase dissolves HA and contributes to HA metabolism; it is an enzyme that is&#160;found in bacteria, such as in&#160;<italic toggle="yes">Staphylococcus aureus</italic>, in venoms of bees and snakes, and in some spices&#8217; testicular extracts [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR2">2</xref>]; Hyaluronidase cleaves HA&#8217;s &#946;1,4-glycosidic bonds. Woodward et. al. [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR9">9</xref>] suggested that 30 Units of hyaluronidase were needed to dissolve 0.1&#160;mL of HA.</p><p id="Par11">The management of HA injection vascular complications is often with infiltration of the entire area with large volume of hyaluronidase (1500 units, every 2&#8211;8 hours) [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR8">8</xref>]. Hyaluronidase is administered directly at the HA injection site and along the course of the obstructed artery [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR10">10</xref>&#8211;<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR12">12</xref>]. Hyaluronidase injection is more likely to be successful when performed early (&lt;&#160;4 h after injection of HA filler) [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR11">11</xref>]. Delay in hyaluronidase administration can lead to tissue necrosis, scarring, blindness, or in rare cases cerebrovascular accidents [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR13">13</xref>, <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR14">14</xref>]. Visual loss occasionally occurred in patients who received HA injections in the glabella, nose, or forehead and often presenting with sudden ocular pain, ptosis, and ophthalmoplegia [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR15">15</xref>]. Intra-arterial injection of 1500 units of hyaluronidase into the facial artery or supratrochlear artery successfully treated tissue necrosis in cases of vascular embolism after facial HA filler injection [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR16">16</xref>].</p><p id="Par12">The incidence of delayed-onset nodules and inflammatory events is about 0.02c4.0% [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR4">4</xref>, <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR17">17</xref>&#8211;<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR21">21</xref>]; they can appear months to years after the injection [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR4">4</xref>&#8211;<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR7">7</xref>] and often require removal of the product [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR4">4</xref>&#8211;<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR7">7</xref>]. Delayed inflammatory events are often type IV hypersensitivity reactions and T-cell mediated [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR4">4</xref>, <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR17">17</xref>&#8211;<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR22">22</xref>]. A review of the delayed HA complications reported in the Manufacturer and User Facility Device Experience (MAUDE) FDA database [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR4">4</xref>] revealed that 33.3% were delayed onset, and of those, 71.8% were nodules (42.1% inflammatory and 29.7% non-inflammatory), 21.5% caused by hypersensitivity, and 6.7% were granulomas. Non-inflammatory nodules are treated mainly with hyaluronidase [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR22">22</xref>]. For inflammatory nodules, a combination of hyaluronidase, antihistamines, corticosteroids, anti-inflammatories, and antibiotics are often used. In case of hypersensitivity, a combination of corticosteroids, antihistamines, and anti-inflammatories are used. Granulomas are also treated with antibiotics and corticosteroids [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR22">22</xref>]. Overall, there is no universal protocol for the management of delayed onset nodules and inflammatory nodules.</p></sec><sec id="Sec3"><title>Mechanism of Action and Therapeutic uses of Hyaluronidase</title><p id="Par13">Hyaluronidases are a group of 6 mucolytic enzymes that break down the HA [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR23">23</xref>] (table <xref rid="Tab1" ref-type="table">1</xref>). They can be derived from mammalian tissue (animal-derived) that is often associated with impurities and their potential for allergic reactions (<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR24">24</xref>, <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR25">25</xref>, <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR26">26</xref>), or synthesized in-vitro in pure form using recombinant technology (rHuPH20) [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR24">24</xref>].<table-wrap id="Tab1" position="float" orientation="portrait"><label>Table 1</label><caption><p>Different forms of hyaluronidase currently available in the market</p></caption><table frame="hsides" rules="groups"><thead><tr><th align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Bovine sources</th><th align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Hyaluronidase extracted from bovine testicular tissue</th><th align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Amphadase<sup>TM</sup> and Hydase<sup>TM</sup></th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Ovine sources</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Hyaluronidase extracted from ovine testicular tissue</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Vitrase<sup>TM</sup> or Hyalase&#174;, a 1500. unit ampoule of powder for reconstitution (Wockhardt UK Ltd)</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Human recombinant hyaluronidase</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Non. animal based, pure form</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Hylenex<sup>TM</sup></td></tr></tbody></table></table-wrap></p><p id="Par14">For this review we briefly summarise the clinical uses of hyaluronidase as follows.</p><p id="Par15"><italic toggle="yes">A-Adjuvants to local anaesthesia to increase the duration and efficacy of anaesthesia in ophthalmic surgery </italic>[<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR25">25</xref>]<italic toggle="yes">, and other fields, as well as</italic> for chronic pain management and treatment of oedema or hematoma [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR23">23</xref>, <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR25">25</xref>].</p><p id="Par16">Hyaluronidase has been used for retrobulbar, peribulbar, and sub-Tenon's anaesthesia in eye surgery, as a &#8216;spreading agent&#8217;. It reduces tissue oedema, <italic toggle="yes">periorbital oedema,</italic> and helps re-absorption of subcutaneous hematomas [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR2">2</xref>, <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR27">27</xref>, <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR28">28</xref>]. It assists vitrectomy, that is the surgery of the retina, where vitreous requires removing (the gel-like substance that fills the middle portion of the eye) and replacing it with another solution [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR2">2</xref>] by degrading hyaluronic acid into disaccharide compounds and dissociating intercellular substance barrier to liquefy the vitreous [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR2">2</xref>].</p><p id="Par17">Hyaluronidase has been used to increase the duration and efficacy of anaesthesia; it hydrolysis the HA, increasing connective tissue permeability and collectively&#160;leading to a faster anaesthetic effect and a greater anaesthetized surface [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR28">28</xref>]. It has been used as an adjunct for inferior alveolar nerve blocks [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR29">29</xref>], intra-pulpal anaesthesia [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR30">30</xref>], or for craniectomy [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR31">31</xref>]. Hyaluronidase may also reduce pain associated with anaesthetic injections by decreasing tissue tension [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR28">28</xref>].</p><p id="Par18"><italic toggle="yes">B-Softening skin and related tissues, this includes topical treatment for phimosis (tight foreskin) </italic>[<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR32">32</xref>]<italic toggle="yes">, prevention of perineal trauma (laceration) during delivery </italic>[<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR33">33</xref>]<italic toggle="yes">, cervical ripening and induction of labour </italic>[<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR34">34</xref>]<italic toggle="yes">, treatment of oral submucous fibrosis </italic>[<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR35">35</xref>]<italic toggle="yes">,</italic> a premalignant condition caused by betel chewing and can lead to squamous cell carcinoma, and <italic toggle="yes">treatment of scleroderma-induced microstomia (limited mouth opening) </italic>[<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR36">36</xref>]<italic toggle="yes">.</italic> The sclerotic tissue found in systemic sclerosis is the result of the over-production of hyaluronan and collagen (types I, III, and VII) [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR36">36</xref>].</p><p id="Par19"><italic toggle="yes">C-Acceleration of insulin exposure,</italic> hyaluronidase can be used in combination with rapid-acting insulin to accelerate insulin exposure, producing an ultra-rapid time-action profile with a faster onset and shorter duration of insulin action [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR37">37</xref>].</p><p id="Par20"><italic toggle="yes">D-Treatment of carpal tunnel syndrome</italic> [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR38">38</xref>]</p><p id="Par21"><italic toggle="yes">E-Treatment of keloids and Hypertrophic scars</italic> [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR39">39</xref>, <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR40">40</xref>]</p><p id="Par22"><italic toggle="yes">F-Off label use,</italic> Hyaluronidase is commonly used for managing over-corrections, asymmetry, lumps, and nodules developed after HA filler injection. It dissolves subcutaneous nodules and degrades HA correcting excessive quantities of injected HA fillers [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR41">41</xref>&#8211;<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR45">45</xref>] and its duration of the activity is about 24&#8211;48 h in dermal tissues [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR10">10</xref>]. It can be used at a high dose of 200 U or higher for treating skin necrosis associated with HA filler injections, caused by vascular occlusion and sometimes intra-arterially as a thrombolytic to treat eye/intracranial complications [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR16">16</xref>], and often without hypersensitivity test [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR23">23</xref>].</p></sec><sec id="Sec4"><title>Safety and Hypersensitivity</title><p id="Par23">Intra-dermal injection of 3 units of hyaluronidase to test for the development of a wheal has been suggested [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR46">46</xref>, <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR47">47</xref>]. Hyaluronidase is contraindicated in patients who developed hypersensitivity reactions to bee or wasp stings, owing to the presence of hyaluronidase in the venom [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR46">46</xref>, <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR48">48</xref>, <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR49">49</xref>]. Relative contraindications are, the concurrent use of aspirin, corticosteroids, estrogens, furosemide, benzodiazepines, and phenytoin and anti-histamines. Above mentioned drugs may make tissues less sensitive to hyaluronidase and patients need a larger dose or repeated treatment [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR46">46</xref>, <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR47">47</xref>, <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR49">49</xref>].</p><p id="Par24">The incidence of IgE-mediated Type I hypersensitivity is rare and estimated to be about 0.1%, unless large intravenous doses (&gt; 200000 units) are given, giving a much higher incidence of 33% [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR13">13</xref>, <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR23">23</xref>]. In case of severe allergy caused by exogenous hyaluronidase, the use of autologous serum may be considered in non-acute cases requiring accelerated removal of HA filler [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR2">2</xref>]. Although rare, delayed allergic hypersensitivity reaction has also been reported after the treatment of granulomatous hyaluronic acid reaction [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR50">50</xref>].</p></sec><sec id="Sec5"><title>Study Objectives</title><p id="Par25">The objective of the present scoping review was to systematically map the available evidence and identify the gaps in our knowledge on the effectiveness of hyaluronidase use in managing the aesthetic complications associated with HA injections (vascular occlusion, blindness, nodules, delayed hypersensivity, granuloma, poor aesthetic&#160;outcome) and to report on the adverse effects associated with the use of hyaluronidase.</p></sec></sec><sec id="Sec6"><title>Methodology</title><p id="Par26">For this scoping review, we used the PRIRMA extension for scoping reviews [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR51">51</xref>] and provided an overview or map of the evidence that was available. Search Strategy included the PubMed, Medline, Embase, and Cochrane Library databases. They were searched up to May 2022 for randomized clinical trials (RCTs), clinical trials, and retrospective case-control studies that assessed the efficacy of hyaluronidase in managing the complications of aesthetic HA injections. The search and MeSH terms are summarised in tables <xref rid="Tab2" ref-type="table">2</xref> and <xref rid="Tab3" ref-type="table">3</xref>. The reference lists of all included studies and previous reviews were also searched for additional RCTs, clinical trials, and retrospective studies. We looked for the parameters such as patient&#8217;s age, gender, indication for hyaluronidase&#160;injection, injection site, dose (hyaluronidase&#160;units), the brand names used for hyaluronidase&#160;and HA filler, follow-up after hyaluronidase&#160;injection, main study findings, as well as reported adverse effects. The PICOS approach was used as follows,<table-wrap id="Tab2" position="float" orientation="portrait"><label>Table 2</label><caption><p>Keyword search and MeSH terms used for PubMed search for the present scoping review.</p></caption><table frame="hsides" rules="groups"><tbody><tr><td align="left" rowspan="2" colspan="1">Concept 1</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">"adverse effect*"[tw] OR nodule*[tw] OR papule*[tw] OR mass*[tw] OR lump*[tw] OR bump*[tw] OR induration*[tw] OR granuloma*[tw] OR "granulation tissue*"[tw] OR "foreign bod*"[tw] OR hypersensitivity*[tw] OR swelling*[tw] OR inflammation*[tw] OR thrombosis[tw] OR ischemia[tw] OR embolism**[tw] OR "vascular embolism*"[tw] OR "vascular occlusion*"[tw] OR necrosis[tw] OR blindness[tw] OR dermatosis[tw] OR "adverse event*"[tw] OR complication*[tw]</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1"><italic toggle="yes">MeSH: "Visual Acuity"[Mesh] OR "Blindness"[Mesh] OR "Embolism"[Mesh] OR "Intracranial Embolism"[Mesh] OR "Embolism and Thrombosis"[Mesh] OR "Intracranial Embolism and Thrombosis"[Mesh] OR "Ischemic Stroke"[Mesh] OR "Edema"[Mesh] OR "Ecchymosis"[Mesh] OR "Skin Diseases, Vascular"[Mesh] OR "Skin Diseases, Papulosquamous"[Mesh] OR "Skin Diseases, Eczematous"[Mesh] OR "Skin and Connective Tissue Diseases"[Mesh] OR "Skin Diseases, Bacterial"[Mesh] OR "Skin Diseases, Viral"[Mesh] OR "Pain"[Mesh] OR "Chronic Pain"[Mesh] OR "Eye Pain"[Mesh] OR "Hypersensitivity"[Mesh] OR "Hypersensitivity, Delayed"[Mesh] OR "Drug Hypersensitivity"[Mesh] OR "Vasculitis, Leukocytoclastic, Cutaneous"[Mesh] OR "Inflammation"[Mesh] OR "Vascular Diseases"[Mesh] OR "Injections, Intra. Arterial"[Mesh] OR "Postoperative Complications"[Mesh]</italic></td></tr><tr><td align="left" rowspan="2" colspan="1">Concept 2</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1"><italic toggle="yes">"Hyaluronic Acid"[tw] OR Hyaluronoglucosaminidase[tw] OR "HA filler*"[tw] OR "Cosmetic Techniq*"[tw] OR "Dermal Filler*"[tw]</italic></td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1"><italic toggle="yes">MeSH: "Hyaluronic Acid"[Mesh] OR "Cosmetic Techniques"[Mesh] OR "Dermal Fillers"[Mesh] OR "Injections, Subcutaneous"[Mesh]</italic></td></tr><tr><td align="left" rowspan="2" colspan="1">Concept 3</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1"><italic toggle="yes">Hyaluronidase[tw] OR </italic>HYAL[tw] OR<italic toggle="yes"> Hylenex[tw] OR Hydase[tw] OR Vitrase[tw] OR Wydase[tw] OR Hyalase[tw]</italic></td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1"><italic toggle="yes">MeSH: "Thrombolytic Therapy"[Mesh] OR "Hyaluronoglucosaminidase"[Mesh]</italic></td></tr><tr><td align="left" rowspan="2" colspan="1">Concept 4</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1"><italic toggle="yes">"RCT*"[tw] OR "Randomi#ed clinical trial*"[tw] OR "clinical trial*"[tw] OR "retrospective stud*"[tw] OR &#8220;Case. Control Stud*"[tw] OR &#8220;Case Control Stud*"[tw]</italic></td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1"><italic toggle="yes">MeSH: "Retrospective Studies"[Mesh] OR "Prospective Studies"[Mesh] OR "Follow. Up Studies"[Mesh] OR "Case. Control Studies"[Mesh]</italic></td></tr></tbody></table></table-wrap><table-wrap id="Tab3" position="float" orientation="portrait"><label>Table 3</label><caption><p>Keyword search and MeSH terms used for Ovid medline for the present scoping review</p></caption><table frame="hsides" rules="groups"><tbody><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">1.</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Hyaluronic acid/</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">2.</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Cosmetic techniques/</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">3.</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Dermal fillers/</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">4.</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Injections, subcutaneous/</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">5.</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">(Hyaluronic Acid or Hyaluronoglucosaminidase or HA filler* or cosmetic techniq* or dermal filler*).mp. [mp=title, abstract, heading word, drug trade name, original title, device manufacturer, drug manufacturer, device trade name, keyword heading word, floating subheading word, candidate term word]</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">6.</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">1 or 2 or 3 or 4 or 5</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">7.</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Postoperative complications/</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">8.</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Injections, intra. arterial/</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">9.</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Vascular diseases/</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">10.</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Inflammation/</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">11.</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Vasculitis, Leukocytoclastic, Cutaneous/</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">12.</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Drug hypersensitivity/</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">13.</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Hypersensitivity, delayed/</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">14.</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Hypersensitivity/</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">15.</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Eye pain/</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">16.</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Chronic pain/</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">17.</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Pain/</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">18.</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Skin diseases, viral/</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">19.</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Skin diseases, bacterial/</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">20.</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Skin.mp. and connective tissue diseases/[mp=title, abstract, heading word, drug trade name, original title, device manufacturer, drug manufacturer, device trade name, keyword heading word, floating subheading word, candidate term word]</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">21.</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Skin diseases, eczematous/</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">22.</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Skin diseases, Papulosquamous/</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">23.</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Skin diseases, vascular/</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">24.</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Ecchymosis/</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">25.</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Ischemic stroke/</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">26.</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Edema/</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">27.</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Intracranial Embolism.mp. and Thrombosis/[mp=title, abstract, heading word, drug trade name, original title, device manufacturer, drug manufacturer, device trade name, keyword heading word, floating subheading word, candidate term word]</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">28.</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Embolism.mp. and Thrombosis/[mp=title, abstract, heading word, drug trade name, original title, device manufacturer, drug manufacturer, device trade name, keyword heading word, floating subheading word, candidate term word]</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">29.</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Intracranial embolism/</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">30.</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Embolism/</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">31.</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Blindness/</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">32.</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Visual acuity/</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">33.</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">(adverse effect* or nodule* or papule* or mass* or lump* or bump* or induration* or granuloma* or granulation tissue* or foreign bod* or hypersensitivit* or swelling* or inflammation* or thrombosis or ischemia or embolism* or vascular embolism* or vascular occlusion* or necrosis or blindness or dermatosis or adverse event* or complication*).mp. [mp=title, abstract, heading word, drug trade name, original title, device manufacturer, drug manufacturer, device trade name, keyword heading word, floating subheading word, candidate term word]</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">34.</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">7 or 8 or 9 or 10 or 11 or 12 or 13 or 14 or 15 or 16 or 17 or 18 or 19 or 20 or 21 or 22 or 23 or 24 or 25 or 26 or 27 or 28 or 29 or 30 or 31 or 32 or 33</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">35.</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Hyaluronoglucosaminidase/</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">36.</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Thrombolytic therapy/</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">37.</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">(Hyaluronidase or HYAL or Hylenex or Hydase or Vitrase or Wydase or Hyalase).mp. [mp=title, abstract, heading word, drug trade name, original title, device manufacturer, drug manufacturer, device trade name, keyword heading word, floating subheading word, candidate term word]</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">38.</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">35 or 36 or 37</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">39.</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Retrospective studies/</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">40.</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Case. Control studies/</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">41.</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Follow. Up studies/</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">42.</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Prospective studies/</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">43.</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">(RCT or Randomi#ed clinical trial* or clinical trial* or retrospective stud* or Case. Control stud* or Case control Stud*).mp. [mp=title, abstract, heading word, drug trade name, original title, device manufacturer, drug manufacturer, device trade name, keyword heading word, floating subheading word, candidate term word]</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">44.</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">39 or 40 or 41 or 42 or 43</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">45.</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">6 and 34 and 38 and 44</td></tr></tbody></table></table-wrap></p><p id="Par27">Participants, <list list-type="bullet"><list-item><p id="Par28">Patients who received hyaluronic acid (HA) for aesthetic interventions and developed complications (necrosis,&#160;blindness, hypersensitivity, delayed nodules, poor aesthetic outcome) and treated with hyaluronidase&#160;</p></list-item><list-item><p id="Par29">Non-complicated subjects who received HA followed by hyaluronidase to assess the effectiveness of hyaluronidase in&#160;removing/degrading HA</p></list-item></list></p><p id="Par30"><bold><italic toggle="yes">Intervention</italic></bold>, hyaluronidase</p><p id="Par31"><bold><italic toggle="yes">Comparison</italic></bold>, placebo, or control (received HA filler, but no hyaluronidase)</p><p id="Par32"><bold><italic toggle="yes">Outcome</italic></bold>, improvement in aesthetic complications, or changes in HA site characteristics (diameter of the HA filler nodule,&#160;elevation, firmness), we also provide a report on adverse effects associated with hyaluronidase&#160;use (hypersensitivity reactions, facial angioedema,&#160;and anaphylaxis)</p><p id="Par33"><bold><italic toggle="yes">Study type</italic></bold>, randomised clinical trials (RCT), clinical trials, retrospective case-control studies</p></sec><sec id="Sec7"><title>Results</title><sec id="Sec8"><title>Search Results</title><p id="Par34">The database search yielded 395 studies (PubMed, Medline, Embase, and Cochrane Library databases). After reviewing the titles and abstracts, authors identified 5 RCTs 4 papers [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR52">52</xref>&#8211;<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR55">55</xref>] (Table <xref rid="Tab4" ref-type="table">4</xref>) that were relevant to this scoping review. Overall, 5 RCTs with 53 subjects reported the effectiveness of hyaluronidase for eliminating uncomplicated HA nodules. All studies were carried out in the USA.<table-wrap id="Tab4" position="float" orientation="portrait"><label>Table 4</label><caption><p>The summary of the findings of the included studies in the present scoping review</p></caption><table frame="hsides" rules="groups"><thead><tr><th align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Authors, country, and funding</th><th align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Follow up</th><th align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Study sample study type</th><th align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Type of hyaluronidase &amp; dose</th><th align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Type of hyaluronic acid &amp; dose</th><th align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Inclusion criteria complication</th><th align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Outcome adverse effects</th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1"><p>Vartanian et. al. [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR52">52</xref>]</p><p>USA</p><p>Funding:</p><p>nothing mentioned</p></td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">4 months</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1"><p>Randomized controlled trial</p><p><italic toggle="yes">n</italic>=12</p><p>Randomly received hyaluronidase or normal saline (control)</p><p>7 female, 5 male</p><p>Mean age=43.7 years (30. 60 yrs. old)</p><p>Palpation scores* (0. 4) were recorded at days 1. 3, 4. 7, 8. 14, 15. 28, 29. 60, 61. 90, and 91. 120 after injection with hyaluronidase or saline</p></td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1"><p>No brand name mentioned</p><p>Each site received 0.5 mL hyaluronidase injection (75 units in normal saline), 1&#8211;3 days after HA gel injection</p><p>30. gauge needle was used</p></td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1"><p>Restylane (Q. Med AB, Uppsala, Sweden)</p><p>0.2. mL of HA gel injected at each site</p><p>30. gauge needle was used</p><p>Injected into the upper to middle dermis</p></td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1"><p>Uncomplicated HA nodule</p><p>Forearm (ipsilateral, 2 sites, 5 cm and 15 cm proximal to the wrist)</p><p>The grading physician and patients were blinded to the post. injection substance</p></td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1"><p>After a week, 80% reduction observed in nodule size in the hyaluronidase group vs. 10% in saline controls</p><p>Suggested an initial injection dose of 5. 10 U of to avoid allergic reaction 2 weeks after HA injection</p><p>4 patients who received hyaluronidase injection developed localized hypersensitivity reactions (site redness and mild pruritus)</p></td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1"><p>Vartanian et. al. [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR52">52</xref>]</p><p>USA</p><p>Funding:</p><p>nothing mentioned</p></td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1"/><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1"><p>Randomized controlled trial</p><p><italic toggle="yes">n=</italic>8</p><p>5 female, 3 male</p><p>Mean age=38.1 years</p><p>Palpation scores (0. 4) recorded</p></td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1"><p>10, 20, or 30 units</p><p>0.4 mL injection</p></td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1"><p>Restylane (Q. Med AB, Uppsala, Sweden)</p><p>0.2. mL of HA gel injected at each site</p></td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1"><p>Uncomplicated HA nodule</p><p>Forearm (3 sites, 5, 10, and 15 cm to the wrist)</p><p>Injection site doses were selected randomly</p></td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1"><p>No statistically significant difference between doses</p><p>Mild localized allergic responses in 2 (25%) subjects</p></td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1"><p>Juh&#225;sz et. al. [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR53">53</xref>]</p><p>USA</p><p>Funding:</p><p>nothing mentioned</p></td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">14 days</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1"><p>Blinded randomized study</p><p><italic toggle="yes">n=</italic>15</p><p>mean age=27.2 years</p><p>Female = 53.3% Male = 46.7%</p><p>Blinded palpation done on day 0, 1, 4, 7, 14</p><p>5. point ordinal grading scale (0. 4) was used (Vartanian et. al., 2005)</p></td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1"><p>Valeant (Laval, Canada)</p><p>On the same day of HA injection, each site received either no injection, normal saline (0.2 mL), 20 units, or 40 units of hyaluronidase. Procedure repeated once.</p><p>30 gage needle was used</p></td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1"><p>7 brands tested</p><p>JUV<sub>X</sub>, JUV<sub>X</sub> &amp; JUV<sub>V</sub> (Juvederm, Allergan, Irvine, CA)</p><p>RES<sub>L</sub>, RES<sub>S</sub> &amp; RES<sub>LYFT</sub> (Restylane, Galderma Laboratories, Lausanne, Switzerland)</p><p>BEL (Merz Aesthetics, Greensboro, NC)</p><p>0.2 mL bolus technique</p><p>27. gauge needle was used</p><p>Injected into the upper to middle dermis</p></td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1"><p>Uncomplicated HA nodule</p><p>Experiment carried out on back skin with patients lie in a prone position</p><p>28 sites (3 cm apart)/patient</p><p>Sites randomly received 0.2 mL of each brand of HA (each brand used in 4 sites)</p><p>blinded palpation score recorded using an ordinate, qualitative palpation scale.</p></td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1"><p>Palpation scale decreased (<italic toggle="yes">p</italic> &lt; 0.05) at days 1, 2, 3, 4, 7, and 14 post. injections for both 20 and 40 units of hyaluronidase, compared with sites that were not injected or injected with normal saline only</p><p>20 and 40 units of hyaluronidase were equally effective in dissolution of all HA fillers</p><p>BEL was the fastest HA filler to degrade. RESS (high cross. linking bonds and HA concentration) was the slowest to dissolve over the 14. day period</p><p>20 units of hyaluronidase for every 4 to 6 mg of HA was suggested.</p><p>There were tenderness over the injection sites (<italic toggle="yes">n</italic> = 6), itching of the back skin after injection (<italic toggle="yes">n</italic> = 2), and minimal bruising (<italic toggle="yes">n</italic> = 1), but all were self. resolving within 2. 3 days.</p></td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1"><p>Alam et. al. [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR54">54</xref>]</p><p>USA</p><p>Funding:</p><p>Departmental research funds, no company mentioned</p></td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1"><p>4 months</p><p>Patients followed 1 week after the third &amp; final hyaluronidase injection and then for final follow. up 3 months later</p><p>Based on &#8220;visual detection&#8221; &amp; &#8220;palpability score&#8221; using a 5. point scale (0. 4)</p><p>Patient and clinician recorded scores</p></td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1"><p>randomized clinical trial</p><p>Split. arm, parallel. group RCT</p><p><italic toggle="yes">n</italic>=9</p><p>All women</p><p>Mean age=45.8 (15.7) years</p></td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1"><p>Vitrase (Alliance Medical Products, Inc)</p><p>At 1, 2 &amp; 3 weeks after HA injection, each site injected with a 0.1 mL of variable. dose hyaluronidase (1.5 U, 3 U, or 9.0 U) or saline (control)</p><p>Experiment Repeated 1, 2, and 3 weeks after HA filler placement.</p><p>Small volume (0.1 mL) injection of very low doses (1.5. 9 unit) of saline. diluted hyaluronidase</p><p>30. gauge needle Was used</p></td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1"><p>Restylane. L (Galderma Laboratories)</p><p>&amp; Juv&#233;derm Ultra XC, (Allergan Inc)</p><p>0.4 mL each</p><p>site</p></td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1"><p>Uncomplicated HA nodule</p><p>Bilateral upper inner arms</p><p>Each subject had 8 injection sites along their bilateral upper inner (medial) arms, 4 on each arm,</p><p>8 sites/patient</p></td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1"><p>injection of small. volume (0.1 mL) of very low doses (9 unit) of hyaluronidase</p><p>at weekly intervals was effective</p><p>Higher dose of hyaluronidase was needed to reverse Juv&#233;derm Ultra XC compared to Restylane. L</p><p>All filler sites decreased in terms of visual detection &amp; palpation over time.</p><p>Normal saline (control) &amp; hyaluronidase were different at 4 weeks &amp; 4 months (<italic toggle="yes">p</italic>&lt;0.05)</p><p>This was also mirrored in subjects&#8217; self. assessment at 4 weeks &amp; 4 months (<italic toggle="yes">p</italic>&lt;0.05)</p><p>The 9 units hyaluronidase injections were less palpable than the 1.5 units injections at both 4 weeks &amp; 4 months</p><p>Differences were more notable for Restylane. L than for Juv&#233;derm Ultra XC</p><p>No adverse events reported.</p></td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1"><p>Zhang. Nunes et. al. [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR55">55</xref>]</p><p>USA</p><p>Funding:</p><p>Unrestricted grant to the USC Department of Ophthal. mology from Research to Prevent Blindness, New York, NY</p><p>No company mentioned</p></td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1"><p>4 years</p><p>Diameter of the HA filler nodule (mm), elevation &amp; firmness (both scored using a Likert. type scale 0,1,2,3) were measured pre. injection &amp; at varying time points</p><p>Time points: Immediately after injection of HA gel, one week prior to hyaluronidase injection, immediately after hyaluronidase injection &amp; at 15 min, 30 min, 1 h, 2 h, 3 h, 5 h, 8 h, 1 day, 2 days, 3 days, 1 week, 2 weeks, 1&#8211;2 months, 5&#8211;6 months, 1 year, 2 years &amp; 4 years</p></td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1"><p>Randomized clinical trial&#160;(<italic toggle="yes">n</italic>=9)</p><p>All women</p><p>Mean age = 45.8 (15.7) years</p><p>Subjects, graders &amp; injectors were masked.</p></td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1"><p>Hylenex (recombinant human hyaluronidase)</p><p>One week after HA injection, each site received its randomized equal volumes (0.15 mL) of 2.5 U, 5 U, 10 U, 20 U of hyaluronidase, saline, or nothing, the seventh site was used as a control for 10 U of hyaluronidase only (to assess the adverse effects, hypersensivity.</p></td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1"><p>Restylane. L</p><p>Juv&#233;derm Ultra</p><p>Juv&#233;derm Voluma</p><p>0.2 mL each</p><p>Site</p></td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1"><p>Uncomplicated</p><p>HA nodule</p><p>Forearm</p><p>7 sites per forearm</p><p>18 forearms</p><p>6 sites received HA</p><p>One site only hyaluronidase (control)</p></td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1"><p>The most notable changes for all fillers occurred between the 30. min and 3 h time points, and followed by continued gradual degradation through week 2.</p><p>There were no allergic reactions;</p><p>3 subjects had significant erythema &amp; minimal irritation of the HA sites starting five hours after initial intradermal implantation &amp; lasting up to 1&#8211;2 days. This irritation was most significant with Restylane.</p><p>Some mild post. inflammatory hyperpigmentation was observed, which resolved after 3 months.</p></td></tr></tbody></table><table-wrap-foot><p><bold>*</bold>A score of 0&#8211;4 given as follows; 4 for maximal augmentation; 3 for moderately raised; 2 to a slightly raised bump; 1 to sites that were barely palpable at examination; and 0 to sites with no tactile trace of injected HA gel [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR52">52</xref>].</p></table-wrap-foot></table-wrap></p></sec><sec id="Sec9"><title>Effectiveness of Hyaluronidase for Removal of Uncomplicated HA Nodules</title><p id="Par35">The follow-ups for 5 clinical trials ranged from 14 days to 4 years. The amount of HA filler injected into each site varied from 0.2 to 0.4 mL per site. The injected hyaluronidase doses were 1.5&#8211;75 units per site. Overall, for removal of every 0.1 mL of HA filler the reviewed studies suggested an injection of 1.25&#8211;37.5 units of hyaluronidase (single injections). When 3 consecutive weekly hyaluronidase injection were used much lower doses of 0.375&#8211;2.25 unit was utilised.</p><p id="Par36">The HA brands tested were Restylane (Q-Med AB, Uppsala, Sweden), JUV<sub>X</sub>, JUV<sub>X</sub> &amp; JUV<sub>V</sub> (Juvederm, Allergan, Irvine, CA), RES<sub>L</sub>, RES<sub>S</sub> &amp; RES<sub>LYFT</sub> (Restylane, Galderma Laboratories, Lausanne, Switzerland), BEL (Merz Aesthetics, Greensboro, NC), Juv&#233;derm Ultra XC, (Allergan Inc), Restylane-L (Galderma Laboratori), and Restylane-L, Juv&#233;derm Ultra &amp; Juv&#233;derm Voluma. They tested the products on ipsilateral forearms, bilateral upper inner (medial) arms, and back skin. The brand of hyaluronidase used for these studies was non-specified [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR52">52</xref>] in one study; Valeant (Laval, Canada), Vitrase (Alliance Medical Products, Inc) and Hylenex (recombinant human hyaluronidase) were used in other studies [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR53">53</xref>&#8211;<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR55">55</xref>]. Mean age and gender were reported for all 5 selected studies.</p><p id="Par37">Overall, 5 RCTs with 53 subjects, confirmed the effectiveness of hyaluronidase for removal/reversal of un-complicated injected HA nodules in the forearm, upper arm and back skin and no major adverse reactions were reported. Vartanian et. al. [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR52">52</xref>] did not observe a significant difference between various doses of hyaluronidase (10, 20, or 30 units) at 4 months; this study didn&#8217;t have a control group (without hyaluronidase injection) and some trends were also seen for the effectiveness of higher doses (30 units) at some time points (1&#8211;3 days, 8&#8211;14 days, and 29&#8211;60 days) [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR52">52</xref>]. Juh&#225;sz et. al. [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR53">53</xref>] reported no significant difference in efficacy and rate of dissolution of all HA filler between 20 and 40 units of hyaluronidase. However, some trends were identified such as, the Restylane Silk was the slowest to dissolve over the 14-day period, contrary to the Belotero Balance, which was the fastest to degrade.</p><p id="Par38">Alam et. al. [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR54">54</xref>] used 3 consecutive doses of hyaluronidase (1.5, 3, 9 Units) at 1, 2, and 3 weeks after HA filler injection, and observed that repeated weekly low-volume (1mL), low-doses of hyaluronidase (9 units) is effective, in particular for correction of minor irregularities. They noted a dose dependent response, with 9.0-unit hyaluronidase injection being more effective than 1.5-unit sites at 4 weeks and 4 months.</p><p id="Par39">Zhang-Nunes et. al. [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR55">55</xref>] studied sites injected with Restylane- Lyft, Juv&#233;derm Ultra, and Juv&#233;derm Voluma for 4 years after hyaluronidase injection (2.5, 5, 10, or 20 units). Most of the changes for all HA filler injected sites occurred between the 30 min and 3 hr time points, after hyaluronidase injection, that continued gradual degradation up to day 3, with minimal change through week two. All 3 tested fillers showed a dose response, with Voluma being more pronounced. Juv&#233;derm Voluma required higher doses of hyaluronidase for dissolution (20 units), and Restylane appeared to respond to lower doses of hyaluronidase (2.5 units).</p><p id="Par40">The present scoping review did not identify similar evidence for HA filler reversal in the facial region.</p></sec><sec id="Sec10"><title>Effectiveness of Hyaluronidase for Management of Over-Corrections, Inflammatory Nodules, or Vascular Occlusions Following Aesthetic HA Filler Injections</title><p id="Par41">Similarly, no evidence was found, in a form of RCTs, clinical trials, and retrospective case-control studies, on the management of over-corrections, inflammatory nodules, or tissue ischemia/necrosis associated with aesthetic HA filler injections; the available evidence was mainly retrospective case reports or case series. We have also listed the summary of 11 excluded studies [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR10">10</xref>, <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR14">14</xref>, <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR16">16</xref>, <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR56">56</xref>&#8211;<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR63">63</xref>] in table <xref rid="Tab5" ref-type="table">5</xref>. They were retrospective case series, with 5 cases or more, reporting on the use of hyaluronidase for managing aesthetic complications associated with aesthetic HA filler injection. This includes management of delayed onset nodules in tear trough augmentation [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR56">56</xref>], lip augmentation [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR59">59</xref>], delayed peri-orbital oedema [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR61">61</xref>, <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR62">62</xref>], aesthetic over-correction [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR10">10</xref>], Tyndall effect, and late nodules [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR10">10</xref>], late inflammatory cutaneous reactions in lip and tear trough regions [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR58">58</xref>], as well as management of skin necrosis [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR14">14</xref>, <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR57">57</xref>], and vascular complications with [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR60">60</xref>, <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR63">63</xref>] or without visual impairment [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR58">58</xref>].<table-wrap id="Tab5" position="float" orientation="portrait"><label>Table 5</label><caption><p>List of the selected excluded studies and their summary findings</p></caption><table frame="hsides" rules="groups"><thead><tr><th align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Authors</th><th align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Follow. up</th><th align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Study sample Study type</th><th align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Hyaluronidase &#177; other medicines</th><th align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Type of hyaluronic acid dose</th><th align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Inclusion criteria complication</th><th align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Outcome adverse effects</th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Hilton et. al. [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR56">56</xref>]</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Not clear</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1"><p>Retrospective study (<italic toggle="yes">N</italic>=20) Case series No control 3 male, 17 female. Age range= 32&#8211;74&#160;years old</p><p>mean age= 49.3&#160;years old</p></td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">20. 75 units (Hylase Dessau&#174;). Diluted in 1.0 mL of normal saline. 0.2&#8211;0.5 mL injection</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">HA brand not reported</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Nodule developed after HA tear trough augmentation. Infraorbital Region. 14 patients had HA injection for tear. trough augmentation. 6 patients had no HA injection and idiopathic edema</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">79% of patients had full nodule resolution with one injection. 3 patients (21%) required an additional injection. No adverse effect observed. There was a loss of original HA treatment effect in two cases (14.3%)</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Sadeghpour et. al. [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR59">59</xref>]</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Not clear</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Retrospective study (<italic toggle="yes">n</italic>=5)No control Case seriesOriginal sample of 1,029 patient All femaleAge range 46. 70 years old</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">All patients treated first with hyaluronidase (Hylenex, no dose given) without significant clinical improvement. Then, a combination of triamcinolone (2. 5 mg/mL) &amp; hyaluronidase (multiple treatment sessions) given.</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">1,250 Vycross HA filler treatments (1,029 patients) Juvederm Volbella Juvederm Vollure Juvederm Voluma</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Delayed. onset nodules (lip) developed in 5 cases (Juvederm Volbella) after 35.8 week on averageSubcutaneous, firm, non. erythematous, and nontender nodule</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Combination of triamcinolone and hyaluronidase (multiple treatment sessions) lead to diminution in nodule size.All patients were treated successfully with near. complete or complete resolutionNo mention of adverse effects</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Bravo et. al. [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR10">10</xref>]</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Not clear</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Retrospective study (<italic toggle="yes">n=</italic>114)Case seriesNo control 112 females, 2 malesMean age = 43 years old</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">HYAL (hyaluronidase 2.000 IU, BIOMETILtm, dissolved in 5 ml of the diluent, saline solution, water for injection &amp; mannitol) 400 IU/ml solution 2. 2000 UI injected with a mean dose of 68 UI</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">HA brand not reportedHA injections were as follows: Eyelid region (<italic toggle="yes">n=</italic>58) Upper lip (<italic toggle="yes">n</italic>=10)Lower lip (<italic toggle="yes">n=</italic>9)Malar region (<italic toggle="yes">n</italic>=9) Melomental fold (<italic toggle="yes">n</italic>=5) Forehead (<italic toggle="yes">n</italic>=4)Nose (<italic toggle="yes">n</italic>=4)Chin (<italic toggle="yes">n</italic>=4) Pyriform aperture (<italic toggle="yes">n</italic>=3) Temple (<italic toggle="yes">n</italic>=2)Lateral orbit (<italic toggle="yes">n</italic>=2) Zygoma (<italic toggle="yes">n</italic>=2)Peri. labial (<italic toggle="yes">n</italic>=1) Acne scar (<italic toggle="yes">n</italic>=1)</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Over. correction (45%)Tyndall effect (44%)Late nodules (11%)</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">40 UI of hyaluronidase injection should be enough for each CM2 of HA that needs removalThe main complications were moderate edema and local burning sensation.One case developed lip angioedema and treated with 80 mg oral prednisolone. No dermal or subcutaneous atrophies were observed</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Skippen et. al. [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR61">61</xref>]</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Mean follow. up = 11 months (6. 20 months)</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Retrospective study <italic toggle="yes">n</italic>=61Case seriesNo control 59 female, 2 male age range = 21. 78 years mean age=48 years old</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">HYAL15. 90 IU per eyelid</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Had different types of HAHA brand not reported</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Had&#160;lower eyelids or cheeks HA injection and developed Lower eyelid edema On average 3 years (1. 10 years) after HA filler injection</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Single hyaluronidase injection was effective in 92% of patients 8% required another hyaluronidase injection to completely eradicate residual edema6 patients (10%) were satisfied after hyaluronidase only 6 patients (10%) had lower eyelid blepharoplasty. 48 patients (80%) had secondary treatment with HA filler injection No adverse effects mentioned</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Dubinsky. Pertzov et. al. [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR62">62</xref>]</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">The mean follow. Up = 10.85 months (6. 36 months)</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Retrospective study <italic toggle="yes">n</italic>=17Case seriesNo control Female Age range = 26. 80 years oldMean age=54.9 years old</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">HYAL3. 90 IU per eyelid</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Had different types of HAHA brand not reported</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Upper eyelid edema (periocular edema) 6. 24 months after HA filler injection in the supraorbital area.</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Edema resolved in all patients after hyaluronidase treatment13 (76.4%)were satisfied and didn&#8217;t receive HA filler again4 received additional HA filler.No mention of adverse effects</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Artzi et. al. [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR58">58</xref>]</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Not clear</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Retrospective study <italic toggle="yes">n=</italic>17No controlCase seriesOriginal sample of 400 patients and 17 developed complications</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">17 patients were first treated with oral ciprofloxacin (500&#8211;750 mg, bd, for 3. 4 weeks), which treated 6 patients with no recurrence11 patients had recurrent episodes and received broad. spectrum antibiotics (ciprofloxacin or rifampicin for a minimum of 3 weeks) and multiple intralesional injections of hyaluronidase (30&#8211;100 unit/mass or nodule)</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">400 patients (360 females, 40 males; average age = 49.6 years) received Juv&#233;derm Volbella (HA. Vb) filler into the tear trough area (<italic toggle="yes">n</italic>=351) or lips (<italic toggle="yes">n</italic>=49).Other HA. fillers were also used in other areas of the face</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Late inflammatory cutaneous reactions in tear trough area &amp; lips17 (4.25%) patients 13 in tear trough area (n. 13) and lips (<italic toggle="yes">n</italic>=4)Patients developed prolonged (up to 11 months) and recurrent (average: 3.17 episodes) late inflammatory cutaneous reactions (average onset: 8.41 weeks following HA filler injection, range: 5&#8211;12 weeks)</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">All symptoms &amp; signs receded in 6 patients who received initially antibiotics and did not recur.Recurrent episodes (11 patients) were treated with repeated courses of broad. spectrum antibiotics and multiple intralesional injections of hyaluronidase. Oral, intramuscular &amp; intralesional administration of corticosteroids were less effective.No mention of adverse effects</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Sun et. al. [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR57">57</xref>]</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Not clear</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Retrospective study <italic toggle="yes">n</italic>=20Case control study20 consecutive referrals with nasal skin necrosis following nose and/or nasolabial fold augmentation with HA fillersAge range 21. 52 years old19 female, 1 male</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">18 received hyaluronidase [ovine testicular hyaluronidase (Shanghai First Biochemical Pharmaceuticals Corp., Shanghai; equivalent to Vitrase in North America, 150 to 300 units] from 0 hrs. 7 days after developing skin problemsAlso given antibiotics, tanshinone, papaverine, topical magnesium sulphate, infrared irradiation, and hyperbaric oxygen. Patients were also given aspirin, unless contraindicated.</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">HA brand not reportedHA was injected into the nasion area (<italic toggle="yes">n</italic>=14), nasolabial fold (<italic toggle="yes">n</italic>=5) or both (<italic toggle="yes">n</italic>=1)</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Skin necrosis after HA injection in nose, nasolabial fold, glabella &amp; forehead, or lip</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">7 patients (%35) developed skin necrosis.13 patients (%65) recovered fully following combination treatment with hyaluronidase.Early (&lt;2 days) combination treatment with hyaluronidase was associated with the full resolution of the complicationsNo mention of adverse effects</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Ors [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR14">14</xref>]</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Followed up for 3&#8211;24&#160;months</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Retrospective study <italic toggle="yes">n</italic>=16No controlCase seriesAge range= 18. 60 years oldAll female</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">6 patients only received palliative treatment 10 patients received 1500 units (300 U with every 4. 6 hrs) hyaluronidase [30 s after HA injection (<italic toggle="yes">n</italic>=4) or 6. 24 h after HA injection] and palliative treatment.Patients with open wounds received topical Fusidic acid antibiotic. Patients with large wounds received amoxicillin&#8211;clavulanate orally for 14&#160;days.</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">HA brand not reportedoverall, 841 cases received HA filler Nasolabial area (391)Lip (225)Glabella&#8211;forehead (90)Infraorbital (46)Malar region (25)Chin (24) Nose (40)</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Vascular occlusion. related ischemia and skin necrosis after HA injectionComplications occurred in 16 cases [Nose (<italic toggle="yes">n</italic>=4), Nasolabial area (<italic toggle="yes">n</italic>=4), Glabella (<italic toggle="yes">n</italic>=8) area]Skin complications presented in 4 patients during HA injection and in 12 patients 6&#8211;24&#160;h after the procedure.</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Recovery time for patients who received palliative treatment and had limited&#160;necrosis was 40. 60&#160;days, without obvious scar.Patients who received hyaluronidase and palliative treatment, had larger necrosis areas, and at the end a large necrosis area was observed in 4 patients. The recovery period in this group was 20. 90&#160;days.Overall, 4 patients healed with a scar and 12 healed without any significant scar.Authors suggested Hyaluronidase injection provides earlier recovery of limited skin necrosis. Immediate hyaluronidase injection allowed small damage to heal in a short time; however, it did not eliminate large necrosis, but limited the necrotic area&#8217;No adverse effect observed</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Zhang et. al. [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR16">16</xref>]</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Average follow. up = 5 months (3. 12 months)</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Retrospective study <italic toggle="yes">n</italic>=17No controlCase series19. 52. year. oldMean age=33 years old14 female, 3 male</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">13 patients had 1500 IU hyaluronidase (Shanghai Shangyao No. 1 Biochemical Pharmaceutical Co., LTD.) injected into facial artery 4 patients had 1500 IU hyaluronidase injected into supratrochlear artery Received&#160;intra. arterial thrombolysis therapy 2 hours to 7 days after&#160;the onset of symptomsPatients also received;1. glucocorticoid pulse therapy (dexamethasone sodium phosphate, 10 mg, ivgtt, qd, 3 d)2. neurotrophic treatment (mecobalamin injection, 0.5 mg, ivgtt, qd, 90 d)3. anti. allergy treatment (loratadine, 10 mg, pol, qd).</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">HA brand not reportedHA filler was injected in the nasolabial fold (<italic toggle="yes">n</italic>=7) or forehead (<italic toggle="yes">n</italic>=5)</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Vascular complications of HA fillerAll had skin necrosis or skin ecchymosis spreading along the surface branches of facial artery or supratrochlear artery4 had severe ptosis and weakness in eye opening, ocular pain, and skin numbness. 2 had ocular motility disordersNone had visual impairment and life. threatening injuries (hypertension, coagulopathy, intracranial and external haemorrhaging)The colour doppler flow imaging was used to locate the facial and supratrochlear arteries</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">The skin necrosis of 16 patients was completely healed and 1 patient left with small, superficial scarsThe ptosis and ocular motility were completely resolved.No mention of adverse effects</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Zhang et. al. [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR60">60</xref>]</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Average follow. up = 3 months (1 month to 1 year)</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Retrospective study <italic toggle="yes">n</italic>=24no controlCase seriesMean age=26 years old23 female, 1 male</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">11 patients received intra. arterial injection of hyaluronidase (500. 1500 units) 13 patients received intra. arterial injection hyaluronidase (750. 1500 units) and urokinase (100,000. 250,000 units)</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">HA brand not reportedHA was injected into the nasion area (<italic toggle="yes">n</italic>=12), followed by the frontal (<italic toggle="yes">n</italic>=10), glabella (<italic toggle="yes">n</italic>=1) &amp; temporal (<italic toggle="yes">n</italic>=1).</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Severe visual impairment (unilateral, 10 right &amp; 14 left eyes were affected) after cosmetic facial hyaluronic acid injectionsAll had ptosis &amp; mydriasis with pupil diameter larger than 5 mm 22 patients had ocular motility disorders. 20 patients had skin lesions in the corresponding region of artery occlusion, being pale, piebald, or necrotic.None had life. threatening injuries or interventional contraindications (hypertension, coagulopathy, intracranial &amp; external haemorrhaging)</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">10 (42%) patients had improved visual acuity after treatment, 14 patients had no visual impairment improvement The ptosis in 24 patients were all healed.&#160;3 patients had secondary embolization, sudden headache, ocular pain, and decline in vision on the 1st or 2nd day after the first intraarterial thrombolysis therapy and had 2nd course of intraarterial thrombolysis therapy with less success.&#160;Partial or total ocular motility limitation healed in 8 patients and ameliorated in 14 patients Intra. arterial thrombolysis therapy significantly improved skin necrosis and ecchymosis, and nearly restored the patients&#8217; appearance to normal, leaving only some superficial scars in several patients.Authors suggested that combined hyaluronidase and urokinase may have a better thrombolysis effect on hyaluronic acid embolismIn addition, early hormone shock (high. dose glucocorticoid), local hyaluronidase injection, oxygen inhalation, Mannitol, and melilotus extract tablets were necessary to reduce tissue edema.Earlier treatment was associated with the higher vision improvementNo mention of adverse effects</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Wang et. al. [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR63">63</xref>]</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">30 days follow. up</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Retrospective study <italic toggle="yes">n</italic>=30Case seriesNo control 1 male, 29 femalesAge range= 18. 35 years old</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">30 had local injection of hyaluronidase at the HA injection site immediately after the onset of vision loss and 25 received retroocular hyaluronidase injection at other hospitals.28 had one and 2 patients had 2 intra. arterial thrombolysis(Using microcatheter, 1500 units of hyaluronidase diluted in 1 mL of saline and were slowly infused followed by infusion of 1 mL papaverine diluted in 2 mL saline)</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">HA brand not reported</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Presented 20. 120 hrs after the onset of blindness (median, 59.5 h).Had monocular blindness due to HA injection in the forehead (<italic toggle="yes">n</italic>=3) and nasal bridge (<italic toggle="yes">n</italic>=27) regions 26 had ptosis 23 had ocular motility disorders.&#160;3 had light perception 27 had no light perception with varying degrees of vascular occlusion in the retina</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">The ptosis disappeared and 18 patients had normal eye movement after the intra. arterial therapy.5 patients had visual improvement 4 patients with complete vision loss gained some light perception.</td></tr></tbody></table></table-wrap></p><p id="Par42">The selected excluded studies used a wide range (2&#8211;2000 units) of hyaluronidase doses for treatment of delayed non-inflammatory HA nodules and over-corrections [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR10">10</xref>, <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR56">56</xref>, <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR59">59</xref>]. Two studies [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR10">10</xref>, <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR56">56</xref>] only used hyaluronidase and the other one [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR59">59</xref>] used triamcinolone (2&#8211;5 mg/mL) in combination to hyaluronidase. Of particular interest was the study by Sadeghpour and colleagues [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR59">59</xref>], indicating higher incidence of delayed non-inflammatory HA nodules in HA fillers used Vycross technology. Two studies [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR61">61</xref>, <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR62">62</xref>] reported on edema management of upper and lower eyelid and tear trough area that used 3&#8211;90 units of hyaluronidase per eyelid to remove the HA filler. Lower eyelid and tear rough area appears to be a challenging area for HA filler removal or corrections as reflected by the %80 need for HA filler reinjection and 10% need for blepharoplasty in this area [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR61">61</xref>]. For upper eyelid only about 25% of patients needed HA filler reinjection [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR62">62</xref>].</p></sec></sec><sec id="Sec11"><title>Discussion</title><p id="Par43">As explained earlier, based on the limited available evidence, a scoping review of the literature was conducted [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR51">51</xref>], suggesting a paucity of studies assessing the efficacy of hyaluronidase for the reversal of HA injections in the facial region. The findings were based on studies with small sample sizes and the experiments on the forearm, upper arm, and back skin [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR52">52</xref>&#8211;<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR55">55</xref>]. The applicability of findings generated from the study of arms (volar forearm or upper arm) or back skin for products designed for the face can be questionable [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR64">64</xref>, <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR65">65</xref>]. This is due to the varying thickness and elastic properties of the skin in different anatomical regions [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR65">65</xref>], which can be influenced by variations in components such as elastic network, fibrous collagen, and glycosaminoglycans [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR64">64</xref>&#8211;<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR66">66</xref>].</p><p id="Par44">There were some variations in the degree of degradation of HA fillers after hyaluronidase injection that could be partly explained by the HA particle size, degree of cross-linking, different cross-linking technologies, and the amount of G-prime [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR2">2</xref>]. We know from research [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR2">2</xref>] that higher HA concentration (such as JUV family), increased amount of G-prime (JUV X+ and RES LYFT), larger HA particle size (such as RES LYFT), and increased number of cross-links (such as in JUV X and JUV X+ using Hylacross technology) contribute to increased durability of injectable HA fillers requiring higher dose of hyaluronidase for dissolution. However, this effect was mainly seen in the in the first 2&#8211;3 weeks following hyaluronidase injections.</p><p id="Par45">For this scoping review, we did not include animal studies, and studies that included other dermal fillers such as silicone [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR67">67</xref>] or calcium hydroxyapatite [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR68">68</xref>]. Congress abstracts [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR69">69</xref>], case reports or case series reporting less than 5 cases [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR70">70</xref>] were excluded. A review of the selected excluded studies (&gt;&#160;= 5 subjects) highlighted some interesting findings, suggesting that hyaluronic acid injections into the glabellar region, nasal dorsum, and nasolabial fold near the eyes were the main sites with serious vascular occlusions and eye problems that needed urgent treatment [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR14">14</xref>, <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR16">16</xref>, <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR57">57</xref>, <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR60">60</xref>]; some authors suggest the injection in these sites is not advised [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR71">71</xref>, <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR72">72</xref>]. Subsequent to vascular occlusion, patients often develop pain and characteristic reticulated erythema [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR57">57</xref>] in the areas supplied by facial artery [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR48">48</xref>, <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR73">73</xref>, <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR74">74</xref>]. The most common initial ocular symptoms after HA injection are vision loss (%50) and orbital pain (%35) as well as headache and dizziness (%26) [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR75">75</xref>].</p><p id="Par46">Different methods of hyaluronidase injection (localised or intra-atrial) have been used to manage the vascular occlusions such as skin necrosis, eye movement and visual impairment disorders, ptosis, as well as blindness or loss of visual field. In order to treat skin necrosis, some researchers used localised infiltration of hyaluronidase at the HA injection site [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR14">14</xref>, <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR57">57</xref>] and some utilised intra-arterial injection of the either facial artery or supratrochlear artery [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR16">16</xref>]. It appears that immediate [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR14">14</xref>] or early treatment (&lt; 2 days) [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR57">57</xref>] with localised hyaluronidase injection or intra-arterial injection [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR16">16</xref>] is associated with better outcome and full resolution of the skin necrosis. Zhang et. al. [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR16">16</xref>] described the ideal location for intra-arterial injection of hyaluronidase, as the&#160;junction of the lower margin of the mandible and the anterior margin of the masseter muscle. The facial artery diameter at this point is about 2.3 mm and less than the needle diameter (0.57&#8211;0.92 mm) [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR16">16</xref>]. Similarly, for management of visual impairments, local injection of hyaluronidase at the HA injection site [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR63">63</xref>], retroocular hyaluronidase injection [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR63">63</xref>], or intra-arterial injection [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR16">16</xref>, <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR60">60</xref>, <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR63">63</xref>] as well as aspirin and a form of steroids (methylprednisolone, prednisone, dexamethasone, or steroid pulse) have been used [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR75">75</xref>]. However, recent systemic reviews [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR76">76</xref>, <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR77">77</xref>] and a consensus opinion paper [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR78">78</xref>] suggested a limited success with retrobulbar hyaluronidase injection. Overall, there is no accepted universal protocol for the use of hyaluronidase in management of vascular complications caused by HA injections. Localised injections of 500&#8211;1500 units of hyaluronidase with hourly intervals as soon as vascular occlusion is detected has been suggested [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR8">8</xref>, <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR79">79</xref>]. It appears that lower doses (150-300 units), delayed injection, or localised infiltration of hyaluronidase [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR16">16</xref>, <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR57">57</xref>] are less effective in management of vascular complications compared to intra-arterial injections of higher doses (1500 units) of hyaluronidase [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR16">16</xref>]. Future studies are therefore, warranted to establish the ideal injection root (local or intra-arterial), the optimal dose of hyaluronidase, as well as additional treatments (i.e., antibiotics, glucocorticoids, other thrombolytics) for management of skin necrosis and visual impairment complications.</p><p id="Par47">The HA slowly breaks down, binding to more water, maintaining the same volume progressively (isovolumetric degradation), contributing to the delayed occurrence of the oedema years after a successful HA treatment [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR74">74</xref>, <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR80">80</xref>], which is the cause of concern for periocular HA injection [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR61">61</xref>, <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR62">62</xref>]. Based on 2 case series [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR61">61</xref>, <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR62">62</xref>], we know that hyaluronidase&#160;maybe more successful in managing periorbital oedema in the upper than the lower eyelid.</p><p id="Par48">There is no universal protocol for reversal of hyaluronic acid fillers and different brand of HA fillers present with various degrees of cross-linkage requiring different amount of hyaluronidase&#160;for dissolution [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR81">81</xref>]. Hyaluronidase also dissolves native hyaluronic acid, but body will restore native HA in 15&#8211;20 hours [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR2">2</xref>]. A limitation of the reviewed studies [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR52">52</xref>&#8211;<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR55">55</xref>] is the use of subjective visual detection [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR54">54</xref>] or finger palpation using a 5-point scale system [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR52">52</xref>&#8211;<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR55">55</xref>] that may not be able to detect and record subtle changes in palpation scores. Recently, there has been an increase in the use of ultrasound&#8211;guided methods [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR82">82</xref>, <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR83">83</xref>] and ultrasound can be used in future studies to quantitatively assess the changes in the volume of HA filler over time.</p><p id="Par49">There is a bit of dichotomy of the RTC trial designs and typical use of HA fillers. HA fillers is almost always injected below the skin in real clinical situations and sometimes over the bone. However, studies typically follow intradermal injection depth of HA (intradermal), followed by injection of hyaluronidase intra-lesionally. The failed dissolution of HA filler following multiple hyaluronidase injections, can to be caused by incorrect depth of injection. If fascial structures or muscles lie between the site of HA filler and the site of hyaluronidase hyaluronidase injection, dissolution is dramatically reduced, especially the HA filler exists in a large bolus. Withing this context, the use of ultrasound&#8211;guided methods [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR82">82</xref>, <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR83">83</xref>] can be a good adjunct to locate the filler and assess quantitatively HA filler degradation after hyaluronidase injection.</p><p id="Par50">The study by Vartanian et. al. [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR52">52</xref>] lacked a third group without any post-injection to assess the changes post HA injection and compare it to saline and hyaluronidase injections. They recommended a small dose of hyaluronidase equivalent to 5&#8211;10 U (0.1&#8211;0.2 mL of drug at 50 U/mL) to be injected initially to avoid an allergic reaction, 2 weeks after HA injection. Juh&#225;sz et. al. [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR53">53</xref>] also reported that lower concentrations (20 Units) of hyaluronidase were just as effective as higher concentrations (40 Units) in the removal of injected HA filler. Repeated weekly low-volume (0.1 mL) and low-doses of hyaluronidase (9 units) seem to be effective, in particular for correction of minor irregularities [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR54">54</xref>]. This reduced the risk hypersensitivity and major changes in the affected area.</p><p id="Par51">Another limitation is that the 0.2&#8211;0.4 mL of injected HA filler that was used in 4 studies is very small and not representative of the volumes used when aesthetic practitioners use HA filler. These small volumes (0.2&#8211;0.4 mL) may be easily cleared by intrinsic enzymes, and therefore future studies may need to study the reversal of larger volumes of injected HA filler. Non-significant differences in the rate of degradation of different HA fillers [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR52">52</xref>, <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR53">53</xref>], and different hyaluronidase doses can also be due to the small sample sizes in the 4 studies and future studies may benefit from larger sample sizes.</p><p id="Par52">Alam et. al. [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR54">54</xref>] introduced the scalping concept with injections of small amount (0.1 mL) of low dose hyaluronidase (1.5&#8211;9 units) to achieve the desired effect. A treat to effect concept has therefore been suggested for elective removal of HA fillers with injection intervals of 2 weeks [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR13">13</xref>]. Heydenrych et. al. [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR79">79</xref>] recommended an intralesional injections of 4&#8211;40 IU per 0.1 mL of injected HA filler [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR79">79</xref>]. This all bears similarity to the findings of the 5 reviewed RCTs in this systemic review, which was 1.25&#8211;37.5 units of hyaluronidase (single injections) per 0.1 mL of injected HA filler. As suggested by Jones et al. [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR84">84</xref>] injection of 10 units of hyaluronidase for removal of every 0.1 mL of HA filler appears to be a safe starting point and can be repeated every 2 week to achieve the desired effect.</p><p id="Par53">Overall, comparison between the 5 RCTs that assessed the efficacy of hyaluronidase was difficult as they used different formulations of HA filler or hyaluronidase, and HA filler brands may not react similarly to different hyaluronidases [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR81">81</xref>]. In addition, there were different time intervals and protocols; however, it was evident that hyaluronidase was effective in reversal/removal of uncomplicated HA fillers located at the forearm, upper arm, and back skin. Further studies with larger sample sizes are warranted to establish the ideal treatment protocol/dose for reversal of facial HA injections or management of complications associated with aesthetic HA injection.</p></sec></body><back><fn-group><fn><p><bold>Publisher's Note</bold></p><p>Springer Nature remains neutral with regard to jurisdictional claims in published maps and institutional affiliations.</p></fn></fn-group><ack><title>Acknowledgement</title><p>This study formed the research component of the first author&#8217;s (AB-F) Master of Surgery (Minimally Invasive Aesthetics) degree course at the University College London (UCL).</p></ack><notes><title>Declarations</title><notes id="FPar1" notes-type="COI-statement"><title>Conflict of interest</title><p id="Par54">The authors declare that they have no conflicts of interest to disclose.</p></notes><notes id="FPar2"><title>Ethical Approval</title><p id="Par55">This article does not contain any studies with human participants or animals performed by any of the authors.</p></notes></notes><ref-list id="Bib1"><title>References</title><ref id="CR1"><label>1.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Owczarczyk-Saczonek</surname><given-names>A</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Zdanowska</surname><given-names>N</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Wygonowska</surname><given-names>E</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Placek</surname><given-names>W</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>The immunogenicity of hyaluronic fillers and its consequences</article-title><source>Clin Cosmet Investig Dermatol</source><year>2021</year><volume>14</volume><fpage>921</fpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.2147/CCID.S316352</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">34295171</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC8291382</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR2"><label>2.</label><mixed-citation publication-type="other">Weber GC, Buhren BA, Schrumpf H, Wohlrab J, Gerber PA (2019) Clinical applications of hyaluronidase. In: Labrou N (Eds) Therapeutic enzymes: function and clinical implications. Advances in experimental medicine and biology, vol 1148. Springer, Singapore. 10.1007/978-981-13-7709-9_12<pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1007/978-981-13-7709-9_12</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">31482503</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="CR3"><label>3.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Rohrich</surname><given-names>RJ</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Bartlett</surname><given-names>EL</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Dayan</surname><given-names>E</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>Practical approach and safety of hyaluronic acid fillers</article-title><source>Plast Reconstr Surg Glob Open</source><year>2019</year><volume>7</volume><fpage>e2172</fpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1097/GOX.0000000000002172</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">31624663</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC6635180</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR4"><label>4.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Cohen</surname><given-names>JL</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Hicks</surname><given-names>J</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Nogueira</surname><given-names>A</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Lane</surname><given-names>V</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Andriopoulos</surname><given-names>B</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>Postmarket safety surveillance of delayed complications for recent FDA-approved hyaluronic acid dermal fillers</article-title><source>Dermatol Surg</source><year>2021</year><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1097/DSS.0000000000003350</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">34935756</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC8806034</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR5"><label>5.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Glogau</surname><given-names>RG</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Kane</surname><given-names>MA</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>Effect of injection techniques on the rate of local adverse events in patients implanted with nonanimal hyaluronic acid gel dermal fillers</article-title><source>Dermatol Surg</source><year>2008</year><volume>34</volume><issue>Suppl 1</issue><fpage>S105</fpage><lpage>S109</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">18547173</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1111/j.1524-4725.2008.34251.x</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR6"><label>6.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Sclafani</surname><given-names>AP</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Fagien</surname><given-names>S</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>Treatment of injectable soft tissue filler complications</article-title><source>Dermatol Surg</source><year>2009</year><volume>35</volume><issue>Suppl 2</issue><fpage>1672</fpage><lpage>1680</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1111/j.1524-4725.2009.01346.x</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">19807763</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR7"><label>7.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>DeLorenzi</surname><given-names>C</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>Complications of injectable fillers</article-title><source>Part I. Aesthet Surg J</source><year>2013</year><volume>33</volume><fpage>561</fpage><lpage>575</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1177/1090820X13484492</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">23636629</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR8"><label>8.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Rouanet</surname><given-names>C</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Kestemont</surname><given-names>P</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Winter</surname><given-names>C</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Lerhe</surname><given-names>B</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Savoldelli</surname><given-names>C</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>Management of vascular complications following facial hyaluronic acid injection: high-dose hyaluronidase protocol: a technical note</article-title><source>J Stomatol Oral Maxillofac Surg.</source><year>2022</year><volume>123</volume><issue>2</issue><fpage>262</fpage><lpage>265</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1016/j.jormas.2021.05.014</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">34157447</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR9"><label>9.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Woodward</surname><given-names>J</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Khan</surname><given-names>T</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Martin</surname><given-names>J</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>Facial filler complications</article-title><source>Facial Plast Surg Clin North Am</source><year>2015</year><volume>23</volume><issue>4</issue><fpage>447</fpage><lpage>458</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1016/j.fsc.2015.07.006</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">26505541</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR10"><label>10.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Bravo</surname><given-names>BSF</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Bianco</surname><given-names>S</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Bastos</surname><given-names>JT</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Carvalho</surname><given-names>RM</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>Hyaluronidase: what is your fear?</article-title><source>J Cosmet Dermatol</source><year>2021</year><volume>20</volume><issue>10</issue><fpage>3169</fpage><lpage>3172</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1111/jocd.14303</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">34242464</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR11"><label>11.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Buhren</surname><given-names>BA</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Schrumpf</surname><given-names>H</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Hoff</surname><given-names>NP</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>B&#246;lke</surname><given-names>E</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Hilton</surname><given-names>S</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Gerber</surname><given-names>PA</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>Hyaluronidase: from clinical applications to molecular and cellular mechanisms</article-title><source>Eur J Med Res</source><year>2016</year><volume>13</volume><issue>21</issue><fpage>5</fpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1186/s40001-016-0201-5</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC4752759</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">26873038</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR12"><label>12.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>DeLorenzi</surname><given-names>C</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>New high dose pulsed hyaluronidase protocol for hyaluronic acid filler vascular adverse events</article-title><source>Aesthet Surg J</source><year>2017</year><volume>37</volume><issue>7</issue><fpage>814</fpage><lpage>825</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1093/asj/sjw251</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">28333326</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR13"><label>13.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Murray</surname><given-names>G</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Convery</surname><given-names>C</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Walker</surname><given-names>L</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Davies</surname><given-names>E</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>Guideline for the safe use of hyaluronidase in aesthetic medicine, including modified high-dose protocol</article-title><source>J Clin Aesthet Dermatol.</source><year>2021</year><volume>14</volume><issue>8</issue><fpage>E69</fpage><lpage>E75</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">34840662</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC8570661</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR14"><label>14.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Ors</surname><given-names>S</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>The effect of hyaluronidase on depth of necrosis in hyaluronic acid filling-related skin complications</article-title><source>Aesthetic Plast Surg</source><year>2020</year><volume>44</volume><issue>5</issue><fpage>1778</fpage><lpage>1785</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1007/s00266-020-01759-2</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">32424534</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR15"><label>15.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Kapoor</surname><given-names>KM</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Kapoor</surname><given-names>P</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Heydenrych</surname><given-names>I</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Bertossi</surname><given-names>D</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>Vision loss associated with hyaluronic acid fillers: a systematic review of literature</article-title><source>Aesthetic Plast Surg</source><year>2020</year><volume>44</volume><issue>3</issue><fpage>929</fpage><lpage>944</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1007/s00266-019-01562-8</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">31822960</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR16"><label>16.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Zheng</surname><given-names>C</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Fu</surname><given-names>Q</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Zhou</surname><given-names>GW</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Lai</surname><given-names>LY</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Zhang</surname><given-names>LX</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Zhang</surname><given-names>DQ</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Chen</surname><given-names>GJ</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Liang</surname><given-names>LM</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Chen</surname><given-names>ML</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>Efficacy of percutaneous intraarterial facial/supratrochlear arterial hyaluronidase injection for treatment of vascular embolism resulting from hyaluronic acid filler cosmetic injection</article-title><source>Aesthet Surg J</source><year>2022</year><volume>42</volume><issue>6</issue><fpage>649</fpage><lpage>655</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1093/asj/sjab425</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">34958671</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR17"><label>17.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Rivers</surname><given-names>JK</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>Incidence and treatment of delayed-onset nodules after VYC filler injections to 2139 patients at a single Canadian clinic</article-title><source>J Cosmet Dermatol</source><year>2022</year><volume>21</volume><issue>6</issue><fpage>2379</fpage><lpage>2386</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1111/jocd.15013</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">35451214</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC9321104</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR18"><label>18.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>King</surname><given-names>M</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Bassett</surname><given-names>S</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Davies</surname><given-names>E</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>King</surname><given-names>S</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>Management of delayed onset nodules</article-title><source>J Clin Aesthet Dermatol</source><year>2016</year><volume>9</volume><fpage>E1</fpage><lpage>5</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">28210391</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC5300719</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR19"><label>19.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Chung</surname><given-names>KL</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Convery</surname><given-names>C</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Ejikeme</surname><given-names>I</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Ghanem</surname><given-names>AM</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>A systematic review of the literature of delayed inflammatory reactions after hyaluronic acid filler injection to estimate the incidence of delayed type hypersensitivity reaction</article-title><source>Aesthet Surg J</source><year>2020</year><volume>40</volume><fpage>286</fpage><lpage>300</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1093/asj/sjz222</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">31410442</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR20"><label>20.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Bhojani-Lynch</surname><given-names>T</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>Late-onset inflammatory response to hyaluronic acid dermal fillers</article-title><source>Plast Reconstr Surg Glob Open</source><year>2017</year><volume>5</volume><fpage>e1532</fpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1097/GOX.0000000000001532</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">29632758</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC5889432</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR21"><label>21.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Lee</surname><given-names>JM</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Kim</surname><given-names>YJ</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>Foreign body granulomas after the use of dermal fillers: pathophysiology, clinical appearance, histologic features, and treatment</article-title><source>Arch Plast Surg</source><year>2015</year><volume>42</volume><fpage>232</fpage><lpage>239</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.5999/aps.2015.42.2.232</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">25798398</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC4366708</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR22"><label>22.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Convery</surname><given-names>C</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Davies</surname><given-names>E</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Murray</surname><given-names>G</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Walker</surname><given-names>L</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>Delayed-onset nodules (dons) and considering their treatment following use of hyaluronic acid (ha) fillers</article-title><source>J Clin Aesthet Dermatol.</source><year>2021</year><volume>14</volume><issue>7</issue><fpage>E59</fpage><lpage>E67</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">34840652</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC8570356</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR23"><label>23.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Jung</surname><given-names>H</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>Hyaluronidase: an overview of its properties, applications, and side effects</article-title><source>Arch Plast Surg</source><year>2020</year><volume>47</volume><issue>4</issue><fpage>297</fpage><lpage>300</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.5999/aps.2020.00752</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">32718106</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC7398804</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR24"><label>24.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Dunn</surname><given-names>AL</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Heavner</surname><given-names>JE</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Racz</surname><given-names>G</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Day</surname><given-names>M</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>Hyaluronidase: a review of approved formulations, indications and off-label use in chronic pain management</article-title><source>Expert Opin Biol Ther</source><year>2010</year><volume>10</volume><issue>1</issue><fpage>127</fpage><lpage>131</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1517/14712590903490382</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">20420518</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR25"><label>25.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Silverstein</surname><given-names>SM</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Greenbaum</surname><given-names>S</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Stern</surname><given-names>R</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>Hyaluronidase in ophthalmology</article-title><source>J Appl Res</source><year>2012</year><volume>12</volume><issue>1</issue><fpage>1</fpage><lpage>13</lpage></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR26"><label>26.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Adams</surname><given-names>L</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>Adjuvants to local anaesthesia in ophthalmic surgery</article-title><source>Br J Ophthalmol</source><year>2011</year><volume>95</volume><issue>10</issue><fpage>1345</fpage><lpage>1349</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1136/bjo.2010.188789</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">21441237</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR27"><label>27.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Kim</surname><given-names>TW</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Lee</surname><given-names>JH</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Yoon</surname><given-names>KB</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Yoon</surname><given-names>DM</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>Allergic reactions to hyaluronidase in pain management-a report of three cases</article-title><source>Korean J Anesth</source><year>2011</year><volume>60</volume><issue>1</issue><fpage>57</fpage><lpage>59</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.4097/kjae.2011.60.1.57</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC3040435</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">21359084</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR28"><label>28.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Searle</surname><given-names>T</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Ali</surname><given-names>FR</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Al-Niaimi</surname><given-names>F</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>Hyaluronidase in dermatology: uses beyond hyaluronic acid fillers</article-title><source>J Drugs Dermatol</source><year>2020</year><volume>19</volume><issue>10</issue><fpage>993</fpage><lpage>998</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.36849/JDD.2020.5416</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">33026763</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR29"><label>29.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Tempestini Horliana</surname><given-names>ACR</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>de Brito</surname><given-names>MAD</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Perez</surname><given-names>FEG</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Simonetti</surname><given-names>MPB</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Rocha</surname><given-names>RG</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Borsatti</surname><given-names>MA</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>Hyaluronidase increases the duration of mepivacaine in inferior alveolar nerve blocks</article-title><source>J Oral Maxillofac Surg</source><year>2008</year><volume>66</volume><issue>2</issue><fpage>286</fpage><lpage>290</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1016/j.joms.2007.06.628</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">18201610</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR30"><label>30.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Sooraparaju</surname><given-names>SG</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Abarajithan</surname><given-names>M</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Sathish</surname><given-names>ES</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Suryakumari</surname><given-names>NBP</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Ealla</surname><given-names>KKR</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Gade</surname><given-names>W</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>Anaesthetic efficacy of topical benzocaine gel combined with hyaluronidase for supplemental intrapulpal injection in teeth with irreversible pulpitis-a double blinded clinical trial</article-title><source>J Clin Diagn Res</source><year>2015</year><volume>9</volume><issue>8</issue><fpage>95</fpage><lpage>97</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.7860/JCDR/2015/12575.6401</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC4576652</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">26436058</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR31"><label>31.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Mohamed</surname><given-names>AA</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Radwan</surname><given-names>TA</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Mohamed</surname><given-names>MM</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Mohamed</surname><given-names>HA</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Mohamed Elemady</surname><given-names>MF</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Osman</surname><given-names>SH</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Safan</surname><given-names>TF</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Khair</surname><given-names>TM</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Ali</surname><given-names>NA</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Fahmy</surname><given-names>RS</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Belita</surname><given-names>MI</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Abdalla</surname><given-names>SR</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Seleem</surname><given-names>AA</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Atta</surname><given-names>EM</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Zaid</surname><given-names>OI</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Ragab</surname><given-names>AS</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Salem</surname><given-names>AE</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>AlKholy</surname><given-names>BM</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>Safety and efficacy of addition of hyaluronidase to a mixture of lidocaine and bupivacaine in scalp nerves block in elective craniotomy operations; comparative study</article-title><source>BMC Anesthesiol</source><year>2018</year><volume>18</volume><issue>1</issue><fpage>129</fpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1186/s12871-018-0590-9</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">30219027</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC6138934</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR32"><label>32.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Garcia de Freitas</surname><given-names>R</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Nobre</surname><given-names>YD</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Demarchi</surname><given-names>GTS</given-names></name><etal/></person-group><article-title>Topical treatment for phimosis: time span and other factors behind treatment effectiveness</article-title><source>J Pediatr Urol.</source><year>2006</year><volume>2</volume><issue>4</issue><fpage>380</fpage><lpage>385</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1016/j.jpurol.2006.05.006</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">18947640</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR33"><label>33.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Scarabotto</surname><given-names>LB</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Riesco</surname><given-names>MLG</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>Use of hyaluronidase to prevent perineal trauma during spontaneous delivery: a pilot study</article-title><source>J Midwifery Women's Health</source><year>2008</year><volume>53</volume><issue>4</issue><fpage>353</fpage><lpage>361</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1016/j.jmwh.2008.02.015</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">18586189</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR34"><label>34.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Kavanagh</surname><given-names>J</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Kelly</surname><given-names>AJ</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Thomas</surname><given-names>J</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>Hyaluronidase for cervical ripening and induction of labour</article-title><source>Cochrane Database Syst Rev</source><year>2006</year><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1002/14651858.CD003097.pub2</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">16625569</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC8691265</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR35"><label>35.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Singh</surname><given-names>M</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Niranjan</surname><given-names>HS</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Mehrotra</surname><given-names>R</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Sharma</surname><given-names>D</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Gupta</surname><given-names>SC</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>Efficacy of hydrocortisone acetate/hyaluronidase vs triamcinolone acetonide/hyaluronidase in the treatment of oral submucous fibrosis</article-title><source>Indian J Med Res</source><year>2010</year><volume>131</volume><issue>5</issue><fpage>665</fpage><lpage>669</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">20516538</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR36"><label>36.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Melvin</surname><given-names>OG</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Hunt</surname><given-names>KM</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Jacobson</surname><given-names>ES</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>Hyaluronidase treatment of scleroderma-induced microstomia</article-title><source>JAMA Dermatol</source><year>2019</year><volume>155</volume><issue>7</issue><fpage>857</fpage><lpage>859</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1001/jamadermatol.2019.0585</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">31141116</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR37"><label>37.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Morrow</surname><given-names>L</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Muchmore</surname><given-names>DB</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Hompesch</surname><given-names>M</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Ludington</surname><given-names>EA</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Vaughn</surname><given-names>DE</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>Comparative pharmacokinetics and insulin action for three rapid-acting insulin analogs injected subcutaneously with and without hyaluronidase</article-title><source>Diabetes Care</source><year>2013</year><volume>36</volume><issue>2</issue><fpage>273</fpage><lpage>275</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.2337/dc12-0808</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">23043164</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC3554283</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR38"><label>38.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Elawamy</surname><given-names>A</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Hassanien</surname><given-names>M</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Hamed</surname><given-names>A</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Roushdy</surname><given-names>ASI</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Abass</surname><given-names>NA</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Mohammed</surname><given-names>G</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Hasan</surname><given-names>MRAR</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Kamel</surname><given-names>EZ</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>Efficacy of hyalase hydrodissection in the treatment of carpal tunnel syndrome: a randomized, double-blind, controlled, clinical trial</article-title><source>Pain Physician</source><year>2020</year><volume>23</volume><issue>2</issue><fpage>E175</fpage><lpage>E183</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">32214296</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR39"><label>39.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Aggarwal</surname><given-names>A</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Ravikumar</surname><given-names>BC</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Vinay</surname><given-names>KN</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Raghukumar</surname><given-names>S</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Yashovardhana</surname><given-names>DP</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>A comparative study of various modalities in the treatment of keloids</article-title><source>Int J Dermatol</source><year>2018</year><volume>57</volume><issue>10</issue><fpage>1192</fpage><lpage>1200</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1111/ijd.14069</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">29993130</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR40"><label>40.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Tabola</surname><given-names>R</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Augoff</surname><given-names>K</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Grabowski</surname><given-names>K</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Cirocchi</surname><given-names>R</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>Role of hyaluronidase in the treatment of hypertrophic scars</article-title><source>Dermatol Surg</source><year>2018</year><volume>44</volume><issue>8</issue><fpage>1155</fpage><lpage>1157</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1097/DSS.0000000000001393</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">29140867</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR41"><label>41.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Rzany</surname><given-names>B</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Becker-Wegerich</surname><given-names>P</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Bachmann</surname><given-names>F</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Erdmann</surname><given-names>R</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Wollina</surname><given-names>U</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>Hyaluronidase in the correction of hyaluronic acid-based fillers: a review and a recommendation for use</article-title><source>J Cosmet Dermatol</source><year>2009</year><volume>8</volume><issue>4</issue><fpage>317</fpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1111/j.1473-2165.2009.00462.x</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">19958438</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR42"><label>42.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Menon</surname><given-names>H</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Thomas</surname><given-names>M</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>D'silva</surname><given-names>J</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>Low dose of hyaluronidase to treat over correction by HA filler-a case report</article-title><source>J Plast Reconstr Aesthetic Surg</source><year>2010</year><volume>63</volume><issue>4</issue><fpage>e416</fpage><lpage>e417</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1016/j.bjps.2010.01.005</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">20133216</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR43"><label>43.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Cavallini</surname><given-names>M</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Gazzola</surname><given-names>R</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Metalla</surname><given-names>M</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Vaienti</surname><given-names>L</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>The role of hyaluronidase in the treatment of complications from hyaluronic acid dermal fillers</article-title><source>Aesthet Surg J</source><year>2013</year><volume>33</volume><issue>8</issue><fpage>1167</fpage><lpage>1174</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1177/1090820X13511970</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">24197934</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR44"><label>44.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>King</surname><given-names>M</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Convery</surname><given-names>C</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Davies</surname><given-names>E</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>The use of hyaluronidase in aesthetic practice (v2.4)</article-title><source>J Clin Aesthetic Dermatol</source><year>2018</year><volume>11</volume><issue>6</issue><fpage>61</fpage><lpage>68</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC6011868</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">29942426</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR45"><label>45.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Sharma</surname><given-names>DSC</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Lahiri</surname><given-names>MA</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>Use of hyaluronidase in plastic surgery: a review</article-title><source>J Plast Reconstr Aesthetic Surg.</source><year>2021</year><volume>74</volume><issue>7</issue><fpage>1610</fpage><lpage>1614</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1016/j.bjps.2021.03.125</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">34024740</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR46"><label>46.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Cohen</surname><given-names>BE</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Bashey</surname><given-names>S</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Wysong</surname><given-names>A</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>The Use of hyaluronidase in cosmetic dermatology: a review of the literature</article-title><source>J Clin Investigat Dermatol.</source><year>2015</year><volume>3</volume><issue>2</issue><fpage>7</fpage></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR47"><label>47.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Brody</surname><given-names>HJ</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>Use of hyaluronidase in the treatment of granulomatous hyaluronic acid reactions or unwanted hyaluronic acid misplacement</article-title><source>Dermatol Surg</source><year>2005</year><volume>31</volume><issue>8 Pt 1</issue><fpage>893</fpage><lpage>897</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1097/00042728-200508000-00001</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">16042932</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR48"><label>48.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Hirsch</surname><given-names>RJ</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Cohen</surname><given-names>JL</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Carruthers</surname><given-names>JD</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>Successful management of an unusual presentation of impending necrosis following a hyaluronic acid injection embolus and a proposed algorithm for management with hyaluronidase</article-title><source>Dermatol Surg</source><year>2007</year><volume>33</volume><fpage>357</fpage><lpage>360</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">17338697</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1111/j.1524-4725.2007.33073.x</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR49"><label>49.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Andre</surname><given-names>P</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Flechet</surname><given-names>ML</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>Angioedema after ovine hyaluronidase injection for treating hyaluronic acid overcorrection</article-title><source>J Cosmet Dermatol</source><year>2008</year><volume>7</volume><fpage>136</fpage><lpage>138</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1111/j.1473-2165.2008.00377.x</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">18482018</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR50"><label>50.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Wu</surname><given-names>L</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Liu</surname><given-names>X</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Jian</surname><given-names>X</given-names></name><etal/></person-group><article-title>Delayed allergic hypersensitivity to hyaluronidase during the treatment of granulomatous hyaluronic acid reactions</article-title><source>J Cosmet Dermatol</source><year>2018</year><volume>17</volume><issue>6</issue><fpage>991</fpage><lpage>995</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1111/jocd.12461</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">29159865</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR51"><label>51.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Tricco</surname><given-names>AC</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Lillie</surname><given-names>E</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Zarin</surname><given-names>W</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>O&#8217;Brien</surname><given-names>KK</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Colquhoun</surname><given-names>H</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Levac</surname><given-names>D</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Moher</surname><given-names>D</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Peters</surname><given-names>MDJ</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Horsley</surname><given-names>T</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Weeks</surname><given-names>L</given-names></name><etal/></person-group><article-title>PRISMA extension for scoping reviews (PRISMAScR): checklist and explanation</article-title><source>Ann Intern Med</source><year>2018</year><volume>169</volume><fpage>467</fpage><lpage>473</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.7326/M18-0850</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">30178033</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR52"><label>52.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Vartanian</surname><given-names>AJ</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Frankel</surname><given-names>AS</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Rubin</surname><given-names>MG</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>Injected hyaluronidase reduces restylane-mediated cutaneous augmentation</article-title><source>Arch Facial Plast Surg</source><year>2005</year><volume>7</volume><issue>4</issue><fpage>231</fpage><lpage>237</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1001/archfaci.7.4.231</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">16027343</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR53"><label>53.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Juh&#225;sz</surname><given-names>MLW</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Levin</surname><given-names>MK</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Marmur</surname><given-names>ES</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>The kinetics of reversible hyaluronic acid filler injection treated with hyaluronidase</article-title><source>Dermatol Surg</source><year>2017</year><volume>43</volume><issue>6</issue><fpage>841</fpage><lpage>847</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1097/DSS.0000000000001084</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">28498207</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR54"><label>54.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Alam</surname><given-names>M</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Hughart</surname><given-names>R</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Geisler</surname><given-names>A</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Paghdal</surname><given-names>K</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Maisel</surname><given-names>A</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Weil</surname><given-names>A</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>West</surname><given-names>DP</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Veledar</surname><given-names>E</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Poon</surname><given-names>E</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>Effectiveness of low doses of hyaluronidase to remove hyaluronic acid filler nodules: a randomized clinical trial</article-title><source>JAMA Dermatol</source><year>2018</year><volume>154</volume><issue>7</issue><fpage>765</fpage><lpage>772</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1001/jamadermatol.2018.0515</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">29710212</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC6128506</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR55"><label>55.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Zhang-Nunes</surname><given-names>S</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Ryu</surname><given-names>C</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Cahill</surname><given-names>K</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Straka</surname><given-names>D</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Nabavi</surname><given-names>C</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Czyz</surname><given-names>C</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Foster</surname><given-names>J</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>Prospective in vivo evaluation of three different hyaluronic acid gels to varying doses of hyaluronidase with long-term follow-up</article-title><source>J Plast Reconstr Aesthet Surg</source><year>2021</year><volume>74</volume><issue>4</issue><fpage>874</fpage><lpage>880</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1016/j.bjps.2020.10.052</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">33281083</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR56"><label>56.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Hilton</surname><given-names>S</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Schrumpf</surname><given-names>H</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Buhren</surname><given-names>BA</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>B&#246;lke</surname><given-names>E</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Gerber</surname><given-names>PA</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>Hyaluronidase injection for the treatment of eyelid edema: a retrospective analysis of 20 patients</article-title><source>Eur J Med Res</source><year>2014</year><volume>19</volume><issue>1</issue><fpage>30</fpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1186/2047-783X-19-30</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">24886711</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC4063423</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR57"><label>57.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Sun</surname><given-names>ZS</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Zhu</surname><given-names>GZ</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Wang</surname><given-names>HB</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Xu</surname><given-names>X</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Cai</surname><given-names>B</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Zeng</surname><given-names>L</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Yang</surname><given-names>JQ</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Luo</surname><given-names>SK</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>Clinical outcomes of impending nasal skin necrosis related to nose and nasolabial fold augmentation with hyaluronic acid fillers</article-title><source>Plast Reconstr Surg</source><year>2015</year><volume>136</volume><issue>4</issue><fpage>434e</fpage><lpage>441e</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1097/PRS.0000000000001579</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">26397262</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR58"><label>58.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Artzi</surname><given-names>O</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Loizides</surname><given-names>C</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Verner</surname><given-names>I</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Landau</surname><given-names>M</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>Resistant and recurrent late reaction to hyaluronic acid&#8211;based gel</article-title><source>Dermatol Surg</source><year>2016</year><volume>42</volume><issue>1</issue><fpage>31</fpage><lpage>37</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1097/DSS.0000000000000562</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">26655699</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR59"><label>59.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Sadeghpour</surname><given-names>M</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Quatrano</surname><given-names>NA</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Bonati</surname><given-names>LM</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Arndt</surname><given-names>KA</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Dover</surname><given-names>JS</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Kaminer</surname><given-names>MS</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>Delayed-onset nodules to differentially crosslinked hyaluronic acids: comparative incidence and risk assessment</article-title><source>Dermatol Surg</source><year>2019</year><volume>45</volume><issue>8</issue><fpage>1085</fpage><lpage>1094</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1097/DSS.0000000000001814</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">30789508</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR60"><label>60.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Zhang</surname><given-names>LX</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Lai</surname><given-names>LY</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Zhou</surname><given-names>GW</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Liang</surname><given-names>LM</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Zhou</surname><given-names>YC</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Bai</surname><given-names>XY</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Dai</surname><given-names>Q</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Yu</surname><given-names>YT</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Tang</surname><given-names>WQ</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Chen</surname><given-names>ML</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>Evaluation of intraarterial thrombolysis in treatment of cosmetic facial filler-related ophthalmic artery occlusion</article-title><source>Plast Reconstr Surg</source><year>2020</year><volume>145</volume><issue>1</issue><fpage>42e</fpage><lpage>50e</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1097/PRS.0000000000006313</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">31881603</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR61"><label>61.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Skippen</surname><given-names>B</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Baldelli</surname><given-names>I</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Hartstein</surname><given-names>M</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Casabona</surname><given-names>G</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Montes</surname><given-names>JR</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Bernardini</surname><given-names>F</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>Rehabilitation of the dysmorphic lower eyelid from hyaluronic acid filler: what to do after a good periocular treatment goes bad</article-title><source>Aesthet Surg J</source><year>2020</year><volume>40</volume><issue>2</issue><fpage>197</fpage><lpage>205</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1093/asj/sjz078</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">30877762</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR62"><label>62.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Dubinsky-Pertzov</surname><given-names>B</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Bernardini</surname><given-names>FP</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Or</surname><given-names>L</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Gazit</surname><given-names>I</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Hartstein</surname><given-names>ME</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>Late-onset upper eyelid and brow edema as a long-term complication of hyaluronic acid filler injection</article-title><source>Aesthet Surg J.</source><year>2021</year><volume>41</volume><issue>6</issue><fpage>464</fpage><lpage>471</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1093/asj/sjaa126</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">32427315</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR63"><label>63.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Wang</surname><given-names>J</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Shen</surname><given-names>H</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Liu</surname><given-names>T</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Li</surname><given-names>Q</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Lyu</surname><given-names>Z</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Yu</surname><given-names>Y</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>An efficacy and safety study of intra-arterial recanalization of occluded ophthalmic arteries in patients with monocular blindness caused by injection of hyaluronic acid in facial tissues</article-title><source>Aesthetic Plast Surg</source><year>2021</year><volume>45</volume><issue>4</issue><fpage>1573</fpage><lpage>1578</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1007/s00266-021-02224-4</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">33770216</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR64"><label>64.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Bazin</surname><given-names>R</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Fanchon</surname><given-names>C</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>Equivalence of face and volar forearm for the testing of moisturizing and firming effect of cosmetics in hydration and biomechanical studies</article-title><source>Int J Cosmet Sci</source><year>2006</year><volume>28</volume><issue>6</issue><fpage>453</fpage><lpage>460</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1111/j.1467-2494.2006.00352.x</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">18489290</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR65"><label>65.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Cua</surname><given-names>AB</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Wilhelm</surname><given-names>KP</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Maibach</surname><given-names>HI</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>Elastic properties of human skin: relation to age, sex, and anatomical region</article-title><source>Arch Dermatol Res</source><year>1990</year><volume>282</volume><fpage>283</fpage><lpage>288</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1007/BF00375720</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">2221979</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR66"><label>66.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Olsen</surname><given-names>LO</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Takiwaki</surname><given-names>H</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Serup</surname><given-names>J</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>High-frequency ultrasound characterization of normal skin. skin thickness and echographic density of 22 anatomical sites</article-title><source>Skin Res Technol</source><year>1995</year><volume>1</volume><issue>2</issue><fpage>74</fpage><lpage>80</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1111/j.1600-0846.1995.tb00021.x</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">27328386</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR67"><label>67.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Park</surname><given-names>TH</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Seo</surname><given-names>SW</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Kim</surname><given-names>JK</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Chang</surname><given-names>CH</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>Clinical outcome in a series of 173 cases of foreign body granuloma: improved outcomes with a novel surgical technique</article-title><source>J Plast Reconstr Aesthet Surg</source><year>2012</year><volume>65</volume><issue>1</issue><fpage>29</fpage><lpage>34</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1016/j.bjps.2011.07.033</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">21885359</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR68"><label>68.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Or</surname><given-names>L</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Eviatar</surname><given-names>JA</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Massry</surname><given-names>GG</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Bernardini</surname><given-names>FP</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Hartstein</surname><given-names>ME</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>Xanthelasma-like reaction to filler injection</article-title><source>Ophthalmic Plastic Reconstr Surg</source><year>2017</year><volume>33</volume><issue>4</issue><fpage>244</fpage><lpage>247</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1097/IOP.0000000000000722</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">27218809</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR69"><label>69.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Maisel</surname><given-names>A</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Hughart</surname><given-names>R</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Geisler</surname><given-names>A</given-names></name><etal/></person-group><article-title>Removing hyaluronic acid filler: a randomized controlled clinical trial</article-title><source>J Am Acad Dermatol</source><year>2018</year><volume>79</volume><issue>3</issue><fpage>AB245</fpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1016/j.jaad.2018.05.974</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR70"><label>70.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Zhang</surname><given-names>L</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Luo</surname><given-names>Z</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Li</surname><given-names>J</given-names></name><etal/></person-group><article-title>Endovascular hyaluronidase application through superselective angiography to rescue blindness caused by hyaluronic acid injection</article-title><source>Aesthet Surg J</source><year>2021</year><volume>41</volume><issue>3</issue><fpage>344</fpage><lpage>355</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1093/asj/sjaa036</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">32401308</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR71"><label>71.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Wu</surname><given-names>S</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Pan</surname><given-names>L</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Wu</surname><given-names>H</given-names></name><etal/></person-group><article-title>Anatomic study of ophthalmic artery embolism following cosmetic injection</article-title><source>J Craniofac Surg</source><year>2017</year><volume>28</volume><fpage>1578</fpage><lpage>1581</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1097/SCS.0000000000003674</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">28749836</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR72"><label>72.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Grunebaum</surname><given-names>LD</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Bogdan Allemann</surname><given-names>I</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Dayan</surname><given-names>S</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Mandy</surname><given-names>S</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Baumann</surname><given-names>L</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>The risk of alar necrosis associated with dermal filler injection</article-title><source>Dermatol Surg</source><year>2009</year><volume>35</volume><issue>Suppl 2</issue><fpage>1635</fpage><lpage>1640</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1111/j.1524-4725.2009.01342.x</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">19807758</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR73"><label>73.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Park</surname><given-names>KY</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Son</surname><given-names>IP</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Li</surname><given-names>K</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Seo</surname><given-names>SJ</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Hong</surname><given-names>CK</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>Reticulated erythema after nasolabial fold injection with hyaluronic acid: the importance of immediate attention</article-title><source>Dermatol Surg</source><year>2011</year><volume>37</volume><fpage>1697</fpage><lpage>1699</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1111/j.1524-4725.2011.02098.x</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">21806708</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR74"><label>74.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Redbord</surname><given-names>KP</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Busso</surname><given-names>M</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Hanke</surname><given-names>CW</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>Soft-tissue augmentation with hyaluronic acid and calcium hydroxyl apatite fillers</article-title><source>Dermatol Ther</source><year>2011</year><volume>24</volume><issue>1</issue><fpage>71</fpage><lpage>81</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1111/j.1529-8019.2010.01380.x</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">21276160</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR75"><label>75.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Mortada</surname><given-names>H</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Seraj</surname><given-names>H</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Barasain</surname><given-names>O</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Bamakhrama</surname><given-names>B</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Alhindi</surname><given-names>NI</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Arab</surname><given-names>K</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>Ocular complications post-cosmetic periocular hyaluronic acid injections: a systematic review</article-title><source>Aesthetic Plast Surg</source><year>2022</year><volume>46</volume><issue>2</issue><fpage>760</fpage><lpage>773</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1007/s00266-021-02730-5</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">35091771</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR76"><label>76.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Sorensen</surname><given-names>EP</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Council</surname><given-names>ML</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>Update in soft-tissue filler-associated blindness</article-title><source>Dermatol Surg</source><year>2020</year><volume>46</volume><issue>5</issue><fpage>671</fpage><lpage>677</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1097/DSS.0000000000002108</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">31490297</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR77"><label>77.</label><mixed-citation publication-type="other">Navarro-Hernandez E, P&#233;rez-L&#243;pez M (2022) Effectiveness of retrobulbar hyaluronidase in the treatment of visual loss caused by periocular hyaluronic acid injection. a systematic review. Arch Soc Esp Oftalmol (Engl Ed) S2173-5794(22)00089-5. 10.1016/j.oftale.2022.06.005.<pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1016/j.oftale.2022.06.005</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">35787383</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="CR78"><label>78.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Walker</surname><given-names>L</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Convery</surname><given-names>C</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Davies</surname><given-names>E</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Murray</surname><given-names>G</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Croasdell</surname><given-names>B</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>Consensus opinion for the management of soft tissue filler induced vision loss</article-title><source>J Clin Aesthet Dermatol</source><year>2021</year><volume>14</volume><issue>12</issue><fpage>E84</fpage><lpage>E94</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">35096260</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC8794490</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR79"><label>79.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Heydenrych</surname><given-names>I</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>De Boulle</surname><given-names>K</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Kapoor</surname><given-names>KM</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Bertossi</surname><given-names>D</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>The 10-point plan 2021: updated concepts for improved procedural safety during facial filler treatments</article-title><source>Clin Cosmet Investig Dermatol</source><year>2021</year><volume>14</volume><fpage>779</fpage><lpage>814</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.2147/CCID.S315711</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">34276222</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC8279269</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR80"><label>80.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Guduk</surname><given-names>SS</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>An unusual delayed type reaction following periorbital filler injection with hyaluronic acid</article-title><source>Aesthet Surg J.</source><year>2018</year><volume>38</volume><issue>8</issue><fpage>109</fpage><lpage>113</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1093/asj/sjy035</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">29420683</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR81"><label>81.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Shumate</surname><given-names>GT</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Chopra</surname><given-names>R</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Jones</surname><given-names>D</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Messina</surname><given-names>DJ</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Hee</surname><given-names>CK</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>In vivo degradation of crosslinked hyaluronic acid fillers by exogenous hyaluronidases</article-title><source>Dermatol Surg</source><year>2018</year><volume>44</volume><issue>8</issue><fpage>1075</fpage><lpage>1083</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1097/DSS.0000000000001525</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">29659410</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR82"><label>82.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Munia</surname><given-names>MA</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Munia</surname><given-names>CG</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Parada</surname><given-names>MB</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Ben-Hurferraz Parente</surname><given-names>J</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Wolosker</surname><given-names>N</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>Doppler ultrasound in the management of vascular complications associated with hyaluronic acid dermal fillers</article-title><source>J Clin Aesthet Dermatol.</source><year>2022</year><volume>15</volume><issue>2</issue><fpage>40</fpage><lpage>43</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">35309877</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC8884183</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR83"><label>83.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Chai</surname><given-names>H</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Su</surname><given-names>X</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Yuan</surname><given-names>L</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Li</surname><given-names>Z</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Liu</surname><given-names>Y</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Dou</surname><given-names>M</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Hu</surname><given-names>J</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>Application of high-frequency ultrasound in detection and identification of nasal filling injection materials</article-title><source>J Cosmet Dermatol</source><year>2022</year><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1111/jocd.14912</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">35279941</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR84"><label>84.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Jones</surname><given-names>D</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Tezel</surname><given-names>A</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Borrel</surname><given-names>M</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>In vitro resistance to degradation of hyaluronic acid dermal fillers by ovine testicular hyaluronidase</article-title><source>Dermatol Surg</source><year>2010</year><volume>36</volume><fpage>804</fpage><lpage>809</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1111/j.1524-4725.2010.01550.x</pub-id></element-citation></ref></ref-list></back></article></pmc-articleset>