<?xml version="1.0"  ?><!DOCTYPE pmc-articleset PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD ARTICLE SET 2.0//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pmc/articleset/nlm-articleset-2.0.dtd"><pmc-articleset><article xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" xmlns:ali="http://www.niso.org/schemas/ali/1.0/" xml:lang="en" article-type="research-article" dtd-version="1.4"><processing-meta base-tagset="archiving" mathml-version="3.0" table-model="xhtml" tagset-family="jats"><restricted-by>pmc</restricted-by></processing-meta><front><journal-meta><journal-id journal-id-type="nlm-ta">Medicine (Baltimore)</journal-id><journal-id journal-id-type="iso-abbrev">Medicine (Baltimore)</journal-id><journal-id journal-id-type="pmc-domain-id">2786</journal-id><journal-id journal-id-type="pmc-domain">medicine</journal-id><journal-id journal-id-type="publisher-id">MD</journal-id><journal-title-group><journal-title>Medicine</journal-title></journal-title-group><issn pub-type="ppub">0025-7974</issn><issn pub-type="epub">1536-5964</issn><publisher><publisher-name>Wolters Kluwer Health</publisher-name></publisher></journal-meta><article-meta><article-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC12212790</article-id><article-id pub-id-type="pmcid-ver">PMC12212790.1</article-id><article-id pub-id-type="pmcaid">12212790</article-id><article-id pub-id-type="pmcaiid">12212790</article-id><article-id pub-id-type="pmid">40587688</article-id><article-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1097/MD.0000000000043109</article-id><article-id pub-id-type="publisher-id">MD-D-25-02849</article-id><article-version-alternatives><article-version article-version-type="pmc-version">1</article-version><article-version vocab="JAV" vocab-identifier="http://www.niso.org/publications/rp/RP-8-2008.pdf" article-version-type="Version of Record">3</article-version></article-version-alternatives><article-categories><subj-group subj-group-type="heading"><subject>4000</subject></subj-group><subj-group><subject>Research Article</subject><subject>Observational Study</subject></subj-group></article-categories><title-group><article-title>The impact of individuals&#8217; self-esteem on cosmetic dermatology preferences assessed using the Rosenberg Self-Esteem Scale: A cross-sectional study</article-title></title-group><contrib-group><contrib contrib-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Almudimeegh</surname><given-names initials="A">Almuntsrbellah</given-names></name><degrees>MD</degrees><email>almontaserbellah@hotmail.com</email><xref rid="aff1" ref-type="aff">a</xref></contrib><contrib contrib-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Almukhadeb</surname><given-names initials="E">Eman</given-names></name><degrees>MD</degrees><email>ealmukhadeb@ksu.edu.sa</email><xref rid="aff1" ref-type="aff">a</xref></contrib><contrib contrib-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Nagshabandi</surname><given-names initials="KN">Khalid Nabil</given-names></name><degrees>MD</degrees><email>khaloed23@gmail.com</email><xref rid="aff1" ref-type="aff">a</xref></contrib><contrib contrib-type="author" corresp="yes"><contrib-id contrib-id-type="orcid" authenticated="true">https://orcid.org/0009-0004-4248-8312</contrib-id><name name-style="western"><surname>Alshehri</surname><given-names initials="N">Naif</given-names></name><degrees>MD</degrees><xref rid="aff1" ref-type="aff">a</xref><xref rid="c1" ref-type="corresp">*</xref></contrib><contrib contrib-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Almusa</surname><given-names initials="HA">Hala Abdullah</given-names></name><degrees>MD</degrees><email>hala.almussa@gmail.com</email><xref rid="aff2" ref-type="aff">b</xref></contrib><contrib contrib-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Aldosari</surname><given-names initials="O">Omar</given-names></name><degrees>MD</degrees><email>omar.aldosari2015@gmail.com</email><xref rid="aff3" ref-type="aff">c</xref></contrib><contrib contrib-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Aldakhil</surname><given-names initials="I">Ibrahim</given-names></name><degrees>MD</degrees><email>Ibrahimkd20@gmail.com</email><xref rid="aff4" ref-type="aff">d</xref></contrib><aff id="aff1"><label>a</label> Department of Dermatology, College of Medicine, King Saud University, Riyadh, Saudi Arabia</aff><aff id="aff2"><label>b</label> Department of Dermatology, College of Medicine, Alfaisal University, Riyadh, Saudi Arabia</aff><aff id="aff3"><label>c</label> Department of Orthopedic Surgery, College of Medicine, King Saud University, Riyadh, Saudi Arabia</aff><aff id="aff4"><label>d</label> Department of Internal Medicine, College of Medicine, King Saud University, Riyadh, Saudi Arabia.</aff></contrib-group><author-notes><corresp id="c1"><label>*</label>Correspondence: Naif Alshehri, Department of Dermatology, College of Medicine, King Saud University, PJ7C+89Q, Riyadh 12372, Saudi Arabia (e-mail: <email xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xlink:href="N.alshehri90@gmail.com">N.alshehri90@gmail.com</email>).</corresp></author-notes><pub-date pub-type="collection"><day>27</day><month>6</month><year>2025</year></pub-date><pub-date pub-type="epub"><day>27</day><month>6</month><year>2025</year></pub-date><volume>104</volume><issue>26</issue><issue-id pub-id-type="pmc-issue-id">491977</issue-id><elocation-id>e43109</elocation-id><history><date date-type="received"><day>10</day><month>3</month><year>2025</year></date><date date-type="rev-recd"><day>23</day><month>5</month><year>2025</year></date><date date-type="accepted"><day>13</day><month>6</month><year>2025</year></date></history><pub-history><event event-type="pmc-release"><date><day>27</day><month>06</month><year>2025</year></date></event><event event-type="pmc-live"><date><day>02</day><month>07</month><year>2025</year></date></event><event event-type="pmc-last-change"><date iso-8601-date="2025-07-02 16:25:19.237"><day>02</day><month>07</month><year>2025</year></date></event></pub-history><permissions><copyright-statement>Copyright &#169; 2025 the Author(s). Published by Wolters Kluwer Health, Inc.</copyright-statement><copyright-year>2025</copyright-year><license><ali:license_ref specific-use="textmining" content-type="ccbynclicense">https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/</ali:license_ref><license-p>This is an open-access article distributed under the terms of the <ext-link xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" ext-link-type="uri" xlink:href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/">Creative Commons Attribution-Non Commercial License 4.0 (CCBY-NC)</ext-link>, where it is permissible to download, share, remix, transform, and buildup the work provided it is properly cited. The work cannot be used commercially without permission from the journal.</license-p></license></permissions><self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" content-type="pmc-pdf" xlink:href="medi-104-e43109.pdf"/><self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xlink:href="medi-104-e43109.pdf"/><abstract><p>The pursuit of aesthetic enhancement through cosmetic dermatology has increased globally, influenced by societal beauty standards and social media. Self-esteem plays a pivotal role in shaping individuals&#8217; choices for cosmetic dermatology procedures. To examine the relationship between self-esteem and preferences for cosmetic dermatologic procedures among the Saudi population, utilizing the Rosenberg Self-Esteem Scale. A cross-sectional survey was conducted among 919 participants in Saudi Arabia. The modified Arabic version of the Rosenberg Self-Esteem Scale assessed self-esteem levels. Demographic data, skincare habits, and cosmetic procedure preferences were analyzed using <italic toggle="yes">&#967;</italic><sup>2</sup> and multivariate regression tests. Low self-esteem was prevalent in 26% of participants and significantly associated with specific skincare habits (e.g., applying routines to hands and neck) and prior cosmetic procedures targeting visible body areas (<italic toggle="yes">P</italic>&#8197;&lt;&#8197;.05). Participants without a history of cosmetic procedures were 1.72 times more likely to exhibit low self-esteem (adjusted odds ratio&#8197;=&#8197;1.718; <italic toggle="yes">P</italic>&#8197;=&#8197;.002), whereas those not planning future procedures showed a decreased likelihood of low self-esteem (adjusted odds ratio&#8197;=&#8197;0.501; <italic toggle="yes">P</italic>&#8197;&lt;&#8197;.001). The study highlights a significant relationship between low self-esteem and increased engagement in cosmetic-seeking behaviors. Understanding these psychological factors can guide practitioners toward more patient-centered care.</p></abstract><kwd-group><kwd>aesthetic dermatology</kwd><kwd>body image</kwd><kwd>cosmetic dermatologic procedures</kwd><kwd>cosmetic dermatology</kwd><kwd>cosmetic-seeking behaviors</kwd><kwd>psychosocial health</kwd><kwd>Rosenberg Self-Esteem Scale</kwd><kwd>self-esteem</kwd></kwd-group><custom-meta-group><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-status-qastatus</meta-name><meta-value>0</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-status-live</meta-name><meta-value>yes</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-status-embargo</meta-name><meta-value>no</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-status-released</meta-name><meta-value>yes</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-open-access</meta-name><meta-value>yes</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-olf</meta-name><meta-value>no</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-manuscript</meta-name><meta-value>no</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-legally-suppressed</meta-name><meta-value>no</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-has-pdf</meta-name><meta-value>yes</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-has-supplement</meta-name><meta-value>no</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-pdf-only</meta-name><meta-value>no</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-suppress-copyright</meta-name><meta-value>no</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-is-real-version</meta-name><meta-value>no</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-is-scanned-article</meta-name><meta-value>no</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-preprint</meta-name><meta-value>no</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-in-epmc</meta-name><meta-value>yes</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>OPEN-ACCESS</meta-name><meta-value>TRUE</meta-value></custom-meta></custom-meta-group></article-meta></front><body><sec sec-type="intro"><title>
1. Introduction</title><p>The pursuit of aesthetic enhancement, encompassing the use of cosmetics and various surgical and nonsurgical procedures, has witnessed remarkable growth globally. This trend is largely driven by the pervasive influence of social media, which continues to redefine societal beauty standards. With over half of the global population actively engaging with social media platforms, and this number steadily increasing,<sup>[<xref rid="R1" ref-type="bibr">1</xref>]</sup> image-centric platforms such as Instagram, Snapchat, and TikTok have amplified the pressure to present an idealized appearance.<sup>[<xref rid="R1" ref-type="bibr">1</xref>,<xref rid="R2" ref-type="bibr">2</xref>]</sup></p><p>This growing emphasis on physical appearance has profound psychosocial implications, particularly concerning self-esteem. The American Psychological Association defines self-esteem as the degree to which an individual views their qualities and characteristics positively.<sup>[<xref rid="R3" ref-type="bibr">3</xref>]</sup> Studies have consistently highlighted the significant impact of physical appearance on self-esteem. Physical appearance, as a central component of self-image, significantly influences how individuals perceive their worth and confidence. This relationship often manifests in the desire to modify or enhance features to meet societal expectations or personal standards of beauty.<sup>[<xref rid="R4" ref-type="bibr">4</xref>]</sup> Cosmetic dermatology, offering an array of procedures from minimally invasive treatments to comprehensive interventions, plays a pivotal role in this dynamic. Choices in aesthetic treatments are not solely motivated by physical enhancement but are deeply intertwined with psychological factors such as self-esteem and self-image. Individuals with lower self-esteem may seek cosmetic procedures to address perceived inadequacies, while those with higher self-esteem might pursue such enhancements to maintain or elevate their appearance.<sup>[<xref rid="R4" ref-type="bibr">4</xref>]</sup> The motivations behind these decisions are complex, reflecting an interplay of internal self-perceptions and external societal pressures.</p><p>In light of these considerations, our study aimed to examine the relationship between self-esteem and individual choices and preferences for cosmetic and aesthetic dermatologic procedures. Using the Rosenberg Self-Esteem Scale (RSES), we focused on the public population of Saudi Arabia, a nation with over 35 million people, where &#8776;80% are active social media users.<sup>[<xref rid="R5" ref-type="bibr">5</xref>]</sup> This demographic provides a unique and relevant context for exploring how social influences and self-esteem intersect with cosmetic-seeking behavior. Understanding this relationship not only sheds light on the psychosocial dimensions of cosmetic dermatology but also informs practitioners about the psychological aspects influencing their patients&#8217; choices, enabling more holistic and patient-centered care.</p></sec><sec sec-type="methods"><title>
2. Materials and methods</title><sec><title>2.1. Study design</title><p>This cross-sectional study employed an online survey distributed via Google Forms, targeting the general Saudi population. The survey was shared across multiple social media platforms, including X, WhatsApp, Instagram, TikTok, Snapchat, and LinkedIn. All adults were eligible to participate, and data collection was conducted from August to October 2024.</p></sec><sec><title>2.2. Sample size</title><p>Convenience sampling was used, with the sample size calculated to achieve a 95% confidence level and a 5% margin of error. A total of 919 participants were enrolled, satisfying the required sample size.</p></sec><sec><title>2.3. Study tool</title><p>The population&#8217;s self-esteem was assessed using the RSES.<sup>[<xref rid="R6" ref-type="bibr">6</xref>]</sup> The RSES measures self-esteem using 10 items answered on a 4-point Likert-type scale: from strongly agree to strongly disagree. For this study, we utilized the modified Arabic version of the RSES as developed by Oweis et al.<sup>[<xref rid="R7" ref-type="bibr">7</xref>]</sup> This version has been adapted to ensure cultural relevance and linguistic accuracy while retaining the psychometric integrity of the original scale, with a reported Cronbach <italic toggle="yes">&#945;</italic> of 0.81 in their study sample.<sup>[<xref rid="R7" ref-type="bibr">7</xref>]</sup> The RSES is one of the most widely used measures of self-esteem. After reverse-scoring the negatively worded items, the scale can also be scored by totaling the individual 4-point items. The RSES demonstrates a Guttman scale coefficient of reproducibility of 0.92, indicating excellent internal consistency. Test&#8211;retest reliability over a period of 2 weeks reveals correlations of 0.85 and 0.88, indicating excellent stability. Low self-esteem was defined as a score below 15, following the cutoff used in the original RSES and in the validated Arabic version of the RSES.<sup>[<xref rid="R6" ref-type="bibr">6</xref>,<xref rid="R7" ref-type="bibr">7</xref>]</sup></p><p>In this study, the term &#8220;cosmetic procedures&#8221; refers to participant-reported interventions aimed at enhancing physical appearance. These included both nonsurgical treatments (e.g., laser therapies, facial treatments like HydraFacial, chemical or cold peels, botulinum toxin, fillers, platelet rich plasma, radiofrequency, and high-intensity focused ultrasound) and cosmetic surgical procedures, as listed in the survey&#8217;s multiple-response items on prior and desired cosmetic interventions.</p></sec><sec><title>2.4. Demographic information</title><p>The demographic section comprised 9 questions addressing age, gender, region of residence, marital status, smoking status, employment status, monthly income, education level, and history of psychiatric diagnoses. Age was categorized as &#8804;30 and &gt;30 years to simplify group comparisons and reflect general cosmetic usage patterns.</p></sec><sec><title>2.5. Ethical consideration</title><p>The study was approved by the institutional review board of the College of Medicine at King Saud University, Riyadh, Saudi Arabia. Participants provided informed consent through an online questionnaire after being briefed on the study&#8217;s objectives and assured of their right to withdraw at any time without obligation. To ensure anonymity, no identifying information was collected, and no incentives or rewards were offered for participation.</p><p>To minimize selection bias, participants were recruited from a diverse range of social media platforms to ensure a broad representation of the Saudi population. Also, to reduce response bias, the survey was designed to be anonymous, preventing social desirability effects.</p></sec><sec><title>2.6. Statistical data analysis</title><p>Categorical variables were summarized as frequencies and percentages (%). The <italic toggle="yes">&#967;</italic><sup>2</sup> test was used to assess the relationship between self-esteem levels, sociodemographic characteristics, and cosmetic dermatology choices. Significant findings were further analyzed using multivariate regression to identify independent predictors of low self-esteem. In addition, the <italic toggle="yes">&#967;</italic><sup>2</sup> test was applied to compare cosmetic/aesthetic dermatology choices by gender. A <italic toggle="yes">P</italic> value threshold of .05 was set to determine statistical significance. All survey questions were mandatory in the Google Forms platform, ensuring complete datasets with no missing responses for analysis. Data analysis was performed using IBM Statistical Package for the Social Sciences Statistics, version 26 (Armonk).</p></sec></sec><sec sec-type="results"><title>
3. Results</title><p>This study enrolled 919 participants. As described in (Table <xref rid="T1" ref-type="table">1</xref>), 45.2% were between 18 and 25 years old, with females being dominant (68.7%). Approximately half (50.1%) lived in the Central Region, and 58.8% were single. The prevalence of smokers in this study was 7.8%. Respondents who were earning &lt;5000 Saudi Riyal per month constituted 21.3%. Participants who were bachelor&#8217;s degree holders were 55.4%. In addition, 12.5% had a previous diagnosis of psychiatric conditions.</p><table-wrap position="float" id="T1" orientation="portrait"><label>Table 1</label><caption><p>Sociodemographic characteristics of participants (n = 919).</p></caption><table frame="hsides" rules="groups"><thead><tr><th align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Study data</th><th align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">N (%)</th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td align="left" colspan="2" rowspan="1">Age group (yr)</td></tr><tr><td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">&#8226;&#8195;18&#8211;25</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">415 (45.2%)</td></tr><tr><td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">&#8226;&#8195;26&#8211;35</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">185 (20.1%)</td></tr><tr><td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">&#8226;&#8195;36&#8211;50</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">256 (27.9%)</td></tr><tr><td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">&#8226;&#8195;&gt;50</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">63 (06.9%)</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="2" rowspan="1">Gender</td></tr><tr><td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">&#8226;&#8195;Male</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">288 (31.3%)</td></tr><tr><td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">&#8226;&#8195;Female</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">631 (68.7%)</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="2" rowspan="1">Region of residence</td></tr><tr><td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">&#8226;&#8195;Central Region</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">460 (50.1%)</td></tr><tr><td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">&#8226;&#8195;Western Region</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">265 (28.8%)</td></tr><tr><td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">&#8226;&#8195;Eastern Region</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">87 (09.5%)</td></tr><tr><td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">&#8226;&#8195;Northern Region</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">48 (05.2%)</td></tr><tr><td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">&#8226;&#8195;Southern Region</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">59 (06.4%)</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="2" rowspan="1">Marital status</td></tr><tr><td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">&#8226;&#8195;Single</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">540 (58.8%)</td></tr><tr><td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">&#8226;&#8195;Married</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">341 (37.1%)</td></tr><tr><td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">&#8226;&#8195;Divorced</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">31 (03.4%)</td></tr><tr><td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">&#8226;&#8195;Widowed</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">07 (0.80%)</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="2" rowspan="1">Smoking status</td></tr><tr><td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">&#8226;&#8195;Smoker</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">72 (07.8%)</td></tr><tr><td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">&#8226;&#8195;Nonsmoker</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">825 (89.8%)</td></tr><tr><td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">&#8226;&#8195;Ex-smoker</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">22 (02.4%)</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="2" rowspan="1">Occupational status</td></tr><tr><td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">&#8226;&#8195;Unemployed</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">160 (17.4%)</td></tr><tr><td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">&#8226;&#8195;Student</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">374 (40.7%)</td></tr><tr><td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">&#8226;&#8195;Health care field</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">69 (07.5%)</td></tr><tr><td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">&#8226;&#8195;Nonhealth care field</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">280 (30.5%)</td></tr><tr><td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">&#8226;&#8195;Retired</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">36 (03.9%)</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="2" rowspan="1">Monthly income (SAR)</td></tr><tr><td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">&#8226;&#8195;No income</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">350 (38.1%)</td></tr><tr><td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">&#8226;&#8195;&lt;5000</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">196 (21.3%)</td></tr><tr><td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">&#8226;&#8195;5000&#8211;10,000</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">135 (14.7%)</td></tr><tr><td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">&#8226;&#8195;10,000&#8211;20,000</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">182 (19.8%)</td></tr><tr><td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">&#8226;&#8195;&gt;20,000</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">56 (06.1%)</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="2" rowspan="1">Educational level</td></tr><tr><td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">&#8226;&#8195;High school or below</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">217 (23.6%)</td></tr><tr><td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">&#8226;&#8195;Diploma</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">63 (06.9%)</td></tr><tr><td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">&#8226;&#8195;Bachelor&#8217;s degree</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">509 (55.4%)</td></tr><tr><td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">&#8226;&#8195;Master&#8217;s degree</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">82 (08.9%)</td></tr><tr><td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">&#8226;&#8195;PhD</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">48 (05.2%)</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="2" rowspan="1">Previous diagnosis of any psychiatric conditions</td></tr><tr><td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">&#8226;&#8195;No</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">804 (87.5%)</td></tr><tr><td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">&#8226;&#8195;Yes</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">115 (12.5%)</td></tr></tbody></table><table-wrap-foot><fn fn-type="other"><p>SAR = Saudi Riyal.</p></fn></table-wrap-foot></table-wrap><p>Table <xref rid="T2" ref-type="table">2</xref> shows that respondents with low self-esteem were associated with applying a skincare routine in their hands (<italic toggle="yes">P</italic>&#8197;=&#8197;.023) and neck (<italic toggle="yes">P</italic>&#8197;=&#8197;.037). Regarding the type of skincare products, based on the multiple-response answers, it was observed that moisturizer was the most commonly used skincare product (low: 75.3% vs normal: 75%), followed by cleansers (low: 63.2% vs 65%) and sunscreen (low: 41.4% vs 47.1%). However, these differences in self-esteem did not reach statistical significance (<italic toggle="yes">P</italic>&#8197;&gt;&#8197;.05). Also, no significant relationship was observed between self-esteem and makeup frequency (<italic toggle="yes">P</italic>&#8197;=&#8197;.234). Regarding previous treatment to body areas, it was shown that respondents with low self-esteem were associated with previous treatment on the neck (<italic toggle="yes">P</italic>&#8197;=&#8197;.021), while respondents without a previous history of body area enhancement were less likely to have experienced low self-esteem (<italic toggle="yes">P</italic>&#8197;=&#8197;.022).</p><table-wrap position="float" id="T2" orientation="portrait"><label>Table 2</label><caption><p>Type and application areas of skin care products in relation to the level of self-esteem (n = 919).</p></caption><table frame="hsides" rules="groups"><thead><tr><th align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Variables</th><th align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Low, N (%)<break/>(n = 239)</th><th align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Normal, N (%)<break/>(n = 680)</th><th align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1"><italic toggle="yes">P</italic> value<xref rid="tab2fn1" ref-type="table-fn">*</xref></th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td align="left" colspan="4" rowspan="1">What are the areas you apply a daily skincare routine<xref rid="tab2fn2" ref-type="table-fn">&#8224;</xref></td></tr><tr><td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">&#8195;Face</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">174 (72.8%)</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">530 (77.9%)</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">.107</td></tr><tr><td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">&#8195;Hands</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">118 (49.4%)</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">278 (40.9%)</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">.023<xref rid="tab2fn3" ref-type="table-fn">&#8225;</xref></td></tr><tr><td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">&#8195;Body</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">100 (41.8%)</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">259 (38.1%)</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">.306</td></tr><tr><td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">&#8195;Around eyes</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">80 (33.5%)</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">210 (30.9%)</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">.459</td></tr><tr><td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">&#8195;Neck</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">76 (31.8%)</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">169 (24.9%)</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">.037<xref rid="tab2fn3" ref-type="table-fn">&#8225;</xref></td></tr><tr><td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">&#8195;None</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">42 (17.6%)</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">108 (15.9%)</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">.543</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="4" rowspan="1">Type of skin care products<xref rid="tab2fn2" ref-type="table-fn">&#8224;</xref></td></tr><tr><td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">&#8195;Moisturizer</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">180 (75.3%)</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">510 (75.0%)</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">.923</td></tr><tr><td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">&#8195;Cleansers</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">151 (63.2%)</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">442 (65.0%)</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">.613</td></tr><tr><td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">&#8195;Sunscreen</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">99 (41.4%)</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">320 (47.1%)</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">.132</td></tr><tr><td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">&#8195;Makeup remover</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">91 (38.1%)</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">244 (35.9%)</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">.545</td></tr><tr><td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">&#8195;Antiaging products</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">54 (22.6%)</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">172 (25.3%)</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">.404</td></tr><tr><td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">&#8195;Toners</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">44 (18.4%)</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">130 (19.1%)</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">.810</td></tr><tr><td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">&#8195;Anticellulite creams</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">07 (02.9%)</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">14 (02.1%)</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">.439</td></tr><tr><td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">&#8195;Others</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">04 (01.7%)</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">09 (01.3%)</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">.751</td></tr><tr><td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">&#8195;None</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">34 (14.2%)</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">81 (11.9%)</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">.352</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="4" rowspan="1">Makeup frequency</td></tr><tr><td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">&#8195;Every day</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">19 (07.9%)</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">79 (11.6%)</td><td align="center" rowspan="5" colspan="1">.234</td></tr><tr><td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">&#8195;A few times a week</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">67 (28.0%)</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">170 (25.0%)</td></tr><tr><td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">&#8195;A few times a month</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">40 (16.7%)</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">124 (18.2%)</td></tr><tr><td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">&#8195;A few time a year</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">33 (13.8%)</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">68 (10.0%)</td></tr><tr><td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">&#8195;Never</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">80 (33.5%)</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">239 (35.1%)</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="4" rowspan="1">The body area you have treated/enhanced before<xref rid="tab2fn2" ref-type="table-fn">&#8224;</xref></td></tr><tr><td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">&#8195;Face</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">150 (62.8%)</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">394 (57.9%)</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">.192</td></tr><tr><td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">&#8195;Body</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">92 (38.5%)</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">219 (32.2%)</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">.077</td></tr><tr><td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">&#8195;Around eyes</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">86 (36.0%)</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">215 (31.6%)</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">.216</td></tr><tr><td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">&#8195;Hands</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">51 (21.3%)</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">108 (15.9%)</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">.055</td></tr><tr><td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">&#8195;Neck</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">46 (19.2%)</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">89 (13.1%)</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">.021<xref rid="tab2fn3" ref-type="table-fn">&#8225;</xref></td></tr><tr><td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">&#8195;None</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">39 (16.3%)</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">159 (23.4%)</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">.022<xref rid="tab2fn3" ref-type="table-fn">&#8225;</xref></td></tr></tbody></table><table-wrap-foot><fn id="tab2fn1"><label>*</label><p><italic toggle="yes">P</italic> value has been calculated using <italic toggle="yes">&#967;</italic><sup>2</sup> test.</p></fn><fn id="tab2fn2"><label>&#8224;</label><p>Variables with multiple-response answers.</p></fn><fn id="tab2fn3"><label>&#8225;</label><p>Significant at <italic toggle="yes">P</italic>&#8197;&lt;&#8197;.05 level.</p></fn></table-wrap-foot></table-wrap><p>In Figure <xref rid="F1" ref-type="fig">1</xref>, the prevalence of participants with low self-esteem was 26%, while the rest were normal (74%). The overall mean score of the RSE scale was 15.5 (SD: 1.88). In Figure <xref rid="F2" ref-type="fig">2</xref>, based on multiple-response answers, the most common cosmetic procedure previously performed among respondents was laser (low: 29.3% vs normal: 35.3%), followed by facial, for example, hydra facial (low: 18% vs normal: 19.1%), and dermal filler (low: 14.6% vs normal: 19.1%). However, respondents who did not have a history of cosmetic procedures were less likely to be diagnosed with lower self-esteem (<italic toggle="yes">P</italic>&#8197;=&#8197;.030). In Figure <xref rid="F3" ref-type="fig">3</xref>), the most common cosmetic procedure that participants wished to undergo was facial, for example, hydra facial (low: 31.4% vs normal: 24.6%; <italic toggle="yes">P</italic>&#8197;=&#8197;.039), followed by laser (low: 28% vs 21.3%; <italic toggle="yes">P</italic>&#8197;=&#8197;.034) and chemical/cold peel (low: 18.8% vs 17.6%; <italic toggle="yes">P</italic>&#8197;=&#8197;.682).</p><fig position="float" id="F1" orientation="portrait"><label>Figure 1.</label><caption><p>Level of self-esteem according to Rosenberg Self-Esteem Scale. PRP = platelet rich plasma.</p></caption><graphic xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" position="float" orientation="portrait" xlink:href="medi-104-e43109-g001.jpg"/></fig><fig position="float" id="F2" orientation="portrait"><label>Figure 2.</label><caption><p>Type of cosmetic procedure previously undertaken in regard to the level of self-esteem.</p></caption><graphic xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" position="float" orientation="portrait" xlink:href="medi-104-e43109-g002.jpg"/></fig><fig position="float" id="F3" orientation="portrait"><label>Figure 3.</label><caption><p>Type of cosmetic procedure wishes to undergo according to the level of self-esteem. PRP = platelet rich plasma.</p></caption><graphic xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" position="float" orientation="portrait" xlink:href="medi-104-e43109-g003.jpg"/></fig><p>Table <xref rid="T3" ref-type="table">3</xref> shows inverse significant correlations between total self-esteem score in terms of the number of treated/enhanced body areas (<italic toggle="yes">r</italic>&#8197;=&#8197;&#8722;0.094, <italic toggle="yes">P</italic>&#8197;=&#8197;.004) and the number of cosmetic procedures wished to be taken (<italic toggle="yes">r</italic>&#8197;=&#8197;&#8722;0.082, <italic toggle="yes">P</italic>&#8197;=&#8197;.013). No significant correlations were observed between the total self-esteem score in relation to the total number of areas applied daily skincare, the total number of skincare products, and the number of cosmetic procedures being undertaken (<italic toggle="yes">P</italic>&#8197;&gt;&#8197;.05). Measuring the relationship between self-esteem among the sociodemographic characteristics and the cosmetic dermatology choices of participants found that younger age group (<italic toggle="yes">P</italic>&#8197;=&#8197;.007), decreasing monthly income (<italic toggle="yes">P</italic>&#8197;=&#8197;.021), no previous history of cosmetic procedure (<italic toggle="yes">P</italic>&#8197;=&#8197;.018) and planned to undergo cosmetic procedure (<italic toggle="yes">P</italic>&#8197;=&#8197;.022) were associated with low self-esteem. No significant relationships were observed between the level of self-esteem in terms of gender, marital status, education, employment status, makeup frequency, total number of areas applied daily skincare, and total number of skincare products (all <italic toggle="yes">P</italic>&#8197;&gt;&#8197;.05) (Table <xref rid="T4" ref-type="table">4</xref>).</p><table-wrap position="float" id="T3" orientation="portrait"><label>Table 3</label><caption><p>Correlation between self-esteem score among the number of body areas and the number of cosmetic surgeries being undertaken and planned to undertake (n = 919).</p></caption><table frame="hsides" rules="groups"><thead><tr><th align="left" rowspan="2" colspan="1">Variables</th><th align="center" colspan="2" rowspan="1">Self-esteem score</th></tr><tr><th align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1"><italic toggle="yes">R</italic> value</th><th align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1"><italic toggle="yes">P</italic> value<xref rid="tab3fn1" ref-type="table-fn">*</xref></th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Total number of areas applied daily skincare</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">&#8722;0.065</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">.051</td></tr><tr><td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Total number of skincare products</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">0.013</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">.695</td></tr><tr><td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Number of treated/enhanced body areas</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">&#8722;0.094</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">.004<xref rid="tab3fn2" ref-type="table-fn">&#8224;</xref></td></tr><tr><td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Number of cosmetic procedures being taken</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">0.036</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">.275</td></tr><tr><td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Number of cosmetic procedures wished to be taken</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">&#8722;0.082</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">.013<xref rid="tab3fn2" ref-type="table-fn">&#8224;</xref></td></tr></tbody></table><table-wrap-foot><fn id="tab3fn1"><label>*</label><p><italic toggle="yes">P</italic> value has been calculated using Pearson correlation test.</p></fn><fn id="tab3fn2"><label>&#8224;</label><p>Significant at <italic toggle="yes">P</italic>&#8197;&lt;&#8197;.05 level.</p></fn></table-wrap-foot></table-wrap><table-wrap position="float" id="T4" orientation="portrait"><label>Table 4</label><caption><p>Relationship between self-esteem among the sociodemographic characteristics and the cosmetic dermatology choices (n = 919).</p></caption><table frame="hsides" rules="groups"><thead><tr><th align="left" rowspan="2" colspan="1">Factor</th><th align="center" colspan="2" rowspan="1">Level of self-esteem</th><th align="center" rowspan="2" colspan="1"><italic toggle="yes">P</italic> value<xref rid="tab4fn2" ref-type="table-fn">*</xref></th></tr><tr><th align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Low, N (%)<break/>(n = 239)</th><th align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Normal, N (%)<break/>(n = 680)</th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td align="left" colspan="4" rowspan="1">Age group (years)</td></tr><tr><td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">&#8195;&#8804;30</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">156 (65.3%)</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">376 (55.3%)</td><td align="center" rowspan="2" colspan="1">.007<xref rid="tab4fn3" ref-type="table-fn">&#8224;</xref></td></tr><tr><td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">&#8195;&gt;30</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">83 (34.7%)</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">304 (44.7%)</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="4" rowspan="1">Gender</td></tr><tr><td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">&#8195;Male</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">78 (32.6%)</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">210 (30.9%)</td><td align="center" rowspan="2" colspan="1">.615</td></tr><tr><td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">&#8195;Female</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">161 (67.4%)</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">470 (69.1%)</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="4" rowspan="1">Marital status</td></tr><tr><td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">&#8195;Never been married</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">145 (60.7%)</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">395 (58.1%)</td><td align="center" rowspan="2" colspan="1">.486</td></tr><tr><td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">&#8195;Been married</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">94 (39.3%)</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">285 (41.9%)</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="4" rowspan="1">Educational level</td></tr><tr><td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">&#8195;Diploma or below</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">75 (31.4%)</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">205 (30.1%)</td><td align="center" rowspan="2" colspan="1">.722</td></tr><tr><td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">&#8195;Bachelor or higher</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">164 (68.6%)</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">475 (69.9%)</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="4" rowspan="1">Employment status</td></tr><tr><td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">&#8195;Unemployed</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">51 (21.3%)</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">145 (21.3%)</td><td align="center" rowspan="3" colspan="1">.992</td></tr><tr><td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">&#8195;Student</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">98 (41.0%)</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">276 (40.6%)</td></tr><tr><td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">&#8195;Employed</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">90 (37.7%)</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">259 (38.1%)</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="4" rowspan="1">Monthly income (SAR)</td></tr><tr><td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">&#8195;No income</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">96 (40.2%)</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">254 (37.4%)</td><td align="center" rowspan="3" colspan="1">.021<xref rid="tab4fn3" ref-type="table-fn">&#8224;</xref></td></tr><tr><td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">&#8195;&lt;10,000</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">97 (40.6%)</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">234 (34.4%)</td></tr><tr><td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">&#8195;&#8805;10,000</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">46 (19.2%)</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">192 (28.2%)</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="4" rowspan="1">Makeup frequency</td></tr><tr><td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">&#8195;Every day</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">19 (07.9%)</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">79 (11.6%)</td><td align="center" rowspan="5" colspan="1">.234</td></tr><tr><td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">&#8195;A few times a week</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">67 (28.0%)</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">170 (25.0%)</td></tr><tr><td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">&#8195;A few times a month</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">40 (16.7%)</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">124 (18.2%)</td></tr><tr><td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">&#8195;A few time a year</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">33 (13.8%)</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">68 (10.0%)</td></tr><tr><td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">&#8195;Never</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">80 (33.5%)</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">239 (35.1%)</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="4" rowspan="1">Total number of areas applied daily skincare</td></tr><tr><td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">&#8195;&#8804;3</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">180 (75.3%)</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">535 (78.7%)</td><td align="center" rowspan="2" colspan="1">.282</td></tr><tr><td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">&#8195;&gt;3</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">59 (24.7%)</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">145 (21.3%)</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="4" rowspan="1">Total number of skincare products</td></tr><tr><td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">&#8195;&#8804;3</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">158 (66.1%)</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">441 (64.9%)</td><td align="center" rowspan="2" colspan="1">.726</td></tr><tr><td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">&#8195;&gt;3</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">81 (33.9%)</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">239 (35.1%)</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="4" rowspan="1">Any cosmetic procedure undertaken</td></tr><tr><td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">&#8195;Yes</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">99 (41.4%)</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">342 (50.3%)</td><td align="center" rowspan="2" colspan="1">.018<xref rid="tab4fn3" ref-type="table-fn">&#8224;</xref></td></tr><tr><td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">&#8195;No</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">140 (58.6%)</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">338 (49.7%)</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="4" rowspan="1">Any cosmetic procedure wished to be taken</td></tr><tr><td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">&#8195;Yes</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">164 (68.6%)</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">410 (60.3%)</td><td align="center" rowspan="2" colspan="1">.022<xref rid="tab4fn3" ref-type="table-fn">&#8224;</xref></td></tr><tr><td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">&#8195;No</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">75 (31.4%)</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">270 (39.7%)</td></tr></tbody></table><table-wrap-foot><fn fn-type="other"><p>SAR = Saudi Riyal.</p></fn><fn id="tab4fn2"><label>*</label><p><italic toggle="yes">P</italic> value has been calculated using the <italic toggle="yes">&#967;</italic><sup>2</sup> test.</p></fn><fn id="tab4fn3"><label>&#8224;</label><p>Significant at <italic toggle="yes">P</italic>&#8197;&lt;&#8197;.05 level.</p></fn></table-wrap-foot></table-wrap><p>On the basis of the significant results obtained from the cross-tabulation method, a multivariate regression analysis was subsequently performed to determine the significant independent predictors of low self-esteem. According to the results, compared with participants who had a previous history of cosmetic procedures, participants without a previous history of cosmetic procedures had an increased chance of having low self-esteem by at least 1.72 times higher (adjusted odds ratio [AOR]&#8197;=&#8197;1.718, 95% confidence interval [CI]&#8197;=&#8197;1.213&#8211;2.433, <italic toggle="yes">P</italic>&#8197;=&#8197;.002). In contrast, compared with participants who wished to undergo cosmetic procedures, participants who had no plans for cosmetic procedures had a decreased chance of low self-esteem by at least 50% (AOR&#8197;=&#8197;0.501, 95% CI&#8197;=&#8197;0.352&#8211;0.714, <italic toggle="yes">P</italic>&#8197;&lt;&#8197;.001). No significant effects were observed between low self-esteem in terms of age and monthly income after adjustments to a regression model (<italic toggle="yes">P</italic>&#8197;&gt;&#8197;.05) (Table <xref rid="T5" ref-type="table">5</xref>).</p><table-wrap position="float" id="T5" orientation="portrait"><label>Table 5</label><caption><p>Multivariate regression analysis to determine the significant independent predictor of low self-esteem (n = 919).</p></caption><table frame="hsides" rules="groups"><thead><tr><th align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Factor</th><th align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">AOR</th><th align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">95% CI</th><th align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1"><italic toggle="yes">P</italic> value</th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td align="left" colspan="4" rowspan="1">Age group (years)</td></tr><tr><td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">&#8195;&#8804;30</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Ref</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1"/><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1"/></tr><tr><td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">&#8195;&gt;30</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">0.752</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">0.523&#8211;1.081</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">.124</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="4" rowspan="1">Monthly income (SAR)</td></tr><tr><td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">&#8195;No income</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Reference</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1"/><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1"/></tr><tr><td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">&#8195;&lt;10,000</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">0.825</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">0.518&#8211;1.314</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">.418</td></tr><tr><td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">&#8195;&#8805;10,000</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">0.668</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">0.432&#8211;1.035</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">.071</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="4" rowspan="1">Any cosmetic procedure undertaken</td></tr><tr><td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">&#8195;Yes</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Ref</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1"/><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1"/></tr><tr><td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">&#8195;No</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">1.718</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">1.213&#8211;2.433</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">.002<xref rid="tab5fn2" ref-type="table-fn">*</xref></td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="4" rowspan="1">Any cosmetic procedure wished to be taken</td></tr><tr><td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">&#8195;Yes</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Reference</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1"/><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1"/></tr><tr><td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">&#8195;No</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">0.501</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">0.352&#8211;0.714</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">&lt;.001<xref rid="tab5fn2" ref-type="table-fn">*</xref></td></tr></tbody></table><table-wrap-foot><fn fn-type="other"><p>AOR = adjusted odds ratio, CI = confidence interval, SAR = Saudi Riyal.</p></fn><fn id="tab5fn2"><label>*</label><p>Significant at <italic toggle="yes">P</italic>&#8197;&lt;&#8197;.05 level.</p></fn></table-wrap-foot></table-wrap></sec><sec sec-type="discussion"><title>
4. Discussion</title><sec><title>4.1. Background and relevance</title><p>This study aimed to explore the relationship between self-esteem and cosmetic-seeking behavior among the public population in Saudi Arabia. The key findings indicate that individuals with low self-esteem are more likely to engage in specific skincare routines and express a desire for certain cosmetic procedures. Notably, low self-esteem was associated with applying skincare routines to the hands and neck, previous treatments on the neck, and a higher inclination toward procedures like facial treatments and laser therapies.</p></sec><sec><title>4.2. Comparison with literature</title><p>Our study included 919 participants, with 45.2% aged between 18 and 25 years, and a majority being female (68.7%). Approximately half of the participants resided in the Central Region of Saudi Arabia (50.1%). In addition, 12.5% reported having a previous diagnosis of psychiatric conditions. Many studies addressed the relationship between self-esteem and cosmetic-seeking behavior such as botox injections, soft tissue fillers, and laser therapies; with middle-aged individuals as the primary target population.<sup>[<xref rid="R8" ref-type="bibr">8</xref>&#8211;<xref rid="R10" ref-type="bibr">10</xref>]</sup> However, children and adolescents were found to have lower self-esteem due to dermatological conditions such as acne vulgaris and hair loss.<sup>[<xref rid="R11" ref-type="bibr">11</xref>,<xref rid="R12" ref-type="bibr">12</xref>]</sup> The predominance of female gender in the study aligned with prior research that reported a statistically significant difference according to gender. They noted that women have a lower level of emotional well-being than men, as well as greater knowledge and a more positive attitude toward cosmetic dermatology.<sup>[<xref rid="R9" ref-type="bibr">9</xref>]</sup> Another study has found that higher engagement in cosmetic-seeking behaviors was attributed to greater exposure to beauty standards and access to media. Nevertheless, partners and peers had some associations with the utilization of cosmetic products and procedures.<sup>[<xref rid="R13" ref-type="bibr">13</xref>]</sup> The proportion of participants with psychiatric conditions mirrors findings that mental health issues are common among individuals interested in cosmetic enhancements. A study conducted in Mexico on women who underwent body-contouring cosmetic surgery showed that one-third of the population received psychological attention, as well as around half of them having an episode of depression during their lifetime.<sup>[<xref rid="R8" ref-type="bibr">8</xref>]</sup></p><p>The study found that respondents with low self-esteem were significantly more likely to apply skincare routines to their hands (<italic toggle="yes">P</italic>&#8197;=&#8197;.023) and neck (<italic toggle="yes">P</italic>&#8197;=&#8197;.037) compared to those with normal self-esteem. These findings align with previous research suggesting that individuals may focus more on enhancing specific visible body areas, as antiaging supplements or vitamins and hair removal procedures were most frequently utilized.<sup>[<xref rid="R13" ref-type="bibr">13</xref>]</sup> On the other hand, a study stated that cosmetic surgery has a significant impact on self-esteem, where enhancing body image reduces appearance-related burdens and provides psychological benefits linked to self-esteem. In addition, cosmetic surgery has been shown to improve overall quality of life outcomes.<sup>[<xref rid="R14" ref-type="bibr">14</xref>]</sup> A recent study found an association between upper face dynamic wrinkles and self-esteem. Interestingly, it showed a statistically significant increase in the self-esteem of the participants who were observed 2 weeks after the injection of botulinum toxin. However, the beneficial effects on self-esteem were not presented 3 months following the injection.<sup>[<xref rid="R15" ref-type="bibr">15</xref>]</sup></p><p>The study found no significant relationship between self-esteem and makeup frequency among participants (<italic toggle="yes">P</italic>&#8197;=&#8197;.234). This goes in contrast with prior research done in 2022 which concluded that higher self-esteem was related to higher makeup frequency.<sup>[<xref rid="R16" ref-type="bibr">16</xref>]</sup> The lack of a significant relationship in our study may be related to the fact that makeup usage is influenced by other factors other than self-esteem alone. Respondents with low self-esteem were significantly more likely to have previously received treatments on the neck (<italic toggle="yes">P</italic>&#8197;=&#8197;.021). The significant link between low self-esteem and previous treatments on the neck supports findings from studies indicating that individuals with lower self-esteem are more likely to pursue cosmetic procedures targeting specific body areas they perceive negatively.<sup>[<xref rid="R17" ref-type="bibr">17</xref>]</sup> In addition, participants without a history of body area enhancement were less likely to experience low self-esteem (<italic toggle="yes">P</italic>&#8197;=&#8197;.022). This finding is consistent with previous research that observed that individuals with greater body appreciation exhibited lower interest in cosmetic surgery, indicating a positive self-perception reduces the desire for aesthetic procedures.<sup>[<xref rid="R18" ref-type="bibr">18</xref>]</sup></p><p>The study found that the most common cosmetic procedures previously performed among respondents were laser treatments (low self-esteem: 29.3% vs normal self-esteem: 35.3%), followed by facials such as hydra facials (low: 18% vs normal: 19.1%) and dermal fillers (low: 14.6% vs normal: 19.1%). Similar findings were reported by Alharethy<sup>[<xref rid="R19" ref-type="bibr">19</xref>]</sup> in a study done in 2017 to report the demographic trends in Saudi patients undergoing cosmetic procedures. Our findings align with the aforementioned research except for dermal fillers in which reported percentages were 5.8%. This may be implied due to the exponential growth of dermal fillers over the years. Importantly, respondents without a history of cosmetic procedures were less likely to have low self-esteem (<italic toggle="yes">P</italic>&#8197;=&#8197;.030). These findings resonate with prior research indicating a complex relationship between self-esteem and engagement in cosmetic procedures. A study has shown that the majority of the patients who received cosmetic enhancement reported a significant difference and an overall improvement in self-esteem; however, 2 patients did not show a significant difference in self-esteem. The data stated that the 2 patients had had previous cosmetic procedures which may have resulted in improved self-esteem to begin with, or repetitive engagement in cosmetic procedures may contribute to less satisfaction, and consequently less likely to have improvement in self-esteem.<sup>[<xref rid="R10" ref-type="bibr">10</xref>]</sup> A systematic review was done on the psychosocial outcomes following cosmetic surgery. The findings showed that most of the reviewed studies reported that patients are generally happy with the outcome of cosmetic procedures. Still, patients who were dissatisfied with cosmetic procedures had unrealistic expectations of outcomes or underwent more extensive procedures that required greater psychological adjustment.<sup>[<xref rid="R20" ref-type="bibr">20</xref>]</sup></p><p>The study assessed participants&#8217; self-esteem using the RSES and found that 26% of the participants exhibited low self-esteem, while the remaining 74% had normal self-esteem levels. The overall mean RSE score was 15.5 with a standard deviation of 1.88. The prevalence of low self-esteem among our participants (26%) is consistent with findings from similar populations. For instance, a study done in 2023 on 1099 Saudi university students reported a low self-esteem prevalence of 24.1%.<sup>[<xref rid="R21" ref-type="bibr">21</xref>]</sup> Moreover, a study done in Poland reported that over half of the sample (n&#8197;=&#8197;798) had global low self-esteem.<sup>[<xref rid="R22" ref-type="bibr">22</xref>]</sup> These parallels suggest that low self-esteem is a prevalent concern not only in Saudi Arabia but also globally.</p><p>The study found significant inverse correlations between total self-esteem scores and both the number of treated/enhanced body areas (<italic toggle="yes">r</italic>&#8197;=&#8197;&#8722;0.094, <italic toggle="yes">P</italic>&#8197;=&#8197;.004) and the number of cosmetic procedures participants wished to undertake (<italic toggle="yes">r</italic>&#8197;=&#8197;&#8722;0.082; <italic toggle="yes">P</italic>&#8197;=&#8197;.013). This means that lower self-esteem is associated with a higher number of body areas treated or enhanced and a greater desire for future cosmetic procedures. These findings align with prior research indicating that individuals with higher self-esteem were significantly associated with lower cosmetic usage.<sup>[<xref rid="R23" ref-type="bibr">23</xref>]</sup> Moreover, a recent study done in Saudi Arabia stated that &gt;70% of the population who sought noninvasive cosmetic procedures reported that the primary motivation to undergo cosmetic procedures was to increase their perceived attractiveness level; consequently, they had high self-esteem.<sup>[<xref rid="R24" ref-type="bibr">24</xref>]</sup></p><p>The analysis revealed that low self-esteem was significantly associated with being in the younger age group (<italic toggle="yes">P</italic>&#8197;=&#8197;.007), having a decreasing monthly income (<italic toggle="yes">P</italic>&#8197;=&#8197;.021), having no previous history of cosmetic procedures (<italic toggle="yes">P</italic>&#8197;=&#8197;.018), and planning to undergo a cosmetic procedure (<italic toggle="yes">P</italic>&#8197;=&#8197;.022). These findings align with prior research indicating that younger individuals often experience lower self-esteem and heightened body image concerns. The study found that higher age was significantly associated with higher self-esteem.<sup>[<xref rid="R24" ref-type="bibr">24</xref>]</sup> The association between lower income is also supported by existing literature. A study reported that socioeconomic status is associated with engagement in cosmetic procedures, with individuals from families with higher incomes having significantly higher possibilities of having cosmetic procedures.<sup>[<xref rid="R25" ref-type="bibr">25</xref>]</sup> Lower-income backgrounds tend to report lower self-esteem levels. Financial limitations may contribute to feelings of inadequacy or restrict access to means of enhancing appearance, thereby impacting self-esteem. The significant association between planning to undergo a cosmetic procedure and low self-esteem (<italic toggle="yes">P</italic>&#8197;=&#8197;.022) suggests that individuals reporting lower self-esteem more frequently express interest in cosmetic enhancements. This is consistent with prior literature, which found that one of the important factors for pursuing cosmetic procedures.<sup>[<xref rid="R26" ref-type="bibr">26</xref>]</sup></p><p>The multivariate regression analysis identified significant independent predictors of low self-esteem among participants. Specifically, individuals without a previous history of cosmetic procedures were 1.72 times more likely to have low self-esteem compared to those who had undergone such procedures (AOR&#8197;=&#8197;1.718, 95% CI&#8197;=&#8197;1.213&#8211;2.433, <italic toggle="yes">P</italic>&#8197;=&#8197;.002). Conversely, participants who had no plans to undergo cosmetic procedures had a decreased likelihood of having low self-esteem compared to those who wished to undergo them (AOR&#8197;=&#8197;0.501, 95% CI&#8197;=&#8197;0.352&#8211;0.714, <italic toggle="yes">P</italic>&#8197;&lt;&#8197;.001). These findings align with previous research exploring the relationship between self-esteem and cosmetic surgery. Studies have indicated that individuals with lower self-esteem are more likely to report interest in cosmetic procedures, possibly as a means to improve their self-image. For example, a systematic review was done to investigate the influence of surgical and minimally invasive facial cosmetic procedures on psychosocial outcomes, and 9 articles measuring self-esteem postprocedure and global improvement were reported.<sup>[<xref rid="R27" ref-type="bibr">27</xref>]</sup> In contrast to prior literature, multiple studies found that low self-esteem is not directly related. For instance, a cross-sectional study assessed the self-esteem and psychological profiles of individuals seeking cosmetic surgery compared with a control group of the general population, the study concluded that individuals seeking cosmetic surgery do not generally exhibit lower self-esteem than the general population.<sup>[<xref rid="R28" ref-type="bibr">28</xref>]</sup> However, associations between body image and other dimensions of self-esteem were significant for both groups, highlighting that the association is multifaceted. Also, the observation that participants without plans for cosmetic procedures had a decreased likelihood of low self-esteem is consistent with studies showing that higher self-esteem is associated with body satisfaction and less interest in altering one&#8217;s appearance. Al Ghadeer et al<sup>[<xref rid="R29" ref-type="bibr">29</xref>]</sup> noted a statistically insignificant weak positive correlation between high self-esteem and cosmetic procedures. It was reported that individuals with higher self-esteem are less likely to desire cosmetic procedures.</p></sec><sec><title>4.3. Strengths and limitations</title><p>A major strength of this study is the sizable sample size of 919 participants, enhancing the representativeness within the digitally active Saudi Arabian population. The use of a validated self-esteem instrument (RSES) adds psychometric reliability to the results. However, the cross-sectional design precludes causal inference, and associations observed should not be interpreted as directional. The reliance on self-reported data may introduce recall and social desirability biases. While anonymity was maintained to reduce such biases, objective validation (e.g., via clinical records) was not feasible given the anonymous, population-based nature of the survey. In addition, the use of convenience sampling through social media may have resulted in demographic overrepresentation &#8211; particularly of younger, female, and urban respondents &#8211; which may limit generalizability to other subgroups such as older adults, males, or those from rural areas. Lastly, unmeasured psychosocial variables such as cultural pressure, peer influence, and media exposure were not assessed and may serve as important confounders in the relationship between self-esteem and cosmetic behavior.</p></sec><sec><title>4.4. Recommendations for future research</title><p>Future studies should consider longitudinal designs to assess changes in self-esteem and cosmetic-seeking behavior over time. In the current study, factors such as media exposure, cultural expectations, and peer influence were not directly measured. However, they may serve as important confounders and moderators in the relationship between self-esteem and cosmetic preferences. Future research should aim to include and control for these psychosocial variables to provide a more comprehensive understanding of the underlying mechanisms driving interest in cosmetic procedures. In addition, studies should strive for more balanced gender representation and explore targeted interventions aimed at improving self-esteem, particularly among populations at greater risk for appearance-related distress.</p></sec></sec><sec><title>
5. Conclusion</title><p>The intersection of self-esteem and cosmetic dermatology is deeply rooted in societal beauty standards and the pervasive influence of social media, which have significantly shaped individual perceptions of attractiveness and self-worth. Globally, the pursuit of aesthetic enhancement has become increasingly common, with cosmetic dermatology offering various procedures to address perceived imperfections. This study highlights a significant association between low self-esteem and cosmetic-seeking behavior among the public population in Saudi Arabia. Individuals with lower self-esteem more frequently reported engaging in specific skincare routines and expressed interest in cosmetic procedures, particularly targeting visible body areas. These insights underscore the need for integrated approaches in healthcare that address both psychological well-being and aesthetic concerns. By acknowledging the underlying self-esteem issues, practitioners can offer more holistic care, and policymakers can develop targeted initiatives to promote mental health and healthy self-perception.</p></sec><sec><title>Author contributions</title><p><bold>Conceptualization:</bold> Almuntsrbellah Almudimeegh, Eman Almukhadeb.</p><p><bold>Methodology:</bold> Almuntsrbellah Almudimeegh, Eman Almukhadeb, Khalid Nabil Nagshabandi, Naif Alshehri, Ibrahim Aldakhil.</p><p><bold>Project administration:</bold> Almuntsrbellah Almudimeegh, Khalid Nabil Nagshabandi.</p><p><bold>Supervision:</bold> Almuntsrbellah Almudimeegh, Eman Almukhadeb.</p><p><bold>Investigation:</bold> Eman Almukhadeb.</p><p><bold>Data curation:</bold> Khalid Nabil Nagshabandi, Omar Aldosari, Ibrahim Aldakhil.</p><p><bold>Formal analysis:</bold> Khalid Nabil Nagshabandi, Omar Aldosari.</p><p><bold>Writing</bold> &#8211; <bold>review &amp; editing:</bold> Khalid Nabil Nagshabandi, Naif Alshehri, Hala Abdullah Almusa.</p><p><bold>Visualization:</bold> Naif Alshehri, Hala Abdullah Almusa, Omar Aldosari.</p><p><bold>Writing</bold> &#8211; <bold>original draft:</bold> Naif Alshehri, Hala Abdullah Almusa, Ibrahim Aldakhil.</p><p><bold>Validation:</bold> Omar Aldosari.</p><p><bold>Resources:</bold> Ibrahim Aldakhil.</p></sec></body><back><fn-group><fn fn-type="abbr"><p><def-list><title>Abbreviations:</title><def-item><term>AOR</term><def><p>adjusted odds ratio</p></def></def-item><def-item><term>CI</term><def><p>confidence interval</p></def></def-item><def-item><term>RSES</term><def><p>Rosenberg Self-Esteem Scale</p></def></def-item></def-list>
</p></fn></fn-group><fn-group><fn fn-type="other"><p>The authors have no funding and conflicts of interest to disclose.</p></fn><fn fn-type="other"><p>The datasets generated during and/or analyzed during the current study are publicly available and are available from the corresponding author upon reasonable request.</p></fn><fn fn-type="other"><p>How to cite this article: Almudimeegh A, Almukhadeb E, Nagshabandi KN, Alshehri N, Almusa HA, Aldosari O, Aldakhil I. The impact of individuals&#8217; self-esteem on cosmetic dermatology preferences assessed using the Rosenberg Self-Esteem Scale: A cross-sectional study. Medicine 2025;104:26(e43109).</p></fn></fn-group><ref-list><title>References</title><ref id="R1"><label>[1]</label><mixed-citation publication-type="other"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Chaffey</surname><given-names>D</given-names></name></person-group>. <article-title>Global social media statistics research summary 2022. Smart Insights.</article-title><year>2023</year>.</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="R2"><label>[2]</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Almudimeegh</surname><given-names>A</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Almukhadeb</surname><given-names>E</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Nagshabandi</surname><given-names>KN</given-names></name><etal/></person-group>. <article-title>The influence of social media on public attitudes and behaviors towards cosmetic dermatologic procedures and skin care practices: a study in Saudi Arabia.</article-title><source>J Cosmet Dermatol</source>. <year>2024</year>;<volume>23</volume>:<fpage>2686</fpage>&#8211;<lpage>96</lpage>.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">38634196</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1111/jocd.16324</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="R3"><label>[3]</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><collab>VandenBos GR</collab>. <article-title>APA dictionary of psychology.</article-title><source>Choice Rev Online</source>. <year>2007</year>;<volume>44</volume>.</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="R4"><label>[4]</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Patzer</surname><given-names>GL</given-names></name></person-group>. <article-title>Improving self-esteem by improving physical attractiveness.</article-title><source>J Esthet Restor Dent</source>. <year>1997</year>;<volume>9</volume>:<fpage>44</fpage>&#8211;<lpage>6</lpage>.<pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1111/j.1708-8240.1997.tb00915.x</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">9468878</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="R5"><label>[5]</label><mixed-citation publication-type="book"><collab>GMI Research Team</collab>. <article-title>Saudi Arabia (KSA) social media statistics 2024.</article-title><publisher-name>Global Media Insight</publisher-name>; <year>2023</year>. <comment><ext-link xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xlink:href="https://www.globalmediainsight.com/blog/saudi-arabia-social-media-statistics/" ext-link-type="uri">https://www.globalmediainsight.com/blog/saudi-arabia-social-media-statistics/</ext-link>. Accessed March 1, 2025</comment>.</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="R6"><label>[6]</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Sinclair</surname><given-names>SJ</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Blais</surname><given-names>MA</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Gansler</surname><given-names>DA</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Sandberg</surname><given-names>E</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Bistis</surname><given-names>K</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>LoCicero</surname><given-names>A</given-names></name></person-group>. <article-title>Psychometric properties of the Rosenberg Self-Esteem Scale: overall and across demographic groups living within the United States.</article-title><source>Eval Health Prof</source>. <year>2010</year>;<volume>33</volume>:<fpage>56</fpage>&#8211;<lpage>80</lpage>.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">20164106</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1177/0163278709356187</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="R7"><label>[7]</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Oweis</surname><given-names>A</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Gharaibeh</surname><given-names>M</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Alhourani</surname><given-names>R</given-names></name></person-group>. <article-title>Rosenberg Self-Esteem Scale &#8211; modified Arabic version (RSES) [Database record].</article-title><source>APA PsycTests</source>. <year>2010</year>.</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="R8"><label>[8]</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Del Aguila</surname><given-names>E</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Mart&#237;nez</surname><given-names>JR</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Pablos</surname><given-names>JL</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Hu&#225;nuco</surname><given-names>MM</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Encina</surname><given-names>VM</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Rhenals</surname><given-names>AL</given-names></name></person-group>. <article-title>Personality traits, anxiety, and self-esteem in patients seeking cosmetic surgery in Mexico City.</article-title><source>Plast Reconstr Surg Glob Open</source>. <year>2019</year>;<volume>7</volume>:<fpage>e2381</fpage>.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">31772874</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1097/GOX.0000000000002381</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC6846321</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="R9"><label>[9]</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Mart&#237;nez-Gonz&#225;lez</surname><given-names>MC</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Mart&#237;Martnez-Gonz&#225;&#237;nez-Gonz&#225;lez</surname><given-names>RA</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Guerra-Tapia</surname><given-names>A</given-names></name></person-group>. <article-title>Esthetic dermatology and emotional well-being according to gender.</article-title><source>J Cosmet Dermatol</source>. <year>2018</year>;<volume>17</volume>:<fpage>410</fpage>&#8211;<lpage>6</lpage>.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">28834187</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1111/jocd.12389</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="R10"><label>[10]</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Pherson</surname><given-names>SM</given-names></name></person-group>. <article-title>Self-esteem and cosmetic enhancement.</article-title><source>Plast Surg Nurs</source>. <year>2004</year>;<volume>25</volume>:<fpage>5</fpage>&#8211;<lpage>20</lpage>.<pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1097/00006527-200501000-00003</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">15785350</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="R11"><label>[11]</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Vilar</surname><given-names>GN</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Dos Santos</surname><given-names>LA</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Filho</surname><given-names>JFS</given-names></name></person-group>. <article-title>Quality of life, self-esteem and psychosocial factors in adolescents with acne vulgaris.</article-title><source>An Bras Dermatol</source>. <year>2015</year>;<volume>90</volume>:<fpage>622</fpage>&#8211;<lpage>9</lpage>.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">26560206</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1590/abd1806-4841.201533726</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC4631226</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="R12"><label>[12]</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>A&#351;kln</surname><given-names>O</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Koyuncu</surname><given-names>Z</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Serdaro&#487;lu</surname><given-names>S</given-names></name></person-group>. <article-title>Association of alopecia with self-esteem in children and adolescents.</article-title><source>Int J Adolesc Med Health</source>. <year>2022</year>;<volume>34</volume>:<fpage>315</fpage>&#8211;<lpage>8</lpage>.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">32829314</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1515/ijamh-2020-0100</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="R13"><label>[13]</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Rodgers</surname><given-names>RF</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Hewett</surname><given-names>RC</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Laveway</surname><given-names>K</given-names></name></person-group>. <article-title>Sociocultural pressures and engagement with cosmetic products and procedures in adult women.</article-title><source>Body Image</source>. <year>2024</year>;<volume>49</volume>:<fpage>101701</fpage>.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">38520843</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1016/j.bodyim.2024.101701</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="R14"><label>[14]</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Figueroa</surname><given-names>C</given-names></name></person-group>. <article-title>Self-esteem and cosmetic surgery: is there a relationship between the two?</article-title><source>Plast Surg Nurs</source>. <year>2003</year>;<volume>23</volume>:<fpage>21</fpage>&#8211;<lpage>4</lpage>.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">12803096</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1097/00006527-200323010-00005</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="R15"><label>[15]</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>ShayesteFard</surname><given-names>M</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Ghaedi</surname><given-names>G</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Seradj</surname><given-names>MH</given-names></name></person-group>. <article-title>Evaluation of self-esteem in patients treated with botulinum toxin A for upper face dynamic wrinkles.</article-title><source>J Plast Reconstr Aesthet Surg</source>. <year>2022</year>;<volume>75</volume>:<fpage>1497</fpage>&#8211;<lpage>520</lpage>.<pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1016/j.bjps.2022.01.028</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">35131193</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="R16"><label>[16]</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Mafra</surname><given-names>AL</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Silva</surname><given-names>CSA</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Varella</surname><given-names>MAC</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Valentova</surname><given-names>JV</given-names></name></person-group>. <article-title>The contrasting effects of body image and self-esteem in the makeup usage.</article-title><source>PLoS One</source>. <year>2022</year>;<volume>17</volume>:<fpage>e0265197</fpage>.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">35333869</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1371/journal.pone.0265197</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC8956164</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="R17"><label>[17]</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Frederick</surname><given-names>DA</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Lever</surname><given-names>J</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Peplau</surname><given-names>LA</given-names></name></person-group>. <article-title>Interest in cosmetic surgery and body image: views of men and women across the lifespan.</article-title><source>Plast Reconstr Surg</source>. <year>2007</year>;<volume>120</volume>:<fpage>1407</fpage>&#8211;<lpage>15</lpage>.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">17898621</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1097/01.prs.0000279375.26157.64</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="R18"><label>[18]</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Swami</surname><given-names>V</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Tov&#233;e</surname><given-names>MJ</given-names></name></person-group>. <article-title>Body appreciation, media influence, and weight status predict consideration of cosmetic surgery among female undergraduates.</article-title><source>Body Image</source>. <year>2009</year>;<volume>6</volume>:<fpage>304</fpage>&#8211;<lpage>7</lpage>.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">19656747</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1016/j.bodyim.2009.07.001</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="R19"><label>[19]</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Alharethy</surname><given-names>SE</given-names></name></person-group>. <article-title>Trends and demographic characteristics of Saudi cosmetic surgery patients.</article-title><source>Saudi Med J</source>. <year>2017</year>;<volume>38</volume>:<fpage>738</fpage>&#8211;<lpage>41</lpage>.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">28674720</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.15537/smj.2017.7.18528</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC5556282</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="R20"><label>[20]</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Castle</surname><given-names>DJ</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Honigman</surname><given-names>RJ</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Phillips</surname><given-names>KA</given-names></name></person-group>. <article-title>Does cosmetic surgery improve psychosocial wellbeing?</article-title><source>Med J Aust</source>. <year>2002</year>;<volume>176</volume>:<fpage>601</fpage>&#8211;<lpage>4</lpage>.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">12064961</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.5694/j.1326-5377.2002.tb04593.x</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC1851945</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="R21"><label>[21]</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Alghamdi</surname><given-names>SA</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Aljaffer</surname><given-names>MA</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Alahmari</surname><given-names>FS</given-names></name><etal/></person-group>. <article-title>The impact of low self-esteem on academic achievement and the behaviors related to it among medical students in Saudi Arabia.</article-title><source>Saudi Med J</source>. <year>2023</year>;<volume>44</volume>:<fpage>613</fpage>&#8211;<lpage>20</lpage>.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">37343984</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.15537/smj.2023.44.6.20230055</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC10284226</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="R22"><label>[22]</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Kupcewicz</surname><given-names>E</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Cybulska</surname><given-names>AM</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Schneider-Matyka</surname><given-names>D</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Jastrz&#281;bski</surname><given-names>P</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Bentkowska</surname><given-names>A</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Grochans</surname><given-names>E</given-names></name></person-group>. <article-title>Global self-esteem and coping with stress by Polish students during the COVID-19 pandemic.</article-title><source>Front Public Health</source>. <year>2024</year>;<volume>12</volume>:<fpage>1419771</fpage>.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">39469210</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.3389/fpubh.2024.1419771</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC11513623</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="R23"><label>[23]</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Fares</surname><given-names>K</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Hallit</surname><given-names>S</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Haddad</surname><given-names>C</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Akel</surname><given-names>M</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Khachan</surname><given-names>T</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Obeid</surname><given-names>S</given-names></name></person-group>. <article-title>Relationship between cosmetics use, self-esteem, and self-perceived attractiveness among Lebanese women.</article-title><source>J Cosmet Sci</source>. <year>2019</year>;<volume>70</volume>:<fpage>47</fpage>&#8211;<lpage>56</lpage>.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">30856095</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="R24"><label>[24]</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Almutlq</surname><given-names>M</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Alruwaili</surname><given-names>S</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Binyousef</surname><given-names>F</given-names></name><etal/></person-group>. <article-title>Self-esteem following noninvasive cosmetic procedures.</article-title><source>Med Sci</source>. <year>2021</year>;<volume>25</volume>:<fpage>1606</fpage>&#8211;<lpage>14</lpage>.</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="R25"><label>[25]</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Zhang</surname><given-names>Y</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Jiang</surname><given-names>M</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Liu</surname><given-names>J</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Liu</surname><given-names>B</given-names></name></person-group>. <article-title>Pursuing beauty: socio-cultural and labor-economic determinants of cosmetic surgery consideration among female college students in China.</article-title><source>BMC Psychol</source>. <year>2024</year>;<volume>12</volume>:<fpage>519</fpage>.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">39350303</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1186/s40359-024-02016-w</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC11440754</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="R26"><label>[26]</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Furnham</surname><given-names>A</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Levitas</surname><given-names>J</given-names></name></person-group>. <article-title>Factors that motivate people to undergo cosmetic surgery.</article-title><source>Can J Plast Surg</source>. <year>2012</year>;<volume>20</volume>:<fpage>e47</fpage>&#8211;<lpage>50</lpage>.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">24294026</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC3513261</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="R27"><label>[27]</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Imadojemu</surname><given-names>S</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Sarwer</surname><given-names>DB</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Percec</surname><given-names>I</given-names></name><etal/></person-group>. <article-title>Influence of surgical and minimally invasive facial cosmetic procedures on psychosocial outcomes: a systematic review.</article-title><source>JAMA Dermatol</source>. <year>2013</year>;<volume>149</volume>:<fpage>1325</fpage>&#8211;<lpage>33</lpage>.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">24068036</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1001/jamadermatol.2013.6812</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="R28"><label>[28]</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Ferraro</surname><given-names>GA</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Rossano</surname><given-names>F</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>D&#8217;Andrea</surname><given-names>F</given-names></name></person-group>. <article-title>Self-perception and self-esteem of patients seeking cosmetic surgery.</article-title><source>Aesthetic Plast Surg</source>. <year>2005</year>;<volume>29</volume>:<fpage>184</fpage>&#8211;<lpage>9</lpage>.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">15959689</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1007/s00266-004-0124-3</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="R29"><label>[29]</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Al Ghadeer</surname><given-names>HA</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>AlAlwan</surname><given-names>MA</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>AlAmer</surname><given-names>MA</given-names></name><etal/></person-group>. <article-title>Impact of self-esteem and self-perceived body image on the acceptance of cosmetic surgery.</article-title><source>Cureus</source>. <year>2021</year>;<volume>13</volume>:<fpage>e18825</fpage>.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">34804682</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.7759/cureus.18825</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC8592260</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref></ref-list></back></article></pmc-articleset>