<?xml version="1.0"  ?><!DOCTYPE pmc-articleset PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD ARTICLE SET 2.0//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pmc/articleset/nlm-articleset-2.0.dtd"><pmc-articleset><article xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" xmlns:ali="http://www.niso.org/schemas/ali/1.0/" xml:lang="en" article-type="review-article" dtd-version="1.4"><processing-meta base-tagset="archiving" mathml-version="3.0" table-model="xhtml" tagset-family="jats"><restricted-by>pmc</restricted-by></processing-meta><front><journal-meta><journal-id journal-id-type="nlm-ta">Aesthet Surg J</journal-id><journal-id journal-id-type="iso-abbrev">Aesthet Surg J</journal-id><journal-id journal-id-type="pmc-domain-id">2717</journal-id><journal-id journal-id-type="pmc-domain">aesurg</journal-id><journal-id journal-id-type="publisher-id">asj</journal-id><journal-title-group><journal-title>Aesthetic Surgery Journal</journal-title></journal-title-group><issn pub-type="ppub">1090-820X</issn><issn pub-type="epub">1527-330X</issn><publisher><publisher-name>Oxford University Press</publisher-name></publisher></journal-meta><article-meta><article-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC11736774</article-id><article-id pub-id-type="pmcid-ver">PMC11736774.1</article-id><article-id pub-id-type="pmcaid">11736774</article-id><article-id pub-id-type="pmcaiid">11736774</article-id><article-id pub-id-type="pmid">39817790</article-id><article-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1093/asj/sjae150</article-id><article-id pub-id-type="publisher-id">sjae150</article-id><article-version article-version-type="pmc-version">1</article-version><article-categories><subj-group subj-group-type="heading"><subject>Radiofrequency Supplement</subject></subj-group><subj-group subj-group-type="category-taxonomy-collection"><subject>AcademicSubjects/MED00987</subject></subj-group><subj-group subj-group-type="category-taxonomy-collection"><subject>Asj/1</subject></subj-group></article-categories><title-group><article-title>The Role of Fractional Radiofrequency in Long-term Acne Remission and Reduction of Acne Scar Load</article-title></title-group><contrib-group><contrib contrib-type="author" corresp="yes"><name name-style="western"><surname>Hamadani</surname><given-names initials="F">Fadi</given-names></name><degrees>MD</degrees><xref rid="FM1" ref-type="author-notes"/><xref rid="sjae150-cor1" ref-type="corresp"/></contrib><contrib contrib-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Vranis</surname><given-names initials="NM">Neil M</given-names></name><degrees>MD</degrees><xref rid="FM1" ref-type="author-notes"/></contrib></contrib-group><author-notes><fn id="FM1"><p>Dr Hamadani is a plastic surgeon in private practice, Ramallah, Palestine. Dr Vranis is a plastic surgeon in private practice, Beverly Hills, CA, USA.</p></fn><corresp id="sjae150-cor1"><bold>Corresponding Author:</bold> Dr Fadi Hamadani, Division of Plastic and Reconstructive Surgery, H Clinic Hospital, Al-Irsal Street, Ramallah, Palestine. E-mail: <email>fhamadan@gmail.com</email>; Instagram: <ext-link xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xlink:href="https://instagram.com/@drfadihamadani" ext-link-type="uri">@drfadihamadani</ext-link></corresp></author-notes><pub-date pub-type="collection"><month>2</month><year>2025</year></pub-date><pub-date pub-type="epub" iso-8601-date="2025-01-16"><day>16</day><month>1</month><year>2025</year></pub-date><volume>45</volume><issue>Suppl 1</issue><issue-id pub-id-type="pmc-issue-id">479721</issue-id><issue-title>The Use of Radiofrequency in the Face and Body</issue-title><fpage>S23</fpage><lpage>S31</lpage><history><date date-type="editorial-decision"><day>08</day><month>7</month><year>2024</year></date></history><pub-history><event event-type="pmc-release"><date><day>16</day><month>01</month><year>2025</year></date></event><event event-type="pmc-live"><date><day>17</day><month>01</month><year>2025</year></date></event><event event-type="pmc-last-change"><date iso-8601-date="2025-01-28 22:25:16.273"><day>28</day><month>01</month><year>2025</year></date></event></pub-history><permissions><copyright-statement>&#169; The Author(s) 2025. Published by Oxford University Press on behalf of The Aesthetic Society.</copyright-statement><copyright-year>2025</copyright-year><license><ali:license_ref specific-use="textmining" content-type="ccbylicense">https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</ali:license_ref><license-p>This is an Open Access article distributed under the terms of the Creative Commons Attribution License (<ext-link xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" ext-link-type="uri" xlink:href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/">https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</ext-link>), which permits unrestricted reuse, distribution, and reproduction in any medium, provided the original work is properly cited.</license-p></license></permissions><self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" content-type="pmc-pdf" xlink:href="sjae150.pdf"/><self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xlink:href="sjae150.pdf"/><abstract><title>Abstract</title><sec id="s1"><title>Background</title><p>Acne is an inflammatory skin disease afflicting the majority of the world's population at some point in their lifetime, and is seen to be chronic in about 50% of cases. Acne leads to significant social withdrawal, depression, and disfiguring scars in many cases. Available treatments are characterized by high rates of relapse, dangerous side effects, and social stigma, which often leads to poor patient compliance and treatment failure.</p></sec><sec id="s2"><title>Objectives</title><p>The aim of this article was to discuss and share the authors&#8217; experiences utilizing fractional radiofrequency (RF) (Morpheus8; InMode Ltd., Lake Forest, CA) in the treatment of both active acne and acne scars.</p></sec><sec id="s3"><title>Methods</title><p>A retrospective review was conducted comparing 3 treatment modalities. In total, 356 patients received acne scar treatments. The cohort comprised a high-dose isotretinoin topical therapy series (n = 128, 36%), a 6-session ablative laser series (n = 89, 25%), and a 3-session fractional RF microneedling series (n = 139, 44).</p></sec><sec id="s4"><title>Results</title><p>Of the patients with extended 3-year follow-up, the relapse rates were: isotretinoin group, 36 of 54 (67%); laser group, 12 of 16 (75%), and fractional RF microneedling group, 7 of 29 (24%).</p></sec><sec id="s5"><title>Conclusions</title><p>In treating older acne scars, fractional RF microneedling technology has served as an effective tool to tighten skin and fill in atrophic scars when used in conjunction with other techniques. This technology is very effective and very safe for treating all skin types with acne and acne scars.</p></sec></abstract><counts><page-count count="9"/></counts><custom-meta-group><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-status-qastatus</meta-name><meta-value>0</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-status-live</meta-name><meta-value>yes</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-status-embargo</meta-name><meta-value>no</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-status-released</meta-name><meta-value>yes</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-open-access</meta-name><meta-value>yes</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-olf</meta-name><meta-value>no</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-manuscript</meta-name><meta-value>no</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-legally-suppressed</meta-name><meta-value>no</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-has-pdf</meta-name><meta-value>yes</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-has-supplement</meta-name><meta-value>no</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-pdf-only</meta-name><meta-value>no</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-suppress-copyright</meta-name><meta-value>no</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-is-real-version</meta-name><meta-value>no</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-is-scanned-article</meta-name><meta-value>no</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-preprint</meta-name><meta-value>no</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-in-epmc</meta-name><meta-value>yes</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-license-ref</meta-name><meta-value>CC BY</meta-value></custom-meta></custom-meta-group></article-meta></front><body><p>Acne is the most common skin disease globally, with over 85% of the world's population having been afflicted at least once in their lifetime.<sup><xref rid="sjae150-B1" ref-type="bibr">1</xref></sup> Increasingly, acne is being recognized as a chronic disease, as it waxes and wanes in over 50% of sufferers and often continues into adulthood.<sup><xref rid="sjae150-B2" ref-type="bibr">2</xref></sup> The complexity of the disease, its well-documented social impact, and the lack of consistent and safe treatments have led an ongoing search for new therapies.<sup><xref rid="sjae150-B3" ref-type="bibr">3</xref>,<xref rid="sjae150-B4" ref-type="bibr">4</xref></sup></p><p>The pathogenesis of acne is a complex interplay of genetic predisposition, hormonal imbalances, and environmental triggers that leads to hyperkeratinization of the pilosebaceous unit, follicular desquamation, colonization by <italic toggle="yes">Cutibacterium acnes</italic> (formerly <italic toggle="yes">Propionibacterium acnes</italic>), and an inflammatory cascade of cytokines.<sup><xref rid="sjae150-B5" ref-type="bibr">5-7</xref></sup> There is mounting evidence that acne has a strong autoimmune component in over 50% of cases.<sup><xref rid="sjae150-B8" ref-type="bibr">8</xref></sup></p><p>The social impact of acne is also well documented. Many patients suffer from disfiguring scars that lead to social withdrawal and depression, often because they fail to seek early treatment.<sup><xref rid="sjae150-B9" ref-type="bibr">9</xref></sup> The stigma surrounding many acne treatments, together with an unfavorable side-effect profile, has led many patients to self-medicate or to receive ineffective therapies.<sup><xref rid="sjae150-B10" ref-type="bibr">10</xref></sup> Traditional therapies have included oral and topical retinoids and antibiotics, hormonal medications, and a large selection of topical keratolytics.<sup><xref rid="sjae150-B11" ref-type="bibr">11</xref>,<xref rid="sjae150-B12" ref-type="bibr">12</xref></sup> There has been a drive to find new and effective therapies for both active acne and acne scars because of the huge market potential.<sup><xref rid="sjae150-B13" ref-type="bibr">13</xref></sup></p><p>Some of the alternative therapies for acne that have shown promise include lasers, fractional techniques, chemical peels, and light therapies,<sup><xref rid="sjae150-B14" ref-type="bibr">14</xref>,<xref rid="sjae150-B15" ref-type="bibr">15</xref></sup> but none have been consistent in their results and there are high levels of relapse. Microneedling, a technique that was developed in the 1990s, utilizes fractional and controlled-depth penetration of the skin with different types of microneedles. Microneedling has been shown to induce a wound-healing cascade of growth factors and cytokines that can improve acne scars, wrinkles, and striae,<sup><xref rid="sjae150-B16" ref-type="bibr">16</xref></sup> but has a very limited number of applications in treating active acne.</p><p>The Morpheus8 (InMode Ltd, Lake Forest, CA) is a fractional radiofrequency (RF) system that delivers thermal energy to variable depths of the skin through 24 parylene-coated gold-plated pins<sup><xref rid="sjae150-B17" ref-type="bibr">17</xref></sup> (<xref rid="sjae150-F1" ref-type="fig">Figure 1</xref>). Fractional RF microneedling has a well-documented effect on improving the thickness of the reticular and papillary dermis connective tissue and fibers of the skin by inducing a cascade of growth factors, both in the face and body.<sup><xref rid="sjae150-B17" ref-type="bibr">17</xref>,<xref rid="sjae150-B18" ref-type="bibr">18</xref></sup> The distal part of the tip, which is uncoated, creates a compact zone of ablation surrounded by 2 expanded zones of necrotic and subnecrotic nonspecific heating.<sup><xref rid="sjae150-B17" ref-type="bibr">17</xref></sup> This leads to a significant tightening of the skin in addition to a noticeable improvement in skin quality via subacute (up to 3 months) neocollagenesis. The treatment acne and acne scars with fractional RF microneedling devices has not previously been described.</p><fig position="float" id="sjae150-F1" fig-type="figure" orientation="portrait"><label>Figure 1.</label><caption><p>Fractional radiofrequency tips. (A) Morpheus8. (B) Morpheus8 T Resurfacing (InMode Ltd, Lake Forest, CA).</p></caption><graphic xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" position="float" orientation="portrait" xlink:href="sjae150f1.jpg"/></fig><p>The purpose of this Supplement is to introduce the utility of applying fractional RF microneedling for the treatment of acne in all its forms, with the goal of providing long-term remission, considered as a relapse rate of less than 15% in a 5-year period, and effective early scar remodeling. Furthermore, specific protocols for late acne scar remodeling that utilize fractional RF in combination with other modalities will also be discussed.</p><sec id="sjae150-s0"><title>DIFFERENCES BETWEEN FRACTIONAL RADIOFREQUENCY TECHNOLOGIES</title><p>There are different forms of RF energy with medical applications. Most available systems are bipolar RF, meaning that the energy alternates between positively and negatively charged electrodes situated close together within the system.<sup><xref rid="sjae150-B19" ref-type="bibr">19</xref></sup> Most fractional devices on the market today consist of a row of positively charged electrodes positioned parallel to a row of negatively charged ones, so that the RF arc travels a very small distance between the pairs of tips. This configuration results in a very small and superficial zone of ablation, and the induced wound-healing cascade is not very different than standard needling without RF.<sup><xref rid="sjae150-B20" ref-type="bibr">20</xref></sup></p><p>The Morpheus8 bipolar fractional RF microneedling system is designed differently and offers noticeable advantages. The electrode pins are all positively/negatively charged, with the grid surrounding each pin located at the interface of the tip near the skin<sup><xref rid="sjae150-B17" ref-type="bibr">17</xref>,<xref rid="sjae150-B20" ref-type="bibr">20</xref></sup> having the opposite charge. As such, the RF loop is large and induces a bigger and deeper zone of ablation or coagulation that leads to a large quantity of released cytokines and growth factors. Fractional RF treatment spares the epidermis, except for the mechanical injury to the skin, and is considered to be significantly safer in darker skin types.<sup><xref rid="sjae150-B21" ref-type="bibr">21</xref></sup></p></sec><sec id="sjae150-s1"><title>TREATMENT PROCEDURE FOR ACTIVE ACNE AND EARLY ACNE SCARS</title><sec id="sjae150-s1.1"><title>Diagnosis and Pretreatment</title><p>Active acne is identified clinically through the identification of well-known lesions on the face such as closed comedones (blackheads), open comedones (whiteheads), and inflammatory papules and pustules. Often, the lesions lie on a background of erythema with varying degrees of scars depending on the severity of the acne.<sup><xref rid="sjae150-B22" ref-type="bibr">22</xref></sup> The majority of acne scars fall into the following categories: icepick, boxcar, and rolling.</p><p>A detailed family history and physical exam are undertaken with special attention paid to recent use of isotretinoin. Although several studies have demonstrated the safety of both ablative and nonablative energy-based devices for patients on isotretinoin, in darker skin types we opt to reduce the energy by 20%. Contraindications to treatment include high doses of corticosteroids, immunocompromised states, active infections other than acne, pregnancy, and unrealistic expectations.</p></sec><sec id="sjae150-s1.2"><title>Skin Preparation and Anesthesia</title><p>Before the treatment, the skin is cleaned and exfoliated with a keratolytic toner. At high energies, fractional RF microneedling can be quite painful and it is important to provide safe and appropriate analgesia. Options for anesthesia include application of topical numbing creams, nerve blocks, or local anesthesia. One helpful option for anesthesia comes from administering a modified tumescent solution that consists of 60 mL normal saline, 400 mg lidocaine, and 0.3 mg epinephrine. This is then administered via a special chamber that connects to the syringe and allows the tumescent to flow through multiple small needles. When sufficient anesthesia is achieved, the face is cleaned with alcohol wipes.</p></sec><sec id="sjae150-s1.3"><title>Treatment</title><p>During the treatment both the standard fractional RF microneedling tip and the &#8220;resurfacing tip&#8221; were used. Both tips consist of 24 pins, but the former is coated (except the distal 0.5 mm) and can reach depths of 1 to 4 mm, whereas the latter is noncoated and fixed at a depth of 0.5 mm. <xref rid="sjae150-T1" ref-type="table">Table 1</xref> provides an outline of the settings used based on Fitzpatrick skin type. The treatment starts with passes at the deeper layers first and continues superficially. Depending on skin thickness, a depth of 3 mm or 2 mm is chosen to commence the treatment. Once the tip is placed firmly against the skin, a foot pedal is used to activate the device and deliver the pulses of energy. In general, at depths of more than 2 mm, the device is set to &#8220;fixed mode,&#8221; which enables it to deliver several pulses of RF energy through the pins continuously as long as the foot pedal is engaged. The system delivers an acoustic signal to indicate the delivery of each pulse, and the tip is activated to deliver double-stacked pulses at the predetermined depth. Once the double-stacked pulses are delivered, the handpiece is moved over the skin such that it overlaps 50% with the previous treatment area. A set of double-stacked pulses is delivered to each site. Once the treatment zone has received 1 pass of stacked pulses, a second pass that overlays the previous treatment is conducted. This ensures that the treatment zone has received 2 passes of 2 stacks each. Following this, the more superficial depth is started, to ensure full coverage of the treatment zones. At depths of 2 mm or less, the &#8220;cycle mode&#8221; is preferred because this reduces the risk of skin surface overexposure to heat. This mode allows for the pins to insert and deliver the preset amount of RF energy before retracting, only to be reintroduced for the second pulse. Once the treatment is completed, a moisturizing lotion is applied.</p><table-wrap position="float" id="sjae150-T1" orientation="portrait"><label>Table 1.</label><caption><p>Morpheus8 Treatment Parameters Based on Fitzpatrick Skin Type</p></caption><table frame="hsides" rules="groups"><colgroup span="1"><col align="left" span="1"/><col align="center" span="1"/><col align="center" span="1"/><col align="center" span="1"/><col align="center" span="1"/></colgroup><thead><tr><th align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Condition</th><th align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Treatment area</th><th align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Depth (mm)</th><th align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">RF energy level</th><th align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Mode</th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td rowspan="3" colspan="1">Active acne, skin type I-IV</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Forehead</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">1 mm</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">25</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Cycle</td></tr><tr><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Cheeks/jaw</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">2 and 3 mm</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">30-45</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Fixed</td></tr><tr><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Neck</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">2 mm</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">30-40</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Cycle</td></tr><tr><td rowspan="3" colspan="1">Active acne, skin type V-VI</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Forehead</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">1 mm</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">20</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Cycle</td></tr><tr><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Cheeks/jaw</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">2 and 3 mm</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">25-35</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Fixed</td></tr><tr><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Neck</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">2 mm</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">25-35</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Cycle</td></tr><tr><td rowspan="2" colspan="1">Acne scars</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Forehead</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">1 mm</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">25</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Cycle</td></tr><tr><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Cheeks/jaw</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">2 and/or 3 mm</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">30-40</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Fixed</td></tr></tbody></table></table-wrap></sec><sec id="sjae150-s1.4"><title>Posttreatment</title><p>Patients are instructed to avoid sun exposure and to moisturize the treated skin multiple times a day. Patients on topical retinols are instructed to avoid using them for at least 1 week. Patients on oral isotretinoin are instructed to continue taking their prescribed medications. Sun protection is emphasized, as is avoiding exposure to any other direct heat sources for at least 30 days. Patients are informed of expected side effects, including swelling, erythema, crusting, and itchiness and are informed that these may last for several days.</p></sec></sec><sec id="sjae150-s2"><title>TREATMENT PROCEDURE FOR OLD ACNE SCARS</title><sec id="sjae150-s2.1"><title>Diagnosis and Pretreatment</title><p>Old acne scars are identified according to their clinical morphology, and classified as ice-pick, boxcar, or rolling scars<sup><xref rid="sjae150-B1" ref-type="bibr">1</xref>,<xref rid="sjae150-B23" ref-type="bibr">23</xref></sup> (<xref rid="sjae150-T2" ref-type="table">Table 2</xref>). This nomenclature provides a general outline of scar morphology and is meant to serve as a guide to scar depth. We have found it to be more useful to think of each subtype as existing on a spectrum, starting with pores on one end, through to pits and then ice-picks on the other end. In the case of boxcar scars, they may present as narrow or wide, deep or shallow. Rolling scars have a classical peau d&#8217;orange appearance and always improve when light traction is applied to the skin. Although classically associated with rolling scars, it is our experience that all acne scars have a degree of tethering due to fibrotic bands between the skin and subcutaneous tissue, often reaching the muscle.</p><table-wrap position="float" id="sjae150-T2" orientation="portrait"><label>Table 2.</label><caption><p>Main Acne Scar Subtypes<sup><xref rid="sjae150-B1" ref-type="bibr">1</xref>,<xref rid="sjae150-B23" ref-type="bibr">23</xref></sup></p></caption><table frame="hsides" rules="groups"><colgroup span="1"><col align="left" span="1"/><col align="center" span="1"/></colgroup><thead><tr><th align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Subtype</th><th align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Description</th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Ice-pick scars</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Narrow and deep scars</td></tr><tr><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Boxcar scars</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Broad or narrow, deep or shallow scars with sharp edges</td></tr><tr><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Rolling scars</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Broad scars with a sunken appearance and tethering that improve on skin traction</td></tr></tbody></table></table-wrap><p>It is important to note the patient's skin type, and to determine if active acne is still present. Patients with active acne are encouraged to treat the active lesions with fractional RF microneedling or other modalities before commencing with scar revision. Darker-skinned patients are encouraged to condition the skin with topical retinol or tyrosinase inhibitors for at least 3 to 4 weeks prior to commencing treatment with fractional RF microneedling. Skin preparation and anesthesia are carried out as described above.</p></sec><sec id="sjae150-s2.2"><title>Treatment</title><sec id="sjae150-s2.2.1"><title>Ice-pick Scars</title><p>Fractional RF microneedling can remodel ice-pick scars because the pins are able to penetrate the skin at varying depths. In our experience, performing a trichloroacetic acid (TCA) or phenol chemical reconstitution of skin scars (CROSS) or even a punch excision of the scar with a disposable 1-mm skin punch device works in synergy with fractional RF microneedling to produce outstanding results for this scar type.<sup><xref rid="sjae150-B24" ref-type="bibr">24</xref>,<xref rid="sjae150-B25" ref-type="bibr">25</xref></sup> A depth of 2 mm in &#8220;cycle mode,&#8221; with an energy level ranging from 35 to 45, is selected. RF delivery of a single pulse with 75% overlap and 2 or 3 passes is applied.</p></sec><sec id="sjae150-s2.2.2"><title>Boxcar Scars</title><p>These scars respond extremely well to fractional RF microneedling and rarely need any adjunctive therapy. Both the depth of the scar and the consistency of the skin improve notably. The same settings and treatment protocol as for ice-pick scars are used.</p></sec><sec id="sjae150-s2.2.3"><title>Rolling Scars</title><p>Almost all atrophic acne scars, by definition, have a certain degree of tethering.<sup><xref rid="sjae150-B26" ref-type="bibr">26</xref></sup> The most important adjunctive procedure in our experience for this scar type is tumescent subcision.<sup><xref rid="sjae150-B26" ref-type="bibr">26</xref>,<xref rid="sjae150-B27" ref-type="bibr">27</xref></sup> The same anesthesia described above is delivered through a 22G, 70-mm cannula until the skin is turgid. A 2-cm region outside of the mapped scars is anesthetized. Utilizing the same cannula, or a larger caliber one (up to 16G can be used for very fibrotic tissue), repeated gentle strokes parallel to the skin surface are made to break through the bands of the fibrosis.<sup><xref rid="sjae150-B28" ref-type="bibr">28</xref></sup> The key is to be firm and slow. Multiple strokes, in parallel passes, are made until a full release of the tethering is accomplished. The endpoint is identified as when the ease of the passage of the cannula increases. An audible sound of the bands breaking is often heard. Fractional RF microneedling is then performed, with the tumescent providing the necessary anesthesia. For rolling scars, the energies are often the same as those for ice-pick and boxcar scars. The option to inject an agent for collagen boosting is also available, although we prefer to carry out this step at a later time, at least 2 weeks after the simultaneous subcision and fractional RF microneedling treatment session.<sup><xref rid="sjae150-B27" ref-type="bibr">27</xref>,<xref rid="sjae150-B29" ref-type="bibr">29</xref></sup></p></sec></sec></sec><sec id="sjae150-s3"><title>ANCILLARY TECHNIQUE UTILIZING ACCUTITE FOR SUBCISION OF SCARS</title><p>The AccuTite handpiece (InMode Ltd, Lake Forest, CA) (<xref rid="sjae150-F2" ref-type="fig">Figure 2</xref>) is a smaller version of the FaceTite probe, which has been described previously.<sup><xref rid="sjae150-B17" ref-type="bibr">17</xref>,<xref rid="sjae150-B18" ref-type="bibr">18</xref>,<xref rid="sjae150-B30" ref-type="bibr">30</xref></sup> Both AccuTite and FaceTite handpieces (InMode Ltd, Lake Forest, CA) are minimally invasive bipolar RF devices that produce deep tissue heating to tighten the overlying fibroseptal network. An internal positively charged electrode and an external negatively charged electrode complete the circuit. The AccuTite handpiece consists of a 6-cm cannula, 0.9 mm in diameter, and is used to treat more sensitive areas of the face such as the nasolabial folds and periorbital area.</p><fig position="float" id="sjae150-F2" fig-type="figure" orientation="portrait"><label>Figure 2.</label><caption><p>AccuTite handpiece (InMode Ltd, Lake Forest, CA).</p></caption><graphic xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" position="float" orientation="portrait" xlink:href="sjae150f2.jpg"/></fig><p>We have developed a new application for this powerful handpiece, using the internal electrode as an internal cannula for subcision. Once the scar bands are mechanically released, RF is delivered at very conservative temperatures: 50&#176;C internal and 35&#176;C external. When treating acne scars with this technique, it is not necessary to reach the cut-off temperatures, but rather to deliver a few passes in the subcised zone. We have found this to be sufficient for remodeling the skin. <xref rid="sjae150-F3" ref-type="fig">Figure 3</xref> demonstrates a typical result achieved at 6 months follow-up visit after the last treatment. The treatment protocol included 2 sessions of fractional RF microneedling treatments for active acne, followed by 3 sessions of minimally invasive bipolar RF with subcisions as described above. In the final session, the patient was administered a collagen booster (calcium hydroxylapatite, diluted 1:1 with lidocaine 2%; Radiesse, Merz Pharma GmbH &amp; Co., Germany), immediately after this treatment session.</p><fig position="float" id="sjae150-F3" fig-type="figure" orientation="portrait"><label>Figure 3.</label><caption><p>Active acne and early acne scar resolution after a treatment protocol with low-dose isotretinoin (10 mg, 3&#215; per week, 6 months) and 3 sessions of fractional radiofrequency microneedling in a 27-year-old female. (A) Pretreatment. (B) Six months posttreatment.</p></caption><graphic xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" position="float" orientation="portrait" xlink:href="sjae150f3.jpg"/></fig></sec><sec id="sjae150-s4"><title>EXAMPLES OF CLINICAL APPLICATIONS OF FRACTIONAL RADIOFREQUENCY FOR VARIOUS ACNE PRESENTATIONS</title><sec sec-type="results" id="sjae150-s4.1"><title>Results of Treatment of Active Acne and Preventing Acne Scars</title><p>Many options exist for the treatment of active acne, but high relapse rates and an unfavorable side-effect profile may lead to poor compliance.<sup><xref rid="sjae150-B31" ref-type="bibr">31</xref></sup> Many patients seek alternative therapies that are able to provide longer remission. Many of our patients had undergone previous treatments and had experienced relapse, including treatments with high doses of isotretinoin. Although isotretinoin has been shown to improve and modulate early acne scars, its ability to do so is limited, especially in cases of severe cystic acne.</p><p>We have noticed in our practice that fractional RF microneedling has the added benefit of significantly improving early acne scars and acne rosacea with excellent results (<xref rid="sjae150-F3" ref-type="fig">Figures 3</xref>, <xref rid="sjae150-F4" ref-type="fig">4</xref>). Most patients have a complete elimination of early scars which are identified by being red and in the early stages of atrophy. We have also noticed higher remission rates of active acne.</p><fig position="float" id="sjae150-F4" fig-type="figure" orientation="portrait"><label>Figure 4.</label><caption><p>Results of treatment in a patient with acne and rosacea. This 23-year-old female underwent 4 sessions of fractional radiofrequency microneedling spaced 2 months apart. (A, C, E) Pretreatment. (B, D, F) Six months posttreatement.</p></caption><graphic xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" position="float" orientation="portrait" xlink:href="sjae150f4.jpg"/></fig><p>Between February 2018 and October 2021, 356 patients received acne and early acne scar treatments at one of our clinics. Of these patients, 128 (36%) opted for treatment with isotretinoin in high doses and a skincare routine. A group of 89 patients (25%) elected for topical therapy involving 6 sessions with a combination of Er:glass and Nd:YAG lasers. The remaining 139 (44%) patients underwent treatment for their active acne with a skin protocol and fractional RF microneedling. The ancillary skincare protocols for the 3 groups were very similar. All patients were prescribed a keratolytic wash, sun protection, and a topical retinol. Of the 3 groups, a subset of 54 patients of the isotretinoin group, 16 patients of the laser group, and 29 patients of the fractional RF microneedling group have completed a 3-year follow-up since treatment. A large proportion of the patients in the isotretinoin group (36/54, 67%) relapsed within a 3-year period. The laser group had an even higher relapse rate of 75% (12/16 patients). Of the fractional RF microneedling group, 24% experienced relapse (7/29 patients). Satisfaction in this patient group had a mean [standard deviation] of 4.2 [0.4] out of 5. Relapse was defined as patient or practitioner observing worsening of acne or acne scarring after the initial improvement after treatment. There were no adverse outcomes observed&#8212;this includes thermal injury to the epidermis, prolonged erythema, or hyper/hypopigmentation.</p><p>Although we were unable to objectively quantify the scar burden in all these patients after treatment, the majority of patients treated with fractional RF microneedling were very satisfied with the quality of their skin, whereas patients in the remaining 2 groups would often complain about the scars they were left with after their acne remission.</p></sec><sec sec-type="results" id="sjae150-s4.2"><title>Results on Old Acne Scars</title><p>Old acne scars present one of the most challenging scar types to treat.<sup><xref rid="sjae150-B32" ref-type="bibr">32</xref></sup> It is difficult to predict response rate and most patients are only able to achieve a modest result.<sup><xref rid="sjae150-B1" ref-type="bibr">1</xref></sup> Darker skin types pose a particular challenge as many of the more aggressive laser options lead to severe pigmentary changes.<sup><xref rid="sjae150-B33" ref-type="bibr">33</xref></sup> Our experience shows that fractional RF treatment for acne scars is a safe and effective option for all skin types when situated within an acne scar revision protocol that combines multiple modalities.</p><p>Some of the most effective treatments for the different scar types have been summarized above. We have found fractional RF microneedling to be a powerful adjunct for acne scar revision. Combining RF energy with the other procedures described helps initiate neocollagenesis and dermal remodeling, as well as significant tightening of the skin over time. In addition to lifting the atrophic tissue, neocollagenesis helps to support the soft tissue architecture surrounding the scar, leading to smoothening and textural improvement.</p><p>The ECCA score (&#233;chelle d'&#233;valuation clinique des cicatrices d&#8217;acn&#233;) is a validated acne scar grading system in use since 2007.<sup><xref rid="sjae150-B34" ref-type="bibr">34</xref></sup> It allows physicians to score acne scars based on number and severity in order to produce an overall score. Between April 2018 and April 2019, 49 patients with average age of 25.4 [5.6] years with varying degrees of old acne scars completed a series of 4 sessions that utilized a combination of treatments together with fractional RF microneedling. After 4 sessions, all patients showed at least a 50% reduction in median ECCA acne scar grading. The average ECCA score for all patients before treatment was 178 [35], but this was reduced after treatment to 132 [17]. Both the number of scars and their depths were significantly reduced, contributing to the overall clinical improvement (<xref rid="sjae150-F5" ref-type="fig">Figure 5</xref>). Most importantly, there were no significant adverse outcomes for these patients. There were no infections, long-term sequelae of thermal injury, or worsening of scars. Satisfaction in this group of patients had a mean of 3.8 [0.5] out of 5. We did not assess the use of fractional RF microneedling alone for old acne scars.</p><fig position="float" id="sjae150-F5" fig-type="figure" orientation="portrait"><label>Figure 5.</label><caption><p>Typical results of acne scar revision protocols utilizing several tools along with fractional radiofrequency microneedling treatment series. In this case, a 25-year-old female underwent punch excision with a 1-mm punch, tumescent subcision, and fractional radiofrequency microneedling. Four sessions were performed every 3 months. (A, C) Pretreatment. (B, D) Nine months after the last session.</p></caption><graphic xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" position="float" orientation="portrait" xlink:href="sjae150f5.jpg"/></fig></sec></sec><sec sec-type="discussion" id="sjae150-s5"><title>DISCUSSION</title><p>Available treatments for acne scars often demonstrate mild improvement, but are frequently inconsistent or fail to present a dramatic outcome.<sup><xref rid="sjae150-B35" ref-type="bibr">35</xref></sup> The use of fractional RF has been a powerful addition to our armamentarium of tools used for acne and acne scar treatments. Especially when including fractional RF microneedling in combination with other treatments, we have seen excellent results in scar remodeling, well beyond what has been seen with other treatments. This is most likely due to the powerful energy that fractional RF microneedling can deliver, especially when considering the depth of the RF penetration into the tissue. The advantages that the fractional RF microneedling system has over other fractional and microneedling RF systems on the market may be attributed to the fact that the return electrode is on the surface of the skin, thus allowing the RF current to travel a longer distance, thereby creating a larger and deeper heating zone. Other systems situate the positive and negative electrodes in parallel and the RF current achieved occurs in a small and superficial area between the short tips at the very end of the needles.</p><p>The high safety profile achieved with fractional RF microneedling in darker skin types can be attributed to the insulation of most of the length of the pin. In their recent consensus paper looking at energy-based devices for acne scars, Salameh et al showed that noninsulated needles produced less effective results.<sup><xref rid="sjae150-B36" ref-type="bibr">36</xref></sup> One argument is that when the device uses noninsulated needles, the RF spark produced between the positive and negative electrodes occurs along the whole length of the needle. Thus, it produces a more superficial zone of heating, increasing the risk of damage to the skin surface and postinflammatory hyperpigmentation.<sup><xref rid="sjae150-B36" ref-type="bibr">36</xref></sup> However, when the pins are insulated, except for the tip, RF energy is selectively delivered specifically to the target depth. Inadequate treatment of acne scars occurs when treatments are too superficial and do not reach the deep component of ice-pick or boxcar scars.</p><p>In 2014, Kaminaka et al were able to show excellent improvements in active acne when they used RF microneedling.<sup><xref rid="sjae150-B37" ref-type="bibr">37</xref></sup> Our experience has been the same, with results from fractional RF microneedling being more consistent than when utilizing lasers or isotretinoin alone. We attribute this to the stronger and deeper heat signal produced by fractional RF microneedling, which in turn leads to a more powerful wound healing response. Furthermore, fractional RF microneedling is known to ablate the sebaceous glands in the skin, and has recently been shown to be an excellent treatment for ectopic sebaceous glands.<sup><xref rid="sjae150-B38" ref-type="bibr">38</xref></sup> Apparently, there is some destruction of the sebaceous glands, resulting in a reduction of sebum overproduction. Histology of adnexal structures in the skin showed higher levels of collagen remodeling than what is seen with laser treatment.<sup><xref rid="sjae150-B37" ref-type="bibr">37</xref></sup> This perhaps explains the observation in our cohort of acne patients that treatment with fractional RF microneedling leads to longer remission rates than treatment with lasers.</p><p>The excellent results seen in acne scar revision are probably due to the deeper and more powerful heat signature that fractional RF microneedling devices are able to achieve. Several studies have shown that in addition to significant sebum reduction, RF microneedling is able to upregulate TGF&#946;, leading to more collagen remodeling, and to downregulate NF-&#954;B and IL-1, associated with improved scar remodeling.<sup><xref rid="sjae150-B39" ref-type="bibr">39</xref></sup> The negative impact of inflammation on scar revision has been well elucidated, and it is apparent that fractional RF microneedling is able to decrease the inflammatory milieu concomitantly with improving collagen remodeling.<sup><xref rid="sjae150-B37" ref-type="bibr">37</xref>,<xref rid="sjae150-B39" ref-type="bibr">39</xref></sup></p><p>The current evaluation demonstrates qualitative improvements, as well as a degree of quantitative improvement measured by ECCA scores. Unfortunately, we are currently unable to objectively measure sebum reduction or to histologically confirm the improvements we noted clinically. Limitations of this study also include the retrospective, observational nature of the data. The study was not designed as a randomized, independent, blinded trial, and the patients themselves often chose which treatment protocol to undergo, based on financial limitations and treatment downtimes, introducing a bias. Patients were not asked to keep diaries and there is no independent mechanism whereby we can confirm treatment compliance. Nevertheless, the treatments were offered in the same clinic and by the same physician with similar treatment parameters/settings. The presented data are for the patients who completed the whole treatment plan. The current data also share the longest follow-up period for patients after completing fractional RF microneedling sessions. Most studies have a follow-up of 12 to 18 months,<sup><xref rid="sjae150-B35" ref-type="bibr">35</xref></sup> whereas we have followed our patients for over 3 years. Future directions will include performing isolated fractional RF microneedling treatments in addition to combination treatments and a control group to further elucidate the therapeutic benefits of fractional RF microneedling in patients with acne/acne scarring.</p></sec><sec sec-type="conclusions" id="sjae150-s6"><title>CONCLUSIONS</title><p>Fractional RF microneedling offers the advantage of effectively treating both active acne lesions and the associated early scars, and results in long-term remission. Fractional RF microneedling has proven to be extremely safe in darker-skinned patients, whereas other modalities have many limitations. In addition, applications of fractional RF microneedling can be very effectively expanded to include treatment of old scars.</p></sec></body><back><sec id="sjae150-s7"><title>Disclosures</title><p>Drs Hamadani and Vranis are consultants for InMode Ltd (Lake Forest, CA).</p></sec><sec id="sjae150-s8"><title>Funding</title><p>This study was not directly funded or supported by industry; the machine and disposable costs required for the study were paid by the senior author (F.H.).</p></sec><sec id="sjae150-s9"><title>Supplement Sponsorship</title><p>This article appears as part of the supplement &#8220;The Use of Radiofrequency in the Face and Body,&#8221; sponsored by InMode Ltd.</p></sec><ref-list id="ref1"><title>REFERENCES</title><ref id="sjae150-B1"><label>1</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><string-name name-style="western"><surname>Fabbrocini</surname><given-names>G</given-names></string-name>, <string-name name-style="western"><surname>Annunziata</surname><given-names>MC</given-names></string-name>, <string-name name-style="western"><surname>D&#8242; Arco</surname><given-names>V</given-names></string-name>, <etal>et al</etal></person-group><article-title>Acne scars: pathogenesis, classification and treatment</article-title>. <source>Dermatol Res Pract</source>. <year>2010</year>;<volume>2010</volume>(<issue>1</issue>):<fpage>893080</fpage>. doi: <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1155/2010/893080</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">20981308</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC2958495</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="sjae150-B2"><label>2</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><string-name name-style="western"><surname>Gollnick</surname><given-names>HP</given-names></string-name>, <string-name name-style="western"><surname>Finlay</surname><given-names>AY</given-names></string-name>, <string-name name-style="western"><surname>Shear</surname><given-names>N</given-names></string-name></person-group>. <article-title>Global alliance to improve out- comes in acne. Can we define acne as a chronic disease? If so, how and when?</article-title><source>Am J Clin Dermatol</source>. <year>2008</year>;<volume>9</volume>(<issue>5</issue>):<fpage>279</fpage>&#8211;<lpage>284</lpage>. doi: <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.2165/00128071-200809050-00001</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">18717602</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="sjae150-B3"><label>3</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><string-name name-style="western"><surname>Dreno</surname><given-names>B</given-names></string-name>, <string-name name-style="western"><surname>Daniel</surname><given-names>F</given-names></string-name>, <string-name name-style="western"><surname>Allaert</surname><given-names>FA</given-names></string-name>, <string-name name-style="western"><surname>Aube</surname><given-names>I</given-names></string-name></person-group>. <article-title>Acne: evolution of the clinical practice and therapeutic management of acne between 1996 and 2000</article-title>. <source>Eur J Dermatol</source>. <year>2003</year>;<volume>13</volume>:<fpage>166</fpage>&#8211;<lpage>170</lpage>.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">12695133</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="sjae150-B4"><label>4</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><string-name name-style="western"><surname>Bhate</surname><given-names>K</given-names></string-name>, <string-name name-style="western"><surname>Williams</surname><given-names>HC</given-names></string-name></person-group>. <article-title>Epidemiology of acne vulgaris</article-title>. <source>Br J Dermatol</source>. <year>2013</year>;<volume>168</volume>(<issue>3</issue>):<fpage>474</fpage>&#8211;<lpage>485</lpage>. doi: <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1111/bjd.12149</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">23210645</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="sjae150-B5"><label>5</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><string-name name-style="western"><surname>Leyden</surname><given-names>JJ</given-names></string-name></person-group>. <article-title>New understandings of the pathogenesis of acne</article-title>. <source>J Am Acad Dermatol</source>. <year>1995</year>;<volume>32</volume>(<issue>5 Pt 3</issue>):<fpage>S15</fpage>&#8211;<lpage>S25</lpage>. doi: <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1016/0190-9622(95)90416-6</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">7738222</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="sjae150-B6"><label>6</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><string-name name-style="western"><surname>Gollnick</surname><given-names>HP</given-names></string-name></person-group>. <article-title>From new findings in acne pathogenesis to new approaches in treatment</article-title>. <source>J Eur Acad Dermatol Venereol</source>. <year>2015</year>;<volume>29</volume>(<issue>Suppl 5</issue>):<fpage>1</fpage>&#8211;<lpage>7</lpage>. doi: <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1111/jdv.13186</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">26059819</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="sjae150-B7"><label>7</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><string-name name-style="western"><surname>Dreno</surname><given-names>B</given-names></string-name>, <string-name name-style="western"><surname>Pecastaings</surname><given-names>S</given-names></string-name>, <string-name name-style="western"><surname>Corvec</surname><given-names>S</given-names></string-name>, <string-name name-style="western"><surname>Veraldi</surname><given-names>S</given-names></string-name>, <string-name name-style="western"><surname>Khammari</surname><given-names>A</given-names></string-name>, <string-name name-style="western"><surname>Roques</surname><given-names>C</given-names></string-name></person-group>. <article-title>Cutibacterium acnes (Propionibacterium acnes) and acne vulgaris: a brief look at the latest updates</article-title>. <source>J Eur Acad Dermatology Venereol</source>. <year>2018</year>;<volume>32</volume>(<issue>S2</issue>):<fpage>5</fpage>&#8211;<lpage>14</lpage>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1111/jdv.15043</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">29894579</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="sjae150-B8"><label>8</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><string-name name-style="western"><surname>Melnik</surname><given-names>BC</given-names></string-name>, <string-name name-style="western"><surname>John</surname><given-names>SM</given-names></string-name>, <string-name name-style="western"><surname>Chen</surname><given-names>W</given-names></string-name>, <string-name name-style="western"><surname>Plewig</surname><given-names>G</given-names></string-name></person-group>. <article-title>T helper 17 cell/regulatory T-cell imbalance in hidradenitis suppurativa/acne inversa: the link to hair follicle dissection, obesity, smoking and autoimmune comorbidities</article-title>. <source>British Journal of Dermatology</source>. <year>2018</year>;<volume>179</volume>(<issue>2</issue>):<fpage>260</fpage>&#8211;<lpage>272</lpage>. doi: <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1111/bjd.16561</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">29573406</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="sjae150-B9"><label>9</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><string-name name-style="western"><surname>Tasoula</surname><given-names>E</given-names></string-name></person-group>. <article-title>The impact of acne vulgaris on quality of life and psychic health in young adolescents in Greece. Results of a population survey</article-title>. <source>An Bras Dermatol</source>. <year>2012</year>;<volume>87</volume>(<issue>6</issue>):<fpage>862</fpage>&#8211;<lpage>869</lpage>. doi: <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1590/S0365-05962012000600007</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">23197205</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC3699905</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="sjae150-B10"><label>10</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><string-name name-style="western"><surname>Fried</surname><given-names>RG</given-names></string-name>, <string-name name-style="western"><surname>Wechsler</surname><given-names>A</given-names></string-name></person-group>. <article-title>Psychological problems in the acne patient</article-title>. <source>Dermatol Ther</source>. <year>2006</year>;<volume>19</volume>(<issue>4</issue>):<fpage>237</fpage>&#8211;<lpage>240</lpage>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1111/j.1529-8019.2006.00079.x</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">17004999</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="sjae150-B11"><label>11</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><string-name name-style="western"><surname>Lynde</surname><given-names>C</given-names></string-name>, <string-name name-style="western"><surname>Tan</surname><given-names>J</given-names></string-name>, <string-name name-style="western"><surname>Andriessen</surname><given-names>A</given-names></string-name>, <etal>et al</etal></person-group><article-title>A consensus on acne management focused on specific patient features</article-title>. <source>J Cutan Med Surg</source>. <year>2014</year>;<volume>18</volume>(<issue>4</issue>):<fpage>243</fpage>&#8211;<lpage>255</lpage>. doi: <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.2310/7750.2013.13154</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">25008441</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="sjae150-B12"><label>12</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><string-name name-style="western"><surname>Thiboutot</surname><given-names>D</given-names></string-name>, <string-name name-style="western"><surname>Gollnick</surname><given-names>H</given-names></string-name>, <string-name name-style="western"><surname>Bettoli</surname><given-names>V</given-names></string-name>, <etal>et al</etal></person-group><article-title>New insights into the management of acne: an update from the global alliance to improve outcomes in acne group</article-title>. <source>J Am Acad Dermatol</source>. <year>2009</year>;<volume>60</volume>(<issue>5 Suppl</issue>):<fpage>S1</fpage>&#8211;<lpage>S50</lpage>. doi: <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1016/j.jaad.2009.01.019</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">19376456</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="sjae150-B13"><label>13</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><string-name name-style="western"><surname>Mialon</surname><given-names>HM</given-names></string-name>, <string-name name-style="western"><surname>Nesson</surname><given-names>ET</given-names></string-name></person-group>. <article-title>Do pimples pay? Acne, human capital, and the labor market</article-title>. <source>J Hum Cap</source>. <year>2019</year>;<volume>13</volume>(<issue>1</issue>):<fpage>39</fpage>&#8211;<lpage>55</lpage>. doi: <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1086/701436</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="sjae150-B14"><label>14</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><string-name name-style="western"><surname>Sobanko</surname><given-names>JF</given-names></string-name>, <string-name name-style="western"><surname>Alster</surname><given-names>TS</given-names></string-name></person-group>. <article-title>Management of acne scarring, part I: a comparative review of laser surgical approaches</article-title>. <source>Am J Clin Dermatol</source>. <year>2012</year>;<volume>13</volume>(<issue>5</issue>):<fpage>319</fpage>&#8211;<lpage>330</lpage>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.2165/11598910-000000000-00000</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">22612738</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="sjae150-B15"><label>15</label><mixed-citation publication-type="book"><person-group person-group-type="author"><string-name name-style="western"><surname>Sakamoto</surname><given-names>FHAM</given-names></string-name>, <string-name name-style="western"><surname>Anderson</surname><given-names>RR.</given-names></string-name></person-group><part-title>Lasers and other energy technologies principles and skin interactions</part-title>. In: <person-group person-group-type="editor"><string-name name-style="western"><surname>Bolognia</surname><given-names>JL</given-names></string-name>, <string-name name-style="western"><surname>Jorizzo</surname><given-names>JL</given-names></string-name>, <string-name name-style="western"><surname>Schaffer</surname><given-names>JV</given-names></string-name></person-group>, eds. <source>Dermatology</source>, <edition>3rd ed</edition>. <publisher-name>Mosby Elsevier</publisher-name>; <year>2012</year>:<fpage>2251</fpage>&#8211;<lpage>2253.</lpage></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="sjae150-B16"><label>16</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><string-name name-style="western"><surname>El-Domyati</surname><given-names>M</given-names></string-name>, <string-name name-style="western"><surname>Barakat</surname><given-names>M</given-names></string-name>, <string-name name-style="western"><surname>Awad</surname><given-names>S</given-names></string-name>, <string-name name-style="western"><surname>Medhat</surname><given-names>W</given-names></string-name>, <string-name name-style="western"><surname>El-Fakahany</surname><given-names>H</given-names></string-name>, <string-name name-style="western"><surname>Farag</surname><given-names>H</given-names></string-name></person-group>. <article-title>Microneedling therapy for atrophic acne scars: an objective evaluation</article-title>. <source>J Clin Aesthet Dermatol</source>. <year>2015</year>;<volume>8</volume>(<issue>7</issue>):<fpage>36</fpage>&#8211;<lpage>42</lpage>.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC4509584</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">26203319</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="sjae150-B17"><label>17</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><string-name name-style="western"><surname>Dayan</surname><given-names>E</given-names></string-name>, <string-name name-style="western"><surname>Chia</surname><given-names>C</given-names></string-name>, <string-name name-style="western"><surname>Burns</surname><given-names>AJ</given-names></string-name>, <string-name name-style="western"><surname>Theodorou</surname><given-names>S</given-names></string-name></person-group>. <article-title>Adjustable depth fractional radiofrequency combined with bipolar radiofrequency: a minimally invasive combination treatment for skin laxity</article-title>. <source>Aesthet Surg J</source>. <year>2019</year>;<volume>39</volume>(<issue>Suppl_3</issue>):<fpage>S112</fpage>&#8211;<lpage>S119</lpage>. doi: <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1093/asj/sjz055</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">30958550</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC6460431</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="sjae150-B18"><label>18</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><string-name name-style="western"><surname>Theodorou</surname><given-names>SJ</given-names></string-name>, <string-name name-style="western"><surname>Del Vecchio</surname><given-names>D</given-names></string-name>, <string-name name-style="western"><surname>Chia</surname><given-names>CT</given-names></string-name></person-group>. <article-title>Soft tissue contraction in body contouring with radiofrequency-assisted liposuction: a treatment gap solution</article-title>. <source>Aesthet Surg J</source>. <year>2018</year>;<volume>38</volume>(<issue>suppl_2</issue>):<fpage>S74</fpage>&#8211;<lpage>S83</lpage>. doi: <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1093/asj/sjy037</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">29767716</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="sjae150-B19"><label>19</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><string-name name-style="western"><surname>Mulholland</surname><given-names>RS</given-names></string-name></person-group>. <article-title>Non- excisional, minimally invasive rejuvenation of the neck</article-title>. <source>Clin Plast Surg</source>. <year>2014</year>;<volume>41</volume>(<issue>1</issue>):<fpage>11</fpage>&#8211;<lpage>31</lpage>. doi: <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1016/j.cps.2013.09.002</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">24295345</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="sjae150-B20"><label>20</label><mixed-citation publication-type="book"><person-group person-group-type="author"><string-name name-style="western"><surname>Mulholland</surname><given-names>RS</given-names></string-name></person-group>. <part-title>Internal and external radiofrequency assisted lipo-coagulation (RFAL) in the control of soft tissue contraction during liposuction: part 1 &#8220;inside out&#8221;. thermal tissue tightening</part-title>. In: <source>Enhanced Liposuction-New Perspectives and Techniques</source>. <publisher-name>IntechOpen</publisher-name>; <year>2021</year>. doi: <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.5772/intechopen.97378</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="sjae150-B21"><label>21</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><string-name name-style="western"><surname>Battle</surname><given-names>EF</given-names></string-name>, <string-name name-style="western"><surname>Battle</surname><given-names>S</given-names></string-name></person-group>. <article-title>Clinical evaluation of safety and efficacy of fractional radiofrequency facial treatment of skin type VI patients</article-title>. <source>J Drugs Dermatol</source>. <year>2018</year>;<volume>17</volume>(<issue>11</issue>):<fpage>1169</fpage>&#8211;<lpage>1172</lpage>.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">30481955</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="sjae150-B22"><label>22</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><string-name name-style="western"><surname>McCarty</surname><given-names>M</given-names></string-name></person-group>. <article-title>Evaluation and management of refractory acne vulgaris in adolescent and adult men</article-title>. <source>Dermatol Clin</source>. <year>2016</year>;<volume>34</volume>(<issue>2</issue>):<fpage>203</fpage>&#8211;<lpage>206</lpage>. doi: <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1016/j.det.2015.11.007</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">27015780</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="sjae150-B23"><label>23</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><string-name name-style="western"><surname>Goodman</surname><given-names>GJ</given-names></string-name></person-group>. <article-title>Post acne scarring: a review of its pathophysiology and treatment</article-title>. <source>Dermatol Surg</source>. <year>2000</year>;<volume>26</volume>(<issue>9</issue>):<fpage>857</fpage>&#8211;<lpage>871</lpage>. doi: <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1046/j.1524-4725.2000.99232.x</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">10971560</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="sjae150-B24"><label>24</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><string-name name-style="western"><surname>Lee</surname><given-names>JW</given-names></string-name>, <string-name name-style="western"><surname>Kim</surname><given-names>BJ</given-names></string-name>, <string-name name-style="western"><surname>Kim</surname><given-names>MN</given-names></string-name>, <string-name name-style="western"><surname>Lee</surname><given-names>CK</given-names></string-name></person-group>. <article-title>Treatment of acne scars using subdermal minimal surgery technology</article-title>. <source>Dermatol Surg</source>. <year>2010</year>;<volume>36</volume>(<issue>8</issue>):<fpage>1281</fpage>&#8211;<lpage>1287</lpage>. doi: <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1111/j.1524-4725.2010.01623.x</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">20573176</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="sjae150-B25"><label>25</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><string-name name-style="western"><surname>Ahmed</surname><given-names>R</given-names></string-name>, <string-name name-style="western"><surname>Mohammed</surname><given-names>G</given-names></string-name>, <string-name name-style="western"><surname>Ismail</surname><given-names>N</given-names></string-name>, <string-name name-style="western"><surname>Elakhras</surname><given-names>A</given-names></string-name></person-group>. <article-title>Randomized clinical trial of CO2 LASER pinpoint irradiation technique versus chemical reconstruction of skin scars (CROSS) in treating ice pick acne scars</article-title>. <source>J Cosmet Laser Ther</source>. <year>2014</year>;<volume>16</volume>(<issue>1</issue>):<fpage>8</fpage>&#8211;<lpage>13</lpage>. doi: <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.3109/14764172.2013.854633</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">24131091</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="sjae150-B26"><label>26</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><string-name name-style="western"><surname>Alam</surname><given-names>M</given-names></string-name>, <string-name name-style="western"><surname>Omura</surname><given-names>N</given-names></string-name>, <string-name name-style="western"><surname>Kaminer</surname><given-names>MS</given-names></string-name></person-group>. <article-title>Subcision for acne scarring: technique and outcomes in 40 patients</article-title>. <source>Dermatol Surg</source>. <year>2005</year>;<volume>31</volume>(<issue>3</issue>):<fpage>310</fpage>&#8211;<lpage>317</lpage>. doi: <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1111/j.1524-4725.2005.31080</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">15841633</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="sjae150-B27"><label>27</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><string-name name-style="western"><surname>Balighi</surname><given-names>K</given-names></string-name>, <string-name name-style="western"><surname>Robati</surname><given-names>RM</given-names></string-name>, <string-name name-style="western"><surname>Moslehi</surname><given-names>H</given-names></string-name>, <string-name name-style="western"><surname>Robati</surname><given-names>AM</given-names></string-name></person-group>. <article-title>Subcision in acne scar with and without subdermal implant: a clinical trial</article-title>. <source>J Eur Acad Dermatol Venereol</source>. <year>2008</year>;<volume>22</volume>(<issue>6</issue>):<fpage>707</fpage>&#8211;<lpage>711</lpage>. doi: <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1111/j.1468-3083.2008.02583.x</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">18341538</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="sjae150-B28"><label>28</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><string-name name-style="western"><surname>Vaishnani</surname><given-names>JB</given-names></string-name></person-group>. <article-title>Subcision in rolling acne scars with 24G needle</article-title>. <source>Indian J Dermatol Venereol Leprol</source>. <year>2008</year>;<volume>74</volume>(<issue>6</issue>):<fpage>677</fpage>. doi: <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.4103/0378-6323.45133</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">19172014</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="sjae150-B29"><label>29</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><string-name name-style="western"><surname>Wollina</surname><given-names>U</given-names></string-name>, <string-name name-style="western"><surname>Goldman</surname><given-names>A</given-names></string-name></person-group>. <article-title>Fillers for the improvement in acne scars</article-title>. <source>Clin Cosmet Investig Dermatol</source>. <year>2015</year>;<volume>8</volume>:<fpage>493</fpage>&#8211;<lpage>499</lpage>. doi: <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.2147/CCID.S8647831)</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC4598204</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">26491364</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="sjae150-B30"><label>30</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><string-name name-style="western"><surname>Dayan</surname><given-names>E</given-names></string-name>, <string-name name-style="western"><surname>Rovatti</surname><given-names>P</given-names></string-name>, <string-name name-style="western"><surname>Aston</surname><given-names>S</given-names></string-name>, <string-name name-style="western"><surname>Chia</surname><given-names>CT</given-names></string-name>, <string-name name-style="western"><surname>Rohrich</surname><given-names>R</given-names></string-name>, <string-name name-style="western"><surname>Theodorou</surname><given-names>S</given-names></string-name></person-group>. <article-title>Multimodal radiofrequency application for lower face and neck laxity</article-title>. <source>Plast Reconstr Surg Glob Open</source>. <year>2020</year>;<volume>8</volume>(<issue>8</issue>):<fpage>e2862</fpage>. doi: <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1097/GOX.0000000000002862</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">32983756</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC7489644</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="sjae150-B31"><label>31</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><string-name name-style="western"><surname>Zaghloul</surname><given-names>SS</given-names></string-name>, <string-name name-style="western"><surname>Cunliffe</surname><given-names>WJ</given-names></string-name>, <string-name name-style="western"><surname>Goodfield</surname><given-names>MJD</given-names></string-name></person-group>. <article-title>Objective assessment of compliance with treatments in acne</article-title>. <source>Br J Dermatol</source>. <year>2005</year>;<volume>152</volume>(<issue>5</issue>):<fpage>1015</fpage>&#8211;<lpage>1021</lpage>. doi: <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1111/j.1365-2133.2005.06357.x</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">15888162</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="sjae150-B32"><label>32</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><string-name name-style="western"><surname>Shashank Bhargava</surname><given-names>PR</given-names></string-name>, <string-name name-style="western"><surname>Cunha</surname><given-names>J</given-names></string-name>, <string-name name-style="western"><surname>Lee</surname><given-names>GK</given-names></string-name></person-group>. <article-title>Acne scarring management: systematic review and evaluation of the evidence</article-title>. <source>Am J Clin Dermatol</source>. <year>2018</year>;<volume>19</volume>(<issue>4</issue>):<fpage>459</fpage>&#8211;<lpage>447</lpage>. doi: <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1007/s40257-018-0358-5</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">29744784</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="sjae150-B33"><label>33</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><string-name name-style="western"><surname>Sobanko</surname><given-names>JF</given-names></string-name>, <string-name name-style="western"><surname>Alster</surname><given-names>TS</given-names></string-name></person-group>. <article-title>Management of acne scarring, part I</article-title>. <source>Am J Clin Dermatol</source>. <year>2012</year>;<volume>13</volume>(<issue>5</issue>):<fpage>319</fpage>&#8211;<lpage>330</lpage>. doi: <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.2165/11598910-000000000-0000036</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">22612738</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="sjae150-B34"><label>34</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><string-name name-style="western"><surname>Dreno</surname><given-names>B</given-names></string-name>, <string-name name-style="western"><surname>Khammari</surname><given-names>A</given-names></string-name>, <string-name name-style="western"><surname>Orain</surname><given-names>N</given-names></string-name>, <etal>et al</etal></person-group><article-title>ECCA grading scale: an original validated acne scar grading scale for clinical practice in dermatology</article-title>. <source>Dermatology</source>. <year>2007</year>;<volume>214</volume>(<issue>1</issue>):<fpage>46</fpage>&#8211;<lpage>51</lpage>. doi: <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1159/000096912</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">17191047</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="sjae150-B35"><label>35</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><string-name name-style="western"><surname>Badawi</surname><given-names>A</given-names></string-name>, <string-name name-style="western"><surname>Marwan</surname><given-names>B</given-names></string-name>, <string-name name-style="western"><surname>Tirzan</surname><given-names>S</given-names></string-name></person-group>. <article-title>Fractional radiofrequency with microneedling to treat acne and acne scars</article-title>. <source>Int J Aesthetic and Anti-Ageing Med</source>. <year>2013</year>;<volume>1</volume>:<fpage>7</fpage>.</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="sjae150-B36"><label>36</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><string-name name-style="western"><surname>Salameh</surname><given-names>F</given-names></string-name>, <string-name name-style="western"><surname>Shumaker</surname><given-names>PR</given-names></string-name>, <string-name name-style="western"><surname>Goodman</surname><given-names>GJ</given-names></string-name>, <etal>et al</etal></person-group><article-title>Energy-based devices for the treatment of acne scars: 2022 international consensus recommendations</article-title>. <source>Lasers Surg Med</source>. <year>2022</year>;<volume>54</volume>(<issue>1</issue>):<fpage>10</fpage>&#8211;<lpage>26</lpage>. doi: <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1002/lsm.23484</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">34719045</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="sjae150-B37"><label>37</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><string-name name-style="western"><surname>Kaminaka</surname><given-names>C</given-names></string-name>, <string-name name-style="western"><surname>Uede</surname><given-names>M</given-names></string-name>, <string-name name-style="western"><surname>Matsunaka</surname><given-names>H</given-names></string-name>, <string-name name-style="western"><surname>Furukawa</surname><given-names>F</given-names></string-name>, <string-name name-style="western"><surname>Yamamoto</surname><given-names>Y</given-names></string-name></person-group>. <article-title>Clinical studies of the treatment of facial atrophic acne scars and acne with a bipolar fractional radiofrequency system</article-title>. <source>J Dermatol</source>. <year>2015</year>;<volume>42</volume>(<issue>6</issue>):<fpage>580</fpage>&#8211;<lpage>587</lpage>. doi: <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1111/1346-8138.12864</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">25855397</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="sjae150-B38"><label>38</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><string-name name-style="western"><surname>Ahn</surname><given-names>GR</given-names></string-name>, <string-name name-style="western"><surname>Park</surname><given-names>SJ</given-names></string-name>, <string-name name-style="western"><surname>Lee</surname><given-names>CK</given-names></string-name>, <string-name name-style="western"><surname>Kim</surname><given-names>BJ</given-names></string-name></person-group>. <article-title>A case of successful treatment of Fordyce spots with a single insulated microneedle radiofrequency device</article-title>. <source>Dermatol Ther</source>. <year>2019</year>;<volume>32</volume>(<issue>5</issue>):<fpage>e13026</fpage>. doi: <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1111/dth.13026</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">31323158</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="sjae150-B39"><label>39</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><string-name name-style="western"><surname>Min</surname><given-names>S</given-names></string-name>, <string-name name-style="western"><surname>Park</surname><given-names>SY</given-names></string-name>, <string-name name-style="western"><surname>Yoon</surname><given-names>JY</given-names></string-name>, <string-name name-style="western"><surname>Suh</surname><given-names>DH</given-names></string-name></person-group>. <article-title>Comparison of fractional microneedling radiofrequency and bipolar radiofrequency on acne and acne scar and investigation of mechanism: comparative randomized controlled clinical trial</article-title>. <source>Arch Dermatol Res</source>. <year>2015</year>;<volume>307</volume>(<issue>10</issue>):<fpage>897</fpage>&#8211;<lpage>904</lpage>. doi: <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1007/s00403-015-1601-z</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">26472097</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref></ref-list></back></article></pmc-articleset>