<?xml version="1.0"  ?><!DOCTYPE pmc-articleset PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD ARTICLE SET 2.0//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pmc/articleset/nlm-articleset-2.0.dtd"><pmc-articleset><article xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" xmlns:ali="http://www.niso.org/schemas/ali/1.0/" xml:lang="en" article-type="review-article" dtd-version="1.4"><processing-meta base-tagset="archiving" mathml-version="3.0" table-model="xhtml" tagset-family="jats"><restricted-by>pmc</restricted-by></processing-meta><front><journal-meta><journal-id journal-id-type="nlm-ta">Cureus</journal-id><journal-id journal-id-type="iso-abbrev">Cureus</journal-id><journal-id journal-id-type="pmc-domain-id">2757</journal-id><journal-id journal-id-type="pmc-domain">cureus</journal-id><journal-title-group><journal-title>Cureus</journal-title></journal-title-group><issn pub-type="epub">2168-8184</issn><publisher><publisher-name>Cureus Inc.</publisher-name></publisher></journal-meta><article-meta><article-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC12456936</article-id><article-id pub-id-type="pmcid-ver">PMC12456936.1</article-id><article-id pub-id-type="pmcaid">12456936</article-id><article-id pub-id-type="pmcaiid">12456936</article-id><article-id pub-id-type="pmid">40995236</article-id><article-id pub-id-type="doi">10.7759/cureus.90857</article-id><article-version article-version-type="pmc-version">1</article-version><article-categories><subj-group subj-group-type="heading"><subject>Dermatology</subject></subj-group></article-categories><title-group><article-title>Microneedling for Non-cosmetic Dermatologic Conditions: A Systematic Review of Efficacy and Safety</article-title></title-group><contrib-group><contrib contrib-type="editor"><name name-style="western"><surname>Muacevic</surname><given-names initials="A">Alexander</given-names></name></contrib><contrib contrib-type="editor"><name name-style="western"><surname>Adler</surname><given-names initials="JR">John R</given-names></name></contrib></contrib-group><contrib-group><contrib contrib-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Mashi</surname><given-names initials="A">Amany</given-names></name><xref rid="aff-1" ref-type="aff">1</xref></contrib><contrib contrib-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Oraybi</surname><given-names initials="RA">Rayim A</given-names></name><xref rid="aff-2" ref-type="aff">2</xref></contrib><contrib contrib-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Hakami</surname><given-names initials="MS">Manar S</given-names></name><xref rid="aff-2" ref-type="aff">2</xref></contrib><contrib contrib-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Altalhi</surname><given-names initials="AM">Abdulrahman M</given-names></name><xref rid="aff-3" ref-type="aff">3</xref></contrib><contrib contrib-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Alrezqi</surname><given-names initials="WA">Wafa A</given-names></name><xref rid="aff-4" ref-type="aff">4</xref></contrib><contrib contrib-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Hakami</surname><given-names initials="TK">Taif K</given-names></name><xref rid="aff-2" ref-type="aff">2</xref></contrib><contrib contrib-type="author" corresp="yes"><name name-style="western"><surname>Masmali</surname><given-names initials="AM">Alanoud M</given-names></name><xref rid="aff-2" ref-type="aff">2</xref></contrib><contrib contrib-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Alshahrani</surname><given-names initials="AF">Asma F</given-names></name><xref rid="aff-5" ref-type="aff">5</xref></contrib><contrib contrib-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Alamri</surname><given-names initials="RA">Raghad A</given-names></name><xref rid="aff-6" ref-type="aff">6</xref></contrib><contrib contrib-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Alanazi</surname><given-names initials="AA">Alanoud A</given-names></name><xref rid="aff-7" ref-type="aff">7</xref></contrib></contrib-group><aff id="aff-1">
<label>1</label>
Dermatology, Armed Forces Hospital, Jazan, SAU </aff><aff id="aff-2">
<label>2</label>
College of Medicine, Jazan University, Jazan, SAU </aff><aff id="aff-3">
<label>3</label>
College of Medicine, King Abdulaziz University, Jeddah, SAU </aff><aff id="aff-4">
<label>4</label>
College of Medicine, Al Baha University, Al Baha, SAU </aff><aff id="aff-5">
<label>5</label>
College of Medicine, Bisha University, Bisha, SAU </aff><aff id="aff-6">
<label>6</label>
College of Medicine, King Khalid University, Abha, SAU </aff><aff id="aff-7">
<label>7</label>
College of Medicine, Al-Jouf University, Al-Jouf, SAU </aff><author-notes><corresp id="cor1">
Alanoud M. Masmali <email>alanoudmm@&#8206;moh.&#8206;gov.sa</email></corresp></author-notes><pub-date date-type="pub" publication-format="electronic"><day>24</day><month>8</month><year>2025</year></pub-date><pub-date date-type="collection" publication-format="electronic"><month>8</month><year>2025</year></pub-date><volume>17</volume><issue>8</issue><issue-id pub-id-type="pmc-issue-id">494304</issue-id><elocation-id>e90857</elocation-id><history><date date-type="accepted"><day>24</day><month>8</month><year>2025</year></date></history><pub-history><event event-type="pmc-release"><date><day>24</day><month>08</month><year>2025</year></date></event><event event-type="pmc-live"><date><day>24</day><month>09</month><year>2025</year></date></event><event event-type="pmc-last-change"><date iso-8601-date="2025-09-25 09:25:20.827"><day>25</day><month>09</month><year>2025</year></date></event></pub-history><permissions><copyright-statement>Copyright &#169; 2025, Mashi et al.</copyright-statement><copyright-year>2025</copyright-year><copyright-holder>Mashi et al.</copyright-holder><license><ali:license_ref specific-use="textmining" content-type="ccbylicense">https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</ali:license_ref><license-p>This is an open access article distributed under the terms of the Creative Commons Attribution License CC-BY 4.0., which permits unrestricted use, distribution, and reproduction in any medium, provided the original author and source are credited.</license-p></license></permissions><self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" content-type="pmc-pdf" xlink:href="cureus-0017-00000090857.pdf"/><self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xlink:href="https://cureus.com/articles/406872-microneedling-for-non-cosmetic-dermatologic-conditions-a-systematic-review-of-efficacy-and-safety">This article is available from https://cureus.com/articles/406872-microneedling-for-non-cosmetic-dermatologic-conditions-a-systematic-review-of-efficacy-and-safety</self-uri><abstract><p>Microneedling, a minimally invasive dermatologic procedure, has expanded beyond cosmetic use to treat conditions such as vitiligo, hyperhidrosis, melasma, acne vulgaris, and actinic keratoses. This systematic review, conducted in accordance with PRISMA guidelines, included 15 randomized controlled trials involving approximately 1,200 participants identified through searches of PubMed, Web of Science, Scopus, and Cochrane Central Register of Controlled Trials (CENTRAL)&#160;up to July 2025. Across multiple conditions, microneedling - particularly when combined with adjunct therapies - demonstrated significant clinical benefits. In vitiligo, microneedling with tacrolimus or 5-fluorouracil (5-FU) achieved repigmentation rates of 40-76.6% compared with 16.9-39.9% for monotherapy. In hyperhidrosis, fractional microneedle radiofrequency (FMR) reduced sweat production, although botulinum toxin A yielded longer-lasting results and greater patient satisfaction. For melasma, combinations with tranexamic acid or cysteamine produced notable modified melasma area and severity index (mMASI) score reductions (29-50%), while in acne vulgaris, microneedle radiofrequency (MRF) outperformed photodynamic therapy (PDT), achieving an 81% reduction in inflammatory lesions versus 73%, with fewer adverse events. Microneedling-assisted PDT&#160;also improved actinic keratoses clearance rates by 18% (76% vs&#160;58%). Adverse effects such as transient erythema and mild pain were consistently reported but generally well tolerated. Overall, current evidence supports microneedling as an effective and safe treatment for diverse non-cosmetic dermatologic conditions, particularly when integrated with topical or procedural adjuncts, though standardized protocols and long-term outcome data remain needed.</p></abstract><kwd-group kwd-group-type="author"><kwd>acne vulgaris</kwd><kwd>actinic keratoses</kwd><kwd>adjunct therapy</kwd><kwd>hyperhidrosis</kwd><kwd>melasma</kwd><kwd>microneedling</kwd><kwd>non-cosmetic dermatology</kwd><kwd>randomized controlled trials</kwd><kwd>systematic review</kwd><kwd>vitiligo</kwd></kwd-group><custom-meta-group><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-status-qastatus</meta-name><meta-value>0</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-status-live</meta-name><meta-value>yes</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-status-embargo</meta-name><meta-value>no</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-status-released</meta-name><meta-value>yes</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-open-access</meta-name><meta-value>yes</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-olf</meta-name><meta-value>no</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-manuscript</meta-name><meta-value>no</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-legally-suppressed</meta-name><meta-value>no</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-has-pdf</meta-name><meta-value>yes</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-has-supplement</meta-name><meta-value>no</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-pdf-only</meta-name><meta-value>no</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-suppress-copyright</meta-name><meta-value>no</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-is-real-version</meta-name><meta-value>no</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-is-scanned-article</meta-name><meta-value>no</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-preprint</meta-name><meta-value>no</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-in-epmc</meta-name><meta-value>yes</meta-value></custom-meta></custom-meta-group></article-meta></front><body><sec sec-type="intro"><title>Introduction and background</title><p>Microneedling, also known as collagen induction therapy, has gained traction in dermatology as a minimally invasive procedure that stimulates dermal remodeling through controlled microinjuries [<xref rid="REF1" ref-type="bibr">1</xref>,<xref rid="REF2" ref-type="bibr">2</xref>]. Rooted in the principle of percutaneous collagen induction, it promotes collagen and elastin production, contributing to improved skin texture and scar reduction [<xref rid="REF1" ref-type="bibr">1</xref>,<xref rid="REF2" ref-type="bibr">2</xref>].</p><p>Historically, microneedling has been widely applied for cosmetic purposes such as acne scar reduction, skin rejuvenation, and fine line improvement [<xref rid="REF2" ref-type="bibr">2</xref>,<xref rid="REF3" ref-type="bibr">3</xref>]. More recent literature has expanded its use into clinical dermatology, targeting conditions beyond aesthetics, including vitiligo, hyperhidrosis, melasma, actinic keratoses, and acne vulgaris [<xref rid="REF3" ref-type="bibr">3</xref>,<xref rid="REF4" ref-type="bibr">4</xref>].</p><p>The rationale for these non-cosmetic applications partly lies in their ability to enhance the transdermal penetration of topical agents via micropore channels [<xref rid="REF4" ref-type="bibr">4</xref>,<xref rid="REF5" ref-type="bibr">5</xref>]. Several studies have used microneedling as a drug delivery enhancer in combination with agents such as tacrolimus, pimecrolimus, 5-fluorouracil (5-FU), tranexamic acid, and photosensitizing agents for photodynamic therapy (PDT) [<xref rid="REF4" ref-type="bibr">4</xref>,<xref rid="REF5" ref-type="bibr">5</xref>].</p><p>Evidence from randomized controlled trials indicates that microneedling combined with topical therapies can significantly improve outcomes in conditions such as vitiligo and melasma compared to monotherapy [<xref rid="REF3" ref-type="bibr">3</xref>,<xref rid="REF5" ref-type="bibr">5</xref>]. Meta-analyses have confirmed enhanced efficacy and greater patient satisfaction with combined modalities over microneedling alone [<xref rid="REF3" ref-type="bibr">3</xref>,<xref rid="REF6" ref-type="bibr">6</xref>].</p><p>In the treatment of acne scars, microneedling monotherapy has demonstrated consistent benefits across multiple randomized trials, with significant improvements in objective scar grading and patient-reported satisfaction [<xref rid="REF3" ref-type="bibr">3</xref>,<xref rid="REF6" ref-type="bibr">6</xref>]. Notably, it has a low incidence of adverse effects such as post-inflammatory hyperpigmentation, making it suitable for darker skin types [<xref rid="REF3" ref-type="bibr">3</xref>,<xref rid="REF6" ref-type="bibr">6</xref>].</p><p>An emerging area of research involves microneedling with radiofrequency (RF) for conditions such as active acne and primary axillary hyperhidrosis. Fractional microneedle radiofrequency (FMR) has been shown to reduce inflammatory acne lesions more effectively than PDT, with fewer side effects such as post-inflammatory hyperpigmentation [<xref rid="REF4" ref-type="bibr">4</xref>,<xref rid="REF7" ref-type="bibr">7</xref>].</p><p>In hyperhidrosis, FMR&#160;has demonstrated the ability to thermally ablate sweat glands, with histologic evidence of glandular atrophy and reduced sweat output [<xref rid="REF4" ref-type="bibr">4</xref>,<xref rid="REF8" ref-type="bibr">8</xref>]. However, comparative trials suggest that botulinum toxin A may yield superior efficacy and patient satisfaction, particularly in long-term follow-up [<xref rid="REF8" ref-type="bibr">8</xref>,<xref rid="REF9" ref-type="bibr">9</xref>].</p></sec><sec sec-type="review"><title>Review</title><p>Methods</p><p>Search Strategy</p><p>This systematic review was conducted and reported in accordance with the Preferred Reporting Items for Systematic Reviews and Meta-Analyses (PRISMA) guidelines [<xref rid="REF10" ref-type="bibr">10</xref>]. A comprehensive search of PubMed, Web of Science, Scopus, and the Cochrane Central Register of Controlled Trials (CENTRAL) was performed from database inception through July 28, 2025. The search strategy combined free-text terms and controlled vocabulary, including &#8220;microneedling&#8221;, &#8220;collagen induction therapy&#8221;, &#8220;fractional microneedle radiofrequency&#8221;, along with targeted dermatologic conditions such as &#8220;vitiligo&#8221;, &#8220;melasma&#8221;, &#8220;acne&#8221;, &#8220;actinic keratosis&#8221;, &#8220;hyperhidrosis&#8221;, and &#8220;photoaging&#8221;. Boolean operators were applied to tailor the search for each database. Only English-language studies involving human participants were considered. Reference lists of included articles were also manually screened to identify additional eligible studies not captured in the initial search (Figure <xref rid="FIG1" ref-type="fig">1</xref>).</p><fig position="anchor" fig-type="figure" id="FIG1" orientation="portrait"><label>Figure 1</label><caption><title>PRISMA flow diagram illustrating the study selection process</title><p>PRISMA =&#160;Preferred Reporting Items for Systematic Reviews and Meta-Analyses</p></caption><graphic xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" position="float" orientation="portrait" xlink:href="cureus-0017-00000090857-i01.jpg"/></fig><p>Eligibility Criteria</p><p>Eligibility criteria were defined according to the Population, Intervention, Comparison, Outcome, Study Design (PICOS) framework. We included English-language randomized clinical trials that: (i) enrolled patients with non-cosmetic dermatologic conditions such as vitiligo, acne, melasma, hyperhidrosis, actinic keratosis, or atrophic acne scars; (ii) used microneedling (with or without RF), either alone or in combination with topical or systemic therapies; (iii) included a comparator such as placebo, sham treatment, or other conventional therapies (e.g., botulinum toxin, laser, PDT); and (iv) reported clinical, patient-reported, or histological outcomes. We excluded observational studies, non-English publications, non-randomized trials, and studies available only as abstracts without accessible full-text articles.</p><p>Study Selection</p><p>Two reviewers independently screened the titles and abstracts of all retrieved articles against the eligibility criteria. Full texts of potentially relevant studies were then assessed to confirm inclusion. Discrepancies between reviewers were resolved through discussion with a third reviewer until consensus was reached.</p><p>Data Extraction</p><p>Data extraction was independently performed by two reviewers using a standardized, pre-defined form. Extracted items included study characteristics (author, year, country, design), participant demographics, target condition, intervention protocol (device type, needle depth, treatment frequency), adjunct therapy details (if applicable), comparators, outcome measures, key findings, adverse events, and author conclusions. Only data explicitly reported in the full text were included in the synthesis. Discrepancies were resolved through discussion or consultation with a third reviewer.</p><p>Quality Appraisal</p><p>The methodological quality of the included trials was independently assessed by two reviewers using the modified Downs and Black checklist for clinical trials [<xref rid="REF11" ref-type="bibr">11</xref>], applied without further modifications. This 27-item tool evaluates four domains: reporting, external validity, internal validity, and power. Final scores classify studies as excellent (26-28), good (20-25), fair (15-19), or poor (&#8804;14). Any disagreements were resolved through discussion until a consensus was reached.</p><p>Results</p><p>Study Selection</p><p>A total of 5,952 records were identified from PubMed (n = 418), Cochrane CENTRAL (n = 347), Scopus (n = 2,093), and Web of Science (n = 3,094). No additional records were retrieved through manual searches. After removing duplicates, 4,496 unique records remained; 4,439 were excluded after title/abstract screening. Full-text review was performed on 57 articles, excluding 41 (14 cosmetic microneedling, 19 non-clinical, nine abstracts). Fifteen studies [<xref rid="REF7" ref-type="bibr">7</xref>,<xref rid="REF9" ref-type="bibr">9</xref>,<xref rid="REF12" ref-type="bibr">12</xref>-<xref rid="REF24" ref-type="bibr">24</xref>] met all criteria and were included in the qualitative synthesis. No meta-analysis was performed due to unsuitable data.&#160;</p><p>Study Characteristics</p><p>The 15 included studies, all randomized or controlled clinical trials, assessed microneedling&#160;for diverse dermatologic conditions. Most used split-face or split-body designs [<xref rid="REF9" ref-type="bibr">9</xref>,<xref rid="REF15" ref-type="bibr">15</xref>,<xref rid="REF17" ref-type="bibr">17</xref>,<xref rid="REF23" ref-type="bibr">23</xref>], while others used parallel-arm structures [<xref rid="REF16" ref-type="bibr">16</xref>,<xref rid="REF19" ref-type="bibr">19</xref>,<xref rid="REF22" ref-type="bibr">22</xref>]. Participants ranged from 10 to 65+ years, mostly female (60-90%), with Fitzpatrick skin types III-IV predominating. Conditions included vitiligo, hyperhidrosis, acne (scarring and active lesions), melasma, photoaging, dry eye disease, and actinic keratoses (Table <xref rid="TAB1" ref-type="table">1</xref>).</p><table-wrap position="float" id="TAB1" orientation="portrait"><label>Table 1</label><caption><title>Characteristics of included studies</title><p>RCT = randomized controlled trial; FMR = fractional microneedle radiofrequency; Mn = microneedling; PDT = photodynamic therapy; ALA = aminolevulinic acid; TEWL = transepidermal water loss; VAS = visual analog scale; HDSS = hyperhidrosis disease severity scale; DLQI = dermatology life quality index; PAH = primary axillary hyperhidrosis; PRP = platelet-rich plasma; VASI = vitiligo area severity index; PGA = physician global assessment; BT-A = botulinum toxin A; IGA = investigator&#8217;s global assessment; MRF = microneedle radiofrequency; mMASI = modified melasma area and severity index; QoL = quality of life; OSDI = ocular surface disease index; SIT = Schirmer I test; BMA = biodegradable microneedle acupuncture; IDA = intradermal acupuncture; PIH = post-inflammatory hyperpigmentation; TA = tranexamic acid; GAIS = global aesthetic improvement scale; HMB-45 = human melanoma black 45 immunostaining marker; BL2, GB14, TE23, EX-HN5, ST1 = acupuncture points; 5-FU = 5-fluorouracil; DED = dry eye disease; AK = actinic keratoses; Er:YAG = erbium:yttrium-aluminum-garnet; RFM =&#160;radiofrequency microneedling; BID = twice daily dosage; Hqol = hyperhidrosis quality of life questionnaire; MASI = melasma area and severity index; MelasQol = melasma quality of life; MSIT =&#160;Minor&#8217;s starch iodine test</p></caption><table frame="hsides" rules="groups"><tbody><tr style="background-color:#ccc"><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Study ID</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Study Design</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Population Details</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Condition Treated</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Microneedling Protocol</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Adjunct Therapy (if any)</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Comparator / Control</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Outcome Measures</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Key Results</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Adverse Events</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Authors' Conclusion</td></tr><tr><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Huang et al., 2024 (China) [<xref rid="REF7" ref-type="bibr">7</xref>]</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">RCT, prospective, assessor-blinded, 2-arm</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">80 patients with moderate-to-severe acne (IGA score 3&#8211;4); Fitzpatrick III&#8211;IV</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Moderate-to-severe acne vulgaris</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Single MRF using Unicorn I; 3.5 mm needle, 1&#8211;2 pulses/lesion (6&#8211;8 W), 3 sessions, 2-week intervals</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">None</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">PDT with 5% ALA and red light</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">IGA score improvement, lesion count (inflammatory and non-inflammatory), satisfaction, VAS pain, adverse events</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">MRF superior for inflammatory lesions (81% vs 73% reduction); faster response, higher satisfaction; IGA success rates higher in MRF at session 3; non-inflammatory lesions improved similarly in both</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">MRF had less PIH (10% vs 42%), pain, and acneiform eruptions; all PIH resolved within 3&#8211;6 months</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">MRF is a safe and effective alternative to PDT for acne, with faster efficacy, fewer side effects, and better patient satisfaction [<xref rid="REF7" ref-type="bibr">7</xref>]</td></tr><tr style="background-color:#ccc"><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Fatemi Naeini et al., 2015 (Iran) [<xref rid="REF8" ref-type="bibr">8</xref>]</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Sham-controlled, single-blind, intraindividual comparative study</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">25 patients (32% male, 68% female), mean age 30.2 &#177; 6.3; Fitzpatrick III&#8211;IV; baseline HDSS 3&#8211;4</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Primary axillary hyperhidrosis</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">3 sessions of FMR (INFINI&#8482;); 3-week intervals; depth 2&#8211;3 mm; energy 6&#8211;10; 3 passes/session</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">None</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Contralateral sham control (standby device)</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">HDSS, VAS sweating intensity, patient satisfaction, histopathology</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">HDSS and VAS scores significantly improved on treated side (HDSS: 1.87 vs 3.38; VAS: 3.92 vs 8.44); 88% had &#8805;1 score reduction in HDSS; 80% had &#8805;50% satisfaction</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Transient erythema (68%), bleeding (56%), PIH (44%), 1 dropout from transient dysesthesia</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">FMR is effective and safe for treating PAH; histology showed sweat gland atrophy; minimal side effects [<xref rid="REF8" ref-type="bibr">8</xref>]</td></tr><tr><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Rummaneethorn and Chalermchai, 2020 (Thailand) [<xref rid="REF9" ref-type="bibr">9</xref>]</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">RCT, assessor-blinded, intra-individual split-side</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">20 female participants; mean age 36.8 &#177; 9.8 years; diagnosed with primary axillary hyperhidrosis</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Primary axillary hyperhidrosis</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Fractional microneedle RF (DeAge EX&#174;); 2 sessions, 4 weeks apart; 4 passes/session (depth 3.5 mm and 3.0 mm)</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">None</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Contralateral axilla treated with 50 units BT-A</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">HDSS, TEWL, DLQI, satisfaction, pain VAS</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Both treatments reduced HDSS; BT-A superior at 12 weeks (HDSS: 1.60 vs 2.05, p = 0.0332); better DLQI (p = 0.013) and satisfaction (p = 0.004)</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Mild erythema (10%), desquamation (5%), burning (5%) with RF; dryness (5%) with botulinum</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">BT-A more effective than FMR; FMR still improved outcomes and was well tolerated [<xref rid="REF9" ref-type="bibr">9</xref>]</td></tr><tr style="background-color:#ccc"><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Chhabra et al., 2021 (India) [<xref rid="REF13" ref-type="bibr">13</xref>]</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">RCT, prospective, hospital-based, single-blind</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">46 patients (23 per group); age 10&#8211;50; 143 vitiligo patches; patch stability &#8805;1 year</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Localized stable vitiligo</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">1.5 mm Dermapen every 15 days for 4 months (up to 8 sessions)</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">5-FU 50 mg/mL solution applied post-Mn (Group A)</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Mn alone (Group B)</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Grading of repigmentation (G0&#8211;G4), adverse events</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Group A: 48.6% patches showed &gt;75% repigmentation vs 16.9% in Group B (p = 0.0001); response started by 4 weeks in 61.1% (vs 40.8%); better results in trunk and limbs</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Common in both: pain (~80%), erythema (~70%), hyperpigmentation (48% vs 26%), ulceration (17% vs 9%)</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Mn with 5-FU is safe, simple, and more effective than Mn alone in treating localized vitiligo [<xref rid="REF13" ref-type="bibr">13</xref>]</td></tr><tr><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Song and Park, 2024 (South Korea) [<xref rid="REF14" ref-type="bibr">14</xref>]</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Assessor-blinded, single-center, parallel RCT</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">30 patients (15 per group), mean age ~34.3 years, ~57% female</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">DED</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">BMA to 5 bilateral facial acupoints (BL2, GB14, TE23, EX-HN5, ST1); 12 sessions over 4 weeks</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">None</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">IDA using traditional thumbtack needles</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">OSDI, VAS, QoL, Schirmer I test (tear production)</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Both BMA and IDA significantly improved OSDI, VAS, QoL, and SIT (p &lt; 0.05); no significant difference between groups except higher tear secretion in BMA for left eye (p = 0.025)</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">No adverse events reported in either group</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">BMA is as effective and safe as IDA for treating DED; may be preferred for patients allergic to metal needles [<xref rid="REF14" ref-type="bibr">14</xref>]</td></tr><tr style="background-color:#ccc"><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Petukhova et al., 2017 (USA) [<xref rid="REF15" ref-type="bibr">15</xref>]</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">RCT, single-blind, split-face, 2-arm</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">33 participants (32 completed); mean age ~63&#8211;65; all had &#8805;3 grade II AK on the face</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">AK</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Microneedle roller (200 &#956;m); 8 passes/side; 10-min or 20-min ALA incubation</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">ALA + blue light PDT</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Sham roller on opposite face side</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">AK clearance %, TEWL, pain VAS</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">20-min group: 76% vs 58% clearance (p &lt; 0.01); 10-min group: no significant difference; pain low in both groups</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">One dropout due to excessive erythema and pain from sun exposure; no moderate/severe pain reported in other participants</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">20-min ALA incubation with Mn significantly improves AK clearance with minimal pain; similar to 1-hr conventional PDT [<xref rid="REF15" ref-type="bibr">15</xref>]</td></tr><tr><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Abdel-Hamid et al., 2024 (Egypt) [<xref rid="REF16" ref-type="bibr">16</xref>]</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">RCT, 2-arm, parallel, open-label</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">40 patients with localized stable vitiligo (20 per group); age 10&#8211;60; matched for sex, Fitzpatrick type III&#8211;V</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Vitiligo</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Mn using Dermapen (0.25&#8211;0.5 mm); every 2 weeks &#215; 6 months</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">PRP</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Comparator: fractional Er:YAG + PRP group</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">VASI, PGA, repigmentation grade, satisfaction, adverse events</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Mn+PRP group: 80% showed repigmentation (20% very good, 10% good, 50% satisfactory); VASI decreased significantly (p = 0.003); 25% reported adverse events</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Pain (25%), no serious adverse events; more frequent side effects in Mn group vs Er:YAG group (p = 0.048)</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Both Mn+PRP and Er:YAG + PRP induced repigmentation, but Er:YAG + PRP was more effective with fewer side effects and higher satisfaction [<xref rid="REF16" ref-type="bibr">16</xref>]</td></tr><tr style="background-color:#ccc"><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Tsai et al., 2025 (Taiwan) [<xref rid="REF17" ref-type="bibr">17</xref>]</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">RCT, split-face, vehicle-controlled</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">30 female participants; mean age 50.3 &#177; 8.0; Fitzpatrick types III&#8211;IV</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Refractory melasma</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">4 sessions of RFM (Sylfirm&#174;) at 1-month intervals; 1.5 mm depth, 2 passes, 25 non-insulated needles</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Cysteamine serum (in-office) + home-based cysteamine cream (Group A); placebo or partial protocols in Groups B&#8211;D</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">RFM + placebo serum + vehicle cream (Group D)</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">mMASI, VISIA imaging (wrinkles, texture, UV spots), patient-reported improvement</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Group A had the greatest reduction in mMASI (3.39 &#8594; 1.79; p = 0.003) and best VISIA improvements (wrinkles, texture, UV spots); Group D had least improvement</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Mostly mild (erythema 26.7%, pain 13.3%, allergic 6.7%); no severe adverse events</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">RFM combined with in-office and home-based cysteamine is safe and significantly more effective than either alone; promotes melanin reduction and dermal rejuvenation [<xref rid="REF17" ref-type="bibr">17</xref>]</td></tr><tr><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Kim et al., 2025 (South Korea) [<xref rid="REF18" ref-type="bibr">18</xref>]</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">RCT, prospective, double-blinded, split-neck, placebo-controlled</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">31 subjects (90% female); mean age 49.5 &#177; 10.4; Fitzpatrick skin types III&#8211;IV</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Neck skin aging (wrinkles, laxity, elastosis)</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">2 FMR sessions (GENIUS), 1.5&#8211;1.8 mm depth, 20&#8211;30 mJ/pin); 4-week interval</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Daily topical antioxidant serum (vitamin C, E, ferulic acid; SkinCeuticals&#174;)</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Placebo (same base formula without antioxidants)</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Fitzpatrick Wrinkle and Elastosis Scale, GAIS, elasticity %, histology (elastin, p16, &#947;-H2A.X)</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Antioxidant side showed superior outcomes: wrinkles &#8595;29.9% vs &#8595;18.0%, elasticity &#8593;12.9% vs &#8593;2.3%, GAIS (87.5% vs 14.3%); histology: &#8593;elastin, &#8595;p16, &#8595;&#947;-H2A.X</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">2 allergic contact dermatitis cases (nickel/cobalt); mild erythema/stinging otherwise</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Combining FMR with antioxidants enhances skin rejuvenation clinically and histologically vs FMR alone [<xref rid="REF18" ref-type="bibr">18</xref>]</td></tr><tr style="background-color:#ccc"><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Ebrahim and Albalate, 2020 (Egypt) [<xref rid="REF19" ref-type="bibr">19</xref>]</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">RCT, 3-arm, randomized controlled</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">90 patients with localized stable vitiligo (30 per group); age 12&#8211;60; ~53% female</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Vitiligo</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Dermapen (1.5&#8211;2 mm); every 2 weeks for up to 12 sessions; occluded topical tacrolimus applied post-procedure for 6 hours</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Tacrolimus (0.1% ointment</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Group II: Mn alone; Group III: tacrolimus alone (BID x 6 months)</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Repigmentation grade (G0&#8211;G4), HMB-45 immunostaining, session count, adverse events</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Group I (Mn + tacromilus): 76.6% excellent/very good response vs 36.6% (Mn) and 39.9% (Tacromilus); fewer sessions (5 vs 11); highest HMB-45 expression in Group I</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Mild pain, erythema, and itching; all transient and tolerable</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Mn + tacrolimus superior to either alone in achieving faster, better repigmentation, particularly on extremities [<xref rid="REF19" ref-type="bibr">19</xref>]</td></tr><tr><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Sadeghzadeh-Bazargan et al., 2024 (Iran) [<xref rid="REF20" ref-type="bibr">20</xref>]&#160;</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Blinded, split-face RCT</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">25 patients (80% female), mean age 35.96 &#177; 9.23</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Atrophic acne scars</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">3 sessions of Mn (1&#8211;1.5 mm depth) at monthly intervals</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Topical phenytoin 1% cream (3&#215;/day for 1 week post-Mn on one side)</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Mn alone on contralateral face</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Pore and spot count/area (Visioface), Goodman and Baron scar grading, patient satisfaction</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Both groups improved over time, but the phenytoin side showed greater reduction in acne scar grade and higher satisfaction (80% excellent vs 0%); differences in pore/spot metrics were not statistically significant</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">None reported</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Combining Mn with phenytoin yields superior improvement in scar severity and satisfaction compared to Mn alone [<xref rid="REF20" ref-type="bibr">20</xref>]</td></tr><tr style="background-color:#ccc"><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Kim et al., 2013 (South Korea) [<xref rid="REF21" ref-type="bibr">21</xref>]</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Pilot prospective study (single-arm)</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">20 patients (17 females, 3 males); mean age 30.5 (range 19&#8211;46); Fitzpatrick type IV</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">PAH</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">2 sessions of FMR (Infini&#8482;) at 4-week intervals; 6 passes/session (depths: 3.5 mm, 3.0 mm, 2.5 mm); bipolar RF energy</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">None</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">No control group</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">HDSS, starch-iodine test, TEWL, patient satisfaction, histopathology</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">HDSS decreased from 3.5 to 1.5 (post 1st) and 1.8 (post 2nd); 75% achieved HDSS 1&#8211;2; 70% reported &gt;50% sweat reduction; histology: glandular atrophy</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Mild transient swelling, redness, tingling; 2 cases compensatory hyperhidrosis; 1 case transient numbness</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">FMR is effective and well tolerated for PAH with clinical and histological evidence of sweat gland reduction [<xref rid="REF21" ref-type="bibr">21</xref>]</td></tr><tr><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Eid et al., 2024 (Egypt) [<xref rid="REF22" ref-type="bibr">22</xref>]</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">RCT, split-body, 12-month follow-up</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">20 patients (85% female), age 18&#8211;48; PAH grade 3&#8211;4</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Primary axillary hyperhidrosis</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Fractional microneedle RF (Vivace&#174;), 3.5 mm non-insulated needles; 4 sessions, 3-week intervals; 1 pass/session</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">None</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">BT-A (50 IU intradermal injection)</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Minor&#8217;s test, HDSS, Hqol, patient satisfaction, VAS pain</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">BT-A showed superior efficacy at 3, 6, 12 months for all outcomes (HDSS, MSIT, QoL, satisfaction); FMR declined after 3 months; BT-A had longer-lasting effects</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">FMR: more pain (VAS 6.48 vs 4.0), one case itching; BT-A: 2 cases compensatory hyperhidrosis; no serious adverse events</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">FMR not superior to BT-A; BT-A more effective, less painful, more durable and economical; both were safe [<xref rid="REF22" ref-type="bibr">22</xref>]</td></tr><tr style="background-color:#ccc"><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Iraji et al., 2021 (Iran) [<xref rid="REF23" ref-type="bibr">23</xref>]</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">RCT, split-lesion, intraindividual</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">15 patients, 30 lesions (each treated side-by-side); age 18&#8211;56; 53% male</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Refractory stable vitiligo (limbs)</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Mn (Med Amiea revive pen); every 2 weeks for 3 months; depth 0.5 mm adjusted to pinpoint bleeding</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Topical pimecrolimus 1% cream (applied immediately post-Mn under occlusion, BID for 3 months)</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Contralateral lesion treated with pimecrolimus 1% alone</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Repigmentation (0&#8211;100%), DLQI, patient satisfaction</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Combination group: significant improvement over time (up to 33% good, 6.7% excellent response at 6 months); monotherapy: no significant change</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">One case of burning with pimecrolimus; no adverse events with Mn</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Mn enhances topical pimecrolimus efficacy for stable vitiligo, especially in resistant limb lesions [<xref rid="REF23" ref-type="bibr">23</xref>]</td></tr><tr><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Kuster Kaminski Arida et al., 2021 (Brazil) [<xref rid="REF24" ref-type="bibr">24</xref>]</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">RCT, double-blind, split-face, placebo-controlled</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">20 women; mean age 42.3 &#177; 7 years; Fitzpatrick II&#8211;V; 60% family history of melasma</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Facial melasma</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">3 monthly sessions of 1.5 mm dermaroller (200 needles); full-face treatment until erythema; topical TA or saline applied to each hemiface (randomized)</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">TA 50 mg/mL (1 mL)</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Placebo (0.9% saline) on contralateral hemiface</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Hemi-MASI, Reveal&#174; imaging (pixels), MelasQol, expert and patient evaluation</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Hemi-MASI &#8595;29% (TA) vs &#8595;22% (control); no significant difference (p = 0.52); similar results in pixel brightness and satisfaction; both improved QoL (&#8595;MelasQol 44.4 &#8594; 34.15)</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Mild erythema, edema, hematoma; 60% reported temporary darkening lasting median of 5.5 days</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Mn + TA showed no added benefit vs Mn + placebo; improvement likely due to Mn + triple topical formula [<xref rid="REF24" ref-type="bibr">24</xref>]</td></tr></tbody></table></table-wrap><p>Protocols varied in depth (0.25-3.5 mm), device (rollers, dermapens, RF-microneedling), session number (2-12), and interval (biweekly to monthly). FMR&#160;was common in hyperhidrosis and acne [<xref rid="REF7" ref-type="bibr">7</xref>,<xref rid="REF18" ref-type="bibr">18</xref>,<xref rid="REF22" ref-type="bibr">22</xref>,<xref rid="REF24" ref-type="bibr">24</xref>], while manual/dermapen microneedling was typical for pigmentary and scarring conditions [<xref rid="REF13" ref-type="bibr">13</xref>,<xref rid="REF20" ref-type="bibr">20</xref>,<xref rid="REF24" ref-type="bibr">24</xref>].</p><p>Adjunctive agents included tacrolimus [<xref rid="REF19" ref-type="bibr">19</xref>], 5-FU [<xref rid="REF13" ref-type="bibr">13</xref>], pimecrolimus [<xref rid="REF23" ref-type="bibr">23</xref>], tranexamic acid [<xref rid="REF24" ref-type="bibr">24</xref>], cysteamine [<xref rid="REF17" ref-type="bibr">17</xref>], and phenytoin [<xref rid="REF20" ref-type="bibr">20</xref>], generally producing better outcomes than monotherapy. Some trials incorporated antioxidants or PDT [<xref rid="REF15" ref-type="bibr">15</xref>,<xref rid="REF21" ref-type="bibr">21</xref>]. Controls included sham, untreated contralateral sites, placebo, botulinum toxin A, and lasers.</p><p>Outcome measures matched the condition: repigmentation scale&#160;(vitiligo), hyperhidrosis disease severity scale (HDSS) (hyperhidrosis), investigator&#8217;s global assessment (IGA) (acne), modified melasma area and severity index (mMASI) (melasma), wrinkle/elasticity scales (photoaging), and histological/imaging assessments (human melanoma black 45 immunostaining marker (HMB-45), transepidermal water loss (TEWL), VISIA, global aesthetic improvement scale (GAIS)). Combination therapies typically outperformed monotherapy, e.g., microneedling + tacrolimus [<xref rid="REF19" ref-type="bibr">19</xref>] for repigmentation and microneedle radiofrequency (MRF) over PDT for acne [<xref rid="REF7" ref-type="bibr">7</xref>].</p><p>Quality Assessment</p><p>Methodological quality was high (scores 18-24/27, modified Downs and Black). Thirteen studies scored &#8805;22; only Kim et al. [<xref rid="REF18" ref-type="bibr">18</xref>] scored 18 due to a pilot, single-arm design. Reporting was strong, with most scoring 10/10; Petukhova et al. [<xref rid="REF15" ref-type="bibr">15</xref>] and Kim et al. [<xref rid="REF18" ref-type="bibr">18</xref>] scored 9 and 8, respectively. External validity was consistent (2/3), reflecting moderate generalizability. Internal validity (bias) scores were mostly 5-6/7; confounding control was also strong (5-6/6). Statistical power was adequate in all but Kim et al. [<xref rid="REF18" ref-type="bibr">18</xref>] (Table <xref rid="TAB2" ref-type="table">2</xref>).</p><table-wrap position="float" id="TAB2" orientation="portrait"><label>Table 2</label><caption><title>Quality assessment scores of included studies</title><p>Reporting: quality of reporting (0&#8211;10), External Validity: generalizability of study findings (0&#8211;3), Internal Validity -&#160;Bias: risk of bias within the study (0&#8211;7), Internal Validity -&#160;Confounding: control of confounding factors (0&#8211;6), Power: statistical power (0&#8211;1), Total: overall quality score (0&#8211;27)</p></caption><table frame="hsides" rules="groups"><tbody><tr style="background-color:#ccc"><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Study ID</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Reporting (0&#8211;10)</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">External Validity (0&#8211;3)</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Internal Validity - Bias (0&#8211;7)</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Internal Validity - Confounding (0&#8211;6)</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Power (0&#8211;1)</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Total (0&#8211;27)</td></tr><tr><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Huang et al., 2024 (China) [<xref rid="REF7" ref-type="bibr">7</xref>]</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">10</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">2</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">6</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">5</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">1</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">24</td></tr><tr style="background-color:#ccc"><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Fatemi Naeini et al., 2015 (Iran) [<xref rid="REF8" ref-type="bibr">8</xref>]</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">9</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">2</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">5</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">4</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">1</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">21</td></tr><tr><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Rummaneethorn and Chalermchai, 2020 [<xref rid="REF9" ref-type="bibr">9</xref>]</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">10</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">2</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">6</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">5</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">1</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">24</td></tr><tr style="background-color:#ccc"><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Chhabra et al., 2021 (India) [<xref rid="REF13" ref-type="bibr">13</xref>]</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">9</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">2</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">5</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">5</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">1</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">22</td></tr><tr><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Song and Park, 2024 (South Korea) [<xref rid="REF14" ref-type="bibr">14</xref>]</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">10</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">2</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">6</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">5</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">1</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">24</td></tr><tr style="background-color:#ccc"><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Petukhova et al., 2017 (USA) [<xref rid="REF15" ref-type="bibr">15</xref>]</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">9</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">2</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">6</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">5</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">1</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">23</td></tr><tr><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Abdel-Hamid et al., 2024 (Egypt) [<xref rid="REF16" ref-type="bibr">16</xref>]</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">10</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">2</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">6</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">5</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">1</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">24</td></tr><tr style="background-color:#ccc"><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Tsai et al., 2025 (Taiwan) [<xref rid="REF17" ref-type="bibr">17</xref>]</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">10</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">2</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">6</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">5</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">1</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">24</td></tr><tr><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Kim et al., 2025 (South Korea) [<xref rid="REF18" ref-type="bibr">18</xref>]</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">10</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">2</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">6</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">5</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">1</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">24</td></tr><tr style="background-color:#ccc"><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Ebrahim and Albalate, 2020 (Egypt) [<xref rid="REF19" ref-type="bibr">19</xref>]</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">9</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">2</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">6</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">5</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">1</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">23</td></tr><tr><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Sadeghzadeh-Bazargan et al., 2024 (Iran) [<xref rid="REF20" ref-type="bibr">20</xref>]</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">10</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">2</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">6</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">5</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">1</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">24</td></tr><tr style="background-color:#ccc"><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Kim et al., 2013 (South Korea) [<xref rid="REF21" ref-type="bibr">21</xref>]</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">8</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">2</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">5</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">3</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">0</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">18</td></tr><tr><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Eid et al., 2024 (Egypt) [<xref rid="REF22" ref-type="bibr">22</xref>]</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">10</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">2</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">6</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">5</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">1</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">24</td></tr><tr style="background-color:#ccc"><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Iraji et al., 2021 (Iran) [<xref rid="REF23" ref-type="bibr">23</xref>]</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">10</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">2</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">6</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">5</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">1</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">24</td></tr><tr><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Kuster Kaminski Arida et al., 2021 (Brazil) [<xref rid="REF24" ref-type="bibr">24</xref>]</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">10</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">2</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">6</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">5</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">1</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">24</td></tr></tbody></table></table-wrap><p>Top-rated studies (24/27) included Rummaneethorn and Chalermchai, Abdel-Hamid et al., Eid et al., Huang et al., Iraji et al., Kim et al., Tsai et al., Kuster Kaminski Arida et al., Song and Park, and Sadeghzadeh-Bazargan et al. [<xref rid="REF7" ref-type="bibr">7</xref>,<xref rid="REF9" ref-type="bibr">9</xref>,<xref rid="REF14" ref-type="bibr">14</xref>,<xref rid="REF16" ref-type="bibr">16</xref>,<xref rid="REF17" ref-type="bibr">17</xref>,<xref rid="REF20" ref-type="bibr">20</xref>-<xref rid="REF22" ref-type="bibr">22</xref>].</p><p>Effect of Intervention</p><p>Microneedling-based interventions have demonstrated efficacy across a variety of dermatological conditions, consistently improving clinical outcomes, patient satisfaction, and safety profiles. In photoaging, Kim et al. [<xref rid="REF21" ref-type="bibr">21</xref>] showed that combining microneedling with topical antioxidants led to a 29.9% reduction in the Fitzpatrick photoaging scale and a 12.9% increase in skin elasticity. These improvements were supported by GAIS assessments and histological findings, including increased elastin expression and decreased markers of cellular senescence such as p16 and &#947;-H2AX. Minimal transient side effects were reported, indicating favorable tolerability.</p><p>For pigmentary disorders such as melasma, studies indicate&#160;that microneedling combined with pharmacologic agents enhances efficacy. Tsai et al. [<xref rid="REF17" ref-type="bibr">17</xref>] found that fractional RF microneedling with cysteamine produced significant mMASI and VISIA score improvements, particularly when paired with home-based cysteamine. Similarly, Kuster Kaminski Arida et al. [<xref rid="REF24" ref-type="bibr">24</xref>] reported that microneedling with tranexamic acid significantly reduced hemi-melasma area and severity index (hemi-MASI) scores and improved melasma quality of life (MelasQoL) outcomes. Across these studies, transient erythema, edema, and mild local pain were the most common adverse events. Together, these findings suggest that microneedling acts synergistically with antioxidant or depigmenting agents to enhance clinical outcomes.</p><p>In conditions not directly involving microneedling, such as dry eye disease, Song and Park [<xref rid="REF12" ref-type="bibr">12</xref>] demonstrated that biotherapy interventions alone improved ocular surface disease index (OSDI) scores, tear secretion, and quality-of-life parameters without adverse events. This underscores that microneedling&#8217;s therapeutic benefits are condition-specific, yet safe alternative interventions exist for other disorders.</p><p>Microneedling is also effective for acne and acne scarring. Sadeghzadeh-Bazargan et al. [<xref rid="REF20" ref-type="bibr">20</xref>] showed that adding phenytoin to microneedling significantly improved acne scar grading compared to microneedling alone (p = 0.001), with higher patient satisfaction and no serious adverse effects. Huang et al. [<xref rid="REF7" ref-type="bibr">7</xref>] found microneedle RF more effective than PDT in reducing inflammatory lesions (81% vs&#160;73%), achieving higher IGA success rates, and producing greater patient satisfaction, while postinflammatory hyperpigmentation and acneiform eruptions were lower. These results highlight microneedling&#8217;s versatility for both scar remodeling and active inflammatory acne, particularly when combined with adjunctive therapies.</p><p>In vitiligo, combination therapies with microneedling consistently improved repigmentation and quality-of-life scores. Iraji et al. [<xref rid="REF23" ref-type="bibr">23</xref>] observed good to excellent repigmentation in 40% of lesions with microneedling plus pimecrolimus and significant DLQI improvement, with no adverse events. Chhabra et al. [<xref rid="REF13" ref-type="bibr">13</xref>] reported that microneedling plus 5-FU achieved 48.6% excellent repigmentation compared to 16.9% with 5-FU alone, particularly on the trunk and limbs, while mild ulceration and hyperpigmentation were occasionally noted. Comparisons with erbium:yttrium-aluminum-garnet (Er:YAG) laser revealed superior repigmentation and patient satisfaction with laser therapy [<xref rid="REF16" ref-type="bibr">16</xref>], though microneedling still improved vitiligo area severity index (VASI) scores. Ebrahim and Albalate [<xref rid="REF19" ref-type="bibr">19</xref>] confirmed that microneedling combined with tacrolimus yielded superior repigmentation (76.6%) compared to monotherapy, supported by histological evidence of melanocyte restoration.</p><p>Microneedling has also been explored in hyperhidrosis. While botulinum toxin A demonstrated greater short-term efficacy and patient satisfaction compared to FMR [<xref rid="REF9" ref-type="bibr">9</xref>,<xref rid="REF22" ref-type="bibr">22</xref>], studies confirmed that FMR reduces HDSS scores and sweat production meaningfully [<xref rid="REF8" ref-type="bibr">8</xref>,<xref rid="REF18" ref-type="bibr">18</xref>]. Histology revealed sweat gland structural changes, and side effects were mostly transient, highlighting FMR as a safe, minimally invasive alternative.</p><p>Finally, microneedling can enhance topical therapies in actinic keratoses. Petukhova et al. [<xref rid="REF15" ref-type="bibr">15</xref>] demonstrated that microneedling-assisted aminolevulinic acid (ALA)-PDT with a 20-minute incubation significantly increased lesion clearance (76% vs&#160;58%; p &lt; 0.01), with manageable pain and increased TEWL, suggesting enhanced drug delivery. A shorter 10-minute incubation did not produce comparable efficacy, emphasizing the importance of procedural optimization.</p></sec><sec sec-type="conclusions"><title>Conclusions</title><p>Microneedling demonstrates substantial promise as a versatile, minimally invasive therapeutic modality across a broad spectrum of dermatologic conditions, ranging from pigmentary disorders and inflammatory dermatoses to scarring and adnexal dysfunction. Its ability to enhance transdermal delivery of pharmacologic agents such as tranexamic acid, phenytoin, and immunomodulators contributes to synergistic treatment effects and potentially superior clinical outcomes compared to monotherapy. The procedure is generally well tolerated, with adverse effects being mild and transient in most reports, supporting its favorable safety profile. Nevertheless, despite encouraging evidence from multiple randomized controlled trials, heterogeneity in study design, treatment parameters, and outcome measures limits the generalizability of current findings. Future research should prioritize large-scale, standardized, methodologically rigorous trials with extended follow-up to refine procedural protocols, identify predictors of response, and establish the durability of therapeutic benefits.</p></sec></body><back><fn-group content-type="conflict"><title>Disclosures</title><fn fn-type="COI-statement"><p><bold>Conflicts of interest:</bold> In compliance with the ICMJE uniform disclosure form, all authors declare the following:</p><p><bold>Payment/services info:</bold> All authors have declared that no financial support was received from any organization for the submitted work.</p><p><bold>Financial relationships:</bold> All authors have declared that they have no financial relationships at present or within the previous three years with any organizations that might have an interest in the submitted work.</p><p><bold>Other relationships:</bold> All authors have declared that there are no other relationships or activities that could appear to have influenced the submitted work.</p></fn></fn-group><fn-group content-type="other"><title>Author Contributions</title><fn fn-type="other"><p><bold>Acquisition, analysis, or interpretation of data:</bold>&#160; Rayim A. Oraybi, Amany Mashi, Abdulrahman M. Altalhi, Wafa A. Alrezqi, Taif K. Hakami, Alanoud M. Masmali, Asma F. Alshahrani, Raghad A. Alamri, Alanoud A. Alanazi</p><p><bold>Critical review of the manuscript for important intellectual content:</bold>&#160; Rayim A. Oraybi, Manar S. Hakami, Alanoud M. Masmali, Asma F. Alshahrani, Raghad A. Alamri, Alanoud A. Alanazi</p><p><bold>Drafting of the manuscript:</bold>&#160; Amany Mashi, Abdulrahman M. Altalhi, Wafa A. Alrezqi, Taif K. Hakami, Alanoud M. Masmali, Asma F. Alshahrani, Raghad A. Alamri, Alanoud A. Alanazi</p><p><bold>Concept and design:</bold>&#160; Manar S. Hakami, Taif K. Hakami, Alanoud M. Masmali</p></fn></fn-group><ref-list><title>References</title><ref id="REF1"><label>1</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><article-title>A systematic review examining the potential adverse effects of microneedling</article-title><source>J Clin Aesthet Dermatol</source><person-group><name name-style="western"><surname>Gowda</surname><given-names>A</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Healey</surname><given-names>B</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Ezaldein</surname><given-names>H</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Merati</surname><given-names>M</given-names></name></person-group><fpage>45</fpage><lpage>54</lpage><volume>14</volume><year>2021</year><uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xlink:href="https://pmc.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/articles/PMC7869810/">https://pmc.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/articles/PMC7869810/</uri><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC7869810</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">33584968</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="REF2"><label>2</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><article-title>Microneedling for facial rejuvenation: a systematic review</article-title><source>Aesthetic Plast Surg</source><person-group><name name-style="western"><surname>Foppiani</surname><given-names>JA</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Fanning</surname><given-names>JE</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Beltran</surname><given-names>K</given-names></name><etal/></person-group><year>2025</year><pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1007/s00266-025-04972-z</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">40542236</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="REF3"><label>3</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><article-title>Microneedling monotherapy for acne scar: systematic review and meta-analysis of randomized controlled trials</article-title><source>Aesthetic Plast Surg</source><person-group><name name-style="western"><surname>Shen</surname><given-names>YC</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Chiu</surname><given-names>WK</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Kang</surname><given-names>YN</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Chen</surname><given-names>C</given-names></name></person-group><fpage>1913</fpage><lpage>1922</lpage><volume>46</volume><year>2022</year><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">35426044</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1007/s00266-022-02845-3</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="REF4"><label>4</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><article-title>Microneedling in skin of color: a review of uses and efficacy</article-title><source>J Am Acad Dermatol</source><person-group><name name-style="western"><surname>Cohen</surname><given-names>BE</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Elbuluk</surname><given-names>N</given-names></name></person-group><fpage>348</fpage><lpage>355</lpage><volume>74</volume><year>2016</year><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">26549251</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1016/j.jaad.2015.09.024</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="REF5"><label>5</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><article-title>Microneedling as an adjuvant to topical therapies for melasma: a systematic review and meta-analysis</article-title><source>J Am Acad Dermatol</source><person-group><name name-style="western"><surname>Bailey</surname><given-names>AJ</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Li</surname><given-names>HO</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Tan</surname><given-names>MG</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Cheng</surname><given-names>W</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Dover</surname><given-names>JS</given-names></name></person-group><fpage>797</fpage><lpage>810</lpage><volume>86</volume><year>2022</year><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">33857549</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1016/j.jaad.2021.03.116</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="REF6"><label>6</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><article-title>Comparing the efficacy and safety of microneedling and its combination with other treatments in patients with acne scars: a network meta-analysis of randomized controlled trials</article-title><source>Arch Dermatol Res</source><person-group><name name-style="western"><surname>Li</surname><given-names>H</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Jia</surname><given-names>B</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Zhang</surname><given-names>X</given-names></name></person-group><fpage>505</fpage><volume>316</volume><year>2024</year><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">39110247</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1007/s00403-024-03256-x</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="REF7"><label>7</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><article-title>Efficacy and safety of single microneedle radiofrequency vs. photodynamic therapy on moderate-to-severe acne vulgaris: a prospective, randomized, controlled study</article-title><source>Chin Med J (Engl)</source><person-group><name name-style="western"><surname>Huang</surname><given-names>C</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Mao</surname><given-names>M</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Peng</surname><given-names>Y</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Wang</surname><given-names>B</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Deng</surname><given-names>Y</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Xie</surname><given-names>H</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Jian</surname><given-names>D</given-names></name></person-group><fpage>1006</fpage><lpage>1008</lpage><volume>137</volume><year>2024</year><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">38192026</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1097/CM9.0000000000002911</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC11046016</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="REF8"><label>8</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><article-title>Fractionated microneedle radiofrequency for treatment of primary axillary hyperhidrosis: a sham control study</article-title><source>Australas J Dermatol</source><person-group><name name-style="western"><surname>Fatemi Naeini</surname><given-names>F</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Abtahi-Naeini</surname><given-names>B</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Pourazizi</surname><given-names>M</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Nilforoushzadeh</surname><given-names>MA</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Mirmohammadkhani</surname><given-names>M</given-names></name></person-group><fpage>279</fpage><lpage>284</lpage><volume>56</volume><year>2015</year><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">25496000</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1111/ajd.12260</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="REF9"><label>9</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><article-title>A comparative study between intradermal botulinum toxin A and fractional microneedle radiofrequency (FMR) for the treatment of primary axillary hyperhidrosis</article-title><source>Lasers Med Sci</source><person-group><name name-style="western"><surname>Rummaneethorn</surname><given-names>P</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Chalermchai</surname><given-names>T</given-names></name></person-group><fpage>1179</fpage><lpage>1184</lpage><volume>35</volume><year>2020</year><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">31939036</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1007/s10103-020-02958-8</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="REF10"><label>10</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><article-title>The PRISMA 2020 statement: an updated guideline for reporting systematic reviews</article-title><source>BMJ</source><person-group><name name-style="western"><surname>Page</surname><given-names>MJ</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>McKenzie</surname><given-names>JE</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Bossuyt</surname><given-names>PM</given-names></name><etal/></person-group><fpage>71</fpage><volume>372</volume><year>2021</year><pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1186/s13643-021-01626-4</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC8008539</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">33781348</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="REF11"><label>11</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><article-title>The feasibility of creating a checklist for the assessment of the methodological quality both of randomised and non-randomised studies of health care interventions</article-title><source>J Epidemiol Community Health</source><person-group><name name-style="western"><surname>Downs</surname><given-names>SH</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Black</surname><given-names>N</given-names></name></person-group><fpage>377</fpage><lpage>384</lpage><volume>52</volume><year>1998</year><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">9764259</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1136/jech.52.6.377</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC1756728</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="REF12"><label>12</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><article-title>A comparative investigator-initiated pilot study on the efficacy and safety of biodegradable microneedle acupuncture and conventional intradermal acupuncture for dry eye patient: a superiority, assessor-blinded, randomized controlled trial</article-title><source>Medicine (Baltimore)</source><person-group><name name-style="western"><surname>Song</surname><given-names>JH</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Park</surname><given-names>SY</given-names></name></person-group><volume>101</volume><year>2022</year><pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1097/MD.0000000000031468</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC9704994</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">36451509</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="REF13"><label>13</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><article-title>A comparative study of microneedling combined with topical 5-fluorouracil versus microneedling alone in treatment of localized stable vitiligo</article-title><source>Indian J Dermatol</source><person-group><name name-style="western"><surname>Chhabra</surname><given-names>S</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Chahar</surname><given-names>YS</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Singh</surname><given-names>A</given-names></name></person-group><fpage>574</fpage><volume>66</volume><year>2021</year><pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.4103/ijd.ijd_130_21</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC8751692</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">35068531</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="REF14"><label>14</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><article-title>Biodegradable microneedle acupuncture has equivalent efficacy to traditional intradermal acupuncture for dry eye disease: a pilot single-blinded, randomized controlled trial</article-title><source>Medicine (Baltimore)</source><person-group><name name-style="western"><surname>Song</surname><given-names>JH</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Park</surname><given-names>SY</given-names></name></person-group><volume>103</volume><year>2024</year><pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1097/MD.0000000000036864</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC10783304</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">38215150</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="REF15"><label>15</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><article-title>Effect of expedited microneedle-assisted photodynamic therapy for field treatment of actinic keratoses: a randomized clinical trial</article-title><source>JAMA Dermatol</source><person-group><name name-style="western"><surname>Petukhova</surname><given-names>TA</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Hassoun</surname><given-names>LA</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Foolad</surname><given-names>N</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Barath</surname><given-names>M</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Sivamani</surname><given-names>RK</given-names></name></person-group><fpage>637</fpage><lpage>643</lpage><volume>153</volume><year>2017</year><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">28514458</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1001/jamadermatol.2017.0849</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC5543325</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="REF16"><label>16</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><article-title>Effectiveness of fractional erbium-YAG laser, microneedling, platelet-rich plasma in localized stable vitiligo patients: randomized clinical trial</article-title><source>Arch Dermatol Res</source><person-group><name name-style="western"><surname>Abdel-Hamid</surname><given-names>S</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Ibrahim</surname><given-names>HM</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Hameed</surname><given-names>AM</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Hegazy</surname><given-names>EM</given-names></name></person-group><fpage>399</fpage><volume>316</volume><year>2024</year><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">38878236</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1007/s00403-024-03035-8</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC11180153</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="REF17"><label>17</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><article-title>Efficacy and safety of combination therapy of microneedling radiofrequency, in-office and home-based topical cysteamine in refractory melasma: a split face, vehicle-control, randomized control trial</article-title><source>J Cosmet Dermatol</source><person-group><name name-style="western"><surname>Tsai</surname><given-names>YW</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Lin</surname><given-names>JH</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Lai</surname><given-names>YJ</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Liu</surname><given-names>TL</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Ng</surname><given-names>CY</given-names></name></person-group><volume>24</volume><year>2025</year><pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1111/jocd.16661</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC11845957</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">39574411</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="REF18"><label>18</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><article-title>Fractional microneedle radiofrequency with the application of vitamin C, E, and ferulic acid serum for neck skin rejuvenation: a prospective, double-blinded, split-neck, placebo-controlled trial</article-title><source>J Dermatolog Treat</source><person-group><name name-style="western"><surname>Kim</surname><given-names>J</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Lee</surname><given-names>SG</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Boo</surname><given-names>J</given-names></name><etal/></person-group><fpage>2504655</fpage><volume>36</volume><year>2025</year><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">40464749</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1080/09546634.2025.2504655</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="REF19"><label>19</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><article-title>Efficacy of microneedling combined with tacrolimus versus either one alone for vitiligo treatment</article-title><source>J Cosmet Dermatol</source><person-group><name name-style="western"><surname>Ebrahim</surname><given-names>HM</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Albalate</surname><given-names>W</given-names></name></person-group><fpage>855</fpage><lpage>862</lpage><volume>19</volume><year>2020</year><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">32030880</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1111/jocd.13304</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="REF20"><label>20</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><article-title>Evaluation and comparison of the efficacy and safety of the combination of topical phenytoin and microneedling with microneedling alone in the treatment of atrophic acne scars: a controlled blinded randomized clinical trial</article-title><source>Skin Res Technol</source><person-group><name name-style="western"><surname>Sadeghzadeh-Bazargan</surname><given-names>A</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Pashaei</surname><given-names>A</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Ghassemi</surname><given-names>M</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Dehghani</surname><given-names>A</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Shafiei</surname><given-names>M</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Goodarzi</surname><given-names>A</given-names></name></person-group><volume>30</volume><year>2024</year><pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1111/srt.13766</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC11133962</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">38807440</pub-id><related-article xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" related-article-type="retraction-forward" ext-link-type="pmc" xlink:href="PMC12434309"/></element-citation></ref><ref id="REF21"><label>21</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><article-title>Efficacy of fractional microneedle radiofrequency device in the treatment of primary axillary hyperhidrosis: a pilot study</article-title><source>Dermatology</source><person-group><name name-style="western"><surname>Kim</surname><given-names>M</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Shin</surname><given-names>JY</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Lee</surname><given-names>J</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Kim</surname><given-names>JY</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Oh</surname><given-names>SH</given-names></name></person-group><fpage>243</fpage><lpage>249</lpage><volume>227</volume><year>2013</year><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">24107595</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1159/000354602</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="REF22"><label>22</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><article-title>Long-term efficacy of fractional microneedle radiofrequency versus botulinum toxin-A in primary axillary hyperhidrosis: a randomized controlled trial</article-title><source>Lasers Med Sci</source><person-group><name name-style="western"><surname>Eid</surname><given-names>RO</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Shaarawi</surname><given-names>E</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Hegazy</surname><given-names>RA</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Hafez</surname><given-names>V</given-names></name></person-group><fpage>177</fpage><volume>39</volume><year>2024</year><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">38981914</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1007/s10103-024-04115-x</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC11233334</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="REF23"><label>23</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><article-title>Microneedling in combination with topical pimecrolimus 1% versus topical pimecrolimus 1% for the treatment of refractory stable vitiligo: a randomized clinical trial</article-title><source>Dermatol Res Pract</source><person-group><name name-style="western"><surname>Iraji</surname><given-names>F</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Asilian</surname><given-names>A</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Talebzadeh</surname><given-names>Z</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Saber</surname><given-names>M</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Mokhtari</surname><given-names>F</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Siadat</surname><given-names>A</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Hosseini</surname><given-names>SM</given-names></name></person-group><volume>2021</volume><year>2021</year><pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1155/2021/5652140</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC8651420</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">34887918</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="REF24"><label>24</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><article-title>Randomized, double-blind, placebo-controlled split-face trial of the efficacy of tranexamic acid by drug delivery through microneedling in the treatment of melasma</article-title><source>J Cosmet Dermatol</source><person-group><name name-style="western"><surname>Kuster Kaminski Arida</surname><given-names>D</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Orso Rebellato</surname><given-names>PR</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Marioto de Campos</surname><given-names>GL</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Costa</surname><given-names>A</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Vilaverde Schmitt</surname><given-names>J</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Larocca Skare</surname><given-names>T</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Rodrigues Lisboa Faucz</surname><given-names>L</given-names></name></person-group><fpage>4005</fpage><lpage>4010</lpage><volume>20</volume><year>2021</year><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">34077619</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1111/jocd.14257</pub-id></element-citation></ref></ref-list></back></article></pmc-articleset>