<?xml version="1.0"  ?><!DOCTYPE pmc-articleset PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD ARTICLE SET 2.0//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pmc/articleset/nlm-articleset-2.0.dtd"><pmc-articleset><article xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" xmlns:ali="http://www.niso.org/schemas/ali/1.0/" xml:lang="en" article-type="research-article" dtd-version="1.4"><processing-meta base-tagset="archiving" mathml-version="3.0" table-model="xhtml" tagset-family="jats"><restricted-by>pmc</restricted-by></processing-meta><front><journal-meta><journal-id journal-id-type="nlm-ta">Aesthet Surg J</journal-id><journal-id journal-id-type="iso-abbrev">Aesthet Surg J</journal-id><journal-id journal-id-type="pmc-domain-id">2717</journal-id><journal-id journal-id-type="pmc-domain">aesurg</journal-id><journal-id journal-id-type="publisher-id">asj</journal-id><journal-title-group><journal-title>Aesthetic Surgery Journal</journal-title></journal-title-group><issn pub-type="ppub">1090-820X</issn><issn pub-type="epub">1527-330X</issn><publisher><publisher-name>Oxford University Press</publisher-name></publisher></journal-meta><article-meta><article-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC11177555</article-id><article-id pub-id-type="pmcid-ver">PMC11177555.1</article-id><article-id pub-id-type="pmcaid">11177555</article-id><article-id pub-id-type="pmcaiid">11177555</article-id><article-id pub-id-type="pmid">38489829</article-id><article-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1093/asj/sjae058</article-id><article-id pub-id-type="publisher-id">sjae058</article-id><article-version article-version-type="pmc-version">1</article-version><article-categories><subj-group subj-group-type="heading"><subject>Original Article</subject></subj-group><subj-group subj-group-type="category-taxonomy-collection"><subject>AcademicSubjects/MED00987</subject></subj-group><subj-group subj-group-type="category-taxonomy-collection"><subject>Asj/1</subject></subj-group></article-categories><title-group><article-title>Lower Eyelid Dark Circles (Tear Trough and Lid-Cheek Junction): A Stepwise Assessment Framework</article-title></title-group><contrib-group><contrib contrib-type="author" corresp="yes"><name name-style="western"><surname>Liew</surname><given-names initials="S">Steven</given-names></name><degrees>MBBS, FRACS</degrees><xref rid="FM1" ref-type="author-notes"/><xref rid="sjae058-cor1" ref-type="corresp"/></contrib><contrib contrib-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Doreian</surname><given-names initials="S">Simone</given-names></name><degrees>MBBS, FCPCA, FRACGP, DRANZCOG</degrees><xref rid="FM10" ref-type="author-notes"/></contrib><contrib contrib-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Kunathathorn</surname><given-names initials="W">Wachira</given-names></name><degrees>MD, MSc, ABAARM</degrees><xref rid="FM2" ref-type="author-notes"/></contrib><contrib contrib-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Lam</surname><given-names initials="S">Stephanie</given-names></name><degrees>MBChB, MRCS, FCSHK, FKHAM</degrees><xref rid="FM3" ref-type="author-notes"/></contrib><contrib contrib-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Jorge</surname><given-names initials="A">Alvin</given-names></name><degrees>MD, FPCS, FPAAS</degrees><xref rid="FM4" ref-type="author-notes"/></contrib><contrib contrib-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Lan</surname><given-names initials="LB">Lam Bee</given-names></name><degrees>MD</degrees><xref rid="FM5" ref-type="author-notes"/></contrib><contrib contrib-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Selkon</surname><given-names initials="E">Ellen</given-names></name><degrees>MBChB, FRNZGP, FNZCAM</degrees><xref rid="FM6" ref-type="author-notes"/></contrib><contrib contrib-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Arendse</surname><given-names initials="S">Sean</given-names></name><degrees>MBBS, FACEM</degrees><xref rid="FM7" ref-type="author-notes"/></contrib><contrib contrib-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Silleri</surname><given-names initials="J">Jodie</given-names></name><degrees>MBBS, FRACGP, FCPCA</degrees><xref rid="FM8" ref-type="author-notes"/></contrib><contrib contrib-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Telfer</surname><given-names initials="T">Tara</given-names></name><degrees>BSC(Hons)</degrees><xref rid="FM9" ref-type="author-notes"/></contrib></contrib-group><author-notes><fn id="FM1"><p>Dr Liew is a plastic surgeon in private practice, Darlinghurst, NSW, Australia.</p></fn><fn id="FM10"><p>Dr Doreian is a cosmetic physician in private practice, Sandringham, VIC, Australia.</p></fn><fn id="FM2"><p>Dr Kunathathorn is a dermatologist in private practice, Ratchaburi, Thailand.</p></fn><fn id="FM3"><p>Dr Lam is a plastic surgeon, Plastic Surgery Unit, Central Health Medical Practice, Hong Kong.</p></fn><fn id="FM4"><p>Dr Jorge is a general and cosmetic surgeon in private practice, Manila, Philippines.</p></fn><fn id="FM5"><p>Dr Lan is a dermatologist in private practice in Singapore.</p></fn><fn id="FM6"><p>Dr Selkon is a cosmetic physician in private practice, Auckland, New Zealand.</p></fn><fn id="FM7"><p>Dr Arendse is a cosmetic physician in private practice, Melbourne, VIC, Australia.</p></fn><fn id="FM8"><p>Dr Silleri is a cosmetic physician in private practice, Surrey Hills, VIC, Australia.</p></fn><fn id="FM9"><p>Ms Telfer is a senior medical advisor, Galderma Australia Pty Ltd, North Sydney, NSW, Australia.</p></fn><corresp id="sjae058-cor1"><bold>Corresponding Author:</bold> Dr Steven Liew, 501/19A Boundary St, Darlinghurst, NSW 2010, Australia. E-mail: <email>steven@shapeclinic.com.au</email>; Instagram and X: <ext-link xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xlink:href="https://instagram.com/liewlift" ext-link-type="uri">@liewlift</ext-link></corresp></author-notes><pub-date pub-type="collection"><month>7</month><year>2024</year></pub-date><pub-date pub-type="epub" iso-8601-date="2024-03-15"><day>15</day><month>3</month><year>2024</year></pub-date><volume>44</volume><issue>7</issue><issue-id pub-id-type="pmc-issue-id">464889</issue-id><fpage>NP476</fpage><lpage>NP485</lpage><history><date date-type="editorial-decision"><day>06</day><month>3</month><year>2024</year></date><date date-type="corrected-typeset"><day>24</day><month>4</month><year>2024</year></date></history><pub-history><event event-type="pmc-release"><date><day>15</day><month>03</month><year>2024</year></date></event><event event-type="pmc-live"><date><day>15</day><month>06</month><year>2024</year></date></event><event event-type="pmc-last-change"><date iso-8601-date="2024-06-15 10:25:13.430"><day>15</day><month>06</month><year>2024</year></date></event></pub-history><permissions><copyright-statement>&#169; The Author(s) 2024. Published by Oxford University Press on behalf of The Aesthetic Society.</copyright-statement><copyright-year>2024</copyright-year><license><ali:license_ref specific-use="textmining" content-type="ccbylicense">https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</ali:license_ref><license-p>This is an Open Access article distributed under the terms of the Creative Commons Attribution License (<ext-link xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" ext-link-type="uri" xlink:href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/">https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</ext-link>), which permits unrestricted reuse, distribution, and reproduction in any medium, provided the original work is properly cited.</license-p></license></permissions><self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" content-type="pmc-pdf" xlink:href="sjae058.pdf"/><self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xlink:href="sjae058.pdf"/><abstract><title>Abstract</title><sec id="s1"><title>Background</title><p>Despite increasing popularity, the use of hyaluronic acid (HA) fillers for the correction of dark under-eye shadows remains challenging. Specific guidance on patient assessment is limited.</p></sec><sec id="s2"><title>Objectives</title><p>The aim of this study was to develop a stepwise assessment framework for lower eyelid dark shadows to help practitioners classify patients based on their underlying problems and facilitate a more strategic approach to treatment.</p></sec><sec id="s3"><title>Methods</title><p>Literature review and peer collaboration informed the current availability of educational material for use by experienced injectors when assessing patients presenting with dark circles. A practitioner survey provided insight into current practices. A focus group convened to review the survey results and discuss best practice approaches to patient assessment.</p></sec><sec id="s4"><title>Results</title><p>Surveyed practitioners (<italic toggle="yes">n</italic> = 39) reported patient concern about under-eye hollows (91%), dark eye circles (80%), and looking tired (60%). All (100%) agreed that midcheek volume was critical when treating tear-trough depression, and only 26% reported use of a tear-trough classification system. The focus group developed a framework for assessing tear-trough depression and the lid-cheek junction in patients presenting with dark circles. Key factors within this framework included the importance of appropriate lighting when conducting a visual inspection, regional inspection of the cheek and tear trough, palpation of the orbital rim and soft tissues, determination of the orbital vector, and assessment of lower eyelid pigmentation and skin quality.</p></sec><sec id="s5"><title>Conclusions</title><p>Careful step-by-step assessment can reduce the challenges of treating dark circles by identifying patients in whom dark eye circles may be improved without the need to directly inject filler into the tear trough.</p></sec><sec id="s6"><title>Level of Evidence: 5</title><p>
<inline-graphic xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xlink:href="sjae058il1.jpg"/>
</p></sec></abstract><counts><page-count count="10"/></counts><custom-meta-group><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-status-qastatus</meta-name><meta-value>0</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-status-live</meta-name><meta-value>yes</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-status-embargo</meta-name><meta-value>no</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-status-released</meta-name><meta-value>yes</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-open-access</meta-name><meta-value>yes</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-olf</meta-name><meta-value>no</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-manuscript</meta-name><meta-value>no</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-legally-suppressed</meta-name><meta-value>no</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-has-pdf</meta-name><meta-value>yes</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-has-supplement</meta-name><meta-value>yes</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-pdf-only</meta-name><meta-value>no</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-suppress-copyright</meta-name><meta-value>no</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-is-real-version</meta-name><meta-value>no</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-is-scanned-article</meta-name><meta-value>no</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-preprint</meta-name><meta-value>no</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-in-epmc</meta-name><meta-value>yes</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-license-ref</meta-name><meta-value>CC BY</meta-value></custom-meta></custom-meta-group></article-meta></front><body><p>A youthful periocular region is characterized by fullness of the periorbital area, minimal or no skin excess, minimal pigmentation or skin wrinkles, and appropriate brow height and shape.<sup><xref rid="sjae058-B1" ref-type="bibr">1</xref></sup> By contrast, lower eyelid dark shadows are characterized by soft tissue loss and bony resorption, which create a sunken appearance and cast dark shadows despite adequate rest.<sup><xref rid="sjae058-B2" ref-type="bibr">2</xref></sup> The presence of dark shadows negatively influences perceptions of youthfulness, attractiveness, and emotion, often resulting in the utilization of descriptors such as tiredness, unhappiness, or sadness.<sup><xref rid="sjae058-B3" ref-type="bibr">3</xref></sup></p><p>The lower periorbital region is one of the most common areas for which patients seek minimally invasive facial aesthetic treatment, citing under-eye bags and dark circles as their primary concerns.<sup><xref rid="sjae058-B4" ref-type="bibr">4</xref></sup> The use of hyaluronic acid (HA) gel filler for the correction of dark under-eye shadows, with its quick results and minimal recovery time, has become a popular rejuvenation treatment and is associated with high levels of posttreatment patient satisfaction.<sup><xref rid="sjae058-B5" ref-type="bibr">5</xref></sup> Yet the lower periorbital is a challenging area to inject.<sup><xref rid="sjae058-B6" ref-type="bibr">6</xref>,<xref rid="sjae058-B7" ref-type="bibr">7</xref></sup> Complications observed with dermal fillers to treat this area include mild, self-limiting adverse effects (puffiness, swelling, bruising), persistent irregularities (irregular surface contours, edema, and a bluish hue or Tyndall effect), and severe (irreversible vision loss) or long-term complications (granulomas).<sup><xref rid="sjae058-B8" ref-type="bibr">8</xref>,<xref rid="sjae058-B9" ref-type="bibr">9</xref></sup> These unacceptable aesthetic outcomes can result from overcorrection, too superficial injections, and inappropriate choice of filler.<sup><xref rid="sjae058-B10" ref-type="bibr">10</xref></sup> Good knowledge of periorbital anatomy, product selection, and appropriate injection technique are therefore vital for optimal treatment outcomes. In recognition of this, the recent literature provides details of therapeutic approaches and comprehensive reviews of periorbital anatomy, as well as guidance for the recognition, prevention, and management of filler-associated complications that are most commonly encountered when treating this region.<sup><xref rid="sjae058-B6" ref-type="bibr">6-8</xref>,<xref rid="sjae058-B10" ref-type="bibr">10-16</xref></sup> However, specific guidance on assessment is limited. This paper draws on recent concepts and current clinical practices to help guide the practitioner through an assessment framework for lower eyelid dark shadows that can be undertaken before establishing a treatment plan with the patient.<sup><xref rid="sjae058-B15" ref-type="bibr">15</xref>,<xref rid="sjae058-B17" ref-type="bibr">17</xref></sup> The aim is to provide an assessment that will better enable the practitioner to classify the patient based on their underlying problems and facilitate a more strategic approach to treatment.</p><sec sec-type="methods" id="sjae058-s0"><title>METHODS</title><p>The focus of this work was on identifying key characteristics that contribute to patient dissatisfaction with the eye area and deriving an assessment framework to account for these characteristics.</p><p>This study was conducted in multiple stages and included multidisciplinary collaboration, a practitioner survey, a focus group, and real-world experience. The study sponsor selected 8 senior educators from the within the Galderma Aesthetics Injection Network (GAIN) and invited an additional 32 GAIN members from within the Asia Pacific region to participate in a scientific exchange to discuss and develop educational materials. The Scientific Exchange Working Group comprised 8 clinicians specializing in dermatology, cosmetic medicine, plastic surgery, and maxillofacial surgery. All of these practitioners provided their first and second choice options across 4 primary domains (perioral, profile, skin, and periorbital). Two members of the working group and 8 of the practitioners were then assigned to each domain, based on their preference and their experience. We discuss here the results from the periorbital domain.</p><p>A literature search was conducted with search terms constructed to provide relevant information regarding 3 core considerations: (1) anatomy of the periorbital region, (2) characterization of key features of the periorbital region and related assessment frameworks, and (3) practical application and choice of treatment for minimally invasive periorbital treatment. The working group convened to discuss the results of the literature search and their current clinical practices. The outputs from this multidisciplinary discussion were then utilized to develop a short practitioner survey (<xref rid="sup1" ref-type="supplementary-material">Appendix</xref>, available at <ext-link xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xlink:href="https://www.aestheticsurgeryjournal.com" ext-link-type="uri">www.aestheticsurgeryjournal.com</ext-link>) to assess the experience, perceptions, and opinions of a wider group of clinicians.</p><p>The practitioner survey was completed online though an emailed link. The survey responses were returned to a medical writer for deidentification, aggregation, and analysis. All working group members and invited physicians completed the survey, irrespective of which domain they had elected to focus on. The survey enabled practitioners to rank the importance of a number of characteristics that contribute to youthful eyes with an 11-point visual analog scale (0 = no contribution, 10 = most contribution). Invited practitioners completed the survey in February 2022, and data in the returned surveys were summarized descriptively. In March 2022 a hybrid focus group meeting was held, during which the authors reviewed the survey results, discussed best practice approaches to patient assessment, and developed an assessment framework.</p></sec><sec sec-type="results" id="sjae058-s1"><title>RESULTS</title><sec id="sjae058-s1.1"><title>Practitioner Survey Responses</title><p>The response rate to the practitioner survey was 98% (39/40 surveys returned). Respondents were from 18 countries (predominantly Australia 46%; <xref rid="sup1" ref-type="supplementary-material">Supplemental Table 1</xref>, available at <ext-link xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xlink:href="https://www.aestheticsurgeryjournal.com" ext-link-type="uri">www.aestheticsurgeryjournal.com</ext-link>). The majority were cosmetic physicians (61%), 21% were dermatologists and 18% were surgeons; almost all respondents (95%) had been practicing aesthetic medicine for more than 10 years. Respondents recognized &#8220;ZOOM dysmorphia,&#8221; with majority agreement that virtual communications platforms during the COVID-19 pandemic had been associated with an increase in patient concerns about under-eye hollows (91%), dark eye circles (80%), and looking tired (60%).<sup><xref rid="sjae058-B18" ref-type="bibr">18</xref></sup> An absence of eye bags and a high, smooth lid-cheek junction were regarded as the most important contributors to the youthful eye, followed by brow position, hollowing, and infraorbital skin quality (<xref rid="sup1" ref-type="supplementary-material">Supplemental Figure 1</xref>, available at <ext-link xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xlink:href="https://www.aestheticsurgeryjournal.com" ext-link-type="uri">www.aestheticsurgeryjournal.com</ext-link>). Taking these factors into consideration, survey respondents unanimously agreed that midcheek volume was critical when treating tear-trough depression. Only 26% of respondents reported employing a specific classification system for assessing tear-trough depression, with the majority relying on clinical assessment and serial photography instead. When scales were utilized, the most frequently cited was Hirmand's classification, followed by the Barton tear-trough grading system.<sup><xref rid="sjae058-B19" ref-type="bibr">19</xref>,<xref rid="sjae058-B20" ref-type="bibr">20</xref></sup></p></sec><sec id="sjae058-s1.2"><title>Best Practice Approach to Patient Assessment</title><p>A variety of factors can contribute to the appearance of lower eyelid dark shadows&#8212;bone structure, midface soft tissues (fat, muscles, ligaments), and skin quality. Determining which factors are most prevalent provides information to guide treatment approaches and counsel patients about expectations, both of which contribute to the development of an appropriate treatment plan. <xref rid="sjae058-F1" ref-type="fig">Figure 1</xref> displays a proposed stepwise approach to assessment.</p><fig position="float" id="sjae058-F1" fig-type="figure" orientation="portrait"><label>Figure 1.</label><caption><p>Lower eyelid dark circles: stepwise assessment framework.</p></caption><graphic xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" position="float" orientation="portrait" xlink:href="sjae058f1.jpg"/></fig></sec><sec id="sjae058-s1.3"><title>Step 1: Inspect the Lid-Cheek Junction</title><p>In patients who present seeking correction of dark circles, physical examination of the lower lid-cheek junction should be conducted with the patient sitting upright directly in front of the examiner at eye level (<xref rid="sjae058-F2" ref-type="fig">Figure 2</xref>).</p><fig position="float" id="sjae058-F2" fig-type="figure" orientation="portrait"><label>Figure 2.</label><caption><p>Inspection of the lid-cheek junction. Patient images reproduced from Liew and DeSilva (with permission from Georg Thieme Verlag KG).<sup><xref rid="sjae058-B15" ref-type="bibr">15</xref></sup></p></caption><graphic xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" position="float" orientation="portrait" xlink:href="sjae058f2.jpg"/></fig><p>After an initial general inspection of the overall facial aesthetics, a more detailed inspection of the shadowing at the lid-cheek junction should be undertaken in a well-lit room in multiple views (frontal, oblique, and lateral). The lid-cheek junction can be divided into 3 segments (<xref rid="sup1" ref-type="supplementary-material">Supplemental Figure 2</xref>, available at <ext-link xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xlink:href="https://www.aestheticsurgeryjournal.com" ext-link-type="uri">www.aestheticsurgeryjournal.com</ext-link>). If present, the location of the dark circles should be recorded (<xref rid="sjae058-T1" ref-type="table">Table 1</xref>).</p><table-wrap position="float" id="sjae058-T1" orientation="portrait"><label>Table 1.</label><caption><p>Functional Classification of Lid-Cheek Junction</p></caption><table frame="hsides" rules="groups"><colgroup span="1"><col align="left" span="1"/><col align="left" span="1"/></colgroup><thead><tr><th align="left" colspan="2" rowspan="1">Whole lower eyelid-cheek junction: Surface landmark bounded by the tear trough ligament and orbicularis retaining ligament</th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Medial lid-cheek junction</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Inner third: Area of the lower eyelid extending inferolaterally from the medial canthus and to a point where the vertical line from the medial limbus meets the eyelid</td></tr><tr><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Central lid-cheek junction</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Middle third: Area extending from where the vertical line from medial limbus bisects the lower eyelid to the point where a vertical line from the lateral canthal angle meets the lower eyelid</td></tr><tr><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Lateral lid-cheek junction</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Outer third: Area extending from the point where a vertical line from the lateral canthal angle meets the lower eyelid to the lateral limit of the lower eyelid</td></tr></tbody></table></table-wrap><p>Further inspection should then be undertaken to determine if the dark circles are due to skin pigmentation, structural deficits, the presence of eye bags, or a combination of these. Lighting and patient position can highlight specific features, and both play a key role in determining the cause of dark circles (<xref rid="sjae058-T2" ref-type="table">Table 2</xref>).</p><table-wrap position="float" id="sjae058-T2" orientation="portrait"><label>Table 2.</label><caption><p>Importance of Lighting and Position</p></caption><table frame="hsides" rules="groups"><colgroup span="1"><col align="left" span="1"/><col align="left" span="1"/></colgroup><thead><tr><th align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Potential underlying cause</th><th align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Practical advice</th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Pigmentation</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">To accentuate pigmentation: Use a bright light on the skin and stretch the lower eyelid skin. The presence of skin pigmentation will be clearly visible. Equally those with transmitted pigmentation of underlying vascularity of the orbicularis oculi from overlying thin eyelid skin can be determined.</td></tr><tr><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Structural deficits</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">To accentuate dark circles caused by structural deficits and/or eye bags: Use an overhead light directly above the patient or dim the ambient light.</td></tr><tr><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Eye bags</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">To accentuate the presence and contribution of eye bags to dark circle: ask the patient to look up, without changing their facial position. The protuberance of eye bags will increase the prominence of dark circles.</td></tr></tbody></table></table-wrap></sec><sec id="sjae058-s1.4"><title>Step 2: Assess Midface, Lower Eyelid Fat Pads, and Skin Quality</title><p>Tear trough inspection should include assessment of the fat pad superior and inferior to the lid cheek junction. Superiorly, excess infraorbital fat pads can contribute to the presence or perceived presence of dark circles (<xref rid="sjae058-T2" ref-type="table">Table 2</xref>). Assessment should also include the midface below the lid-cheek junction (<xref rid="sjae058-F3" ref-type="fig">Figure 3</xref>) to determine any midface volume deficit. Assessment of volume deficit should focus specifically on the medial suborbicularis oculi fat (SOOF) and deep medial cheek fat (DMCF) that could be contributing to the demarcation of the lid-cheek junction and the appearance of the dark circles. Liew and DaSilva provide a detailed description on the rigid nature of the tear trough ligamental attachment medially and the extensibility of the central part of the orbital retaining ligament of the lid-cheek junction.<sup><xref rid="sjae058-B15" ref-type="bibr">15</xref></sup></p><fig position="float" id="sjae058-F3" fig-type="figure" orientation="portrait"><label>Figure 3.</label><caption><p>Assess midface and lower eyelid skin quality. Patient images reproduced from Liew and DeSilva (with permission from Georg Thieme Verlag KG).<sup><xref rid="sjae058-B15" ref-type="bibr">15</xref></sup></p></caption><graphic xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" position="float" orientation="portrait" xlink:href="sjae058f3.jpg"/></fig><p>Excess skin, thinness of skin, and skin crepiness have been identified as factors that may negatively impact the results of filler treatments.<sup><xref rid="sjae058-B6" ref-type="bibr">6</xref>,<xref rid="sjae058-B10" ref-type="bibr">10</xref>,<xref rid="sjae058-B15" ref-type="bibr">15</xref></sup> The quality of the lower eyelid skin should be assessed to determine if skin pigmentation is present and contributes to the dark circles. Evaluation of the lower eyelid should encompass objective and subjective measures of skin quality, with validated scales when available (<xref rid="sjae058-T3" ref-type="table">Table 3</xref>).</p><table-wrap position="float" id="sjae058-T3" orientation="portrait"><label>Table 3.</label><caption><p>Skin Quality Factors That Contribute to Dark Eye Circles</p></caption><table frame="hsides" rules="groups"><colgroup span="1"><col align="left" span="1"/></colgroup><thead><tr><th align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Skin quality factors</th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Visually assess the patient for presence/absence of skin quality issues that might compound the appearance of dark circles:<list list-type="bullet"><list-item><p>Thin skin</p></list-item><list-item><p>Laxity</p></list-item><list-item><p>Excess skin</p></list-item><list-item><p>Edema</p></list-item><list-item><p>Wrinkles<sup><xref rid="tblfn1" ref-type="table-fn">a</xref></sup></p></list-item><list-item><p>Pigmentation<sup>b</sup></p></list-item></list></td></tr></tbody></table><table-wrap-foot><fn id="tblfn1"><p>
<sup>a</sup>Validated objective scale, eg, Glogau scale.<sup><xref rid="sjae058-B21" ref-type="bibr">21</xref></sup> &#160;<sup>b</sup>Validated photonumeric assessment scales are available to determine the severity of hyperpigmentation which also account for ethnic differences in skin tone.<sup><xref rid="sjae058-B22" ref-type="bibr">22-25</xref></sup></p></fn></table-wrap-foot></table-wrap></sec><sec id="sjae058-s1.5"><title>Step 3: Palpate the Orbital Rim and Lid-Cheek Junction</title><p>Palpation of the orbital rim is conducted to determine if there is any underlying structural deficit, if so whether it is limited to the orbital rim, part of it or involving the whole orbital rim, and if it involves the maxilla, which is prevalent among East Asian patients.<sup><xref rid="sjae058-B26" ref-type="bibr">26</xref></sup> The orbital vector is determined with the patient in a profile position (<xref rid="sjae058-F4" ref-type="fig">Figure 4</xref>).<sup><xref rid="sjae058-B27" ref-type="bibr">27</xref></sup> It refers to the relative position of the globe to that of the supporting bony orbital floor, which is formed mainly by the maxillary bone.<sup><xref rid="sjae058-B28" ref-type="bibr">28</xref>,<xref rid="sjae058-B29" ref-type="bibr">29</xref></sup> Patients with negative orbital vectors tend to present early with dark circles due to orbital fat prominence. With the patient gazing forward, place a finger on the anterior surface of the orbital rim and determine the relative position of the apex of the cornea to the orbital rim by dropping an imaginary line from apex of the cornea to the orbital rim. The vector is described as positive when the orbital rim is in front of the corneal apex, negative when the orbital rim is behind the cornea and neutral when it is in a vertical plane.<sup><xref rid="sjae058-B17" ref-type="bibr">17</xref></sup> Kato et al provide schematic images showing the relationship between the facial vector and eye bags.<sup><xref rid="sjae058-B17" ref-type="bibr">17</xref></sup></p><fig position="float" id="sjae058-F4" fig-type="figure" orientation="portrait"><label>Figure 4.</label><caption><p>Palpation of the orbital rim and lid-cheek junction. Underlying bone tissue image, sourced from Mendelson and Wong.<sup><xref rid="sjae058-B27" ref-type="bibr">27</xref></sup> *Finger on midface pushing cephalad toward the lid-cheek junction, simulating the effect on volumizing the medial SOOF on lid-cheek junction. DMCF, deep medial cheek fat; SOOF, suborbicularis oculi fat; TTL, tear trough ligament.</p></caption><graphic xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" position="float" orientation="portrait" xlink:href="sjae058f4.jpg"/></fig><p>If tear-trough depression is present, gentle pulling of the skin from the underlying bone with finger and thumb will give an indication of the tightness of the tear trough ligament (TTL). A tight TTL is indicative of a difficult case for optimal correction. In this case, the patient needs to be counseled about realistic expectations from filler treatment.</p><p>In patients with volume loss to the midface, finger maneuvers can simulate the effect of volumizing of the medial SOOF and DMCF on the lid-cheek junction. To help determine the extent to which midfacial volume loss is contributing to the dark circles, gently push the midfacial tissue just caudal to the medial SOOF in a cephalad direction toward the lid-cheek junction. This will simulate the effect of medial SOOF volumization and visually highlight the improvement of the lid-cheek junction.<sup><xref rid="sjae058-B15" ref-type="bibr">15</xref></sup></p></sec><sec id="sjae058-s1.6"><title>Step 4: Patient Classification</title><p>Based on the assessment process above, patients with dark circles associated with some degree of depression or hollowing of the lid-cheek junction can be classified into 2 broad groups (<xref rid="sjae058-T4" ref-type="table">Table 4</xref>). Group 1 comprises patients with dark circle depression that is due to an anatomical structural deficit from the underlying bone. Because this is not associated with aging, these cases tend to be younger patients in their early adulthood. They are not associated with midfacial volume loss. The other, larger group includes those with lid-cheek junction pathology secondary to the aging process, with age-associated maxillary retrusion, deep fat pad volume loss, and the associated degeneration changes of the overlying skin, muscle, and orbital retaining ligament and orbital septum.<sup><xref rid="sjae058-B15" ref-type="bibr">15</xref></sup></p><table-wrap position="float" id="sjae058-T4" orientation="portrait"><label>Table 4.</label><caption><p>Classification of Patients Presenting With Dark Circles</p></caption><table frame="hsides" rules="groups"><colgroup span="1"><col align="left" span="1"/><col align="left" span="1"/></colgroup><thead><tr><th align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Group</th><th align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Characteristics</th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Group 1</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Congenital structural bony deficiencies of:<list list-type="bullet"><list-item><p>Maxilla</p></list-item><list-item><p>Orbital margin/rim</p></list-item></list></td></tr><tr><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Group 2</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Age-related changes (bony recession and soft tissue deflation) with:<list list-type="bullet"><list-item><p>Tear trough and infraorbital hollow (Group 2a)</p></list-item><list-item><p>Prominent eye bags (Group 2b)</p></list-item></list></td></tr></tbody></table><table-wrap-foot><fn id="tblfn2"><p>Adapted from Liew and De Dilva, with permission.<sup><xref rid="sjae058-B15" ref-type="bibr">15</xref></sup></p></fn></table-wrap-foot></table-wrap></sec><sec id="sjae058-s1.7"><title>Group 1: Congenital Structural Deficit of the Underlying Maxilla</title><p>This group of patients tends to present complaining of dark circles early in adulthood or in the late teens. Within this group there are 3 subvariants:</p><list list-type="bullet"><list-item><p>1a: The structural deficit is confined to the medial orbital rim of the maxilla. Patients tend to present in their early adulthood with deep tear-trough depression associated with a minimal degree of extension laterally and minimal to no volume loss of the midface (<xref rid="sup1" ref-type="supplementary-material">Supplemental Figure 3</xref>, available at <ext-link xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xlink:href="https://www.aestheticsurgeryjournal.com" ext-link-type="uri">www.aestheticsurgeryjournal.com</ext-link>).</p></list-item><list-item><p>1b: The entire maxilla is retruded and there is a negative orbital vector (<xref rid="sjae058-F5" ref-type="fig">Figure 5A</xref>). This group of patients tends to present early complaining of dark circles or eye bags. Anatomically, the retrusion of the maxilla creates a &#8220;short orbital floor&#8221; for the size of the globe and the orbital content. This leads to a spillage of the orbital fat beyond the lower orbital rim rather than excessive fat pad, causing &#8220;pseudo eye bags&#8221; at an earlier age (<xref rid="sjae058-F5" ref-type="fig">Figure 5B</xref>). The same anatomical retrusion of the maxilla also creates a recessed alar base with deep nasolabial retrusion at an early age. Group 1b is common among patients of Northeast and Southeast Asian ethnicity.</p></list-item><list-item><p>1c: The structural deficit is confined mainly to the entire maxillary orbital rim. Palpation of the lower orbital rim displays a recessive orbital rim posteriorly beyond that of the body of the maxilla. The lower eyelid in this group tends to be short and recline further posteriorly as it approaches the lid-cheek junction. This eyelid configuration creates a distinct eye appearance of large prominent eyes with excessive scleral show (<xref rid="sup1" ref-type="supplementary-material">Supplemental Figure 4</xref>, available at <ext-link xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xlink:href="https://www.aestheticsurgeryjournal.com" ext-link-type="uri">www.aestheticsurgeryjournal.com</ext-link>). Group 1c is common among patients of Southern Asian, Middle Eastern, Turkish, and Iranian descents.</p></list-item></list><fig position="float" id="sjae058-F5" fig-type="figure" orientation="portrait"><label>Figure 5.</label><caption><p>Classification Group 1b. A 25-year-old female displaying typical features including a negative orbital vector (A) and pseudo eye bags (B, arrow).</p></caption><graphic xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" position="float" orientation="portrait" xlink:href="sjae058f5.jpg"/></fig></sec><sec id="sjae058-s1.8"><title>Group 2: Age-related Changes</title><p>This group of patients tends to present from the late 20s to the early 30s onward, complaining of looking tired and of lower eyelid dark circles. Group 2 constitutes the main bulk of patients seeking treatment for dark circles. This group also encompasses the original Group 1 cohort whose structural deficits are now compounded by the aging process and its sequelae. In this case, the lower eyelid appearance is associated with various degrees of midfacial aging. Within this group there are 2 broad categories:</p><list list-type="bullet"><list-item><p>2a: There is typically recession and hollowing along the lid-cheek junction, and the hollowed appearance may extend across the entire lid-cheek junction (<xref rid="sup1" ref-type="supplementary-material">Supplemental Figure 5</xref>).</p></list-item><list-item><p>2b: These patients present with predominantly lower eye bag formation associated with a varying degree of lid-cheek junction hollowing (<xref rid="sup1" ref-type="supplementary-material">Supplemental Figure S5</xref>, available at <ext-link xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xlink:href="https://www.aestheticsurgeryjournal.com" ext-link-type="uri">www.aestheticsurgeryjournal.com</ext-link>).</p></list-item></list></sec><sec id="sjae058-s1.9"><title>Practical Tips for Treatment Planning</title><p>A detailed description of treatment for each of the above groups is beyond the scope of this article. In essence a more precise understanding of the appearance of the lid-cheek junction pathology, as described through the steps in our assessment framework, enables the clinician to optimize the most logical ways of treating each patient type (<xref rid="sjae058-F6" ref-type="fig">Figure 6</xref>). For example:</p><list list-type="bullet"><list-item><p>Group 1a: Requires precise placement of the minimum amount of the least hygroscopic filler deep on the medial orbital rim, with the aid of stretching of those with a tight TTL to ensure adequate correction with the least amount of product and minimize potential swelling posttreatment.<sup><xref rid="sjae058-B26" ref-type="bibr">26</xref></sup></p></list-item><list-item><p>Group 1b: Requires treatment to deal with the structural retrusion of the maxilla by placement of an appropriate volumizing filler in the medial SOOF, DMCF, and/or deep piriform fat pad. By assessing the patient (<xref rid="sjae058-F7" ref-type="fig">Figure 7A</xref>) and determining the underlying cause of the dark circles (<xref rid="sjae058-F7" ref-type="fig">Figure 7B</xref>), dark circle correction can be accomplished without the need to directly inject the tear trough (<xref rid="sjae058-F7" ref-type="fig">Figure 7C</xref>).</p></list-item><list-item><p>Group 1c: Requires filler placed just below the orbicularis retaining ligament within the upper portion of the medial SOOF and a minute amount of filler placed judiciously on the bony level at the tear-trough depression, where it can be applied as a filler strut to augment the retruded orbital rim and correct the hollowness.</p></list-item><list-item><p>Group 2a: Requires replenishment of volume loss of the medial SOOF and DMCF to see the extent of improvement of the lid-cheek junction (<xref rid="sjae058-F8" ref-type="fig">Figure 8</xref>). Once that is achieved, consultation with the patient should be undertaken to decide if any of the residual deficit in the tear-trough depression needs to be dealt with. If this is determined necessary, then additional smaller volumes of filler can be injected directly into the medial and lateral lid-cheek junction.</p></list-item><list-item><p>Group 2b: Patients in this subgroup are candidates for surgery, and therefore treatment is beyond the scope of this article.</p></list-item></list><fig position="float" id="sjae058-F6" fig-type="figure" orientation="portrait"><label>Figure 6.</label><caption><p>Patient characteristics and treatment planning. DMCF, deep medial cheek fat; SOOF, suborbicularis oculi fat.</p></caption><graphic xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" position="float" orientation="portrait" xlink:href="sjae058f6.jpg"/></fig><fig position="float" id="sjae058-F7" fig-type="figure" orientation="portrait"><label>Figure 7.</label><caption><p>(A) The same Group 1b 25-year-old female shown in <xref rid="sjae058-F5" ref-type="fig">Figure 5</xref> presented with dark lower lid circles. (B) The lower eyelid dark circle is due to structural retrusion of the maxilla. The triangle shows the position of the underlying structural bony deficit and indicates the optimal placement of filler in the medial suborbicularis oculi fat pad and deep medial cheek fat pad to achieve correction. (C) Three months post injection with a small volume of soft hyaluronic acid filler, showing an elevation and effacement of the lid-cheek junction and improved appearance of dark circles without actual treatment of the lower eyelid region.</p></caption><graphic xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" position="float" orientation="portrait" xlink:href="sjae058f7.jpg"/></fig><fig position="float" id="sjae058-F8" fig-type="figure" orientation="portrait"><label>Figure 8.</label><caption><p>Classification Group 2a. (A) A 54-year-old female exhibiting depression across all segments of the lid-cheek junction. (B) The same patient immediately following filling of the medial suborbicularis oculi fat pad and deep medial cheek fat pad with filler, showing elevation and effacement of the central lid-cheek junction. Image reproduced from Liew and DeSilva, with permission from Georg Thieme Verlag KG.<sup><xref rid="sjae058-B15" ref-type="bibr">15</xref></sup></p></caption><graphic xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" position="float" orientation="portrait" xlink:href="sjae058f8.jpg"/></fig></sec></sec><sec sec-type="discussion" id="sjae058-s2"><title>DISCUSSION</title><p>In this article, the phrase &#8220;dark eye circles&#8221; was intentionally utilized because this is the lay term coined by patients as they seek treatment. Equally, this term helps clarify to practitioners the number of etiological factors that can present as common complaints that are not amenable to HA filler treatment.</p><p>HA fillers are an effective solution for the correction of tear-trough deformities.<sup><xref rid="sjae058-B30" ref-type="bibr">30</xref>,<xref rid="sjae058-B31" ref-type="bibr">31</xref></sup> Despite having been available for many years, injecting HA fillers in the tear trough and the lower eyelid is technically challenging and associated with a high incidence of posttreatment complications.<sup><xref rid="sjae058-B6" ref-type="bibr">6</xref>,<xref rid="sjae058-B7" ref-type="bibr">7</xref>,<xref rid="sjae058-B16" ref-type="bibr">16</xref>,<xref rid="sjae058-B32" ref-type="bibr">32</xref>,<xref rid="sjae058-B33" ref-type="bibr">33</xref></sup> Why are we still seeing these problems and what can be done to minimize or avoid them?</p><p>The problem is directly related to the complex anatomy of the tear-trough area. The anatomy of the tear trough and lid-cheek junction has been previously reviewed.<sup><xref rid="sjae058-B15" ref-type="bibr">15</xref></sup> Due to the tight compartmental nature of this region, there is limited space within which to inject filler. If large volumes are injected, they can saturate the deeper muscle layer and be dispersed into the more mobile orbicularis muscle layer. Common complications, both early and late, associated with lower eyelid HA filler injections such as swelling, puffiness, Tyndall effect, and sausage-shaped lumps almost always appear on the medial lid-cheek junction as the result of too much filler being placed directly in 1 treatment, or repeatedly over time, in the tear trough.</p><p>We believe a proper assessment process can guide diagnosis, which in turn underpins appropriate patient selection, choice of management technique, and optimal outcomes. Several classification scales are available to help evaluate tear-trough deformity and guide treatment selection.<sup><xref rid="sjae058-B19" ref-type="bibr">19</xref>,<xref rid="sjae058-B20" ref-type="bibr">20</xref>,<xref rid="sjae058-B34" ref-type="bibr">34-36</xref></sup> Our practitioner survey highlighted a limited use of classification systems and an increased reliance on clinical assessment. However, comprehensive guidance on clinical assessment of dark eye circles is limited. Previous work supports a functional anatomical classification of the lid-cheek junction for soft tissue filler treatment.<sup><xref rid="sjae058-B15" ref-type="bibr">15</xref></sup> This classification has established a simplified clinical approach enabling categorization of patients presenting with dark eye circles into 2 broad groups&#8212;those with tear-trough depression due to underlying congenital bony structural deficits (Group 1) and those with age-related changes (Group 2).<sup><xref rid="sjae058-B15" ref-type="bibr">15</xref></sup> Here we provide a practical application of this classification system for a clinical setting. Through stepwise, detailed examination practitioners can assess patients presenting with lower eyelid dark circles and stratify them to guide a more strategic approach to treatment.</p><p>Palpation of the orbital rim is a crucial assessment step. It is important to determine if there are congenital abnormalities predisposing the patient to under-eye hollowness, particularly in younger patients in whom age-related changes do not yet apply.<sup><xref rid="sjae058-B37" ref-type="bibr">37</xref></sup> While ethnic differences in orbital rim morphology and depth of the orbital floor should be accounted for, it is established that filler in 1 area can enhance other areas without direct injection.<sup><xref rid="sjae058-B14" ref-type="bibr">14</xref>,<xref rid="sjae058-B15" ref-type="bibr">15</xref>,<xref rid="sjae058-B38" ref-type="bibr">38-41</xref></sup> Reflation of the SOOF and DMCF with HA filler can improve the appearance of the central part of the lid-cheek junction without requiring direct treatment of the lid-cheek junction itself. Foregoing the need for direct HA filler injection into the tear trough negates the risks of posttreatment complications due to overfilling in this area.</p><p>During initial physical inspection of the patient, the authors recommend strategic lighting and assessment from multiple views to provide helpful insights about the various underlying pathological and anatomical causes of shadowing. Overhead lighting worsens the appearance of dark eye circles, while direct lighting may mask them. Turning down the light intensity in the room helps to reveal the shadows, and looking at the oblique view helps to better visualize the extent of any infraorbital hollowing.</p><p>Three key contributors of skin quality to dark eye circles have been identified; lower eyelid skin thickness, the number and/or thickness of under-eye capillaries, and hyperpigmentation.<sup><xref rid="sjae058-B22" ref-type="bibr">22</xref></sup> The lower eyelid skin is extremely thin.<sup><xref rid="sjae058-B42" ref-type="bibr">42</xref></sup> It is also inelastic due to lower levels of collagen, elastin, and glycosaminoglycans than are observed in other areas of the face, and dry due to the presence of few sebaceous glands.<sup><xref rid="sjae058-B43" ref-type="bibr">43</xref></sup> Thinner skin contributes to the appearance of dark circles because it increases the likelihood that underlying pigmentation and dilated vessels are visible.<sup><xref rid="sjae058-B22" ref-type="bibr">22</xref></sup> This is further compounded by the aging process, during which loss of elasticity leads to folding and redundancy (dermatochalasis) with associated increases in edema, laxity, and sagging that accentuate the appearance of dark circles, and the appearance of wrinkles that accentuate the extent of fat prolapse and the depth of the visible grooves.<sup><xref rid="sjae058-B43" ref-type="bibr">43-45</xref></sup> Careful lighting and stretching of the skin allow a detailed inspection of the eyelid skin quality and can confirm or rule out pigmentation. Pigmentation does not contribute directly to the depth of the tear trough; rather it creates an illusion of depth.<sup><xref rid="sjae058-B45" ref-type="bibr">45</xref></sup> Pigmentation of the lower eyelid skin is relatively common as part of the presentation of dark circles, but will not be improved by HA filler injection.<sup><xref rid="sjae058-B44" ref-type="bibr">44</xref></sup> Irrespective of whether a patient falls into functional classification Group 1 or Group 2, if pigmentation is a contributory cause of their dark circles counseling on outcomes is paramount. Patients should be made aware of this and offered additional treatment options when necessary and appropriate.</p><p>This work has been underpinned by literature and expert opinion. The literature provides ample guidance on anatomy, injection technique, and management of posttreatment complications.<sup><xref rid="sjae058-B6" ref-type="bibr">6-8</xref>,<xref rid="sjae058-B10" ref-type="bibr">10-16</xref></sup> But practical guidance on patient assessment is limited. The practitioner survey highlighted a preference for clinical assessment over formal classification systems, which in turn drove the development of an assessment algorithm. However, this research was undertaken in a selective group that could have introduced opinion bias. Although we do not believe this limitation to have resulted in any significant negative impact, future refinement might come from the application of the algorithm in a more diverse population. Formal further study is not necessary because the algorithm is not intended to provide a formal validated scale. However, it is our hope that in the future it can be incorporated into educational meetings at which attendees can be taught how to use the algorithm and apply it in their day-to-day practice.</p></sec><sec id="sjae058-s3"><title>CONCLUSIONS</title><p>The utilization of HA fillers for dark eye circles is popular but challenging and associated with a high rate of complications. We present a comprehensive assessment framework that combines inspection, assessment, and palpation. The overall aim is to encourage practitioners to pause and think before they treat, rather than simply treating the problem location. Careful step-by-step assessment, conducted with judicious lighting, can help to identify patients in whom dark eye circles may be improved without the need to directly inject HA filler into the tear trough. Correct patient classification can facilitate individualized treatment planning and optimize treatment outcomes while avoiding the known challenges associated with treating this area.</p></sec><sec id="sjae058-s4"><title>Supplemental Material</title><p>This article contains <xref rid="sup1" ref-type="supplementary-material">supplemental material</xref> located online at <ext-link xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xlink:href="https://www.aestheticsurgeryjournal.com" ext-link-type="uri">www.aestheticsurgeryjournal.com</ext-link>.</p></sec><sec sec-type="supplementary-material"><title>Supplementary Material</title><supplementary-material id="sup1" position="float" content-type="local-data" orientation="portrait"><label>sjae058_Supplementary_Data</label><media xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xlink:href="sjae058_supplementary_data.zip" position="float" orientation="portrait"/></supplementary-material></sec></body><back><ack id="ack1"><title>Acknowledgments</title><p>The authors thank the co-chairs of the Scientific Exchange Working Group for their input into the early stages of this work, including the development and analysis of the practitioner survey. The authors thank Hazel Palmer MSc, ISMPP, CMPP of Scriptix Pty Ltd (Sydney, NSW, Australia) for providing administrative support, professional writing assistance, and editorial support in the preparation of this manuscript, which, in accordance with the Good Publication Practice guidelines as defined by the International Society for Medical Publication Professionals, was funded through an educational grant provided by Galderma Australia Pty Ltd. Members of the Scientific Exchange Working Group were as follows: Steven Liew, MBBS, FRACS; Simone Doreian, MBBS, FCPCA, FRACGP, DRANZCOG; Greg J. Goodman, MBBS (Hons), GradDipClinEpi, FACD; Katherine Armour, MBChB, FACD; Christoph Martschin, MD; Van Park, MD; Frank Rosengaus, MD; and Kate Morlet-Brown, MD.</p></ack><sec id="sjae058-s5"><title>Disclosures</title><p>Dr Liew reports having received honoraria for the Scientific Exchange Working Group and travel support for attending the focus group meeting from Galderma Australia Pty Ltd. (North Sydney NSW, Australia). Outside of the current work, he receives royalties as the owner of the Complete Face app (Darlinghurst, NSW, Australia), consulting fees for advisory board attendance from Galderma (Lausanne, Switzerland), Allergan (Irvine, CA), Teoxane (Geneva, Switzerland), and BTL Industries (Stevenage, Hertfordshire, UK); honoraria for teaching lectures and workshops from Galderma, Allergan, and Teoxane; and travel support for attending meetings from Allergan and Galderma. Dr Doreian reports having received honoraria for the working group and travel support for attending the focus group meeting from Galderma Australia Pty Ltd. and, outside the current work, honoraria for teaching lectures and workshops, travel support for attending meetings, and participation in advisory boards from Galderma Australia Pty Ltd. Drs Kunathathorn Lam and Lan declared no potential conflicts of interest with respect to the research, authorship, and publication of this article. Dr Jorge reports having received travel support for attending meetings and honoraria as a customer education lead from Galderma Philippines Inc. (Pasig, Philippines). He is the Philippine subdistributor, CEO, and Medical Director of Skinmedicine Inc. (Quezon City, Philippines). Dr Selkon reports having received consulting fees, honoraria for speaking events, payment for expert testimony, support for attending meetings, participation in an advisory board, and receipt of equipment and materials from Galderma Australia Pty Ltd., and consulting fees, honoraria for speaking events, payment for expert testimony, and receipt of equipment and materials from Dermocosm&#232;tica (Melbourne, VIC, Australia) on behalf of her private practice establishment. Dr Arensde reports having received travel support for attending the focus group meeting from Galderma Australia Pty Ltd. Outside the current work he has received travel support for attending meetings from Cutera (Brisbane, CA) and holding a leadership role in the Cosmetic Physicians College of Australia. Dr Silleri has received travel support for attending the focus group meeting from Galderma Australia Pty Ltd. Ms Telfer is an employee of Galderma Australia Pty Ltd.</p></sec><sec id="sjae058-s6"><title>Funding</title><p>Galderma Australia Pty Ltd (North Sydney NSW, Australia) funded the study and editorial assistance (Hazel Palmer ISMP CMPP, Scriptix Pty Ltd). The authors were responsible for all content, interpretation of the data, and the decision to publish the results. The authors received no honoraria related to the development of this manuscript.</p></sec><ref-list id="ref1"><title>REFERENCES</title><ref id="sjae058-B1"><label>1</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><string-name name-style="western"><surname>Liew</surname> &#160;<given-names>S</given-names></string-name>, <string-name name-style="western"><surname>Nguyen</surname> &#160;<given-names>DQA</given-names></string-name></person-group>. <article-title>Nonsurgical volumetric upper periorbital rejuvenation: a plastic surgeon's perspective</article-title>. <source>Aesthetic Plast Surg</source>. <year>2011</year>;<volume>35</volume>(<issue>3</issue>):<fpage>319</fpage>&#8211;<lpage>325</lpage>. doi: <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1007/s00266-010-9609-4</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">21046102</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="sjae058-B2"><label>2</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><string-name name-style="western"><surname>Bravo</surname> &#160;<given-names>BSF</given-names></string-name>, <string-name name-style="western"><surname>Rocha</surname> &#160;<given-names>CRM</given-names></string-name>, <string-name name-style="western"><surname>De Bastos</surname> &#160;<given-names>JT</given-names></string-name>, <string-name name-style="western"><surname>Silva</surname> &#160;<given-names>PMCE</given-names></string-name></person-group>. <article-title>Comprehensive treatment of periorbital region with hyaluronic acid</article-title>. <source>J Clin Aesthet Dermatol</source>. <year>2015</year>;<volume>8</volume>(<issue>6</issue>):<fpage>30</fpage>&#8211;<lpage>35</lpage>.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC4479367</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">26155325</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="sjae058-B3"><label>3</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><string-name name-style="western"><surname>Sundelin</surname> &#160;<given-names>T</given-names></string-name>, <string-name name-style="western"><surname>Lekander</surname> &#160;<given-names>M</given-names></string-name>, <string-name name-style="western"><surname>Kecklund</surname> &#160;<given-names>G</given-names></string-name>, <string-name name-style="western"><surname>Van Someren</surname> &#160;<given-names>EJ</given-names></string-name>, <string-name name-style="western"><surname>Olsson</surname> &#160;<given-names>A</given-names></string-name>, <string-name name-style="western"><surname>Axelsson</surname> &#160;<given-names>J</given-names></string-name></person-group>. <article-title>Cues of fatigue: effects of sleep deprivation on facial appearance</article-title>. <source>Sleep</source>. <year>2013</year>;<volume>36</volume>(<issue>9</issue>):<fpage>1355</fpage>&#8211;<lpage>1360</lpage>. doi: <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.5665/sleep.2964</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">23997369</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC3738045</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="sjae058-B4"><label>4</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><string-name name-style="western"><surname>Fabi</surname> &#160;<given-names>S</given-names></string-name>, <string-name name-style="western"><surname>Alexiades</surname> &#160;<given-names>M</given-names></string-name>, <string-name name-style="western"><surname>Chatrath</surname> &#160;<given-names>V</given-names></string-name>, <etal>et al</etal></person-group> &#160;<article-title>Facial aesthetic priorities and concerns: a physician and patient perception global survey</article-title>. <source>Aesthet Surg J</source>. <year>2022</year>;<volume>42</volume>(<issue>4</issue>):<fpage>NP218</fpage>&#8211;<lpage>NP229</lpage>. doi: <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1093/asj/sjab358</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">34626170</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC8922705</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="sjae058-B5"><label>5</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><string-name name-style="western"><surname>Gorbea</surname> &#160;<given-names>E</given-names></string-name>, <string-name name-style="western"><surname>Kidwai</surname> &#160;<given-names>S</given-names></string-name>, <string-name name-style="western"><surname>Rosenberg</surname> &#160;<given-names>J</given-names></string-name></person-group>. <article-title>Nonsurgical tear trough volumization: a systematic review of patient satisfaction</article-title>. <source>Aesthet Surg J</source>. <year>2021</year>;<volume>41</volume>(<issue>8</issue>):<fpage>NP1053</fpage>&#8211;<lpage>NP1060</lpage>. doi: <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1093/asj/sjab116</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">33693530</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="sjae058-B6"><label>6</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><string-name name-style="western"><surname>Anido</surname> &#160;<given-names>J</given-names></string-name>, <string-name name-style="western"><surname>Fern&#225;ndez</surname> &#160;<given-names>JM</given-names></string-name>, <string-name name-style="western"><surname>Genol</surname> &#160;<given-names>I</given-names></string-name>, <string-name name-style="western"><surname>Rib&#233;</surname> &#160;<given-names>N</given-names></string-name>, <string-name name-style="western"><surname>Perez Sevilla</surname> &#160;<given-names>G</given-names></string-name></person-group>. <article-title>Recommendations for the treatment of tear trough deformity with cross-linked hyaluronic acid filler</article-title>. <source>J Cosmet Dermatol</source>. <year>2021</year>;<volume>20</volume>(<issue>1</issue>):<fpage>6</fpage>&#8211;<lpage>17</lpage>. doi: <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1111/jocd.13475</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">32844581</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC7818415</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="sjae058-B7"><label>7</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><string-name name-style="western"><surname>Urdiales-G&#225;lvez</surname> &#160;<given-names>F</given-names></string-name>, <string-name name-style="western"><surname>Farollch-Prats</surname> &#160;<given-names>L</given-names></string-name></person-group>. <article-title>Management of tear trough with hyaluronic acid fillers: a clinical-practice dual approach</article-title>. <source>Clin Cosmet Investig Dermatol</source>. <year>2021</year>;<volume>14</volume>:<fpage>467</fpage>&#8211;<lpage>483</lpage>. doi: <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.2147/ccid.S301117</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC8127324</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">34012281</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="sjae058-B8"><label>8</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><string-name name-style="western"><surname>Zein</surname> &#160;<given-names>M</given-names></string-name>, <string-name name-style="western"><surname>Tie-Shue</surname> &#160;<given-names>R</given-names></string-name>, <string-name name-style="western"><surname>Pirakitikulr</surname> &#160;<given-names>N</given-names></string-name>, <string-name name-style="western"><surname>Lee</surname> &#160;<given-names>WW</given-names></string-name></person-group>. <article-title>Complications after cosmetic periocular filler: prevention and management</article-title>. <source>Plast Aesthet Res</source>. <year>2020</year>;<volume>7</volume>:<fpage>44</fpage>. doi: <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.20517/2347-9264.2020.133</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">33102629</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC7583139</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="sjae058-B9"><label>9</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><string-name name-style="western"><surname>D&#8217;Amato</surname> &#160;<given-names>S</given-names></string-name>, <string-name name-style="western"><surname>Fragola</surname> &#160;<given-names>R</given-names></string-name>, <string-name name-style="western"><surname>Bove</surname> &#160;<given-names>P</given-names></string-name>, <etal>et al</etal></person-group> &#160;<article-title>Is the treatment of the tear trough deformity with hyaluronic acid injections a safe procedure? A systematic review</article-title>. <source>Appl Sci</source>. <year>2021</year>;<volume>11</volume>(<issue>23</issue>):<fpage>11489</fpage>. doi: <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.3390/app112311489</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="sjae058-B10"><label>10</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><string-name name-style="western"><surname>Sharad</surname> &#160;<given-names>J</given-names></string-name></person-group>. <article-title>Dermal fillers for the treatment of tear trough deformity: a review of anatomy, treatment techniques, and their outcomes</article-title>. <source>J Cutan Aesthet Surg</source>. <year>2012</year>;<volume>5</volume>(<issue>4</issue>):<fpage>229</fpage>&#8211;<lpage>238</lpage>. doi: <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.4103/0974-2077.104910</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">23378704</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC3560162</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="sjae058-B11"><label>11</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><string-name name-style="western"><surname>Sharad</surname> &#160;<given-names>J</given-names></string-name></person-group>. <article-title>Treatment of the tear trough and infraorbital hollow with hyaluronic acid fillers using both needle and cannula</article-title>. <source>Dermatol Ther</source>. <year>2020</year>;<volume>33</volume>(<issue>3</issue>):<fpage>e13353</fpage>. doi: <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1111/dth.13353</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">32239729</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="sjae058-B12"><label>12</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><string-name name-style="western"><surname>Tr&#233;vidic</surname> &#160;<given-names>P</given-names></string-name>, <string-name name-style="western"><surname>Kaufman-Janette</surname> &#160;<given-names>J</given-names></string-name>, <string-name name-style="western"><surname>Weinkle</surname> &#160;<given-names>S</given-names></string-name>, <etal>et al</etal></person-group> &#160;<article-title>Injection guidelines for treating midface volume deficiency with hyaluronic acid fillers: the ATP approach (anatomy, techniques, products)</article-title>. <source>Aesthet Surg J</source>. <year>2022</year>;<volume>42</volume>(<issue>8</issue>):<fpage>920</fpage>&#8211;<lpage>934</lpage>. doi: <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1093/asj/sjac007</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">35039828</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC9373948</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="sjae058-B13"><label>13</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><string-name name-style="western"><surname>Lee</surname> &#160;<given-names>J-H</given-names></string-name>, <string-name name-style="western"><surname>Hong</surname> &#160;<given-names>G</given-names></string-name></person-group>. <article-title>Definitions of groove and hollowness of the infraorbital region and clinical treatment using soft-tissue filler</article-title>. <source>Arch Plast Surg</source>. <year>2018</year>;<volume>45</volume>(<issue>3</issue>):<fpage>214</fpage>&#8211;<lpage>221</lpage>. doi: <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.5999/aps.2017.01193</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">29788683</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC5968317</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="sjae058-B14"><label>14</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><string-name name-style="western"><surname>Woodward</surname> &#160;<given-names>J</given-names></string-name>, <string-name name-style="western"><surname>Cox</surname> &#160;<given-names>SE</given-names></string-name>, <string-name name-style="western"><surname>Kato</surname> &#160;<given-names>K</given-names></string-name>, <string-name name-style="western"><surname>Urdiales-Galvez</surname> &#160;<given-names>F</given-names></string-name>, <string-name name-style="western"><surname>Boyd</surname> &#160;<given-names>C</given-names></string-name>, <string-name name-style="western"><surname>Ashourian</surname> &#160;<given-names>N</given-names></string-name></person-group>. <article-title>Infraorbital hollow rejuvenation: considerations, complications, and the contributions of midface volumization</article-title>. <source>Aesthet Surg J Open Forum</source>. <year>2023</year>;<volume>5</volume>:ojad016. doi: <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1093/asjof/ojad016</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC10045888</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">36998744</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="sjae058-B15"><label>15</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><string-name name-style="western"><surname>Liew</surname> &#160;<given-names>S</given-names></string-name>, <string-name name-style="western"><surname>De Silva</surname> &#160;<given-names>D</given-names></string-name></person-group>. <article-title>Tear trough and lid-cheek junction anatomy: current understanding and nonsurgical treatment</article-title>. <source>Facial Plast Surg</source>. <year>2022</year>;<volume>38</volume>(<issue>2</issue>):<fpage>143</fpage>&#8211;<lpage>151</lpage>. doi: <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1055/s-0041-1741498</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">35114710</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="sjae058-B16"><label>16</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><string-name name-style="western"><surname>Trinh</surname> &#160;<given-names>LN</given-names></string-name>, <string-name name-style="western"><surname>McGuigan</surname> &#160;<given-names>KC</given-names></string-name>, <string-name name-style="western"><surname>Gupta</surname> &#160;<given-names>A</given-names></string-name></person-group>. <article-title>Delayed complications following dermal filler for tear trough augmentation: a systematic review</article-title>. <source>Facial Plast Surg</source>. <year>2022</year>;<volume>38</volume>(<issue>3</issue>):<fpage>250</fpage>&#8211;<lpage>259</lpage>. doi: <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1055/s-0041-1736390</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">34666405</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="sjae058-B17"><label>17</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><string-name name-style="western"><surname>Kato</surname> &#160;<given-names>K</given-names></string-name>, <string-name name-style="western"><surname>Kajiwara</surname> &#160;<given-names>T</given-names></string-name>, <string-name name-style="western"><surname>Furuyama</surname> &#160;<given-names>N</given-names></string-name>, <string-name name-style="western"><surname>Liew</surname> &#160;<given-names>S</given-names></string-name></person-group>. <article-title>Filler-based correction of tear trough depressions and eye bags in Japanese patients: a classification system and treatment algorithm</article-title>. <source>J Cosmet Dermatol</source>. <year>2023</year>;<volume>22</volume>(<issue>2</issue>):<fpage>439</fpage>&#8211;<lpage>448</lpage>. doi: <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1111/jocd.15449</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">36208029</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC10092177</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="sjae058-B18"><label>18</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><string-name name-style="western"><surname>Rice</surname> &#160;<given-names>SM</given-names></string-name>, <string-name name-style="western"><surname>Siegel</surname> &#160;<given-names>JA</given-names></string-name>, <string-name name-style="western"><surname>Libby</surname> &#160;<given-names>T</given-names></string-name>, <string-name name-style="western"><surname>Graber</surname> &#160;<given-names>E</given-names></string-name>, <string-name name-style="western"><surname>Kourosh</surname> &#160;<given-names>AS</given-names></string-name></person-group>. <article-title>Zooming into cosmetic procedures during the COVID-19 pandemic: the provider's perspective</article-title>. <source>Int J Women's Dermatol</source>. <year>2021</year>;<volume>7</volume>(<issue>2</issue>):<fpage>213</fpage>&#8211;<lpage>216</lpage>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1016/j.ijwd.2021.01.012</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">33937497</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC8072483</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="sjae058-B19"><label>19</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><string-name name-style="western"><surname>Hirmand</surname> &#160;<given-names>H</given-names></string-name></person-group>. <article-title>Anatomy and nonsurgical correction of the tear trough deformity</article-title>. <source>Plast Reconstr Surg</source>. <year>2010</year>;<volume>125</volume>(<issue>2</issue>):<fpage>699</fpage>&#8211;<lpage>708</lpage>. doi: <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1097/PRS.0b013e3181c82f90</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">20124855</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="sjae058-B20"><label>20</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><string-name name-style="western"><surname>Barton</surname> &#160;<given-names>FE</given-names> &#160;<suffix>Jr</suffix></string-name>, <string-name name-style="western"><surname>Ha</surname> &#160;<given-names>R</given-names></string-name>, <string-name name-style="western"><surname>Awada</surname> &#160;<given-names>M</given-names></string-name></person-group>. <article-title>Fat extrusion and septal reset in patients with the tear trough triad: a critical appraisal</article-title>. <source>Plast Reconstr Surg</source>. <year>2004</year>;<volume>113</volume>(<issue>7</issue>):<fpage>2115</fpage>&#8211;<lpage>2121</lpage>; discussion 2122-3. doi: <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1097/01.prs.0000122409.00716.34</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">15253207</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="sjae058-B21"><label>21</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><string-name name-style="western"><surname>Glogau</surname> &#160;<given-names>RG</given-names></string-name></person-group>. <article-title>Aesthetic and anatomic analysis of the aging skin</article-title>. <source>Semin Cutan Med Surg</source>. <year>1996</year>;<volume>15</volume>(<issue>3</issue>):<fpage>134</fpage>&#8211;<lpage>138</lpage>. doi: <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1016/s1085-5629(96)80003-4</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">8948530</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="sjae058-B22"><label>22</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><string-name name-style="western"><surname>Mac-Mary</surname> &#160;<given-names>S</given-names></string-name>, <string-name name-style="western"><surname>Zornoza Solinis</surname> &#160;<given-names>I</given-names></string-name>, <string-name name-style="western"><surname>Predine</surname> &#160;<given-names>O</given-names></string-name>, <etal>et al</etal></person-group> &#160;<article-title>Identification of three key factors contributing to the aetiology of dark circles by clinical and instrumental assessments of the infraorbital region</article-title>. <source>Clin Cosmet Investig Dermatol</source>. <year>2019</year>;<volume>12</volume>:<fpage>919</fpage>&#8211;<lpage>929</lpage>. doi: <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.2147/ccid.S217956</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC6927230</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">31908515</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="sjae058-B23"><label>23</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><string-name name-style="western"><surname>Tan</surname> &#160;<given-names>Y</given-names></string-name>, <string-name name-style="western"><surname>Jiang</surname> &#160;<given-names>Y</given-names></string-name>, <string-name name-style="western"><surname>Chen</surname> &#160;<given-names>J</given-names></string-name>, <string-name name-style="western"><surname>Sun</surname> &#160;<given-names>H</given-names></string-name>, <string-name name-style="western"><surname>Qiu</surname> &#160;<given-names>Y</given-names></string-name></person-group>. <article-title>Establishment of visual assessment for the severity of dark circles in Chinese Han women</article-title>. <source>Skin Res Technol</source>. <year>2021</year>;<volume>27</volume>(<issue>6</issue>):<fpage>1023</fpage>&#8211;<lpage>1028</lpage>. doi: <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1111/srt.13052</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">33998699</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC9290015</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="sjae058-B24"><label>24</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><string-name name-style="western"><surname>Park</surname> &#160;<given-names>SR</given-names></string-name>, <string-name name-style="western"><surname>Kim</surname> &#160;<given-names>HJ</given-names></string-name>, <string-name name-style="western"><surname>Park</surname> &#160;<given-names>HK</given-names></string-name>, <etal>et al</etal></person-group> &#160;<article-title>Classification by causes of dark circles and appropriate evaluation method of dark circles</article-title>. <source>Skin Res Technol</source>. <year>2016</year>;<volume>22</volume>(<issue>3</issue>):<fpage>276</fpage>&#8211;<lpage>283</lpage>. doi: <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1111/srt.12258</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">26346687</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="sjae058-B25"><label>25</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><string-name name-style="western"><surname>O'Mahony</surname> &#160;<given-names>MM</given-names></string-name>, <string-name name-style="western"><surname>Sladen</surname> &#160;<given-names>C</given-names></string-name>, <string-name name-style="western"><surname>Crone</surname> &#160;<given-names>M</given-names></string-name>, <etal>et al</etal></person-group> &#160;<article-title>A validated photonumeric scale for infraorbital dark circles and its application in evaluating the efficacy of a cosmetic treatment product in a split-face randomized clinical trial</article-title>. <source>Int J Cosmet Sci</source>. <year>2021</year>;<volume>43</volume>(<issue>1</issue>):<fpage>48</fpage>&#8211;<lpage>56</lpage>. doi: <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1111/ics.12668</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">33038017</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC7898348</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="sjae058-B26"><label>26</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><string-name name-style="western"><surname>Philippe</surname> &#160;<given-names>B</given-names></string-name>, <string-name name-style="western"><surname>Atlan</surname> &#160;<given-names>L</given-names></string-name>, <string-name name-style="western"><surname>Hubschman</surname> &#160;<given-names>S</given-names></string-name>, <string-name name-style="western"><surname>Converset</surname> &#160;<given-names>S</given-names></string-name>, <string-name name-style="western"><surname>Enright</surname> &#160;<given-names>KM</given-names></string-name>, <string-name name-style="western"><surname>Nikolis</surname> &#160;<given-names>A</given-names></string-name></person-group>. <article-title>Novel treatment protocol for combined tear through ligament stretching and injection</article-title>. <source>Plast Reconstr Surg</source>. <year>2023</year>;<volume>152</volume>(<issue>5</issue>):<fpage>808e</fpage>&#8211;<lpage>816e</lpage>. doi: <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1097/prs.0000000000010410</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">36912918</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="sjae058-B27"><label>27</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><string-name name-style="western"><surname>Mendelson</surname> &#160;<given-names>B</given-names></string-name>, <string-name name-style="western"><surname>Wong</surname> &#160;<given-names>C-H</given-names></string-name></person-group>. <article-title>Changes in the facial skeleton with aging: implications and clinical applications in facial rejuvenation</article-title>. <source>Aesthetic Plast Surg</source>. <year>2012</year>;<volume>36</volume>(<issue>4</issue>):<fpage>753</fpage>&#8211;<lpage>760</lpage>. doi: <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1007/s00266-012-9904-3</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">22580543</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC3404279</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="sjae058-B28"><label>28</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><string-name name-style="western"><surname>Jelks</surname> &#160;<given-names>GW</given-names></string-name>, <string-name name-style="western"><surname>Jelks</surname> &#160;<given-names>EB</given-names></string-name></person-group>. <article-title>Preoperative evaluation of the blepharoplasty patient. Bypassing the pitfalls</article-title>. <source>Clin Plast Surg</source>. <year>1993</year>;<volume>20</volume>(<issue>2</issue>):<fpage>213</fpage>&#8211;<lpage>223</lpage>; discussion 224. doi: <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1016/S0094-1298(20)31213-X</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">8485931</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="sjae058-B29"><label>29</label><mixed-citation publication-type="book"><person-group person-group-type="author"><string-name name-style="western"><surname>Cohen</surname> &#160;<given-names>AJ</given-names></string-name>, <string-name name-style="western"><surname>Burkat</surname> &#160;<given-names>CN</given-names></string-name></person-group>. <source>Oculofacial, Orbital, and Lacrimal Surgery: A Compendium</source>. <publisher-name>Springer Nature</publisher-name>; <year>2019</year>.</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="sjae058-B30"><label>30</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><string-name name-style="western"><surname>Nikolis</surname> &#160;<given-names>A</given-names></string-name>, <string-name name-style="western"><surname>Berros</surname> &#160;<given-names>P</given-names></string-name>, <string-name name-style="western"><surname>Enright</surname> &#160;<given-names>KM</given-names></string-name>, <string-name name-style="western"><surname>Cordoba</surname> &#160;<given-names>M</given-names></string-name>, <string-name name-style="western"><surname>Nguyen</surname> &#160;<given-names>Q</given-names></string-name></person-group>. <article-title>A randomized, crossover-controlled evaluator-blinded trial evaluating cannula- vs needle-assisted hyaluronic acid injections for infraorbital deformities</article-title>. <source>Aesthet Surg J</source>. <year>2022</year>;<volume>42</volume>(<issue>3</issue>):<fpage>285</fpage>&#8211;<lpage>297</lpage>. doi: <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1093/asj/sjab284</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">34282831</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="sjae058-B31"><label>31</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><string-name name-style="western"><surname>Nikolis</surname> &#160;<given-names>A</given-names></string-name>, <string-name name-style="western"><surname>Chesnut</surname> &#160;<given-names>C</given-names></string-name>, <string-name name-style="western"><surname>Biesman</surname> &#160;<given-names>B</given-names></string-name>, <etal>et al</etal></person-group> &#160;<article-title>Expert recommendations on the use of hyaluronic acid filler for tear trough rejuvenation</article-title>. <source>J Drugs Dermatol</source>. <year>2022</year>;<volume>21</volume>(<issue>4</issue>):<fpage>387</fpage>&#8211;<lpage>392</lpage>. doi: <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.36849/jdd.6597</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">35389598</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="sjae058-B32"><label>32</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><string-name name-style="western"><surname>Trinh</surname> &#160;<given-names>LN</given-names></string-name>, <string-name name-style="western"><surname>Grond</surname> &#160;<given-names>SE</given-names></string-name>, <string-name name-style="western"><surname>Gupta</surname> &#160;<given-names>A</given-names></string-name></person-group>. <article-title>Dermal fillers for tear trough rejuvenation: a systematic review</article-title>. <source>Facial Plast Surg</source>. <year>2022</year>;<volume>38</volume>(<issue>3</issue>):<fpage>228</fpage>&#8211;<lpage>239</lpage>. doi: <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1055/s-0041-1731348</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">34192769</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="sjae058-B33"><label>33</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><string-name name-style="western"><surname>Liu</surname> &#160;<given-names>X</given-names></string-name>, <string-name name-style="western"><surname>Gao</surname> &#160;<given-names>Y</given-names></string-name>, <string-name name-style="western"><surname>Ma</surname> &#160;<given-names>J</given-names></string-name>, <string-name name-style="western"><surname>Li</surname> &#160;<given-names>J</given-names></string-name></person-group>. <article-title>The efficacy and safety of hyaluronic acid injection in tear trough deformity: a systematic review and meta-analysis</article-title>. <source>Aesthetic Plast Surg</source>. <year>2024</year>;<volume>48</volume>(<issue>3</issue>):<fpage>478</fpage>&#8211;<lpage>490</lpage>. doi: <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1007/s00266-023-03613-7</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">37684413</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="sjae058-B34"><label>34</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><string-name name-style="western"><surname>Sadick</surname> &#160;<given-names>NS</given-names></string-name>, <string-name name-style="western"><surname>Bosniak</surname> &#160;<given-names>SL</given-names></string-name>, <string-name name-style="western"><surname>Cantisano-Zilkha</surname> &#160;<given-names>M</given-names></string-name>, <string-name name-style="western"><surname>Glavas</surname> &#160;<given-names>IP</given-names></string-name>, <string-name name-style="western"><surname>Roy</surname> &#160;<given-names>D</given-names></string-name></person-group>. <article-title>Definition of the tear trough and the tear trough rating scale</article-title>. <source>J Cosmet Dermatol</source>. <year>2007</year>;<volume>6</volume>(<issue>4</issue>):<fpage>218</fpage>&#8211;<lpage>222</lpage>. doi: <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1111/j.1473-2165.2007.00336.x</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">18047604</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="sjae058-B35"><label>35</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><string-name name-style="western"><surname>Turkmani</surname> &#160;<given-names>MG</given-names></string-name></person-group>. <article-title>New classification system for tear trough deformity</article-title>. <source>Dermatol Surg</source>. <year>2017</year>;<volume>43</volume>(<issue>6</issue>):<fpage>836</fpage>&#8211;<lpage>840</lpage>. doi: <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1097/dss.0000000000001056</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">28244901</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="sjae058-B36"><label>36</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><string-name name-style="western"><surname>Jiang</surname> &#160;<given-names>J</given-names></string-name>, <string-name name-style="western"><surname>Wang</surname> &#160;<given-names>X</given-names></string-name>, <string-name name-style="western"><surname>Chen</surname> &#160;<given-names>R</given-names></string-name>, <string-name name-style="western"><surname>Xia</surname> &#160;<given-names>X</given-names></string-name>, <string-name name-style="western"><surname>Sun</surname> &#160;<given-names>S</given-names></string-name>, <string-name name-style="western"><surname>Hu</surname> &#160;<given-names>K</given-names></string-name></person-group>. <article-title>Tear trough deformity: different types of anatomy and treatment options</article-title>. <source>Postepy Dermatol Alergol</source>. <year>2016</year>;<volume>33</volume>(<issue>4</issue>):<fpage>303</fpage>&#8211;<lpage>308</lpage>. doi: <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.5114/ada.2016.61607</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">27605904</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC5004220</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="sjae058-B37"><label>37</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><string-name name-style="western"><surname>Liew</surname> &#160;<given-names>S</given-names></string-name>, <string-name name-style="western"><surname>Wu</surname> &#160;<given-names>WTL</given-names></string-name>, <string-name name-style="western"><surname>Chan</surname> &#160;<given-names>HH</given-names></string-name>, <etal>et al</etal></person-group> &#160;<article-title>Consensus on changing trends, attitudes, and concepts of Asian beauty</article-title>. <source>Aesthetic Plast Surg</source>. <year>2020</year>;<volume>44</volume>(<issue>4</issue>):<fpage>1186</fpage>&#8211;<lpage>1194</lpage>. doi: <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1007/s00266-020-01808-w</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">32844263</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="sjae058-B38"><label>38</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><string-name name-style="western"><surname>Patra</surname> &#160;<given-names>A</given-names></string-name>, <string-name name-style="western"><surname>Singla</surname> &#160;<given-names>RK</given-names></string-name>, <string-name name-style="western"><surname>Mathur</surname> &#160;<given-names>M</given-names></string-name>, <etal>et al</etal></person-group> &#160;<article-title>Morphological and morphometric analysis of the orbital aperture and their correlation with age and gender: a retrospective digital radiographic study</article-title>. <source>Cureus</source>. <year>2021</year>;<volume>13</volume>(<issue>9</issue>):<fpage>e17739</fpage>. doi: <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.7759/cureus.17739</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">34659952</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC8491795</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="sjae058-B39"><label>39</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><string-name name-style="western"><surname>Jeon</surname> &#160;<given-names>A</given-names></string-name>, <string-name name-style="western"><surname>Lee</surname> &#160;<given-names>U-Y</given-names></string-name>, <string-name name-style="western"><surname>Kwak</surname> &#160;<given-names>D-S</given-names></string-name>, <string-name name-style="western"><surname>Lee</surname> &#160;<given-names>JH</given-names></string-name>, <string-name name-style="western"><surname>Ra</surname> &#160;<given-names>H</given-names></string-name>, <string-name name-style="western"><surname>Han</surname> &#160;<given-names>SH</given-names></string-name></person-group>. <article-title>Aging of the bony orbit in East Asians: a three-dimensional computed tomographic study</article-title>. <source>Surg Radiol Anat</source>. <year>2020</year>;<volume>42</volume>(<issue>5</issue>):<fpage>617</fpage>&#8211;<lpage>626</lpage>. doi: <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1007/s00276-019-02410-9</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">31960087</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="sjae058-B40"><label>40</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><string-name name-style="western"><surname>Kahn</surname> &#160;<given-names>DM</given-names></string-name>, <string-name name-style="western"><surname>Shaw</surname> &#160;<given-names>RB</given-names> &#160;<suffix>Jr</suffix></string-name></person-group>. <article-title>Aging of the bony orbit: a three-dimensional computed tomographic study</article-title>. <source>Aesthet Surg J</source>. <year>2008</year>;<volume>28</volume>(<issue>3</issue>):<fpage>258</fpage>&#8211;<lpage>264</lpage>. doi: <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1016/j.asj.2008.02.007</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">19083535</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="sjae058-B41"><label>41</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><string-name name-style="western"><surname>Glaser</surname> &#160;<given-names>DA</given-names></string-name>, <string-name name-style="western"><surname>Lambros</surname> &#160;<given-names>V</given-names></string-name>, <string-name name-style="western"><surname>Kolodziejczyk</surname> &#160;<given-names>J</given-names></string-name>, <string-name name-style="western"><surname>Magyar</surname> &#160;<given-names>A</given-names></string-name>, <string-name name-style="western"><surname>Dorries</surname> &#160;<given-names>K</given-names></string-name>, <string-name name-style="western"><surname>Gallagher</surname> &#160;<given-names>CJ</given-names></string-name></person-group>. <article-title>Relationship between midface volume deficits and the appearance of tear troughs and nasolabial folds</article-title>. <source>Dermatol Surg</source>. <year>2018</year>;<volume>44</volume>(<issue>12</issue>):<fpage>1547</fpage>&#8211;<lpage>1554</lpage>. doi: <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1097/dss.0000000000001684</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">30379685</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="sjae058-B42"><label>42</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><string-name name-style="western"><surname>Chopra</surname> &#160;<given-names>K</given-names></string-name>, <string-name name-style="western"><surname>Calva</surname> &#160;<given-names>D</given-names></string-name>, <string-name name-style="western"><surname>Sosin</surname> &#160;<given-names>M</given-names></string-name>, <etal>et al</etal></person-group> &#160;<article-title>A comprehensive examination of topographic thickness of skin in the human face</article-title>. <source>Aesthet Surg J</source>. <year>2015</year>;<volume>35</volume>(<issue>8</issue>):<fpage>1007</fpage>&#8211;<lpage>1013</lpage>. doi: <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1093/asj/sjv079</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">26508650</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="sjae058-B43"><label>43</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><string-name name-style="western"><surname>Cheng</surname> &#160;<given-names>L</given-names></string-name>, <string-name name-style="western"><surname>Zhang</surname> &#160;<given-names>L</given-names></string-name>, <string-name name-style="western"><surname>Sun</surname> &#160;<given-names>X</given-names></string-name>, <etal>et al</etal></person-group> &#160;<article-title>Progress of laser and light treatments for lower eyelid rejuvenation</article-title>. <source>Chinese J Plast Reconstr Surg</source>. <year>2021</year>;<volume>3</volume>(<issue>4</issue>):<fpage>218</fpage>&#8211;<lpage>223</lpage>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1016/j.cjprs.2021.12.003</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="sjae058-B44"><label>44</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><string-name name-style="western"><surname>Vrcek</surname> &#160;<given-names>I</given-names></string-name>, <string-name name-style="western"><surname>Ozgur</surname> &#160;<given-names>O</given-names></string-name>, <string-name name-style="western"><surname>Nakra</surname> &#160;<given-names>T</given-names></string-name></person-group>. <article-title>Infraorbital dark circles: a review of the pathogenesis, evaluation and treatment</article-title>. <source>J Cutan Aesthet Surg</source>. <year>2016</year>;<volume>9</volume>(<issue>2</issue>):<fpage>65</fpage>&#8211;<lpage>72</lpage>. doi: <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.4103/0974-2077.184046</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">27398005</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC4924417</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="sjae058-B45"><label>45</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><string-name name-style="western"><surname>Stutman</surname> &#160;<given-names>RL</given-names></string-name>, <string-name name-style="western"><surname>Codner</surname> &#160;<given-names>MA</given-names></string-name></person-group>. <article-title>Tear trough deformity: review of anatomy and treatment options</article-title>. <source>Aesthet Surg J</source>. <year>2012</year>;<volume>32</volume>(<issue>4</issue>):<fpage>426</fpage>&#8211;<lpage>440</lpage>. doi: <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1177/1090820X12442372</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">22523096</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref></ref-list></back></article></pmc-articleset>