<?xml version="1.0"  ?><!DOCTYPE pmc-articleset PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD ARTICLE SET 2.0//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pmc/articleset/nlm-articleset-2.0.dtd"><pmc-articleset><article xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" xmlns:ali="http://www.niso.org/schemas/ali/1.0/" xml:lang="en" article-type="review-article" dtd-version="1.4"><processing-meta base-tagset="archiving" mathml-version="3.0" table-model="xhtml" tagset-family="jats"><restricted-by>pmc</restricted-by></processing-meta><front><journal-meta><journal-id journal-id-type="nlm-ta">Medicine (Baltimore)</journal-id><journal-id journal-id-type="iso-abbrev">Medicine (Baltimore)</journal-id><journal-id journal-id-type="pmc-domain-id">2786</journal-id><journal-id journal-id-type="pmc-domain">medicine</journal-id><journal-id journal-id-type="publisher-id">MEDI</journal-id><journal-title-group><journal-title>Medicine</journal-title></journal-title-group><issn pub-type="ppub">0025-7974</issn><issn pub-type="epub">1536-5964</issn><publisher><publisher-name>Wolters Kluwer Health</publisher-name></publisher></journal-meta><article-meta><article-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC12245382</article-id><article-id pub-id-type="pmcid-ver">PMC12245382.1</article-id><article-id pub-id-type="pmcaid">12245382</article-id><article-id pub-id-type="pmcaiid">12245382</article-id><article-id pub-id-type="pmid">32481409</article-id><article-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1097/MD.0000000000020332</article-id><article-id pub-id-type="publisher-id">MD-D-19-06492</article-id><article-version article-version-type="pmc-version">1</article-version><article-categories><subj-group subj-group-type="heading"><subject>4200</subject></subj-group><subj-group><subject>Research Article</subject><subject>Systematic Review and Meta-Analysis</subject></subj-group></article-categories><title-group><article-title>Foam sclerotherapy compared with liquid sclerotherapy for the treatment of lower extremity varicose veins</article-title><subtitle>A protocol for systematic review and meta analysis</subtitle></title-group><contrib-group><contrib contrib-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Bi</surname><given-names initials="M">Minglei</given-names></name><degrees>MD</degrees></contrib><contrib contrib-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Li</surname><given-names initials="D">Danyi</given-names></name><degrees>MD</degrees></contrib><contrib contrib-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Chen</surname><given-names initials="Z">Zhenyu</given-names></name><degrees>MD</degrees></contrib><contrib contrib-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Wang</surname><given-names initials="Y">Yanjin</given-names></name><degrees>MD</degrees></contrib><contrib contrib-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Ren</surname><given-names initials="J">Jizhen</given-names></name><degrees>MD</degrees></contrib><contrib contrib-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Zhang</surname><given-names initials="W">Weina</given-names></name><xref rid="cor1" ref-type="corresp">
<sup>&#8727;</sup>
</xref></contrib></contrib-group><contrib-group><contrib contrib-type="editor"><name name-style="western"><surname>Das.</surname><given-names initials="UN">Undurti N.</given-names></name></contrib></contrib-group><aff>Department of Plastic Surgery, The Affiliated Hospital of Qingdao University, Qingdao, China.</aff><author-notes id="cor1"><corresp><label>&#8727;</label>Correspondence: Weina Zhang, Department of Plastic Surgery, The Affiliated Hospital of Qingdao University, Jiangsu 16 Road, Qingdao 266000, Shandong, P.R. China (e-mail: <email>dr13864865856@163.com</email>).</corresp></author-notes><pub-date pub-type="collection"><day>29</day><month>5</month><year>2020</year></pub-date><pub-date pub-type="epub"><day>29</day><month>5</month><year>2020</year></pub-date><volume>99</volume><issue>22</issue><issue-id pub-id-type="pmc-issue-id">363939</issue-id><elocation-id>e20332</elocation-id><history><date date-type="received"><day>16</day><month>8</month><year>2019</year></date><date date-type="rev-recd"><day>13</day><month>1</month><year>2020</year></date><date date-type="accepted"><day>3</day><month>4</month><year>2020</year></date></history><pub-history><event event-type="pmc-release"><date><day>29</day><month>05</month><year>2020</year></date></event><event event-type="pmc-live"><date><day>10</day><month>07</month><year>2025</year></date></event><event event-type="pmc-last-change"><date iso-8601-date="2025-07-11 17:25:26.247"><day>11</day><month>07</month><year>2025</year></date></event></pub-history><permissions><copyright-statement>Copyright &#169; 2020 the Author(s). Published by Wolters Kluwer Health, Inc.</copyright-statement><copyright-year>2020</copyright-year><license><ali:license_ref specific-use="textmining" content-type="ccbylicense">https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</ali:license_ref><license-p>This is an open access article distributed under the Creative Commons Attribution License 4.0 (CCBY), which permits unrestricted use, distribution, and reproduction in any medium, provided the original work is properly cited. <ext-link xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" ext-link-type="uri" xlink:href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/">http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0</ext-link></license-p></license></permissions><self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" content-type="pmc-pdf" xlink:href="medi-99-e20332.pdf"/><self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xlink:href="medi-99-e20332.pdf"/><abstract><title>Abstract</title><sec sec-type="background"><title>Background:</title><p>There is a continued discussion on which is the best sclerosant to treat lower extremity varicose veins. Therefore, we did this meta-analysis to determine that foam sclerotherapy versus liquid sclerotherapy, which could perform better in the treatment of lower extremity varicose veins.</p></sec><sec sec-type="materials"><title>Materials and methods:</title><p>We independently searched 5 databases from inception to February 1, 2019, for randomized controlled trials and prospective controlled trials for comparing foam sclerotherapy and liquid sclerotherapy for the treatment of lower extremity varicose veins. The Newcastle-Ottawa Scale (NOS) was used to assess the quality of studies. The primary outcome and secondary outcomes were analyzed using stata 15.0. This meta-analysis was performed according to Cochrane Handbook.</p></sec><sec sec-type="results"><title>Results:</title><p>There were significant differences in effective rate (<italic toggle="yes">P</italic>&#8202;&lt;&#8202;.001, odd ratios&#8202;=&#8202;5.64, 95% confidence interval&#8202;=&#8202;3.93&#8211;8.10) and incidence rate of pain (<italic toggle="yes">P</italic>&#8202;=&#8202;.030, odd ratios&#8202;=&#8202;1.52, 95% confidence interval&#8202;=&#8202;1.04&#8211;2.21) between foam sclerotherapy and liquid sclerotherapy. And there were no significant differences among local inflammation (<italic toggle="yes">P</italic>&#8202;=&#8202;.896, rate difference&#8202;=&#8202;0.00, 95% confidence interval&#8202;=&#8202;&#8211;0.03 to 0.03), thrombophlebitis (<italic toggle="yes">P</italic>&#8202;=&#8202;.90, rate difference&#8202;=&#8202;0.00, 95% confidence interval&#8202;=&#8202;&#8722;0.02 to 0.02) and hyperpigmentation (<italic toggle="yes">P</italic>&#8202;=&#8202;.336, rate difference&#8202;=&#8202;0.05, 95% confidence interval&#8202;=&#8202;&#8722;0.05 to 0.14).</p></sec><sec sec-type="conclusion"><title>Conclusions:</title><p>Although foam sclerotherapy has a higher incidence rate of complications, it could achieve a more stable clinical efficacy in the treatment of lower extremity varicose veins than liquid sclerotherapy.</p></sec></abstract><kwd-group><title>Keywords</title><kwd>lower extremity</kwd><kwd>meta-analysis</kwd><kwd>sclerotherapy</kwd><kwd>varicose veins</kwd></kwd-group><custom-meta-group><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-status-qastatus</meta-name><meta-value>0</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-status-live</meta-name><meta-value>yes</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-status-embargo</meta-name><meta-value>no</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-status-released</meta-name><meta-value>yes</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-open-access</meta-name><meta-value>yes</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-olf</meta-name><meta-value>no</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-manuscript</meta-name><meta-value>no</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-legally-suppressed</meta-name><meta-value>no</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-has-pdf</meta-name><meta-value>yes</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-has-supplement</meta-name><meta-value>no</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-pdf-only</meta-name><meta-value>no</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-suppress-copyright</meta-name><meta-value>no</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-is-real-version</meta-name><meta-value>no</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-is-scanned-article</meta-name><meta-value>no</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-preprint</meta-name><meta-value>no</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-in-epmc</meta-name><meta-value>yes</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>OPEN-ACCESS</meta-name><meta-value>TRUE</meta-value></custom-meta></custom-meta-group></article-meta></front><body><sec><label>1</label><title>Introduction</title><p>Lower extremity varicose veins are the condition where blood flow refluxes and distal veins engorge because pliable valves fail to prevent retrograde blood flow. It will lead to pathological changes of abnormal veins such as expansion, denaturation, and twist. Generally, lower extremity varicose veins is a common disease and affects up to 25% women, especially those people who always stand for a long time.<sup>[<xref rid="R1" ref-type="bibr">1</xref>]</sup> Furthermore, it can cause the deterioration of the quality of life and other serve complications such as chronic venous ulceration, haemorrhage, venous thromboembolism and the limitation of activity.<sup>[<xref rid="R2" ref-type="bibr">2</xref>]</sup></p><p>The variety of therapeutic strategies have ranged from more invasive surgical methods such as high ligation and stripping, stab avulsion phlebectomy, valvuloplasty and valve transplantation, to less invasive therapies such as radiofrequency ablation (RFA), endovenous laser therapy (EVLA), and compression therapy.<sup>[<xref rid="R3" ref-type="bibr">3</xref>,<xref rid="R4" ref-type="bibr">4</xref>]</sup> Although there are many existing referral guidelines, the majority of them are &#8220;localism&#8221; and not evidence based.<sup>[<xref rid="R5" ref-type="bibr">5</xref>]</sup> Therefore, clinical managements of this kind of diseases are driven by doctors&#8217; experience and patients&#8217; economic capabilities mostly. As a traditional and effective method, venous sclerotherapy, which contained polidocanol (POL) and sodium tetradecyl sulfate (STS), has enjoyed a great popularity among above-mentioned treatments because of its simple procedures and positive clinical effects, it could cause endothelial damage which leads to fibrosis of the vessel.<sup>[<xref rid="R6" ref-type="bibr">6</xref>]</sup></p><p>However, since Orbach invented foam sclerotherapy by mixing detergent sclerosants with the usually air,<sup>[<xref rid="R7" ref-type="bibr">7</xref>]</sup> there has been a hot debate on the clinical efficacy for lower extremity varicose veins of foam sclerotherapy versus liquid sclerotherapy.<sup>[<xref rid="R8" ref-type="bibr">8</xref>]</sup> Nevertheless, no authorized data could be found to put an end to this debate because there are few multi-center trials with a large size of patients, lacking sufficient scientific evidence to support. To explore this question, we did this meta-analysis of randomized controlled trials (RCTs) or prospective controlled trials (PCTs) to compare foam sclerotherapy and liquid sclerotherapy, determining which is the optimal method to treat lower extremity varicose veins.</p></sec><sec><label>2</label><title>Materials and methods</title><sec><label>2.1</label><title>Eligibility criteria</title><p>Studies were included if they were RCTs or PCTs comparing foam sclerotherapy with liquid sclerotherapy in the treatment of lower extremity varicose veins. We excluded any other types of studies such as review, editorial, case report, observational study et al. Inclusion criteria were:</p><list list-type="simple"><list-item><label>1.</label><p>the study comparing the effective rate or incidence rate of complications of foam sclerotherapy and liquid sclerotherapy.</p></list-item></list><p>Exclusion criteria were:</p><list list-type="simple"><list-item><label>1.</label><p>non-English language articles,</p></list-item><list-item><label>2.</label><p>only described foam sclerotherapy or liquid sclerotherapy,</p></list-item><list-item><label>3.</label><p>randomized trials comparing foam sclerotherapy and liquid sclerotherapy in which both effective rate and incidence rate of complications were not evaluated.</p></list-item></list></sec><sec><label>2.2</label><title>Information sources</title><p>For this meta-analysis, we searched 5 database including PubMed, MEDLINE, Web of Science, EMBASE, and Cochrane Library from inception to April 1, 2019. Several keywords were used during the search procedure and we had English language restriction. Only RCTs or PCTs that compared foam sclerotherapy with liquid sclerotherapy were searched.</p></sec><sec><label>2.3</label><title>Search strategy</title><p>The following concrete search strategy was used in PubMed, which was made on the basis of the requirements of the Preferred Reporting Items for Systematic Reviews and Meta-Analysis (PRISMA) statement.<sup>[<xref rid="R9" ref-type="bibr">9</xref>,<xref rid="R10" ref-type="bibr">10</xref>]</sup> ((((&#8220;Sclerotherapy&#8221;[Mesh]) OR Sclerotherapies)) AND ((&#8220;Varicose Veins&#8221;[Mesh]) OR (((((Varicose Vein) OR Vein, Varicose) OR Veins, Varicose) OR Varix) OR Varices))) AND Foam.</p></sec><sec><label>2.4</label><title>Study selection</title><p>Two reviewers (Bi and Li) independently looked through the titles and abstracts of all citations according to the inclusion and exclusion criteria strictly. Full-text of all possible qualified studies was screened by both authors individually. If there was any divergence, the senior reviewer (Chen) would judge it objectively. Studies which met all the inclusion criteria could be collected for this meta-analysis.</p></sec><sec><label>2.5</label><title>Data extraction process and quality measurement</title><p>Data were collected and evaluated respectively by two authors (Zhang and Wang) and disagreements would be solved by the third author (Chen). The following information should be extracted:</p><list list-type="simple"><list-item><label>1.</label><p>author's name, year, region, number of participants, sex, study design, follow-up duration;</p></list-item><list-item><label>2.</label><p>the effective rate and incidence rate of complications such as pain, local inflammation, hyperpigmentation and thrombophlebitis.</p></list-item></list><p>If necessary, we would contact with corresponding authors for more available information. Otherwise, Newcastle-Ottawa Scale (NOS) was used to assess the quality of all included studies.<sup>[<xref rid="R11" ref-type="bibr">11</xref>]</sup> This scale contains three aspects: selection (0&#8211;4 scores), comparability (0&#8211;2 scores), outcomes (0&#8211;3 scores). The maximal scores were 9 and studies which were more than 6 scores were considered as high quality articles.</p></sec><sec><label>2.6</label><title>Statistical analysis and additional analysis</title><p>This meta-analysis was performed using Stata 15.0. Odd ratios (OR) were used to analyze dichotomous data (effective rate, incidence rate of pain) and rate difference (RD) were used to analyze other dichotomous data (local inflammation, hyperpigmentation, and thrombophlebitis), with 95% confidence interval (CI).<sup>[<xref rid="R12" ref-type="bibr">12</xref>]</sup> Otherwise, <italic toggle="yes">P</italic> value&#8202;&lt;&#8202;.05 was considered significant. As for heterogeneity, chi-squared test was applied to evaluate it. If <italic toggle="yes">I</italic><sup>2</sup>&#8202;&gt;&#8202;50%, it was considered suggestive of statistical heterogeneity, the random-effect model should be applied. The fixed-effect model should be used if <italic toggle="yes">I</italic><sup>2</sup>&#8202;&lt;&#8202;50% because there was no significant statistical heterogeneity.<sup>[<xref rid="R13" ref-type="bibr">13</xref>]</sup> In addition, we evaluated publication bias of this meta-analysis by Egger test.<sup>[<xref rid="R14" ref-type="bibr">14</xref>]</sup> We also performed sensitivity analysis to assess the robustness of results.</p></sec></sec><sec><label>3</label><title>Results</title><sec><label>3.1</label><title>Screening and inclusion of studies</title><p>The flow diagram of our literatures searching process was displayed in Figure <xref rid="F1" ref-type="fig">1</xref>. First, our search had identified 2106 records through 5 database. Secondly, 874 records were excluded because of duplication. Then, after a precise screening through titles and abstracts, there were 151 full-text articles reminded which would be assessed for eligibility. Finally, we had a strict requirement of the type of included studies so such other types of studies as review, letter, observative studies, case report et al would be excluded.</p><fig position="float" id="F1" orientation="portrait"><label>Figure 1</label><caption><p>Flow diagram of study selection.</p></caption><graphic xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" position="float" orientation="portrait" xlink:href="medi-99-e20332-g001.jpg"/></fig><p>After the careful and strict searching process, 8 studies with 1089 participants (female 80.52%), completed from 2003 to 2018 among 5 different countries (Europe 7, Asia 1), with the mean follow-up period of 10 months, met all the aforementioned inclusion criteria in this meta-analysis. All included articles were full-text studies which were only written in English, and there were 6 RCTs and 2 PCTs. In addition, the mean score of NOS was 7 of 9 and 6 studies were deemed as high quality (&gt;6 scores), the rest were moderate quality. Characteristics of studies included were generally shown in Table <xref rid="T1" ref-type="table">1</xref>. Furthermore, we had extracted other important information such as different techniques to produce foam, different diagnosis standards of lower extremity varicose veins among included studies, which were all manifested in Table <xref rid="T2" ref-type="table">2</xref>.</p><table-wrap position="float" id="T1" orientation="portrait"><label>Table 1</label><caption><p>Characteristics of studies included in this meta-analysis.</p></caption><graphic xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" position="float" orientation="portrait" xlink:href="medi-99-e20332-g002.jpg"/></table-wrap><table-wrap position="float" id="T2" orientation="portrait"><label>Table 2</label><caption><p>Different techniques to produce foam sclerosant and diagnosis standards of lower extremity varicose veins among included studies.</p></caption><graphic xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" position="float" orientation="portrait" xlink:href="medi-99-e20332-g003.jpg"/></table-wrap></sec><sec><label>3.2</label><title>Primary outcome</title><sec><label>3.2.1</label><title>Effective rate</title><p>The clinical efficacy of foam sclerotherapy or liquid sclerotherapy could be illustrated by this outcome completely and it could be calculated easily by such formula as n(effective events)/n(total events). Seven studies with 771 participants reported this outcome. We used fixed-effect model (<italic toggle="yes">I</italic><sup>2</sup>&#8202;=&#8202;41.8%) and there was a significant difference between foam sclerotherapy and liquid sclerotherapy, with OR&#8202;=&#8202;5.64 (<italic toggle="yes">P</italic>&#8202;&lt;&#8202;.0001, 95% CI&#8202;=&#8202;3.93&#8211;8.10) (Fig. <xref rid="F2" ref-type="fig">2</xref>) (Table <xref rid="T3" ref-type="table">3</xref>).</p><fig position="float" id="F2" orientation="portrait"><label>Figure 2</label><caption><p>Forest plot to assess effect rate between foam sclerotherapy and liquid sclerotherapy.</p></caption><graphic xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" position="float" orientation="portrait" xlink:href="medi-99-e20332-g004.jpg"/></fig><table-wrap position="float" id="T3" orientation="portrait"><label>Table 3</label><caption><p>Pooled outcomes indicators for lower extremity varicose veins patients.</p></caption><graphic xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" position="float" orientation="portrait" xlink:href="medi-99-e20332-g005.jpg"/></table-wrap></sec></sec><sec><label>3.3</label><title>Secondary outcomes</title><sec><label>3.3.1</label><title>Incidence rate of pain</title><p>It included 7 studies with 1001 participants and fixed-effect model (<italic toggle="yes">I</italic><sup>2</sup>&#8202;=&#8202;48.2%) was used. Results showed that there was a significant difference between foam group and liquid group, with OR&#8202;=&#8202;1.52 (<italic toggle="yes">P</italic>&#8202;=&#8202;.030, 95% CI&#8202;=&#8202;1.04&#8211;2.21) (Fig. <xref rid="F3" ref-type="fig">3</xref>) (Table <xref rid="T3" ref-type="table">3</xref>).</p><fig position="float" id="F3" orientation="portrait"><label>Figure 3</label><caption><p>Forest plot to assess incidence rate of pain between foam sclerotherapy and liquid sclerotherapy.</p></caption><graphic xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" position="float" orientation="portrait" xlink:href="medi-99-e20332-g006.jpg"/></fig></sec><sec><label>3.3.2</label><title>Incidence rate of local inflammation</title><p>This outcome contained 7 included studies as well as 959 participants. After meta-analysis on incidence rate of local inflammation outcome, no significant difference was found between foam sclerotherapy and liquid sclerotherapy, with RD&#8202;=&#8202;0.00 (<italic toggle="yes">P</italic>&#8202;=&#8202;.896, 95% CI&#8202;=&#8202;&#8722;0.03 to 0.03) and we used random-effect model (<italic toggle="yes">I</italic><sup>2</sup>&#8202;=&#8202;64.9%) (Fig. <xref rid="F4" ref-type="fig">4</xref>) (Table <xref rid="T3" ref-type="table">3</xref>).</p><fig position="float" id="F4" orientation="portrait"><label>Figure 4</label><caption><p>Forest plot to assess Incidence rate of local inflammation between foam sclerotherapy and liquid sclerotherapy.</p></caption><graphic xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" position="float" orientation="portrait" xlink:href="medi-99-e20332-g007.jpg"/></fig></sec><sec><label>3.3.3</label><title>Incidence rate of thrombophlebitis</title><p>Five studies assessed thrombophlebitis after sclerotherapy of lower extremity varicose veins, including 709 participants totally. When we compared foam sclerotherapy with liquid sclerotherapy, we chose fixed-effect model because of its low heterogeneity (<italic toggle="yes">I</italic><sup>2</sup>&#8202;=&#8202;0.0%) and there was no significant difference between foam group and liquid group, with RD&#8202;=&#8202;0.00 (<italic toggle="yes">P</italic>&#8202;=&#8202;.900, 95% CI&#8202;=&#8202;&#8722;0.02 to 0.02) (Fig. <xref rid="F5" ref-type="fig">5</xref>) (Table <xref rid="T3" ref-type="table">3</xref>).</p><fig position="float" id="F5" orientation="portrait"><label>Figure 5</label><caption><p>Forest plot to assess Incidence rate of thrombophlebitis between foam sclerotherapy and liquid sclerotherapy.</p></caption><graphic xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" position="float" orientation="portrait" xlink:href="medi-99-e20332-g008.jpg"/></fig></sec><sec><label>3.3.4</label><title>Incidence rate of hyperpigmentation</title><p>This secondary outcome could be extracted from 6 included studies with 871 participants in this meta-analysis which existed in the comparison between foam group and liquid group, using the random-effect model because of its high heterogeneity (<italic toggle="yes">I</italic><sup>2</sup>&#8202;=&#8202;86.6%). However, there was no significant difference between these two groups, with RD&#8202;=&#8202;0.05 (<italic toggle="yes">P</italic>&#8202;=&#8202;.336, 95% CI&#8202;=&#8202;&#8722;0.05 to 0.14) (Fig. <xref rid="F6" ref-type="fig">6</xref>) (Table <xref rid="T3" ref-type="table">3</xref>).</p><fig position="float" id="F6" orientation="portrait"><label>Figure 6</label><caption><p>Forest plot to assess Incidence rate of hyperpigmentation between foam sclerotherapy and liquid sclerotherapy.</p></caption><graphic xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" position="float" orientation="portrait" xlink:href="medi-99-e20332-g009.jpg"/></fig></sec></sec><sec><label>3.4</label><title>Publication bias and sensitivity analysis</title><p>Egger test was performed to assess the publication bias in this meta-analysis, with <italic toggle="yes">P</italic>&#8202;=&#8202;.911 (<italic toggle="yes">P</italic>&#8202;&gt;&#8202;.05) (data were not shown).<sup>[<xref rid="R14" ref-type="bibr">14</xref>]</sup> Incidence rate of local inflammation showed a high heterogeneity (<italic toggle="yes">I</italic><sup>2</sup>&#8202;=&#8202;64.9%) and we performed the sensitivity analysis to explore its reasons. From Figure <xref rid="F7" ref-type="fig">7</xref>, we found that the third study (J. Al&#242;s 2006)<sup>[<xref rid="R17" ref-type="bibr">17</xref>]</sup> and the last study (Ali Kaygin 2018)<sup>[<xref rid="R20" ref-type="bibr">20</xref>]</sup> had great impacts on statistic and we found that the heterogeneity reduced dramatically after exclusion of these two studies (Fig. <xref rid="F8" ref-type="fig">8</xref>). As for incidence rate of hyperpigmentation, we used the same analysis and we found that J. Al&#242;s 2006 and H. Uncu 2010 maybe reasons of its high hetergeneity (Figs. <xref rid="F9" ref-type="fig">9</xref> and <xref rid="F10" ref-type="fig">10</xref>).</p><fig position="float" id="F7" orientation="portrait"><label>Figure 7</label><caption><p>Sensitivity analysis of Incidence rate of local inflammation between foam sclerotherapy and liquid sclerotherapy.</p></caption><graphic xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" position="float" orientation="portrait" xlink:href="medi-99-e20332-g010.jpg"/></fig><fig position="float" id="F8" orientation="portrait"><label>Figure 8</label><caption><p>Forest plot to assess Incidence rate of local inflammation between foam sclerotherapy and liquid sclerotherapy after exclusion.</p></caption><graphic xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" position="float" orientation="portrait" xlink:href="medi-99-e20332-g011.jpg"/></fig><fig position="float" id="F9" orientation="portrait"><label>Figure 9</label><caption><p>Sensitivity analysis of Incidence rate of hyperpigmentation between foam sclerotherapy and liquid sclerotherapy.</p></caption><graphic xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" position="float" orientation="portrait" xlink:href="medi-99-e20332-g012.jpg"/></fig><fig position="float" id="F10" orientation="portrait"><label>Figure 10</label><caption><p>Forest plot to assess Incidence rate of hyperpigmentation between foam sclerotherapy and liquid sclerotherapy after exclusion.</p></caption><graphic xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" position="float" orientation="portrait" xlink:href="medi-99-e20332-g013.jpg"/></fig></sec></sec><sec><label>4</label><title>Discussion</title><p>Lower extremity varicose veins is a commonly chronic medical condition and a substantial cause of morbidity around the world.<sup>[<xref rid="R23" ref-type="bibr">23</xref>]</sup> The natural history of this kind of diseases is progressive over time, ranging from simple telangiectasias to venous ulcerations if treated inappropriately, leading to a huge amount of care and costs.<sup>[<xref rid="R24" ref-type="bibr">24</xref>,<xref rid="R25" ref-type="bibr">25</xref>]</sup> Treatments of lower extremity varicose veins are diversified and could be divided into two parts: surgical strategy (e.g., high ligation and stripping, stab avulsion phlebectomy, valvuloplasty) and non-surgical strategy (RFA, EVLA, compression therapy).</p><p>As one of the emerging and promising treatments, sclerotherapy with foam sclerosant or liquid sclerosant has enjoyed a great popularity nowadays. Sclerosants could destroy vascular cell membranes, leading to continued vasospasm and denudation of the venous monolayer.<sup>[<xref rid="R26" ref-type="bibr">26</xref>]</sup> A series of pathological changes would cause irreversible fibrous obliteration of lesional veins, resulting in occluding varicose veins for therapeutic purposes.<sup>[<xref rid="R27" ref-type="bibr">27</xref>]</sup> However, with the invention and development of foam sclerosant, hot debate on the clinical efficacy for lower extremity varicose veins of foam sclerotherapy versus liquid sclerotherapy. To date, this is the first meta-analysis to compare these two different sclerosants and offer clinical practitioners and stakeholders sufficient scientific evidence for the clinical efficacy of foam sclerotherapy as an optimal treatment for patients suffering lower extremity varicose veins.</p></sec><sec><label>5</label><title>Summary of evidence</title><p>Our study manifests that although foam sclerotherapy might make some patients more painful than liquid sclerotherapy, foam group have a significantly higher effective rate than liquid group. Furthermore, as for other complications analyzed by us, such as local inflammation, thrombophlebitis, hyperpigmentation, there were no significant differences among them between two groups. Furthermore, Egger test showed that there was no significant publication bias in this meta-analysis. Our results reflect an authentic clinical efficacy of foam sclerotherapy and liquid sclerotherapy, rather than an artefact of statistical heterogeneity.</p><p>Yamaki et al<sup>[<xref rid="R28" ref-type="bibr">28</xref>]</sup> and Gibson et al<sup>[<xref rid="R29" ref-type="bibr">29</xref>]</sup> reported that foam sclerotherapy was better than liquid sclerotherapy because foam sclerosant could contact with venous endothelial for a longer period than would occur with the injection of liquid. A RCT published by Hamel-Desnos C et al<sup>[<xref rid="R21" ref-type="bibr">21</xref>]</sup> also showed that closure rates of the great saphenous vein (GSV) treated with foam sclerotherapy were higher than that of liquid sclerotherapy (3 weeks: 84% vs 40%; 6 weeks: 80% vs 26%). Nevertheless, Kathleen Gibson et al<sup>[<xref rid="R30" ref-type="bibr">30</xref>]</sup> reported that liquid sclerotherapy was preferred for spider telangiectasias, but when it came to truncal veins such as lower extremity varicose veins, foam sclerotherapy were superior. Although there were relative studies giving us similar conclusions, the level of each evidences was low and the amount of patients of each study was small. But our meta-analysis was the first high-level clinical evidence of which the sample size was large (&gt;1000 patients), so our conclusions would be more convinced and could offer clinical pratitioners valuable practice guideline.</p><p>To make this study more scientific and rational, after a thorough screen of included studies, we extracted some important data based on such six clinical and objective evaluation indicators such length of the sclerosed veins, reduced mean influx time, required sclerotherapy sessions, recanalization rate, Venous Clinical Severity Scoring (VCSS) and complete disappearance rate of varicose veins (Table <xref rid="T4" ref-type="table">4</xref>). From outcomes we could include that compared with liquid sclerotherapy, foam sclerotherapy could achieve better treatment effects when it comes to length of the sclerosed veins, reduced mean influx time, required sclerotherapy sessions, Venous Clinical Severity Scoring (VCSS) and complete disappearance rate of varicose veins. In addition, the recurrence rate of foam sclerotherapy is lower than liquid sclerotherapy (recanalization rate, 4.55% vs 13.64%).</p><table-wrap position="float" id="T4" orientation="portrait"><label>Table 4</label><caption><p>Evaluation indicators of treatments for lower extremity varicose veins.</p></caption><graphic xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" position="float" orientation="portrait" xlink:href="medi-99-e20332-g014.jpg"/></table-wrap></sec><sec><label>6</label><title>Limitations</title><p>However, there were some limitations in this meta-analysis. First, all included studies were from Asia and Europe, so included participants were Asian ethnicity and European ethnicity in this meta-analysis. Therefore, our study may be not applicable to African ethnicity.</p><p>Secondly, only 5 outcomes were evaluated and analyzed in our study, which would deteriorate the persuasion and rationality of our conclusions inevitably. Moreover, there were other complications after sclerotherapy such as immediate spasm, hematoma, itching, hypertension et al. We did not collect these complications because its incidence rates were rare and relative studies were not enough to be analyzed.</p><p>Thirdly, the evaluation methods of each study were not uniform and the majority of studies (5/8) mainly depended on clinical experience. It would bring about some biases during the trials because clinical experience was very subjective and it would vary easily with different evaluators, hospitals, and countries.</p></sec><sec><label>7</label><title>Conclusions</title><p>In summary, although foam sclerotherapy has a higher incidence rate of complications, it could achieve a more stable clinical efficacy in the treatment of lower extremity varicose veins than liquid sclerotherapy. Moreover, based on the above conclusions we had draw, more high quality researches should be performed to determine how to optimize foam sclerosant in order to reduce the incidence rate of complications after injections.</p></sec><sec><title>Author contributions</title><p><bold>Data curation:</bold> minglei Bi.</p><p><bold>Formal analysis:</bold> minglei Bi.</p><p><bold>Methodology:</bold> danyi Li.</p><p><bold>Software:</bold> minglei Bi, danyi Li, weina Zhang.</p><p><bold>Supervision:</bold> weina Zhang.</p><p><bold>Writing &#8211; original draft:</bold> zhenyu Chen, weina Zhang.</p><p><bold>Writing &#8211; review &amp; editing:</bold> zhenyu Chen, yanjin Wang, jizhen Ren, weina Zhang.</p></sec></body><back><fn-group><fn fn-type="abbr"><p>Abbreviations: CI = confidence interval, EVLA = endovenous laser therapy, NOS = the Newcastle-Ottawa Scale, OR = odd ratios, PCTs = prospective controlled trials, POL = polidocanol, RCTs = randomized controlled trials, RD = rate difference, RFA = radiofrequency ablation, STS = sodium tetradecyl sulfate.</p></fn><fn fn-type="other"><p>How to cite this article: Bi M, Li D, Chen Z, Wang Y, Ren J, Zhang W. Foam sclerotherapy compared with liquid sclerotherapy for the treatment of lower extremity varicose veins: a protocol for systematic review and meta analysis. <italic toggle="yes">Medicine</italic>. 2020;99:22(e20332).</p></fn><fn fn-type="other"><p>Ethical Approval: Meta-analysis does not need ethical approval in that no patients&#8217; private information is included.</p></fn><fn fn-type="COI-statement"><p>The authors have no conflicts of interest to disclose.</p></fn></fn-group><ref-list><title>References</title><ref id="R1"><label>[1]</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>DePopas</surname><given-names>E</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Brown</surname><given-names>M</given-names></name></person-group>. <article-title>Varicose veins and lower extremity venous insufficiency</article-title>. <source>Semin Intervent Radiol</source><year>2018</year>;<volume>35</volume>:<fpage>56</fpage>&#8211;<lpage>61</lpage>.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">29628617</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1055/s-0038-1636522</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC5886767</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="R2"><label>[2]</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Spinedi</surname><given-names>L</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Broz</surname><given-names>P</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Engelberger</surname><given-names>RP</given-names></name><etal/></person-group>. <article-title>Clinical and duplex ultrasound evaluation of lower extremities varicose veins&#8212;a practical guideline</article-title>. <source>Vasa</source><year>2017</year>;<volume>46</volume>:<fpage>325</fpage>&#8211;<lpage>36</lpage>.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">28447881</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1024/0301-1526/a000635</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="R3"><label>[3]</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Novak</surname><given-names>CJ</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Khimani</surname><given-names>N</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Kaye</surname><given-names>AD</given-names></name><etal/></person-group>. <article-title>Current therapeutic interventions in lower extremity venous insufficiency: a comprehensive review</article-title>. <source>Curr Pain Headache</source><year>2019</year>;<volume>23</volume>:<fpage>16</fpage>.<pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1007/s11916-019-0759-z</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">30830460</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="R4"><label>[4]</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Mauck</surname><given-names>KF</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Asi</surname><given-names>N</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Undavalli</surname><given-names>C</given-names></name><etal/></person-group>. <article-title>Systematic review and meta-analysis of surgical interventions versus conservative therapy for venous ulcers</article-title>. <source>J Vasc Surg</source><year>2014</year>;<volume>60</volume>:<fpage>60S</fpage>&#8211;<lpage>70S.e1-2</lpage>.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">24835693</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1016/j.jvs.2014.04.059</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="R5"><label>[5]</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Berridge</surname><given-names>D</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Bradbury</surname><given-names>AW</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Davies</surname><given-names>AH</given-names></name><etal/></person-group>. <article-title>Recommendations for the referral and treatment of patients with lower limb chronic venous insufficiency (including varicose veins)</article-title>. <source>Phlebology</source><year>2011</year>;<volume>26</volume>:<fpage>91</fpage>&#8211;<lpage>3</lpage>.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">21471582</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1258/phleb.2011.011g01</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="R6"><label>[6]</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Schwartz</surname><given-names>L</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Maxwell</surname><given-names>H</given-names></name></person-group>. <article-title>Sclerotherapy for lower limb telangiectasias</article-title>. <source>Cochrane Datab System Rev</source><year>2011</year>;<volume>12</volume>:<fpage>1</fpage>&#8211;<lpage>44</lpage>.<pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1002/14651858.CD008826.pub2</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC7389636</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">22161437</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="R7"><label>[7]</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Orbach</surname><given-names>EJ</given-names></name></person-group>. <article-title>Sclerotherapy of varicose veins: utilization of an intravenous air block</article-title>. <source>Am J Surg</source><year>1944</year>;<volume>66</volume>:<fpage>362</fpage>&#8211;<lpage>6</lpage>.</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="R8"><label>[8]</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Tessari</surname><given-names>L</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Cavezzi</surname><given-names>A</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Frullini</surname><given-names>A</given-names></name></person-group>. <article-title>Preliminary experience with a new sclerosing foam in the treatment of varicose veins</article-title>. <source>Dermatol Surg</source><year>2001</year>;<volume>27</volume>:<fpage>58</fpage>&#8211;<lpage>60</lpage>.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">11231246</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="R9"><label>[9]</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Liberati</surname><given-names>A</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Altman</surname><given-names>DG</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Tetzlaff</surname><given-names>J</given-names></name><etal/></person-group>. <article-title>The PRISMA statement for reporting systematic reviews and meta-analyses of studies that evaluate health care interventions: explanation and elaboration</article-title>. <source>Ann Intern Med</source><year>2009</year>;<volume>151</volume>: <comment>W65-94</comment>.<pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.7326/0003-4819-151-4-200908180-00136</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">19622512</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="R10"><label>[10]</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Moher</surname><given-names>D</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Liberati</surname><given-names>A</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Tetzlaff</surname><given-names>J</given-names></name><etal/></person-group>. <article-title>Preferred reporting items for systematic reviews and meta-analyses: the PRISMA statement</article-title>. <source>BMJ</source><year>2009</year>;<volume>339</volume>: <comment>b2535</comment>.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC3090117</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">21603045</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="R11"><label>[11]</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Stang</surname><given-names>A</given-names></name></person-group>. <article-title>Critical evaluation of the Newcastle-Ottawa scale for the assessment of the quality of nonrandomized studies in meta-analyses</article-title>. <source>Eur J Epidemiol</source><year>2010</year>;<volume>25</volume>:<fpage>603</fpage>&#8211;<lpage>5</lpage>.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">20652370</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1007/s10654-010-9491-z</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="R12"><label>[12]</label><mixed-citation publication-type="book"><publisher-name>The Cochrane Colaboration</publisher-name>; <year>2011</year>;<person-group person-group-type="editor"><name name-style="western"><surname>Higgins</surname><given-names>JPT</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Green</surname><given-names>S</given-names></name></person-group>. <article-title>Cochrane Handbook for Systematic Reviews of Interventions Version 5.1.0 [Updated March 2011]</article-title>.</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="R13"><label>[13]</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Higgins</surname><given-names>JP</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Thompson</surname><given-names>SG</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Deeks</surname><given-names>JJ</given-names></name><etal/></person-group>. <article-title>Measuring inconsistency in meta-analyses</article-title>. <source>BMJ</source><year>2003</year>;<volume>327</volume>:<fpage>557</fpage>&#8211;<lpage>60</lpage>.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">12958120</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1136/bmj.327.7414.557</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC192859</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="R14"><label>[14]</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Higgins</surname><given-names>JP</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Altman</surname><given-names>DG</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Gotzsche</surname><given-names>PC</given-names></name><etal/></person-group>. <article-title>The Cochrane Collaboration's tool for assessing risk of bias in randomised trials</article-title>. <source>BMJ</source><year>2011</year>;<volume>343</volume>: <comment>d5928</comment>.<pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1136/bmj.d5928</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC3196245</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">22008217</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="R15"><label>[15]</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Ukritmanoroat</surname><given-names>T</given-names></name></person-group>. <article-title>Comparison of efficacy and safety between foam sclerotherapy and conventional sclerotherapy: a controlled clinical trial</article-title>. <source>J Med Assoc Thai</source><year>2011</year>;<volume>94</volume>:<fpage>S35</fpage>&#8211;<lpage>40</lpage>.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">21717876</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="R16"><label>[16]</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Rabe</surname><given-names>E</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Otto</surname><given-names>J</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Schliephake</surname><given-names>D</given-names></name><etal/></person-group>. <article-title>Efficacy and safety of great saphenous vein sclerotherapy using standardised polidocanol foam (ESAF): a randomised controlled multicentre clinical trial</article-title>. <source>Eur J Vasc Endovasc Surg</source><year>2008</year>;<volume>35</volume>:<fpage>238</fpage>&#8211;<lpage>45</lpage>.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">17988905</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1016/j.ejvs.2007.09.006</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="R17"><label>[17]</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Al&#242;s</surname><given-names>J</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Carre&#241;o</surname><given-names>P</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>L&#243;pez</surname><given-names>JA</given-names></name><etal/></person-group>. <article-title>Efficacy and safety of sclerotherapy using polidocanol foam: a controlled clinical trial</article-title>. <source>Eur J Vasc Endovasc Surg</source><year>2006</year>;<volume>31</volume>:<fpage>101</fpage>&#8211;<lpage>7</lpage>.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">16226901</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1016/j.ejvs.2005.08.018</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="R18"><label>[18]</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Moser</surname><given-names>KH</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Mosch</surname><given-names>C</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Walgenbach</surname><given-names>M</given-names></name><etal/></person-group>. <article-title>Efficacy and safety of sclerotherapy with polidocanol foam in comparison with fluid sclerosant in the treatment of first-grade haemorrhoidal disease: a randomised, controlled, single-blind, multicentre trial</article-title>. <source>Int J Colorectal Dis</source><year>2013</year>;<volume>28</volume>:<fpage>1439</fpage>&#8211;<lpage>47</lpage>.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">23775099</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1007/s00384-013-1729-2</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="R19"><label>[19]</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Ouvry</surname><given-names>P</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Allaert</surname><given-names>FA</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Desnos</surname><given-names>P</given-names></name><etal/></person-group>. <article-title>Efficacy of polidocanol foam versus liquid in sclerotherapy of the great saphenous vein: a multicentre randomised controlled trial with a 2-year follow-up</article-title>. <source>Eur J Vasc Endovasc Surg</source><year>2008</year>;<volume>36</volume>:<fpage>366</fpage>&#8211;<lpage>70</lpage>.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">18524643</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1016/j.ejvs.2008.04.010</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="R20"><label>[20]</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Kaygin</surname><given-names>MA</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Halici</surname><given-names>U</given-names></name></person-group>. <article-title>Evaluation of liquid or foam sclerotherapy in small varicose veins (ceap c1) with venous clinical severity score</article-title>. <source>Rev Assoc Med Bras (1992)</source><year>2018</year>;<volume>64</volume>:<fpage>1117</fpage>&#8211;<lpage>21</lpage>.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">30569988</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1590/1806-9282.64.12.1117</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="R21"><label>[21]</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Hamel-Desnos</surname><given-names>C</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Desnos</surname><given-names>P</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Wollmann</surname><given-names>JC</given-names></name><etal/></person-group>. <article-title>Evaluation of the efficacy of polidocanol in the form of foam compared with liquid form in sclerotherapy of the greater saphenous vein: initial results</article-title>. <source>Dermatol Surg</source><year>2003</year>;<volume>29</volume>:<fpage>1170</fpage>&#8211;<lpage>5</lpage>.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">14725657</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1111/j.1524-4725.2003.29398.x</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="R22"><label>[22]</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Uncu</surname><given-names>H</given-names></name></person-group>. <article-title>Sclerotherapy: a study comparing polidocanol in foam and liquid form</article-title>. <source>Phlebology</source><year>2010</year>;<volume>25</volume>:<fpage>44</fpage>&#8211;<lpage>9</lpage>.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">20118346</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1258/phleb.2009.008064</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="R23"><label>[23]</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Beebe-Dimmer</surname><given-names>JL</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Pfeifer</surname><given-names>JR</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Engle</surname><given-names>JS</given-names></name><etal/></person-group>. <article-title>The epidemiology of chronic venous insufficiency and varicose veins</article-title>. <source>Ann Epidemiol</source><year>2005</year>;<volume>15</volume>:<fpage>175</fpage>&#8211;<lpage>84</lpage>.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">15723761</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1016/j.annepidem.2004.05.015</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="R24"><label>[24]</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Lohr</surname><given-names>JM</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Bush</surname><given-names>RL</given-names></name></person-group>. <article-title>Venous disease in women: epidemiology, manifestations, and treatment</article-title>. <source>J Vasc Surg</source><year>2013</year>;<volume>57</volume>:<fpage>37S</fpage>&#8211;<lpage>45S</lpage>.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">23522716</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1016/j.jvs.2012.10.121</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="R25"><label>[25]</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Kolluri</surname><given-names>R</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Hays</surname><given-names>KU</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Gohel</surname><given-names>MS</given-names></name></person-group>. <article-title>Foam Sclerotherapy Augmented Phlebectomy (SAP) procedure for varicose veins: report of a novel technique</article-title>. <source>EJVES Short Rep</source><year>2018</year>;<volume>41</volume>:<fpage>16</fpage>&#8211;<lpage>8</lpage>.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">30519649</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1016/j.ejvssr.2018.10.007</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC6260319</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="R26"><label>[26]</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Bergan</surname><given-names>J</given-names></name></person-group>. <article-title>Sclerotherapy: a truly minimally invasive technique</article-title>. <source>Perspect Vasc Surg Endovasc Ther</source><year>2008</year>;<volume>20</volume>:<fpage>70</fpage>&#8211;<lpage>2</lpage>.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">18403470</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1177/1531003507313216</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="R27"><label>[27]</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Bai</surname><given-names>T</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Jiang</surname><given-names>W</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Chen</surname><given-names>Y</given-names></name><etal/></person-group>. <article-title>Effect of Multiple Factors on Foam Stability in Foam Sclerotherapy</article-title>. <source>Sci Rep</source><year>2018</year>;<volume>8</volume>:<fpage>15683</fpage>.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">30356108</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1038/s41598-018-33992-w</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC6200734</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="R28"><label>[28]</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Yamaki</surname><given-names>T</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Nozaki</surname><given-names>M</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Iwasaka</surname><given-names>S</given-names></name></person-group>. <article-title>Comparative study of duplex-guided foam sclerotherapy and duplex-guided liquid sclerotherapy for the treatment of superficial venous insufficiency</article-title>. <source>Dermatol Surg</source><year>2004</year>;<volume>30</volume>:<fpage>718</fpage>&#8211;<lpage>22</lpage>.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">15099313</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1111/j.1524-4725.2004.30202.x</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="R29"><label>[29]</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Gibson</surname><given-names>K</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Ferris</surname><given-names>B</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Pepper</surname><given-names>D</given-names></name></person-group>. <article-title>Foam sclerotherapy for the treatment of superficial venous insufficiency</article-title>. <source>Surg Clin North Am</source><year>2007</year>;<volume>87</volume>:<fpage>1285</fpage>&#8211;<lpage>95</lpage>.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">17936487</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1016/j.suc.2007.07.001</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="R30"><label>[30]</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Gibson</surname><given-names>K</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Gunderson</surname><given-names>K</given-names></name></person-group>. <article-title>Liquid and foam sclerotherapy for spider and varicose veins</article-title>. <source>Surg Clin North Am</source><year>2018</year>;<volume>98</volume>:<fpage>415</fpage>&#8211;<lpage>29</lpage>.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">29502781</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1016/j.suc.2017.11.010</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref></ref-list></back></article></pmc-articleset>