<?xml version="1.0"  ?><!DOCTYPE pmc-articleset PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD ARTICLE SET 2.0//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pmc/articleset/nlm-articleset-2.0.dtd"><pmc-articleset><article xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" xmlns:ali="http://www.niso.org/schemas/ali/1.0/" article-type="research-article" xml:lang="en" dtd-version="1.4"><processing-meta base-tagset="archiving" mathml-version="3.0" table-model="xhtml" tagset-family="jats"><restricted-by>pmc</restricted-by></processing-meta><front><journal-meta><journal-id journal-id-type="nlm-ta">Aesthetic Plast Surg</journal-id><journal-id journal-id-type="iso-abbrev">Aesthetic Plast Surg</journal-id><journal-id journal-id-type="pmc-domain-id">365</journal-id><journal-id journal-id-type="pmc-domain">springeropen</journal-id><journal-title-group><journal-title>Aesthetic Plastic Surgery</journal-title></journal-title-group><issn pub-type="ppub">0364-216X</issn><issn pub-type="epub">1432-5241</issn><custom-meta-group><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-is-collection-domain</meta-name><meta-value>yes</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-collection-title</meta-name><meta-value>Springer</meta-value></custom-meta></custom-meta-group></journal-meta><article-meta><article-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC10980616</article-id><article-id pub-id-type="pmcid-ver">PMC10980616.1</article-id><article-id pub-id-type="pmcaid">10980616</article-id><article-id pub-id-type="pmcaiid">10980616</article-id><article-id pub-id-type="pmid">38315229</article-id><article-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1007/s00266-023-03812-2</article-id><article-id pub-id-type="publisher-id">3812</article-id><article-version article-version-type="pmc-version">1</article-version><article-categories><subj-group subj-group-type="heading"><subject>Original Articles</subject></subj-group></article-categories><title-group><article-title>Chin Augmentation and Treatment of Chin Retrusion with a Flexible Hyaluronic Acid Filler in Asian Subjects: A Randomized, Controlled, Evaluator-Blinded Study</article-title></title-group><contrib-group><contrib contrib-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Xie</surname><given-names initials="Y">Yun</given-names></name><xref ref-type="aff" rid="Aff1">1</xref></contrib><contrib contrib-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Zhao</surname><given-names initials="H">Hongyi</given-names></name><xref ref-type="aff" rid="Aff2">2</xref></contrib><contrib contrib-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Wu</surname><given-names initials="W">Wenyu</given-names></name><xref ref-type="aff" rid="Aff3">3</xref></contrib><contrib contrib-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Xu</surname><given-names initials="J">Jinhua</given-names></name><xref ref-type="aff" rid="Aff3">3</xref></contrib><contrib contrib-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Li</surname><given-names initials="B">Bi</given-names></name><xref ref-type="aff" rid="Aff4">4</xref></contrib><contrib contrib-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Wu</surname><given-names initials="S">Sufan</given-names></name><xref ref-type="aff" rid="Aff5">5</xref></contrib><contrib contrib-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Chen</surname><given-names initials="K">Kevin</given-names></name><xref ref-type="aff" rid="Aff6">6</xref></contrib><contrib contrib-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Brom&#233;e</surname><given-names initials="T">Torun</given-names></name><xref ref-type="aff" rid="Aff7">7</xref></contrib><contrib contrib-type="author" corresp="yes"><contrib-id contrib-id-type="orcid" authenticated="false">http://orcid.org/0000-0001-7822-618X</contrib-id><name name-style="western"><surname>Li</surname><given-names initials="Q">Qingfeng</given-names></name><address><email>dr.liqingfeng@shsmu.edu.cn</email></address><xref ref-type="aff" rid="Aff1">1</xref></contrib><aff id="Aff1"><label>1</label><institution-wrap><institution-id institution-id-type="GRID">grid.412523.3</institution-id><institution-id institution-id-type="ISNI">0000 0004 0386 9086</institution-id><institution>Department of Plastic and Reconstructive Surgery, Shanghai Ninth People&#8217;s Hospital, Shanghai Jiao Tong University School of Medicine, </institution></institution-wrap>Shanghai, China </aff><aff id="Aff2"><label>2</label><institution-wrap><institution-id institution-id-type="ROR">https://ror.org/02jwb5s28</institution-id><institution-id institution-id-type="GRID">grid.414350.7</institution-id><institution-id institution-id-type="ISNI">0000 0004 0447 1045</institution-id><institution>Beijing Hospital, </institution></institution-wrap>Beijing, China </aff><aff id="Aff3"><label>3</label><institution-wrap><institution-id institution-id-type="GRID">grid.8547.e</institution-id><institution-id institution-id-type="ISNI">0000 0001 0125 2443</institution-id><institution>Huashan Hospital, </institution><institution>Fudan University, </institution></institution-wrap>Shanghai, China </aff><aff id="Aff4"><label>4</label><institution-wrap><institution-id institution-id-type="ROR">https://ror.org/04wwqze12</institution-id><institution-id institution-id-type="GRID">grid.411642.4</institution-id><institution-id institution-id-type="ISNI">0000 0004 0605 3760</institution-id><institution>Peking University Third Hospital, </institution></institution-wrap>Beijing, China </aff><aff id="Aff5"><label>5</label><institution-wrap><institution-id institution-id-type="ROR">https://ror.org/03k14e164</institution-id><institution-id institution-id-type="GRID">grid.417401.7</institution-id><institution-id institution-id-type="ISNI">0000 0004 1798 6507</institution-id><institution>Zhejiang Provincial People&#8217;s Hospital, </institution></institution-wrap>Hangzhou, Zhejiang Province China </aff><aff id="Aff6"><label>6</label>Galderma Trading Co, Shanghai, China </aff><aff id="Aff7"><label>7</label>Galderma, Uppsala, Sweden </aff></contrib-group><pub-date pub-type="epub"><day>5</day><month>2</month><year>2024</year></pub-date><pub-date pub-type="ppub"><year>2024</year></pub-date><volume>48</volume><issue>5</issue><issue-id pub-id-type="pmc-issue-id">458894</issue-id><fpage>1030</fpage><lpage>1036</lpage><history><date date-type="received"><day>8</day><month>9</month><year>2023</year></date><date date-type="accepted"><day>13</day><month>12</month><year>2023</year></date></history><pub-history><event event-type="pmc-release"><date><day>05</day><month>02</month><year>2024</year></date></event><event event-type="pmc-live"><date><day>31</day><month>03</month><year>2024</year></date></event><event event-type="pmc-last-change"><date iso-8601-date="2024-03-31 00:25:15.183"><day>31</day><month>03</month><year>2024</year></date></event></pub-history><permissions><copyright-statement>&#169; The Author(s) 2024</copyright-statement><license><ali:license_ref specific-use="textmining" content-type="ccbylicense">https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</ali:license_ref><license-p><bold>Open Access</bold> This article is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution 4.0 International License, which permits use, sharing, adaptation, distribution and reproduction in any medium or format, as long as you give appropriate credit to the original author(s) and the source, provide a link to the Creative Commons licence, and indicate if changes were made. The images or other third party material in this article are included in the article's Creative Commons licence, unless indicated otherwise in a credit line to the material. If material is not included in the article's Creative Commons licence and your intended use is not permitted by statutory regulation or exceeds the permitted use, you will need to obtain permission directly from the copyright holder. To view a copy of this licence, visit <ext-link xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" ext-link-type="uri" xlink:href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/">http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</ext-link>.</license-p></license></permissions><self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" content-type="pmc-pdf" xlink:href="266_2023_Article_3812.pdf"/><abstract id="Abs1"><sec><title>Background</title><p id="Par1">Aesthetic improvement of the chin is increasingly requested by patients, including those of Chinese origin.</p></sec><sec><title>Methods</title><p id="Par2">A randomized, evaluator-blinded, no-treatment controlled study evaluated the effectiveness and safety of a flexible hyaluronic acid (HA) filler, Restylane<sup>&#174;</sup> Defyne<sup>TM</sup> (HA<sub>DEF</sub>), in the correction of chin retrusion in a Chinese adult population over 12&#160;months after treatment. On Day 1, subjects were randomized 3:1 into two groups, HA<sub>DEF</sub> or delayed-treatment controls, and those in the HA<sub>DEF</sub> group were administered treatment. An optional touch-up treatment was administered 1&#160;month after treatment to obtain optimal chin augmentation. The initially untreated control group was offered delayed-treatment after 6 months (including 1-month touch-up).</p></sec><sec><title>Results</title><p id="Par3">HA<sub>DEF</sub> was superior to no-treatment in improving chin retrusion according to the blinded evaluator at 6&#160;months [Galderma Chin Retrusion Scale (GCRS) responder rate (&#8805;&#160;1-point improvement from baseline) of 81% vs<italic toggle="yes">.</italic> 5% for untreated controls; <italic toggle="yes">p&#160;</italic>&lt;&#160;0.001, meeting the primary effectiveness objective. A majority of subjects maintained improvement at 12&#160;months (61% in the HA<sub>DEF</sub> group). All subjects reported satisfaction with results at 6&#160;months after treatment with HA<sub>DEF</sub> and aesthetic improvement rates per the global aesthetic improvement scale (GAIS) were high for 12&#160;months following treatment, with an acceptable safety profile.</p></sec><sec><title>Conclusions</title><p id="Par4">These results demonstrated HA<sub>DEF</sub> to be effective and safe for the correction of mild-to-moderate chin retrusion in Chinese subjects, confirming findings previously observed in a western population.</p></sec><sec><title>Level of Evidence I</title><p id="Par5"> This journal requires that authors assign a level of evidence to each article. For a full description of these Evidence-Based Medicine ratings, please refer to the Table of Contents or the online Instructions to Authors <ext-link xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" ext-link-type="uri" xlink:href="http://www.springer.com/00266">www.springer.com/00266</ext-link>.</p></sec></abstract><kwd-group xml:lang="en"><title>Keywords</title><kwd>Hyaluronic acid</kwd><kwd>Filler</kwd><kwd>Chin retrusion</kwd><kwd>Randomized controlled trial</kwd><kwd>Aesthetic improvement</kwd><kwd>Asian</kwd></kwd-group><funding-group><award-group><funding-source><institution-wrap><institution-id institution-id-type="FundRef">http://dx.doi.org/10.13039/501100009754</institution-id><institution>Galderma</institution></institution-wrap></funding-source></award-group></funding-group><custom-meta-group><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-status-qastatus</meta-name><meta-value>0</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-status-live</meta-name><meta-value>yes</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-status-embargo</meta-name><meta-value>no</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-status-released</meta-name><meta-value>yes</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-open-access</meta-name><meta-value>yes</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-olf</meta-name><meta-value>no</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-manuscript</meta-name><meta-value>no</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-legally-suppressed</meta-name><meta-value>no</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-has-pdf</meta-name><meta-value>yes</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-has-supplement</meta-name><meta-value>no</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-pdf-only</meta-name><meta-value>no</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-suppress-copyright</meta-name><meta-value>no</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-is-real-version</meta-name><meta-value>no</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-is-scanned-article</meta-name><meta-value>no</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-preprint</meta-name><meta-value>no</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-in-epmc</meta-name><meta-value>yes</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-license-ref</meta-name><meta-value>CC BY</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>issue-copyright-statement</meta-name><meta-value>&#169; Springer Science+Business Media, LLC, part of Springer Nature and International Society of Aesthetic Plastic Surgery 2024</meta-value></custom-meta></custom-meta-group></article-meta></front><body><sec id="Sec1"><title>Introduction</title><p id="Par6">The chin profile is considered as an essential part of facial beauty and along with an expanding global filler market, there is also a rising demand for aesthetic improvement of this facial region [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR1">1</xref>]. Hyaluronic acid (HA) fillers allow for augmentation of facial tissues while avoiding surgical procedures and are frequently used in clinical practice to inject the chin in Chinese individuals. [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR2">2</xref>, <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR3">3</xref>] However, to our knowledge, no randomized and controlled clinical investigation has yet evaluated the effectiveness and safety of HA filler for this indication in China.</p><p id="Par7">The study presented herein was the pivotal study to evaluate effectiveness and safety of Restylane<sup>&#174;</sup> Defyne<sup>TM</sup> (HA<sub>DEF</sub>) in the correction of chin retrusion in a Chinese population. HA<sub>DEF</sub> is approved in China for treatment of nasolabial folds since 2021, and recently (2023) also received the extended approval to include injection into the chin. The product is approved in the USA for use in the chin since 2021 [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR4">4</xref>], following demonstration of effective and safe use of HA<sub>DEF</sub> for the chin indication in a US population [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR5">5</xref>]. HA<sub>DEF</sub> is designed with OBT&#8482;/XpresHAn&#8482; technology that enables distributed integration into the tissue and provides flexible support and contour enhancement. [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR6">6</xref>, <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR7">7</xref>]</p></sec><sec id="Sec2"><title>Methods</title><sec id="Sec3"><title>Study Design</title><p id="Par8">This randomized, evaluator-blinded, no-treatment controlled study (ClinicalTrials.Gov Number <ext-link xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" ext-link-type="pmc:clinical-trial" xlink:href="NCT03597256">NCT03597256</ext-link>) enrolled five sites in China (from Beijing, Shanghai, and Zhejiang Province) and was conducted from October 2018 to September 2020. On Day 1, subjects were randomized 3:1 into two groups, HA<sub>DEF</sub> or delayed-treatment controls, and those in the HA<sub>DEF</sub> group were administered treatment. An optional touch-up treatment was administered at 1 month after treatment to obtain optimal chin augmentation. Effectiveness and safety were followed until 12 months after the last HA<sub>DEF</sub> treatment. The initially untreated control group was offered delayed- treatment after 6 months (including a 1-month touch-up), and control subjects who received this treatment were then assessed for an additional 12 months for safety and effectiveness.</p></sec><sec id="Sec4"><title>Eligibility Criteria</title><p id="Par9">Eligible subjects were adults 18 years or older of Chinese origin with mild-to-moderate chin retrusion. Key exclusion criteria included scars or deformities, disease, or lesions near or in the area to be treated; previous hypersensitivity to any injectable HA gel or to local anesthetics, history of severe allergies; previous tissue augmentation therapy with any permanent or semi-permanent filler; previous facial surgical therapy, laser treatment, or chemical peeling (below the level of the horizontal line from subnasale) within 6 months of study treatment; or use of neurotoxin or HA-based/collagen-based fillers (below the level of the horizontal line from subnasale) within 12 months of study treatment.</p></sec><sec id="Sec5"><title>Treatment</title><p id="Par10">HA<sub>DEF</sub> comprises 20&#160;mg HA/mL and lidocaine hydrochloride 3&#160;mg/mL and was injected using a 27G &#215; &#189;&#8221; ultra-thin wall needle, primarily in the area defined as inferior to the lower lip, between the lines from oral commissure and pre-jowl sulcus. At each treatment session (initial treatment or optional touch-up), it was recommended to inject a maximum dosage of 2&#160;mL in this area. One potential injection technique included administration of HA<sub>DEF</sub> at one injection point at the most anterior portion of the chin with or without 1-point on each side of the chin at the discretion of Investigators. To obtain optimal results, an additional 2&#160;mL could be injected in other areas of the chin at each treatment session. Injections could be given at more than one injection depth (mid to deep dermis, subcutis or supraperiostic zone), and with more than one injection method.</p></sec><sec id="Sec6"><title>Assessments</title><p id="Par11">The primary effectiveness objective of this study was to evaluate whether aesthetic improvement of the chin (chin retrusion) at 6 months following injection with HA<sub>DEF</sub> was superior to no-treatment. The corresponding primary effectiveness endpoint was percentage of responders [defined as at least 1-point improvement from baseline on the galderma chin retrusion scale (GCRS, a 4-point scale from no to severe retrusion) [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR8">8</xref>] assessed by a blinded evaluator] in the treatment group versus control group (6 months after last treatment or randomization, respectively).</p><p id="Par12">Secondary effectiveness objectives were to evaluate chin retrusion, aesthetic improvement, and subject satisfaction. Specifically, secondary effectiveness endpoints comprised GCRS (% responders) to evaluate chin retrusion at other time points at 3, 9, and 12 months after last treatment by the blinded evaluator and at each follow-up visit for treating investigators (i.e., 1, 3, 6, 9, and 12 months after last treatment). Aesthetic improvement was based on a global aesthetic improvement scale (GAIS, a 5-point scale from worse to very much improved), assessed by the subject and treating investigator at each follow-up visit up to 12 months after treatment. The endpoint of GAIS was % responders, defined as having at least an &#8220;improved&#8221; score according to GAIS (i.e. including &#8220;improved&#8221;, &#8220;much improved,&#8221; and &#8220;very much improved&#8221;). Finally, a subject satisfaction questionnaire about treatment outcomes was administered at 3 and 6 months after last treatment.</p><p id="Par13">Safety was evaluated based on adverse event collection throughout the study and pre-defined expected injection-related events recorded using subject diaries for two weeks after each treatment.</p></sec><sec id="Sec7"><title>Statistical Methods</title><p id="Par14">Three analysis populations were defined for the study. They are the safety population (all subjects who were treated with HA<sub>DEF</sub> or randomized to delayed-treatment control, and analyzed according to the as-treated principle), the full analysis set (FAS, all subjects who were treated with HA<sub>DEF</sub> or randomized to delayed-treatment control, and analyzed according to the as-randomized principle), and the per protocol (PP) population (all FAS subjects who had no deviations that could affect evaluation of the primary variable). The primary endpoint (blinded evaluator GCRS at Month 6) was imputed using the baseline observation carried forward method. The FAS population was the primary population for all effectiveness analyzes, and the primary effectiveness analysis was repeated using the PP population.</p><p id="Par15">This study was designed to confirm that the effectiveness in the treatment group is superior to the no-treatment control. The primary effectiveness variable was GCRS responder rates at month six, where the percentage of responders in the HA<sub>DEF</sub> group was compared to the percentage of responders in the control group using Fisher's exact test at a significance level of 5%. The two-sided 95% CIs around the estimates of the percentage of responders for each group were calculated. Superiority was achieved if the 95% CIs for the difference between groups excluded 0, and the p-value was less than 0.05. The sample size was calculated to achieve 90% power to detect a difference between the groups. Also, Fisher&#8217;s exact test was used to compare response rates for GCRS at other time points. GAIS, satisfaction, and safety variables were summarized descriptively.</p></sec></sec><sec id="Sec8"><title>Results</title><sec id="Sec9"><title>Subject Disposition, Demographic, Baseline, and Injection Data</title><p id="Par16">A total of 111 subjects were randomized to HA<sub>DEF</sub> and 37 to the control group. Demographic data are presented in Table <xref rid="Tab1" ref-type="table">1</xref>, and injection details are presented in Table <xref rid="Tab2" ref-type="table">2</xref>. All subjects were treated on Day 1, and touch-up injections were administered at month 1 to 48 subjects in the HA<sub>DEF</sub> group. A mean of 2.1&#160;mL of HA<sub>DEF</sub> was injected in the primary treatment area of the chin (<italic toggle="yes">n</italic>=111) and another 1.4&#160;mL in other areas of the chin for augmentation (<italic toggle="yes">n</italic>=65) in the group randomized to HA<sub>DEF</sub>, including initial and touch-up treatments. In the control group, initial treatment occurred at 6 months, with similar volumes injected as in the treatment group.<table-wrap id="Tab1" position="float" orientation="portrait"><label>Table 1</label><caption><p>Demographic data and baseline characteristics</p></caption><table frame="hsides" rules="groups"><thead><tr><th align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1"/><th align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1"/><th align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">HA<sub>DEF</sub> (<italic toggle="yes">n</italic>= 111)</th><th align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Control (<italic toggle="yes">n</italic>= 37)</th><th align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Total (<italic toggle="yes">n</italic>= 148)</th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td align="left" rowspan="3" colspan="1">Age (years)</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Mean (SD)</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">33.4 (8.0)</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">32.1 (7.1)</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">33.0 (7.8)</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Median</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">34.0</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">31.0</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">32.0</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Min, Max</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">21, 54</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">21, 52</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">21, 54</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Gender <italic toggle="yes">n</italic> (%)</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Female</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">105 (94.6%)</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">35 (94.6%)</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">140 (94.6%)</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1"/><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Male</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">6 (5.4%)</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">2 (5.4%)</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">8 (5.4%)</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Ethnicity <italic toggle="yes">n</italic> (%)</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Han Chinese</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">109 (98.2%)</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">36 (97.3%)</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">145 (98.0%)</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1"/><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Other<sup>a</sup></td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">2 (1.8%)</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">1 (2.7%)</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">3 (2.0%)</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="5" rowspan="1">GCRS: blinded evaluator</td></tr><tr><td align="left" rowspan="2" colspan="1"><italic toggle="yes">n</italic> (%)</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">1 &#8211; Mild</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">39 (35.1%)</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">9 (24.3%)</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">48 (32.4%)</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">2 - Moderate</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">72 (64.9%)</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">28 (75.7%)</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">100 (67.6%)</td></tr></tbody></table><table-wrap-foot><p><sup>a</sup>Mongolian, Man Chinese, the Hui nationality</p></table-wrap-foot></table-wrap><table-wrap id="Tab2" position="float" orientation="portrait"><label>Table 2</label><caption><p>Volume (mL) of HA<sub>DEF</sub> injected</p></caption><table frame="hsides" rules="groups"><thead><tr><th align="left" rowspan="2" colspan="2"/><th align="left" colspan="3" rowspan="1">HA<sub>DEF</sub></th><th align="left" colspan="3" rowspan="1">Control<sup>a</sup></th></tr><tr><th align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1"><italic toggle="yes">N</italic></th><th align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Mean (mL) &#177; SD</th><th align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Range</th><th align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1"><italic toggle="yes">N</italic></th><th align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Mean (mL) &#177; SD</th><th align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Range</th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td align="left" rowspan="3" colspan="1">Primary treatment area of the chin</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Initial</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">111</td><td char="&#xB1;" align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">1.7 &#177; 0.4</td><td char="(" align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">(0.6, 2.0)</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">34</td><td char="&#xB1;" align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">1.7 &#177; 0.4</td><td char="(" align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">(1.0, 2.0)</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">touch-up</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">48</td><td char="&#xB1;" align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">1.1 &#177; 0.5</td><td char="(" align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">(0.2, 2.0)</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">16</td><td char="&#xB1;" align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">1.2 &#177; 0.6</td><td char="(" align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">(0.1, 2.0)</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">total</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">111</td><td char="&#xB1;" align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">2.1 &#177; 0.9</td><td char="(" align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">(0.6, 4.0)</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">34</td><td char="&#xB1;" align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">2.2 &#177; 1.0</td><td char="(" align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">(1.0, 4.0)</td></tr><tr><td align="left" rowspan="3" colspan="1">Other areas of chin</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Initial</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">61</td><td char="&#xB1;" align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">1.1 &#177; 0.6</td><td char="(" align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">(0.1, 2.0)</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">22</td><td char="&#xB1;" align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">1.1 &#177; 0.6</td><td char="(" align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">(0.2, 2.0)</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">touch-up</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">30</td><td char="&#xB1;" align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.8 &#177; 0.5</td><td char="(" align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">(0.1, 2.0)</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">14</td><td char="&#xB1;" align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">1.0 &#177; 0.7</td><td char="(" align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">(0.1, 2.0)</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">total</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">65</td><td char="&#xB1;" align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">1.4 &#177; 1.0</td><td char="(" align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">(0.1, 3.9)</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">23</td><td char="&#xB1;" align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">1.7 &#177; 1.3</td><td char="(" align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">(0.2, 4.0)</td></tr></tbody></table><table-wrap-foot><p><sup>a</sup>In the control group, the initial treatment was at 6 months. 2 patients withdrew before 6 months, and 1 patient declined injection.</p></table-wrap-foot></table-wrap></p><p id="Par17">In the HA<sub>DEF</sub> group, supraperiosteal-depth injections were administered in all but one subject (99%) at initial treatment and in all 48 subjects treated at touch-up; approximately 13% of treated subjects at each treatment occasion were also injected subcutaneously. In terms of the injection method, in the HA<sub>DEF</sub> group, a bolus injection was administered at all initial and touch-up treatments in combination with fanning injection (in 21% and 8% of treated subjects, respectively) and linear retrograde threading (in 7% and 6% of treated subjects, respectively).</p></sec><sec id="Sec10"><title>Effectiveness</title><p id="Par18">Meeting the primary objective at 6 months, the HA<sub>DEF</sub> group was superior to no-treatment in terms of improved chin retrusion according to the blinded evaluator, measured by the GCRS responder rate (81% vs<italic toggle="yes">.</italic> 5% for control; <italic toggle="yes">p&#160;</italic>&lt;&#160;0.001) (Fig. <xref rid="Fig1" ref-type="fig">1</xref>).<fig id="Fig1" position="float" orientation="portrait"><label>Fig. 1.</label><caption><p>Chin retrusion responder rates (GCRS by blinded evaluator) (FAS). ***p&lt;0.001 <italic toggle="yes">vs.</italic> control. FAS- full analysis set. Analysis based on FAS, and for the primary effectiveness endpoint (Month 6), missing values were imputed using the baseline observation carried forward (BOCF) method. Month 3, month 9, and month 12 are based on observed cases, i.e., no imputation of missing data was done for these time points.</p></caption><graphic xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" id="MO1" position="float" orientation="portrait" xlink:href="266_2023_3812_Fig1_HTML.jpg"/></fig></p><p id="Par19">Moreover, secondary efficacy objectives supported the effectiveness of HA<sub>DEF</sub> in terms of GCRS at other time points, GAIS, and subject satisfaction. At 3 months, a significantly greater proportion of subjects had improved GCRS scores in the HA<sub>DEF</sub> group than in the control group as assessed by the blinded evaluator (84% vs<italic toggle="yes">.</italic> 9% for control; <italic toggle="yes">p&#160;</italic>&lt;&#160;0.001), and a majority of subjects maintained improvement at 12 months (61% in the HA<sub>DEF</sub> group) (Fig. <xref rid="Fig1" ref-type="fig">1</xref>). Likewise, results were similar in GCRS assessments made by treating investigators (Table <xref rid="Tab3" ref-type="table">3</xref>).<table-wrap id="Tab3" position="float" orientation="portrait"><label>Table 3</label><caption><p>Chin retrusion responder rates (GCRS, % of responders) (FAS, OC)</p></caption><table frame="hsides" rules="groups"><thead><tr><th align="left" colspan="2" rowspan="1"/><th align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Month 3</th><th align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Month 6</th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td align="left" rowspan="3" colspan="1">Treating investigator, <italic toggle="yes">n</italic>/<italic toggle="yes">N</italic> (%)</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">HA<sub>DEF</sub></td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">92/109 (84.4%)</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">86/107 (80.4%)</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Control</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1"><italic toggle="yes">p-</italic>value</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">&lt;0.001</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">&lt;0.001</td></tr></tbody></table><table-wrap-foot><p><italic toggle="yes">n</italic>number of responders; <italic toggle="yes">N</italic>number of subjects</p><p><italic toggle="yes">FAS</italic> Full Analysis Set, <italic toggle="yes">OC</italic> observed cases</p><p><italic toggle="yes">P</italic>-values for the difference in percentage of responders based on the Fisher&#8217;s exact test</p></table-wrap-foot></table-wrap></p><p id="Par20">Aesthetic improvement (GAIS) in the HA<sub>DEF</sub> group remained high up to 12 months after treatment, as reported by both investigators (&#8805;&#160;97% of subjects) and subjects (&#8805;&#160;80%, Fig. <xref rid="Fig2" ref-type="fig">2</xref>). Subject photographs illustrating this improvement are shown in Fig. <xref rid="Fig3" ref-type="fig">3</xref>, <xref rid="Fig4" ref-type="fig">4</xref>.<fig id="Fig2" position="float" orientation="portrait"><label>Fig. 2.</label><caption><p>GAIS response rate over time in HA<sub>DEF</sub> group, treating investigators and subjects (FAS, OC). FAS: full analysis set; OC: observed cases. A responder was a subject with a GAIS score of improved, much improved or very much improved.</p></caption><graphic xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" id="MO2" position="float" orientation="portrait" xlink:href="266_2023_3812_Fig2_HTML.jpg"/></fig><fig id="Fig3" position="float" orientation="portrait"><label>Fig. 3.</label><caption><p>Subject photographs at (<bold>a</bold>) baseline (GCRS: 2&#8212;moderate) and, (<bold>b)</bold> 6 months (GCRS: 1&#8212;mild) after treatment with HA<sub>DEF</sub>. This 24-year-old male was randomized to the treatment group and received supraperiosteal bolus injections: 2&#160;mL in the chin + 2&#160;mL in other areas at initial treatment, and 1&#160;mL in the chin + 1&#160;mL in other areas at touch-up.</p></caption><graphic xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" id="MO3" position="float" orientation="portrait" xlink:href="266_2023_3812_Fig3_HTML.jpg"/></fig><fig id="Fig4" position="float" orientation="portrait"><label>Fig. 4.</label><caption><p>Subject photographs at (<bold>a</bold>) baseline (GCRS: 2&#8212;moderate) and <bold>(b</bold>) 6 months (GCRS: 1&#8212;mild) after treatment with HA<sub>DEF.</sub> This 23-year-old female was randomized to the treatment group and received supraperiosteal bolus injections: 2&#160;mL in the chin + 2&#160;mL in other areas at initial treatment, with no touch-up treatment.</p></caption><graphic xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" id="MO4" position="float" orientation="portrait" xlink:href="266_2023_3812_Fig4_HTML.jpg"/></fig></p><p id="Par21">Subject satisfaction, assessed through 6 months, also remained high (Fig. <xref rid="Fig5" ref-type="fig">5</xref>). All subjects reported overall satisfaction with their results at 6 months after treatment with HA<sub>DEF</sub>. The majority reported natural-looking results (99%), felt more attractive (90%) and better about themselves (96%), thought their chin retrusion was improved (94%) with no downtime after treatment (78%), would like to receive HA<sub>DEF</sub> again (94%), and would recommend it to others (97%).<fig id="Fig5" position="float" orientation="portrait"><label>Fig. 5.</label><caption><p>Subject satisfaction at 6 months in HA<sub>DEF</sub> group</p></caption><graphic xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" id="MO5" position="float" orientation="portrait" xlink:href="266_2023_3812_Fig5_HTML.jpg"/></fig></p><p id="Par22">Subjects in the control group who received treatment at 6 months showed similar responder rates at 12 months after treatment as in the HA<sub>DEF</sub> group for both GCRS (blinded investigator) and subject-assessed GAIS (data not shown). For the GAIS evaluated by the treating investigator, the responder rate was slightly higher for the HA<sub>DEF</sub> group (approximately 16 percentage units higher compared to the treated controls).</p></sec><sec id="Sec11"><title>Safety</title><p id="Par23">Most subjects (97.2%) reported at least one pre-defined, expected post-treatment event after initial treatment in their 2-week diary, most commonly swelling (86%) and tenderness (82.5%), and most events were transient and mild or moderate in intensity. Treatment-related AEs were also mild or moderate, and consisted of injection site erythema (1.4%), injection site papule (0.7%), and syncope (0.7%). There were no serious treatment-related adverse events.</p></sec></sec><sec id="Sec12"><title>Discussion</title><p id="Par24">The primary objective of this study was met, HA<sub>DEF</sub> led to superior aesthetic improvement of the chin compared to no-treatment in a chinese population at 6 months following injection. The improvement in chin retrusion as shown by GCRS scores was maintained in a majority of subjects (61%) for the 12 months of the study, with an acceptable safety profile. Furthermore, treatment with HA<sub>DEF</sub> led to high subject satisfaction (assessed through 6 months), and high rates of aesthetic improvement for 12 months per GAIS scores. While further studies would be needed to assess the responder rates beyond 12 months, a duration of improvement of 12 months after the last treatment was shown for the majority of treated subjects in this study. A 6-12-month duration of effect is the generally expected longevity for HA filler treatments. Compared to permanent treatment options for correction of chin retrusion, e.g., silicone implants, augmentation of the chin via HA filler injection provides a non-surgical option for patients who do not want a permanent intervention or be exposed to the risks of surgery.</p><p id="Par25">To our knowledge, this is the first randomized and controlled study conducted in an asian population to demonstrate effectiveness and safety of an HA filler for aesthetic treatment of the chin. This evidence is important to meet an increased demand for chin treatments [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR1">1</xref>] in China. For example, in a survey of over 1000 chinese individuals and over 700 chinese aesthetic practitioners, chin enhancement was the fourth most requested treatment (after square jaw/masseter reduction, wrinkle reduction, and nose enhancement) [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR9">9</xref>]. In addition, Liew et al. (2020) confirms that a well-projected chin is considered attractive among asian individuals. [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR10">10</xref>, <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR11">11</xref>]</p><p id="Par26">The assessment scale used to measure chin retrusion in this study was the validated 4-point GCRS designed to measure a clinically relevant improvement. This scale has also been used in a previous US study (Marcus <italic toggle="yes">et al</italic>) [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR5">5</xref>] using the same HA product, HA<sub>DEF</sub>, and was therefore considered the most appropriate choice for confirming the effectiveness in this additional population.</p><p id="Par27">In the prior mentioned US study (Marcus <italic toggle="yes">et al</italic>) [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR5">5</xref>], HA<sub>DEF</sub> was evaluated using a randomized, evaluator-blinded, no-treatment control design for 48 weeks in adults with mild-to-moderate chin retrusion with similar outcomes as in the present study. The endpoints and definitions used were comparable to our study (i.e., GCRS responder rate was also &#8805;&#160;1-grade improvement). In terms of baseline severity, Marcus <italic toggle="yes">et al</italic> [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR5">5</xref>] presented that 63% of patients in the HA<sub>DEF</sub> group in the US study had moderate retrusion, which was comparable to 65% in this study (Table <xref rid="Tab1" ref-type="table">1</xref>).</p><p id="Par28">The US study&#8217;s primary objective, to evaluate effectiveness of HA<sub>DEF</sub> versus no-treatment at 3 months, was met with a significantly higher GCRS responder rate for HA<sub>DEF</sub> (81%) than control (6%) (p&lt;0.001), with maintained responder rates at 6 months. This mirrored the current study at both 3 months (84% vs<italic toggle="yes">.</italic> 9%) and 6 months (81% vs<italic toggle="yes">.</italic> 5%, respectively). In the US study, <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR5">5</xref> comparable effectiveness in the primary endpoint was found across subgroups (e.g., different skin types, subject populations, genders and age groups; about 6% of patients included were asian). This is consistent with effectiveness seen in asian patients in this study, supporting that HA<sub>DEF</sub> appears to be suitable for different populations. GCRS responder rates remained slightly higher in the HA<sub>DEF</sub> group at 12 months (74% vs<italic toggle="yes">.</italic> 11% for control; <italic toggle="yes">p&#160;</italic>&lt;&#160;0.001) in the US study, and this reached 61% in our study. Nevertheless, high aesthetic improvement and subject satisfaction were found in both studies.</p><p id="Par29">Overall, results of this study demonstrated HA<sub>DEF</sub> to be effective and safe for the correction of mild-to-moderate chin retrusion in chinese subjects over 18&#160;years of age. This study confirms the findings previously observed in a western population and supports expanded use of this HA filler in the chin in an asian population.</p></sec></body><back><fn-group><fn><p><bold>Publisher's Note</bold></p><p>Springer Nature remains neutral with regard to jurisdictional claims in published maps and institutional affiliations.</p></fn></fn-group><notes><title>Declarations</title><notes id="FPar1" notes-type="COI-statement"><title>Conflict of Interest</title><p id="Par30">Galderma funded the study and provided the study product. Drs. Yun Xie, Hongyi Zhao, Wenyu Wu, Jinhua Xu, Bi Li, Sufan Wu, and Qingfeng Li were investigators in the clinical trial. Kevin Chen and Torun Brom&#233;e are employees of Galderma.</p></notes><notes id="FPar2"><title>Ethical Approval</title><p id="Par31">The study was approved by independent ethics committees, conformed to the Declaration of Helsinki, and was conducted in accordance with ISO14155 and Good Clinical Practice.</p></notes><notes id="FPar3"><title>Informed Consent</title><p id="Par32">Subjects signed informed consent for participation.</p></notes></notes><ref-list id="Bib1"><title>References</title><ref id="CR1"><label>1.</label><mixed-citation publication-type="other">International Society of Aesthetic Plastic Surgery (ISAPS) (2023) ISAPS international survey on aesthetic/cosmetic procedures performed in 2021. <ext-link xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" ext-link-type="uri" xlink:href="https://isaps.org/media/vdpdanke/isaps-global-survey_2021.pdf">https://isaps.org/media/vdpdanke/isaps-global-survey_2021.pdf</ext-link>. Accessed 30 Mar 2023</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="CR2"><label>2.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Zhou</surname><given-names>J</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Lyu</surname><given-names>W</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Fan</surname><given-names>J-F</given-names></name><etal/></person-group><article-title>Chin augmentation with hyaluronic acid injection</article-title><source>Chin J Aesth Plast Surg</source><year>2014</year><volume>25</volume><issue>1</issue><fpage>26</fpage><lpage>28</lpage></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR3"><label>3.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Zhang</surname><given-names>HJ</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Yu</surname><given-names>B</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Niu</surname><given-names>F</given-names></name><etal/></person-group><article-title>Clinical application and observation of injectable modified sodium hyaluronate gel filler for facial cosmetic surgery</article-title><source>Chin J Stomatol</source><year>2017</year><volume>52</volume><issue>3</issue><fpage>194</fpage><lpage>197</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.3760/cma.j.issn.1002-0098.2017.03.013</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">28279059</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR4"><label>4.</label><mixed-citation publication-type="other">FDA. Directions for use: Restylane Defyne [package insert]. <ext-link xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" ext-link-type="uri" xlink:href="https://www.accessdata.fda.gov/cdrh_docs/pdf14/P140029S027C.pdf">https://www.accessdata.fda.gov/cdrh_docs/pdf14/P140029S027C.pdf</ext-link>. Accessed 5 May 2023</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="CR5"><label>5.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Marcus</surname><given-names>K</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Moradi</surname><given-names>A</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Kaufman-Janette</surname><given-names>J</given-names></name><etal/></person-group><article-title>A randomized trial to assess effectiveness and safety of a hyaluronic acid filler for chin augmentation and correction of chin retrusion</article-title><source>Plast Reconstr Surg</source><year>2022</year><volume>150</volume><issue>6</issue><fpage>1240e</fpage><lpage>1248e</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1097/PRS.0000000000009733</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">36126213</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC9698183</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR6"><label>6.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Lundgren</surname><given-names>B</given-names></name><etal/></person-group><article-title>Using a new photo scale to compare product integration of different hyaluronan-based fillers after injection in human ex vivo skin</article-title><source>J Drugs Dermatol</source><year>2018</year><volume>17</volume><issue>9</issue><fpage>982</fpage><lpage>986</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">30235386</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR7"><label>7.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>&#214;hrlund</surname><given-names>&#197;</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>Evaluation of rheometry amplitude sweep cross-over point as an index of flexibility for HA fillers</article-title><source>J Cosmet, Dermatol Sci Appl.</source><year>2018</year><volume>8</volume><fpage>47</fpage><lpage>54</lpage></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR8"><label>8.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Moradi</surname><given-names>A</given-names></name><etal/></person-group><article-title>Validation of photonumeric assessment scales for temple volume deficit, infraorbital hollows, and chin retrusion</article-title><source>Dermatol Surg</source><year>2020</year><volume>46</volume><issue>9</issue><fpage>1148</fpage><lpage>1154</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1097/DSS.0000000000002269</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">31770155</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR9"><label>9.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Moon</surname><given-names>HJ</given-names></name><etal/></person-group><article-title>Expert consensus on hyaluronic acid filler facial injection for chinese patients</article-title><source>Plast Reconstr Surg Glob Open</source><year>2020</year><volume>8</volume><issue>10</issue><fpage>e3219</fpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1097/GOX.0000000000003219</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">33173709</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC7647603</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR10"><label>10.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Samizadeh</surname><given-names>S</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>Chinese facial physiognomy and modern day aesthetic practice</article-title><source>J Cosmet Dermatol</source><year>2020</year><volume>19</volume><issue>1</issue><fpage>161</fpage><lpage>166</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1111/jocd.12980</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">31102329</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR11"><label>11.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Liew</surname><given-names>S</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Wu</surname><given-names>WTL</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Chan</surname><given-names>HH</given-names></name><etal/></person-group><article-title>Consensus on changing trends, attitudes, and concepts of asian beauty</article-title><source>Aesthet Plast Surg</source><year>2020</year><volume>44</volume><issue>4</issue><fpage>1186</fpage><lpage>1194</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1007/s00266-020-01808-w</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">32844263</pub-id></element-citation></ref></ref-list></back></article></pmc-articleset>