<?xml version="1.0"  ?><!DOCTYPE pmc-articleset PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD ARTICLE SET 2.0//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pmc/articleset/nlm-articleset-2.0.dtd"><pmc-articleset><article xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" xmlns:ali="http://www.niso.org/schemas/ali/1.0/" xml:lang="en" article-type="research-article" dtd-version="1.4"><processing-meta base-tagset="archiving" mathml-version="3.0" table-model="xhtml" tagset-family="jats"><restricted-by>pmc</restricted-by></processing-meta><front><journal-meta><journal-id journal-id-type="nlm-ta">Aesthet Surg J Open Forum</journal-id><journal-id journal-id-type="iso-abbrev">Aesthet Surg J Open Forum</journal-id><journal-id journal-id-type="pmc-domain-id">3943</journal-id><journal-id journal-id-type="pmc-domain">asjopen</journal-id><journal-id journal-id-type="publisher-id">asjopenforum</journal-id><journal-title-group><journal-title>Aesthetic Surgery Journal. Open Forum</journal-title></journal-title-group><issn pub-type="epub">2631-4797</issn><publisher><publisher-name>Oxford University Press</publisher-name></publisher></journal-meta><article-meta><article-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC12342753</article-id><article-id pub-id-type="pmcid-ver">PMC12342753.1</article-id><article-id pub-id-type="pmcaid">12342753</article-id><article-id pub-id-type="pmcaiid">12342753</article-id><article-id pub-id-type="pmid">40800045</article-id><article-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1093/asjof/ojaf081</article-id><article-id pub-id-type="publisher-id">ojaf081</article-id><article-version article-version-type="pmc-version">1</article-version><article-categories><subj-group subj-group-type="heading"><subject>Original Article</subject></subj-group><subj-group subj-group-type="category-taxonomy-collection"><subject>AcademicSubjects/MED00987</subject></subj-group><subj-group subj-group-type="category-taxonomy-collection"><subject>Asj/1</subject></subj-group></article-categories><title-group><article-title>A Prospective, Open-Label Study to Evaluate Dual-Modality Treatment With Deoxycholic Acid (ATX-101) and Hyaluronic Acid (VYC-20L) for Overall Improvement in Jawline Contour</article-title></title-group><contrib-group><contrib contrib-type="author" corresp="yes"><contrib-id contrib-id-type="orcid" authenticated="false">https://orcid.org/0000-0003-4089-9690</contrib-id><name name-style="western"><surname>Goodman</surname><given-names initials="GJ">Greg J</given-names></name><degrees>MBBS, MD, FACD</degrees><xref rid="FM1" ref-type="author-notes"/><xref rid="ojaf081-cor1" ref-type="corresp"/></contrib><contrib contrib-type="author"><contrib-id contrib-id-type="orcid" authenticated="false">https://orcid.org/0000-0001-7994-1812</contrib-id><name name-style="western"><surname>Roberts</surname><given-names initials="S">Stefania</given-names></name><degrees>MBBS, FRACGP</degrees><xref rid="FM2" ref-type="author-notes"/></contrib><contrib contrib-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Cook</surname><given-names initials="N">Natasha</given-names></name><degrees>MBBS, MD, FACD</degrees><xref rid="FM3" ref-type="author-notes"/></contrib><contrib contrib-type="author"><contrib-id contrib-id-type="orcid" authenticated="false">https://orcid.org/0000-0002-5104-480X</contrib-id><name name-style="western"><surname>Ashton</surname><given-names initials="M">Mark</given-names></name><degrees>MBBS, MD, FRACS</degrees><xref rid="FM4" ref-type="author-notes"/></contrib><contrib contrib-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Alker</surname><given-names initials="L">Lucille</given-names></name><degrees>RN, MSN</degrees><xref rid="FM5" ref-type="author-notes"/></contrib><contrib contrib-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Silberberg</surname><given-names initials="M">Michael</given-names></name><degrees>MD, MBA</degrees><xref rid="FM6" ref-type="author-notes"/></contrib></contrib-group><author-notes><fn id="FM1"><p>Dr Goodman is a dermatologist, Monash University, Clayton, VIC, Australia.</p></fn><fn id="FM2"><p>Dr Roberts is a cosmetic physician in private practice, East Melbourne, Australia.</p></fn><fn id="FM3"><p>Dr Cook is a dermatologist in private practice, Darlinghurst, Australia.</p></fn><fn id="FM4"><p>Dr Ashton is a plastic surgeon, Department of Surgery, University of Melbourne, Melbourne, Australia.</p></fn><fn id="FM5"><p>Dr Alker is Director of Medical Affairs Trial Management, Allergan Aesthetics, an AbbVie Company, Irvine, CA, USA.</p></fn><fn id="FM6"><p>Dr Silberberg is former Global Therapeutic Area Head, Allergan Aesthetics, an AbbVie Company, Marlow, UK.</p></fn><corresp id="ojaf081-cor1"><bold>Corresponding Author:</bold> Dr Greg J. Goodman, 8-10 Howitt Street, South Yarra, VIC 3141, Australia. E-mail: <email>gg@div.net.au</email>; X/Twitter: <ext-link xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xlink:href="https://twitter.com/aprofggoodman" ext-link-type="uri">@aprofggoodman</ext-link></corresp></author-notes><pub-date pub-type="collection"><year>2025</year></pub-date><pub-date pub-type="epub" iso-8601-date="2025-06-28"><day>28</day><month>6</month><year>2025</year></pub-date><volume>7</volume><issue-id pub-id-type="pmc-issue-id">478988</issue-id><elocation-id>ojaf081</elocation-id><history><date date-type="editorial-decision"><day>13</day><month>6</month><year>2025</year></date><date date-type="corrected-typeset"><day>09</day><month>8</month><year>2025</year></date></history><pub-history><event event-type="pmc-release"><date><day>28</day><month>06</month><year>2025</year></date></event><event event-type="pmc-live"><date><day>12</day><month>08</month><year>2025</year></date></event><event event-type="pmc-last-change"><date iso-8601-date="2025-08-13 17:25:29.030"><day>13</day><month>08</month><year>2025</year></date></event></pub-history><permissions><copyright-statement>&#169; The Author(s) 2025. Published by Oxford University Press on behalf of The Aesthetic Society.</copyright-statement><copyright-year>2025</copyright-year><license><ali:license_ref specific-use="textmining" content-type="ccbylicense">https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</ali:license_ref><license-p>This is an Open Access article distributed under the terms of the Creative Commons Attribution License (<ext-link xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" ext-link-type="uri" xlink:href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/">https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</ext-link>), which permits unrestricted reuse, distribution, and reproduction in any medium, provided the original work is properly cited.</license-p></license></permissions><self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" content-type="pmc-pdf" xlink:href="ojaf081.pdf"/><self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xlink:href="ojaf081.pdf"/><abstract><title>Abstract</title><sec id="s1"><title>Background</title><p>A poorly defined jawline and blunting of the submental angle by excess submental fat (SMF) contribute to the loss of jawline contour. The injectable adipocytolytic agent ATX-101 reduces SMF, and the hyaluronic acid filler VYC-20L restores facial volume in the chin and jaw.</p></sec><sec id="s2"><title>Objectives</title><p>The objective of this study was to evaluate the benefits of ATX-101 followed by VYC-20L for improving overall jawline contour and definition.</p></sec><sec id="s3"><title>Methods</title><p>In this Phase 4, prospective, open-label, multicenter trial, participants received 1 to 6 ATX-101 treatments (8 weeks apart), followed by VYC-20L with optional VYC-20L touch-up after 14 days. The primary endpoint was Allergan Loss of Jawline Definition Scale (ALJDS) responder rate (proportion achieving &#8805;1-point improvement from baseline in investigator-assessed ALJDS score 4 weeks after final VYC-20L treatment). Secondary and exploratory endpoints included clinician- and participant-assessed measures of jawline definition, satisfaction, skin laxity, and SMF. Treatment-emergent adverse events (TEAEs) were monitored.</p></sec><sec id="s4"><title>Results</title><p>Overall, 53 adults were enrolled and treated. Among 42 evaluable participants, the ALJDS responder rate was 92.9% (95% CI, 80.5-98.5). Consistent improvement across a range of clinician- and participant-assessed scales was achieved, including improvements in SMF Rating Scale score, Submental Skin Laxity Grade, and Global Aesthetic Improvement Scale score. Improvements in FACE-Q Satisfaction with Lower Face and Jawline and Appraisal of Area Under Chin indicated high levels of patient satisfaction. All participants experienced at least 1 TEAE; the majority of TEAEs were moderate in severity.</p></sec><sec id="s5"><title>Conclusions</title><p>Sequential treatment with ATX-101 and VYC-20L may be effective for improving overall jawline contour and definition, with an acceptable safety profile.</p></sec><sec id="s6"><title>Level of Evidence: 2 (Therapeutic)</title><p>
<inline-graphic xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xlink:href="ojaf081il1.jpg"/>
</p></sec></abstract><funding-group><award-group award-type="grant"><funding-source><institution-wrap><institution>Allergan Aesthetics, an AbbVie Company</institution></institution-wrap></funding-source></award-group><award-group award-type="grant"><funding-source><institution-wrap><institution>IL</institution><institution-id institution-id-type="DOI">10.13039/100010667</institution-id></institution-wrap></funding-source></award-group><award-group award-type="grant"><funding-source><institution-wrap><institution>AND</institution><institution-id institution-id-type="DOI">10.13039/100019216</institution-id></institution-wrap></funding-source></award-group><award-group award-type="grant"><funding-source><institution-wrap><institution>Jenna Bassett</institution></institution-wrap></funding-source></award-group><award-group award-type="grant"><funding-source><institution-wrap><institution>LLC</institution><institution-id institution-id-type="DOI">10.13039/100023970</institution-id></institution-wrap></funding-source></award-group><award-group award-type="grant"><funding-source><institution-wrap><institution>HEALTH</institution><institution-id institution-id-type="DOI">10.13039/100010677</institution-id></institution-wrap></funding-source></award-group></funding-group><counts><page-count count="10"/></counts><custom-meta-group><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-status-qastatus</meta-name><meta-value>0</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-status-live</meta-name><meta-value>yes</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-status-embargo</meta-name><meta-value>no</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-status-released</meta-name><meta-value>yes</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-open-access</meta-name><meta-value>yes</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-olf</meta-name><meta-value>no</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-manuscript</meta-name><meta-value>no</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-legally-suppressed</meta-name><meta-value>no</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-has-pdf</meta-name><meta-value>yes</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-has-supplement</meta-name><meta-value>yes</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-pdf-only</meta-name><meta-value>no</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-suppress-copyright</meta-name><meta-value>no</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-is-real-version</meta-name><meta-value>no</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-is-scanned-article</meta-name><meta-value>no</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-preprint</meta-name><meta-value>no</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-in-epmc</meta-name><meta-value>yes</meta-value></custom-meta></custom-meta-group></article-meta></front><body><p>The jawline and adjoining submental area impact the overall aesthetic appearance of the face.<sup><xref rid="ojaf081-B1" ref-type="bibr">1-3</xref></sup> Excess submental fat (SMF) detracts from jawline definition and contributes to an aged or overweight appearance, which can negatively impact self-perception.<sup><xref rid="ojaf081-B1" ref-type="bibr">1</xref>,<xref rid="ojaf081-B4" ref-type="bibr">4</xref></sup> An American Society for Dermatologic Surgery consumer survey showed that 73% of consumers are bothered by excess fat under the chin or neck and, in another survey, 77% of participants reported noticing extra fat in the submental area and 61% wanted it reduced.<sup><xref rid="ojaf081-B5" ref-type="bibr">5</xref>,<xref rid="ojaf081-B6" ref-type="bibr">6</xref></sup> The negative psychological impacts of excess SMF and its effect on jawline aesthetics may drive individuals to seek cosmetic correction.<sup><xref rid="ojaf081-B1" ref-type="bibr">1</xref></sup> These data highlight the importance of jawline aesthetics and the large demand for effective methods to improve jawline definition.</p><p>Although surgical liposuction of the neck and chin (alone or as part of a platysmaplasty) can effectively address SMF and enhance existing jawline definition, it may not be a practical or preferable option for all patients.<sup><xref rid="ojaf081-B7" ref-type="bibr">7</xref>,<xref rid="ojaf081-B8" ref-type="bibr">8</xref></sup> The availability of nonsurgical treatments for SMF reduction allows patients further options to improve their neck in conjunction with their lower face and also allows practitioners options to include the neck in conjunction with their facial analysis. Nonsurgical options for SMF reduction may serve a broader range of patients and can be employed in a multimodal treatment approach to create customizable treatment plans.<sup><xref rid="ojaf081-B8" ref-type="bibr">8</xref></sup></p><p>Improvements in chin appearance and jawline contour can be achieved with injectable products. ATX-101 (Kybella/Belkyra; Allergan Aesthetics, an AbbVie Company, Irvine, CA) is a formulation of deoxycholic acid that causes adipocytolysis and is indicated for improvement in the appearance of moderate-to-severe convexity or fullness associated with SMF.<sup><xref rid="ojaf081-B9" ref-type="bibr">9-13</xref></sup> After SMF reduction, dermal fillers may help further define the jawline. The choice of dermal filler is influenced by patient anatomy, product characteristics, and preference of the patient and provider.<sup><xref rid="ojaf081-B14" ref-type="bibr">14</xref></sup> VYC-20L (Juv&#233;derm Voluma with Lidocaine; Allergan Aesthetics) is a hyaluronic acid (HA) filler employed to restore facial volume and is approved for jawline contouring in Australia.<sup><xref rid="ojaf081-B15" ref-type="bibr">15</xref>,<xref rid="ojaf081-B16" ref-type="bibr">16</xref></sup> Previous studies have evaluated the effectiveness of VYC-20L for structural support of the chin and for improvements in the angle of the jaw and jawline.<sup><xref rid="ojaf081-B17" ref-type="bibr">17</xref>,<xref rid="ojaf081-B18" ref-type="bibr">18</xref></sup> Compared with properties of other HA fillers from the same manufacturer, the stiffer gel characteristics and enhanced cross-linking of VYC-20L are desirable properties for providing structure along the jaw.<sup><xref rid="ojaf081-B16" ref-type="bibr">16</xref>,<xref rid="ojaf081-B19" ref-type="bibr">19</xref></sup></p><p>The objective of this study was to evaluate the benefits of sequential treatment with ATX-101 followed by VYC-20L for improving overall jawline contour and definition.</p><sec sec-type="methods" id="ojaf081-s1"><title>METHODS</title><sec id="ojaf081-s1.1"><title>Participants</title><p>Participants were recruited from a combination of advertisements and study investigators&#8217; private practices. The inclusion and exclusion criteria are given in <xref rid="sup1" ref-type="supplementary-material">Supplemental Table 1</xref>. Briefly, enrolled participants were men and women aged 18 to 65 years with Grade &#8805;2 on the Allergan Loss of Jawline Definition Scale (ALJDS) on both sides of the face as determined by the investigator and Grade 2 or 3 on the Clinician-Reported Submental Fat Rating Scale (CR-SMFRS) who agreed to abstain from treatment/behavior that would affect the assessments of the submental area during the study. Participants with anatomic features that would affect assessments of the submental area (eg, BMI &gt; 35&#8197;kg/m<sup>2</sup>, lower face asymmetry) were excluded, as were those with a history of filler or toxin injections or any intervention to treat SMF. All participants provided written consent for their data to be analyzed.</p></sec><sec id="ojaf081-s1.2"><title>Study Design</title><p>This was a Phase 4, prospective, open-label, multicenter, interventional study conducted at 3 centers in Australia from February 2018 to December 2019 (<ext-link xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" ext-link-type="pmc:clinical-trial" xlink:href="NCT03425253">NCT03425253</ext-link>). The study design called for sequential treatment with ATX-101 followed by VYC-20L in order to observe the independent contributions of these agents to the final outcome.</p><p>All study treatments were performed by study investigators who were dermatologists, cosmetic physicians, or plastic surgeons (authors G.J.G., S.R., N.C., and M.A.). Participants received at least 1 ATX-101 treatment followed by up to 5 optional ATX-101 treatments at least 8 weeks apart (<xref rid="ojaf081-F1" ref-type="fig">Figure 1</xref>). The minimum 8-week interval was chosen because the results from previous studies suggested that a 4-week interval was too short to see the final result before retreatment.<sup><xref rid="ojaf081-B20" ref-type="bibr">20</xref></sup> For each treatment, a maximum of 50 ATX-101 injections (0.2&#8197;mL each) were spaced 1&#8197;cm apart in the subcutaneous fat tissue of the submental area to attain a dose of 2&#8197;mg/cm<sup>2</sup>. Maximum total volumes of 10&#8197;mL per treatment visit and 60&#8197;mL over 6 visits were permitted. An injection grid was employed to outline the planned treatment area and to mark the injection sites. The injection sites were marked by outlining the planned treatment area with a surgical pen and a 1&#8197;cm injection grid, avoiding the area of the marginal mandibular nerve. The participant was asked to tense the platysma. While pinching the SMF, 0.2&#8197;mL of ATX-101 was injected into the preplatysmal fat next to each marked injection site by a 30&#8197;G or smaller, 0.5-inch needle, advancing the needle perpendicular to the skin. Superficial (ie, into the dermis) injections were avoided to prevent skin ulceration. ATX-101 was injected at a depth of approximately midway into the subcutaneous fat layer to avoid injection into the postplatysmal fat; muscle, salivary glands, and lymph nodes were also avoided. The needle was not withdrawn from the subcutaneous fat during injection to prevent intradermal exposure and skin ulceration. However, the needle was withdrawn to an appropriate depth before injection if resistance (indicating possible contact with fascial or nonfat tissue) was met. Upon needle withdrawal, pressure was applied to the injection site to minimize bleeding, and an adhesive dressing was applied as needed. Oral analgesics or nonsteroidal anti-inflammatory drugs, topical and/or injectable local anesthesia (eg, lidocaine), and/or cooling packs were allowed at the area of injection (for treatment or biopsy) at the discretion of the investigator/injector. The injected area was massaged to ensure uniform distribution of ATX-101.</p><fig position="float" id="ojaf081-F1" fig-type="figure" orientation="portrait"><label>Figure 1.</label><caption><p>Study design.</p></caption><graphic xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" position="float" orientation="portrait" xlink:href="ojaf081f1.jpg"/></fig><p>Eight weeks after each ATX-101 treatment, the investigator and participant evaluated whether desired results had been achieved and discussed whether additional ATX-101 treatments were required, at the final discretion of the investigator. After it was determined that further ATX-101 intervention was not required or the maximum of 6 ATX-101 treatments had been administered, participants received VYC-20L along the mandibular border with an optional touch-up treatment after 14 days. The maximum total volume allowed for the initial and touch-up treatments combined was 6&#8197;mL (3&#8197;mL per side of the face). Depending on the investigator's judgment, VYC-20L was administered into the supraperiosteal plane by a needle or cannula per Allergan guidance. After insertion of the needle or cannula but before injection, the plunger was withdrawn to aspirate and verify that the needle or cannula was not intravascular. The injected volume of VYC-20L was distributed between the right and left sides of the face according to the needs of each area. After the injection, the treated area was massaged to ensure uniform distribution of VYC-20L.</p><p>The study design was conducted in compliance with the guidelines on Good Clinical Practice and approved by a central ethics committee (Bellberry Human Research Ethics Committee, Eastwood, South Australia, Australia).</p></sec><sec id="ojaf081-s1.3"><title>Effectiveness Endpoints</title><p>Details of the endpoints assessed in this study and scale descriptions are given in <xref rid="sup1" ref-type="supplementary-material">Supplemental Table 2</xref>. The primary endpoint was ALJDS responder rate, defined as the proportion of participants achieving &#8805;1-point improvement from baseline in the ALJDS score (average of both sides of the face) at the final study visit (4 weeks after final VYC-20L treatment to allow sufficient time to observe final results) as assessed by the investigator. Investigator assessments of ALJDS were performed by study investigators and other trained clinical staff.</p><p>Secondary endpoints included ALJDS responder rate and change from baseline in the ALJDS score as assessed by an independent reviewer, changes in the validated CR-SMFRS and Patient-Reported Submental Fat Rating Scale (PR-SMFRS), Submental Skin Laxity Grade (SMSLG) score, and validated FACE-Q scale scores for jawline, lower face, and chin assessment.<sup><xref rid="ojaf081-B10" ref-type="bibr">10</xref>,<xref rid="ojaf081-B21" ref-type="bibr">21-23</xref></sup> Independent reviewer assessments were based on standardized photographs captured by trained study staff using a VECTRA M3 camera system (Canfield Scientific). Exploratory endpoints assessed change from baseline to 8 weeks after last ATX-101 treatment on the CR-SMFRS, PR-SMFRS, SMSLG, and FACE-Q scores as well as Global Aesthetic Improvement Scale (GAIS) scores (<xref rid="sup1" ref-type="supplementary-material">Supplemental Table 2</xref>). Total follow-up time could range from 12 to 58 weeks, depending on the number of ATX-101 treatments received.</p></sec><sec id="ojaf081-s1.4"><title>Safety</title><p>Adverse events (AEs) were monitored throughout the study. Participants recorded injection site reactions in a 28-day diary during the VYC-20L treatment period.</p></sec><sec id="ojaf081-s1.5"><title>Statistical Analysis and Analysis Populations</title><p>Statistical analyses were performed by SAS version 9.4 or higher (SAS Institute Inc, Cary, NC). Effectiveness endpoints were summarized descriptively with 95% CIs, and statistical differences from baseline in ALJDS, CR-SMFRS, PR-SMFRS, and SMSLG scores were analyzed by paired <italic toggle="yes">t</italic> test (or Wilcoxon&#8217;s signed-rank test if normality assumptions were not met). FACE-Q scores were presented as Rasch-transformed scores (0 [worst] to 100 [best]), and differences from baseline were analyzed by paired <italic toggle="yes">t</italic> tests. Data were pooled across clinical centers for all analyses.</p><p>Three analysis populations were employed for statistical analysis. The primary endpoint was analyzed in the evaluable set, which comprised participants who received both study treatments (ATX-101 and VYC-20L) and had 1 posttreatment effectiveness assessment. Other effectiveness endpoints were analyzed in the full analysis set, which comprised participants who received at least 1 ATX-101 treatment and 1 posttreatment effectiveness assessment. Safety outcomes were evaluated in the safety population, which included participants who consented to participate in the study and met eligibility criteria.</p></sec></sec><sec sec-type="results" id="ojaf081-s2"><title>RESULTS</title><sec id="ojaf081-s2.1"><title>Participants</title><p>Of 58 enrolled participants, 53 met eligibility criteria (safety population). Most participants were female (<italic toggle="yes">n</italic>/<italic toggle="yes">N</italic> = 44/53 [83.0%] vs <italic toggle="yes">n</italic>/<italic toggle="yes">N</italic> = 9/53, [17.0%] males) and White (96.2% [<italic toggle="yes">n</italic> = 51]), with a mean age of 48.0 years (range, 24-64 years) and a mean (standard deviation [SD]) BMI of 28.0 (3.53) kg/m<sup>2</sup> (<xref rid="ojaf081-T1" ref-type="table">Table 1</xref>). Of the 53 eligible participants, all received at least 1 ATX-101 treatment and 1 posttreatment effectiveness assessment (full analysis set), and 42 (79.2%) received both study treatments and 1 posttreatment effectiveness assessment (evaluable set); all participants in the evaluable set completed the study. Eleven participants discontinued during the study owing to withdrawal of consent (<italic toggle="yes">n</italic> = 6), loss to follow-up (<italic toggle="yes">n</italic> = 3), and withdrawal by investigator owing to AEs (<italic toggle="yes">n</italic> = 2). Of the 6 participants who withdrew consent, 1 did so owing to an AE.</p><table-wrap position="float" id="ojaf081-T1" orientation="portrait"><label>Table 1.</label><caption><p>Participant Demographics and Baseline Data</p></caption><table frame="hsides" rules="groups"><colgroup span="1"><col align="left" span="1"/><col align="center" span="1"/></colgroup><thead><tr><th align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Parameter</th><th align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">
<italic toggle="yes">N</italic> = 53</th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Sex, <italic toggle="yes">n</italic> (%)</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1"/></tr><tr><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">&#8195;Female</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">44 (83.0)</td></tr><tr><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">&#8195;Male</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">9 (17.0)</td></tr><tr><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Age, mean (SD), years</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">48.0 (11.1)</td></tr><tr><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">&#8195;Age range, years</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">24-64</td></tr><tr><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Race, <italic toggle="yes">n</italic> (%)</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1"/></tr><tr><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">&#8195;White; not Hispanic or Latino</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">51 (96.2)</td></tr><tr><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">&#8195;Asian</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">1 (1.9)</td></tr><tr><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">&#8195;Other</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">1 (1.9)</td></tr><tr><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Weight, mean (SD), kg</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">79.4 (13.5)</td></tr><tr><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">&#8195;Weight range, kg</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">51.0-108.0</td></tr><tr><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">BMI, mean (SD), kg/m<sup>2</sup></td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">28.0 (3.5)</td></tr><tr><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">&#8195;BMI range, kg/m<sup>2</sup></td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">20.0-34.6</td></tr><tr><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Fitzpatrick skin type, <italic toggle="yes">n</italic> (%)</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1"/></tr><tr><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">&#8195;I-III</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">51 (96.2)</td></tr><tr><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">&#8195;IV-VI</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">2 (3.8)</td></tr><tr><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Baseline ALJDS, left side, right side, <italic toggle="yes">n</italic> (%)</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1"/></tr><tr><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">&#8195;Grade 2 (moderate)</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">20 (37.7), 24 (45.3)</td></tr><tr><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">&#8195;Grade 3 (severe)</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">32 (60.4), 29 (54.7)</td></tr><tr><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">&#8195;Grade 4 (extreme)</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">1 (1.9), 0 (0)</td></tr><tr><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Baseline CR-SMFRS, <italic toggle="yes">n</italic> (%)</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1"/></tr><tr><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">&#8195;Grade 3 (severe)</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">32 (60.4)</td></tr><tr><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">&#8195;Grade 4 (extreme)</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">21 (39.6)</td></tr><tr><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Baseline SMSLG, <italic toggle="yes">n</italic> (%)</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1"/></tr><tr><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">&#8195;Grade 1 (none)</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">13 (24.5)</td></tr><tr><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">&#8195;Grade 2 (mild)</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">32 (60.4)</td></tr><tr><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">&#8195;Grade 3 (moderate)</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">8 (15.1)</td></tr></tbody></table><table-wrap-foot><fn id="tblfn1"><p>ALJDS, Allergan Loss of Jawline Definition Scale; CR-SMFRS, Clinician-Reported Submental Fat Rating Scale; SD, standard deviation; SMSLG, Submental Skin Laxity Grade.</p></fn></table-wrap-foot></table-wrap></sec><sec id="ojaf081-s2.2"><title>Treatment Sessions</title><p>During the study, a total mean (SD) of 5.2 (2.3) mL of ATX-101 was injected per treatment session. On average (SD), participants received 4.9 (1.5) sessions with ATX-101 and duration of treatment was 237.3 (94.1; range, 1-404) days. A total mean (SD) of 2.4 (1.2) mL of VYC-20L was injected (distributed between both sides of the face) for both initial and touch-up treatments combined. On average (SD), participants received 1.9 (0.3) treatment sessions with VYC-20L and duration of treatment was 18.4 (9.4; range, 1-6) days. The mean follow-up time for participants who completed the study was 388.5 (SD, 90.0; range, 163-511) days.</p></sec><sec id="ojaf081-s2.3"><title>Primary Endpoint</title><p>Of 42 participants, 39 (92.9%; 95% CI, 80.5-98.5) demonstrated a &#8805;1-point improvement from baseline to final study visit in the investigator-assessed ALJDS (<xref rid="ojaf081-F2" ref-type="fig">Figure 2A</xref>).</p><fig position="float" id="ojaf081-F2" fig-type="figure" orientation="portrait"><label>Figure 2.</label><caption><p>Investigator-assessed Allergan Loss of Jawline Definition Scale (ALJDS). (A) Proportion of participants achieving improvement on the ALJDS. (B) Mean ALJDS score from baseline to final study visit (4 weeks after final VYC-20L treatment). Lower scores indicate improvement in jawline definition. *<italic toggle="yes">P</italic> &lt; .001 vs baseline. ALJDS is based on the average of both the left and right sides of the face. ALJDS grades: 0 (none), 1 (mild), 2 (moderate), 3 (severe), and 4 (extreme).</p></caption><graphic xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" position="float" orientation="portrait" xlink:href="ojaf081f2.jpg"/></fig></sec><sec id="ojaf081-s2.4"><title>Secondary Endpoints</title><p>The mean improvement from baseline on the ALJDS was &#8722;1.0 point (95% CI, &#8722;1.2 to &#8722;0.7; <italic toggle="yes">P</italic> &lt; .001) at 8 weeks after final ATX-101 treatment and &#8722;1.8 points (95% CI, &#8722;2.1 to &#8722;1.5; <italic toggle="yes">P</italic> &lt; .001) at 4 weeks after final VYC-20L treatment (<xref rid="ojaf081-F2" ref-type="fig">Figure 2B</xref>). The proportion of participants achieving a &#8805;1-point improvement from baseline to final study visit in the independent reviewer&#8211;assessed ALJDS included 23 of 42 participants (54.8%; 95% CI, 38.7-70.2; <xref rid="ojaf081-F3" ref-type="fig">Figure 3A</xref>). The mean improvement from baseline was &#8722;0.4 points (95% CI, &#8722;0.7 to &#8722;0.1; <italic toggle="yes">P</italic> = .004) at 8 weeks after final ATX-101 treatment and &#8722;0.7 points (95% CI, &#8722;1.0 to &#8722;0.4; <italic toggle="yes">P</italic> &lt; .001) at 4 weeks after final VYC-20L treatment (<xref rid="ojaf081-F3" ref-type="fig">Figure 3B</xref>).</p><fig position="float" id="ojaf081-F3" fig-type="figure" orientation="portrait"><label>Figure 3.</label><caption><p>Independent reviewer&#8211;assessed Allergan Loss of Jawline Definition Scale (ALJDS). (A) Proportion of participants achieving improvement on the ALJDS. (B) Mean ALJDS score from baseline to final study visit (4 weeks after final VYC-20L treatment). Lower scores indicate improvement in jawline definition. *<italic toggle="yes">P</italic> &lt; .005 vs baseline. ALJDS is based on the average of both the left and right sides of the face. ALJDS grades: 0 (none), 1 (mild), 2 (moderate), 3 (severe), and 4 (extreme).</p></caption><graphic xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" position="float" orientation="portrait" xlink:href="ojaf081f3.jpg"/></fig><p>At 4 weeks after final VYC-20L treatment, the mean improvement from baseline in the CR-SMFRS was &#8722;1.9 (95% CI, &#8722;2.2 to &#8722;1.7; <italic toggle="yes">P</italic> &lt; .001; <xref rid="ojaf081-F4" ref-type="fig">Figure 4A</xref>). The mean improvement in PR-SMFRS was &#8722;1.6 (95% CI, &#8722;1.9 to &#8722;1.3; <italic toggle="yes">P</italic> &lt; .001; <xref rid="ojaf081-F4" ref-type="fig">Figure 4B</xref>), and in SMSLG was &#8722;0.3 points (95% CI, &#8722;0.5 to &#8722;0.1; <italic toggle="yes">P</italic> = .003) from baseline to final study visit at 4 weeks after final VYC-20L treatment (<xref rid="ojaf081-F5" ref-type="fig">Figure 5</xref>).</p><fig position="float" id="ojaf081-F4" fig-type="figure" orientation="portrait"><label>Figure 4.</label><caption><p>Mean (A) Clinician-Reported Submental Fat Rating Scale (CR-SMFRS) and (B) Patient-Reported Submental Fat Rating Scale (PR-SMFRS) scores from baseline to final study visit (4 weeks after final VYC-20L treatment). Lower scores indicate improvement. *<italic toggle="yes">P</italic> &lt; .001 vs baseline. CR-SMFRS grades: 0 (absent), 1 (mild), 2 (moderate), 3 (severe), and 4 (extreme). PR-SMFRS grades: 0 (no chin fat at all), 1 (slight amount of chin fat), 2 (moderate amount of chin fat), 3 (large amount of chin fat), and 4 (a very large amount of chin fat).</p></caption><graphic xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" position="float" orientation="portrait" xlink:href="ojaf081f4.jpg"/></fig><fig position="float" id="ojaf081-F5" fig-type="figure" orientation="portrait"><label>Figure 5.</label><caption><p>Mean Submental Skin Laxity Grade (SMSLG) scores from baseline to final study visit (4 weeks after final VYC-20L treatment). Lower scores indicate improvement. *<italic toggle="yes">P</italic> &#8804; .005 vs baseline. SMSLG scale: 1 (none), 2 (mild), 3 (moderate), and 4 (severe).</p></caption><graphic xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" position="float" orientation="portrait" xlink:href="ojaf081f5.jpg"/></fig><p>The mean improvement from baseline in FACE-Q score for the Satisfaction with Lower Face and Jawline scale was +55.9 points (95% CI, 48.6-63.3; <italic toggle="yes">P</italic> &lt; .001) at 4 weeks after final VYC-20L treatment (<xref rid="ojaf081-F6" ref-type="fig">Figure 6A</xref>). The mean improvement from baseline in the FACE-Q score for the Appraisal of Area Under Chin scale was &#8722;45.4 points (95% CI, &#8722;54.5 to &#8722;36.3; <italic toggle="yes">P</italic> &lt; .001) at 4 weeks after final VYC-20L treatment (<xref rid="ojaf081-F6" ref-type="fig">Figure 6B</xref>).</p><fig position="float" id="ojaf081-F6" fig-type="figure" orientation="portrait"><label>Figure 6.</label><caption><p>Mean Rasch-transformed FACE-Q. (A) Satisfaction with Lower Face and Jawline and (B) Appraisal of Area Under Chin scores from baseline to final study visit (4 weeks after final VYC-20L treatment). Higher scores for the Satisfaction with Lower Face and Jawline and lower scores for the Appraisal of Area Under Chin indicate improvement. *<italic toggle="yes">P</italic> &lt; .001 vs baseline. Satisfaction with Lower Face and Jawline scores range from 1 (very dissatisfied) to 4 (very satisfied). Appraisal of area under chin scores range from 1 (not at all) to 4 (extremely). Rasch-transformed scores range from 0 (worst) to 100 (best).</p></caption><graphic xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" position="float" orientation="portrait" xlink:href="ojaf081f6.jpg"/></fig></sec><sec id="ojaf081-s2.5"><title>Exploratory Endpoints</title><p>The mean improvement from baseline in the CR-SMFRS was &#8722;1.7 points (95% CI, &#8722;1.8 to &#8722;1.5; <italic toggle="yes">P</italic> &lt; .001) at 8 weeks after final ATX-101 treatment (<xref rid="ojaf081-F4" ref-type="fig">Figure 4A</xref>). The mean improvement from baseline in PR-SMFRS was &#8722;1.4 points (95% CI, &#8722;1.7 to &#8722;1.2; <italic toggle="yes">P</italic> &lt; .001) at 8 weeks after final ATX-101 treatment (<xref rid="ojaf081-F4" ref-type="fig">Figure 4B</xref>). The mean improvement from baseline in SMSLG was &#8722;0.3 points (95% CI, &#8722;0.6 to &#8722;0.1; <italic toggle="yes">P</italic> = .005) at 8 weeks after final ATX-101 treatment (<xref rid="ojaf081-F5" ref-type="fig">Figure 5</xref>).</p><p>At 8 weeks after final ATX-101 treatment, the mean improvement from baseline in FACE-Q score for the Satisfaction with Lower Face and Jawline scale was +31.7 points (95% CI, 23.0-40.3; <italic toggle="yes">P</italic> &lt; .001; <xref rid="ojaf081-F6" ref-type="fig">Figure 6A</xref>), and the mean improvement from baseline in the FACE-Q score for the Appraisal of Area Under Chin scale was &#8722;31.1 points (95% CI, &#8722;42.3 to &#8722;19.8; <italic toggle="yes">P</italic> &lt; .001; <xref rid="ojaf081-F6" ref-type="fig">Figure 6B</xref>).</p><p>The mean investigator- and participant-assessed GAIS scores were 1.6 and 1.7 (2 = much improved), respectively, at 8 weeks after final ATX-101 treatment. The mean investigator- and participant-assessed GAIS scores were 1.7 and 1.8, respectively, at 4 weeks after final VYC-20L treatment. Representative photographs illustrating changes from baseline in the lower facial appearance of 2 study participants are shown in <xref rid="ojaf081-F7" ref-type="fig">Figure 7</xref>.</p><fig position="float" id="ojaf081-F7" fig-type="figure" orientation="portrait"><label>Figure 7.</label><caption><p>Representative photographs of participants showing a &#8805;2-point improvement on the Allergan Loss of Jawline Definition Scale (ALJDS). (A) A 45-year-old female participant (BMI, 24.8&#8197;kg/m<sup>2</sup>) was injected with a mean of 8.2 (SD, 0.35; range, 8.0-8.6) mL of ATX-101 per treatment session (1 initial and 2 additional treatment sessions), followed by a total of 4.0 and 2.0&#8197;mL of VYC-20L for both sides of the face for initial and touch-up treatments, respectively (combined total of 6.0&#8197;mL). (B) A 57-year-old female participant (BMI, 21.4&#8197;kg/m<sup>2</sup>) was injected with a mean of 7.0 (SD, 1.73; range, 5.0-8.0) mL of ATX-101 per treatment session (1 initial and 2 additional treatment sessions), followed by a total of 5.0 and 1.0&#8197;mL of VYC-20L for both sides of the face for initial and touch-up treatments, respectively (combined total of 6.0&#8197;mL). Injected volumes of VYC-20L were distributed between the right and left sides of the face according to the needs of each area.</p></caption><graphic xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" position="float" orientation="portrait" xlink:href="ojaf081f7.jpg"/></fig></sec><sec id="ojaf081-s2.6"><title>Safety</title><p>All participants (<italic toggle="yes">N</italic> = 53) reported at least 1 treatment-emergent AE (TEAE), and the majority of TEAEs were mild to moderate in severity (69.8%). All 53 participants (100%) reported at least 1 TEAE related to ATX-101, and 3 of 53 participants (5.7%) reported at least 1 TEAE related to VYC-20L (<xref rid="ojaf081-T2" ref-type="table">Table 2</xref>). Two (3.8%) of 53 participants experienced a total of 5 serious AEs (SAEs), which were unrelated to treatments or study procedures. One participant experienced an SAE of lower respiratory tract infection, and 1 participant experienced SAEs of severe volvulus, uterine leiomyoma, and vaginal hemorrhage (2 dates). No participants were discontinued from treatment owing to an SAE.</p><table-wrap position="float" id="ojaf081-T2" orientation="portrait"><label>Table 2.</label><caption><p>Treatment-Emergent Adverse Events (TEAEs) Related to ATX-101 and VYC-20L Treatment (<italic toggle="yes">N</italic> = 53)</p></caption><table frame="hsides" rules="groups"><colgroup span="1"><col align="left" span="1"/><col align="center" span="1"/><col align="center" span="1"/></colgroup><thead><tr><th align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">TEAEs</th><th align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Related to ATX-101, <italic toggle="yes">n</italic> (%)<sup><xref rid="tblfn3" ref-type="table-fn">a</xref></sup></th><th align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Related to VYC-20L, <italic toggle="yes">n</italic> (%)</th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">IS pain</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">39 (73.6)</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">1 (1.9)</td></tr><tr><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">IS swelling</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">39 (73.6)</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">0</td></tr><tr><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">IS bruising</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">36 (67.9)</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">2 (3.8)</td></tr><tr><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">IS mass</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">30 (56.6)</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">0</td></tr><tr><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">IS hypoesthesia</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">29 (54.7)</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">0</td></tr><tr><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">IS induration</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">24 (45.3)</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">0</td></tr><tr><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">IS reaction</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">11 (20.8)</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">0</td></tr><tr><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">IS erythema</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">11 (20.8)</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">0</td></tr><tr><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Contusion</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">8 (15.1)</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">0</td></tr><tr><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">IS discomfort</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">8 (15.1)</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">1 (1.9)</td></tr><tr><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">IS warmth</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">8 (15.1)</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">0</td></tr><tr><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">IS discoloration</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">7 (13.2)</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">0</td></tr><tr><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Headache</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">7 (13.2)</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">0</td></tr><tr><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Swelling face</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">6 (11.3)</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">0</td></tr><tr><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">IS pruritus</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">5 (9.4)</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">0</td></tr><tr><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Swelling</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">4 (7.5)</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">0</td></tr><tr><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Weight decreased</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">3 (5.7)</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">0</td></tr><tr><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Nausea</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">3 (5.7)</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">0</td></tr><tr><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Alopecia</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">2 (3.8)</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">0</td></tr><tr><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Postprocedural contusion</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">2 (3.8)</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">0</td></tr><tr><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">IS paresthesia</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">2 (3.8)</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">0</td></tr></tbody></table><table-wrap-foot><fn id="tblfn2"><p>IS, injection site; TEAE, treatment-emergent adverse event.</p></fn><fn id="tblfn3"><p>
<sup>a</sup>TEAEs related to ATX-101 in &gt;1 participant.</p></fn></table-wrap-foot></table-wrap><p>Of the 53 participants who experienced TEAEs related to ATX-101, the most common were injection site pain (39, 73.6%), injection site swelling (39, 73.6%), and injection site bruising (36, 67.9%; <xref rid="ojaf081-T2" ref-type="table">Table 2</xref>). Ten (18.9%) of 53 participants reported the following complications related to ATX-101: contusion (8, 15.1%), postprocedural contusion (2, 3.8%), and procedural pain (1, 1.9%). Three (5.7%) of 53 participants discontinued the study owing to ATX-101-related AEs. Of these 3 participants, 1 elected to withdraw consent from the study owing to procedural pain and the other 2 were withdrawn by the investigator because of injection site&#8211;related AEs, including discoloration, induration, pain, and rash. The most common TEAE related to VYC-20L was injection site bruising (2/53, 3.8%; <xref rid="ojaf081-T2" ref-type="table">Table 2</xref>). No participants reported a complication related to VYC-20L.</p></sec></sec><sec sec-type="discussion" id="ojaf081-s3"><title>DISCUSSION</title><p>The jawline plays a prominent role in the facial profile.<sup><xref rid="ojaf081-B1" ref-type="bibr">1-3</xref></sup> During aging, the jawline loses definition as a result of structural, bony, soft tissue, and skin changes.<sup><xref rid="ojaf081-B24" ref-type="bibr">24</xref></sup> These include an increasing cervicomental angle (an angle between the vertical portion of the neck and the transverse portion of the submandibular region), mandible recession, SMF accumulation, weakening of the mandible septum (which holds fat compartments in place), and skin laxity (which leads to sagging jowl fat).<sup><xref rid="ojaf081-B1" ref-type="bibr">1</xref>,<xref rid="ojaf081-B24" ref-type="bibr">24</xref></sup> The change in the appearance of the jawline over time may cause feelings of embarrassment and low self-esteem.<sup><xref rid="ojaf081-B1" ref-type="bibr">1</xref></sup> The negative psychological impact of excess SMF underlines the importance of optimizing treatment options for jawline rejuvenation.</p><p>Here, we report the results of a nonsurgical, multimodal approach to improve jawline aesthetics. This study demonstrates that sequential, noninvasive treatment by ATX-101 followed by VYC-20L improves the jawline contour by reducing submental fullness and enhancing mandibular border definition, respectively. The primary endpoint was met, with 92.9% of participants achieving a &#8805;1-point improvement in jawline definition from baseline to final study visit using the ALJDS scale. Consistent improvement across a range of clinician- and participant-assessed scales was achieved, including a high level of satisfaction with treatment results. In addition, skin laxity was improved following reduction in SMF, which supports the findings of previous studies with ATX-101.<sup><xref rid="ojaf081-B12" ref-type="bibr">12</xref>,<xref rid="ojaf081-B21" ref-type="bibr">21</xref></sup> These data support the effectiveness of these 2 agents in improving jawline contour to help patients achieve a satisfactory facial aesthetic.</p><p>Several studies investigating the effectiveness of ATX-101 and HA fillers individually on the chin and jawline have been conducted. ATX-101 treatment has been shown to be safe and effective in reducing SMF and resulted in increased patient satisfaction with facial appearance.<sup><xref rid="ojaf081-B9" ref-type="bibr">9-12</xref></sup> Similarly, HA filler injections have demonstrated effectiveness in chin and jawline enhancement with high levels of patient satisfaction.<sup><xref rid="ojaf081-B18" ref-type="bibr">18</xref>,<xref rid="ojaf081-B25" ref-type="bibr">25</xref>,<xref rid="ojaf081-B26" ref-type="bibr">26</xref></sup> Combination treatment has also shown promise in early studies: sequential treatment by ATX-101 and HA fillers improved overall facial appearance and perceived age in addition to having psychosocial benefits.<sup><xref rid="ojaf081-B27" ref-type="bibr">27</xref></sup> Panfacial aesthetic treatment by different minimally invasive modalities is recognized as a valid approach to optimizing treatment outcomes.<sup><xref rid="ojaf081-B28" ref-type="bibr">28</xref></sup></p><p>Treatment with ATX-101 and VYC-20L was well tolerated in the present study. AEs and injection site reactions, including swelling, which is an expected part of the recovery period, were consistent with studies using ATX-101 or HA fillers individually for chin and jawline reshaping.<sup><xref rid="ojaf081-B9" ref-type="bibr">9-13</xref>,<xref rid="ojaf081-B18" ref-type="bibr">18</xref>,<xref rid="ojaf081-B25" ref-type="bibr">25</xref>,<xref rid="ojaf081-B26" ref-type="bibr">26</xref></sup> The majority of TEAEs were mild to moderate in severity and involved the injection site.</p><p>The study design has limitations. Investigator-conducted assessments are subjective and may be influenced by individual biases. Responder rates based on investigator-assessed ALJDS scores were substantially higher than those based on independent reviewer&#8211;assessed scores (92.9% vs 54.8%, respectively) and were in line with large improvements from baseline on participant-assessed scales, indicating that live investigator assessments may have resulted in more positive ratings vs the static photograph assessments conducted by the independent reviewer and/or that the open-label study design may have led to more positive responses from the evaluating investigators and participants compared with a blinded study design. Previous studies of ATX-101 for SMF reduction analyzed the effects of treatment by magnetic resonance imaging.<sup><xref rid="ojaf081-B9" ref-type="bibr">9</xref>,<xref rid="ojaf081-B10" ref-type="bibr">10</xref></sup> The current study did not include supporting radiological assessments to measure effectiveness. The number of treatments with ATX-101 and VYC-20L was higher than the number of anticipated treatments based on clinical experience, which may have been owing to the cost of treatment being covered by the study sponsor. In real-world practice, it is possible that treatment costs would contribute to limiting the number of treatments sought. Furthermore, the current study only evaluated dual-modality treatment with ATX-101 and VYC-20L and did not assess other means of surgical (eg, liposuction) and nonsurgical SMF reduction (eg, cryolipolysis), or other HA fillers, such as VYC-25L (Juv&#233;derm Volux with Lidocaine; Allergan Aesthetics), which has been approved for restoring and creating volume in the chin and jawline area.<sup><xref rid="ojaf081-B26" ref-type="bibr">26</xref></sup> Comparisons of ATX-101 and VYC-20L with other dual-modality approaches may be considered for future studies. The study population was mostly White and female, limiting generalizability to other racial groups and males. In addition to increasing gender and racial diversity, future studies may consider subanalyses by age, gender, and skin type. The discontinuation rate among the 53 participants who received treatment (11, 19%) may also limit the ability to extrapolate the study findings to the general population. Although 3 participants discontinued owing to AEs (1 of whom was categorized as having withdrawn consent because of procedural pain), none discontinued owing to an SAE. A larger, longer-term study may be needed to provide a full assessment of the duration of effectiveness and safety.</p><p>Overall, this study demonstrated the benefit of combined treatment with ATX-101 followed by VYC-20L for improving jawline aesthetics, enhancing a growing trend in the aesthetic field of using multimodal treatment approaches that consider both the face/jawline and submental area.<sup><xref rid="ojaf081-B28" ref-type="bibr">28</xref></sup> This study investigates minimally invasive treatment options for patients, especially those who are not suitable candidates for, or are unwilling to undergo, traditional invasive procedures for SMF reduction, which have the potential for postprocedural complications.</p></sec><sec sec-type="conclusions" id="ojaf081-s4"><title>CONCLUSIONS</title><p>Sequential treatments of ATX-101 and VYC-20L enhanced the overall contour of the jawline by addressing convexity or fullness associated with SMF and restoring volume along the mandible, respectively, with an acceptable safety profile. Participants were satisfied with the results of this multimodal treatment approach on validated outcome measures.</p><p>The clinical trial data associated with this article can be requested online by qualified researchers through Vivli (Burlington, MA) following review and approval of a research proposal, statistical analysis plan, and execution of a data sharing agreement. The data will be accessible for 12 months.</p></sec><sec id="ojaf081-s5"><title>Supplemental Material</title><p>This article contains <xref rid="sup1" ref-type="supplementary-material">supplemental material</xref> located online at <ext-link xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xlink:href="https://doi.org/10.1093/asjof/ojaf081" ext-link-type="uri">https://doi.org/10.1093/asjof/ojaf081</ext-link>.</p></sec><sec sec-type="supplementary-material"><title>Supplementary Material</title><supplementary-material id="sup1" position="float" content-type="local-data" orientation="portrait"><label>ojaf081_Supplementary_Data</label><media xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xlink:href="ojaf081_supplementary_data.docx" position="float" orientation="portrait"/></supplementary-material></sec></body><back><sec id="ojaf081-s6"><title>Disclosures</title><p>Dr Cook is an investigator and advisory board member for Allergan Aesthetics, an AbbVie Company. Dr Goodman is a consultant, speaker, and investigator for Allergan Aesthetics, an AbbVie Company. Dr Roberts is a consultant for AbbVie. Drs Alker and Silberberg are employees of AbbVie and may own AbbVie stock. The remaining authors have nothing to disclose.</p></sec><sec id="ojaf081-s7"><title>Funding</title><p>Allergan Aesthetics, an AbbVie Company (Irvine, CA), funded this study and participated in the study design, research, analysis, data collection, interpretation of data, reviewing, and approval of the publication. All authors had access to relevant data and participated in the drafting, review, and approval of this publication. No honoraria or payments were made for authorship. Medical writing and editing support was provided by Jenna Bassett, PhD of Peloton Advantage, LLC, an OPEN Health company, and funded by Allergan Aesthetic, an AbbVie Company. Erika von Grote, PhD, a former employee of AbbVie, provided input on drafting the manuscript.</p></sec><ref-list id="ref1"><title>REFERENCES</title><ref id="ojaf081-B1"><label>1</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><string-name name-style="western"><surname>Baumann</surname> &#160;<given-names>L</given-names></string-name>, <string-name name-style="western"><surname>Shridharani</surname> &#160;<given-names>SM</given-names></string-name>, <string-name name-style="western"><surname>Humphrey</surname> &#160;<given-names>S</given-names></string-name>, <string-name name-style="western"><surname>Gallagher</surname> &#160;<given-names>CJ</given-names></string-name></person-group>. <article-title>Personal (self) perceptions of submental fat among adults in the United States</article-title>. <source>Dermatol Surg</source>. <year>2019</year>;<volume>45</volume>:<fpage>124</fpage>&#8211;<lpage>130</lpage>. doi: <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1097/DSS.0000000000001648</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">30234657</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC6319576</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="ojaf081-B2"><label>2</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><string-name name-style="western"><surname>de Maio</surname> &#160;<given-names>M</given-names></string-name>, <string-name name-style="western"><surname>Wu</surname> &#160;<given-names>WTL</given-names></string-name>, <string-name name-style="western"><surname>Goodman</surname> &#160;<given-names>GJ</given-names></string-name>, <string-name name-style="western"><surname>Monheit</surname> &#160;<given-names>G</given-names></string-name></person-group>. <article-title>Facial assessment and injection guide for botulinum toxin and injectable hyaluronic acid fillers: focus on the lower face</article-title>. <source>Plast Reconstr Surg</source>. <year>2017</year>;<volume>140</volume>:<fpage>393e</fpage>&#8211;<lpage>404e</lpage>. doi: <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1097/prs.0000000000003646</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">28841604</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="ojaf081-B3"><label>3</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><string-name name-style="western"><surname>Goodman</surname> &#160;<given-names>GJ</given-names></string-name>, <string-name name-style="western"><surname>Subramanian</surname> &#160;<given-names>M</given-names></string-name>, <string-name name-style="western"><surname>Sutch</surname> &#160;<given-names>S</given-names></string-name>, <string-name name-style="western"><surname>Dayan</surname> &#160;<given-names>SH</given-names></string-name></person-group>. <article-title>Beauty from the neck up: introduction to the special issue</article-title>. <source>Dermatol Surg</source>. <year>2016</year>;<volume>42</volume>:<fpage>S260</fpage>&#8211;<lpage>S262</lpage>. doi: <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1097/dss.0000000000000874</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">27787265</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="ojaf081-B4"><label>4</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><string-name name-style="western"><surname>Palm</surname> &#160;<given-names>MD</given-names></string-name>, <string-name name-style="western"><surname>Schlessinger</surname> &#160;<given-names>J</given-names></string-name>, <string-name name-style="western"><surname>Callender</surname> &#160;<given-names>VD</given-names></string-name>, <etal>et al</etal></person-group> &#160;<article-title>Final data from the Condition of Submental Fullness and Treatment Outcomes Registry (CONTOUR)</article-title>. <source>J Drugs Dermatol</source>. <year>2019</year>;<volume>18</volume>:<fpage>40</fpage>&#8211;<lpage>48</lpage>. <comment>PMID 30681793</comment>.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">30681793</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="ojaf081-B5"><label>5</label><mixed-citation publication-type="other"><person-group person-group-type="author"><collab>American Society for Dermatologic Surgery</collab></person-group>. 2019 ASDS consumer survey on cosmetic dermatologic procedures. 2020. Accessed November 6, 2023. <ext-link xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xlink:href="https://www.asds.net/medical-professionals/practice-resources/asds-consumer-survey-on-cosmetic-dermatologic-procedures" ext-link-type="uri">https://www.asds.net/medical-professionals/practice-resources/asds-consumer-survey-on-cosmetic-dermatologic-procedures</ext-link></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="ojaf081-B6"><label>6</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><string-name name-style="western"><surname>Schlessinger</surname> &#160;<given-names>J</given-names></string-name>, <string-name name-style="western"><surname>Weiss</surname> &#160;<given-names>SR</given-names></string-name>, <string-name name-style="western"><surname>Jewell</surname> &#160;<given-names>M</given-names></string-name>, <etal>et al</etal></person-group> &#160;<article-title>Perceptions and practices in submental fat treatment: a survey of physicians and patients</article-title>. <source>Skinmed</source>. <year>2013</year>;<volume>11</volume>:<fpage>27</fpage>&#8211;<lpage>31</lpage>. <comment>PMID: 23540074</comment>.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">23540074</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="ojaf081-B7"><label>7</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><string-name name-style="western"><surname>Koehler</surname> &#160;<given-names>J</given-names></string-name></person-group>. <article-title>Complications of neck liposuction and submentoplasty</article-title>. <source>Oral Maxillofac Surg Clin North Am</source>. <year>2009</year>;<volume>21</volume>:<fpage>43</fpage>&#8211;<lpage>52</lpage>. doi: <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1016/j.coms.2008.10.008</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">19185794</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="ojaf081-B8"><label>8</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><string-name name-style="western"><surname>Shah</surname> &#160;<given-names>GM</given-names></string-name>, <string-name name-style="western"><surname>Greenberg</surname> &#160;<given-names>JN</given-names></string-name>, <string-name name-style="western"><surname>Tanzi</surname> &#160;<given-names>EL</given-names></string-name>, <string-name name-style="western"><surname>Monheit</surname> &#160;<given-names>GD</given-names></string-name></person-group>. <article-title>Noninvasive approach to treatment of submental fullness</article-title>. <source>Semin Cutan Med Surg</source>. <year>2017</year>;<volume>36</volume>:<fpage>164</fpage>&#8211;<lpage>169</lpage>. doi: <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.12788/j.sder.2017.040</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">29224033</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="ojaf081-B9"><label>9</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><string-name name-style="western"><surname>Jones</surname> &#160;<given-names>DH</given-names></string-name>, <string-name name-style="western"><surname>Carruthers</surname> &#160;<given-names>J</given-names></string-name>, <string-name name-style="western"><surname>Joseph</surname> &#160;<given-names>JH</given-names></string-name>, <etal>et al</etal></person-group> &#160;<article-title>REFINE-1, a multicenter, randomized, double-blind, placebo-controlled, phase 3 trial with ATX-101, an injectable drug for submental fat reduction</article-title>. <source>Dermatol Surg</source>. <year>2016</year>;<volume>42</volume>:<fpage>38</fpage>&#8211;<lpage>49</lpage>. doi: <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1097/dss.0000000000000578</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">26673433</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="ojaf081-B10"><label>10</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><string-name name-style="western"><surname>Humphrey</surname> &#160;<given-names>S</given-names></string-name>, <string-name name-style="western"><surname>Sykes</surname> &#160;<given-names>J</given-names></string-name>, <string-name name-style="western"><surname>Kantor</surname> &#160;<given-names>J</given-names></string-name>, <etal>et al</etal></person-group> &#160;<article-title>ATX-101 for reduction of submental fat: a phase III randomized controlled trial</article-title>. <source>J Am Acad Dermatol</source>. <year>2016</year>;<volume>75</volume>:<fpage>788</fpage>&#8211;<lpage>797.e7</lpage>. doi: <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1016/j.jaad.2016.04.028</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">27430612</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="ojaf081-B11"><label>11</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><string-name name-style="western"><surname>Rzany</surname> &#160;<given-names>B</given-names></string-name>, <string-name name-style="western"><surname>Griffiths</surname> &#160;<given-names>T</given-names></string-name>, <string-name name-style="western"><surname>Walker</surname> &#160;<given-names>P</given-names></string-name>, <string-name name-style="western"><surname>Lippert</surname> &#160;<given-names>S</given-names></string-name>, <string-name name-style="western"><surname>McDiarmid</surname> &#160;<given-names>J</given-names></string-name>, <string-name name-style="western"><surname>Havlickova</surname> &#160;<given-names>B</given-names></string-name></person-group>. <article-title>Reduction of unwanted submental fat with ATX-101 (deoxycholic acid), an adipocytolytic injectable treatment: results from a phase III, randomized, placebo-controlled study</article-title>. <source>Br J Dermatol</source>. <year>2014</year>;<volume>170</volume>:<fpage>445</fpage>&#8211;<lpage>453</lpage>. doi: <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1111/bjd.12695</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">24147933</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC4232897</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="ojaf081-B12"><label>12</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><string-name name-style="western"><surname>Ascher</surname> &#160;<given-names>B</given-names></string-name>, <string-name name-style="western"><surname>Hoffmann</surname> &#160;<given-names>K</given-names></string-name>, <string-name name-style="western"><surname>Walker</surname> &#160;<given-names>P</given-names></string-name>, <string-name name-style="western"><surname>Lippert</surname> &#160;<given-names>S</given-names></string-name>, <string-name name-style="western"><surname>Wollina</surname> &#160;<given-names>U</given-names></string-name>, <string-name name-style="western"><surname>Havlickova</surname> &#160;<given-names>B</given-names></string-name></person-group>. <article-title>Efficacy, patient-reported outcomes and safety profile of ATX-101 (deoxycholic acid), an injectable drug for the reduction of unwanted submental fat: results from a phase III, randomized, placebo-controlled study</article-title>. <source>J Eur Acad Dermatol Venereol</source>. <year>2014</year>;<volume>28</volume>:<fpage>1707</fpage>&#8211;<lpage>1715</lpage>. doi: <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1111/jdv.12377</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">24605812</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC4263247</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="ojaf081-B13"><label>13</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><string-name name-style="western"><surname>Goodman</surname> &#160;<given-names>GJ</given-names></string-name>, <string-name name-style="western"><surname>Spelman</surname> &#160;<given-names>LJ</given-names></string-name>, <string-name name-style="western"><surname>Lowe</surname> &#160;<given-names>N</given-names></string-name>, <string-name name-style="western"><surname>Bowen</surname> &#160;<given-names>B</given-names></string-name></person-group>. <article-title>Randomized, placebo-controlled phase 1/2 study to determine the appropriate ATX-101 concentration for reduction of submental fat</article-title>. <source>Dermatol Surg</source>. <year>2021</year>;<volume>47</volume>:<fpage>1065</fpage>&#8211;<lpage>1070</lpage>. doi: <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1097/dss.0000000000003092</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">34115682</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="ojaf081-B14"><label>14</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><string-name name-style="western"><surname>Moradi</surname> &#160;<given-names>A</given-names></string-name>, <string-name name-style="western"><surname>Shirazi</surname> &#160;<given-names>A</given-names></string-name>, <string-name name-style="western"><surname>David</surname> &#160;<given-names>R</given-names></string-name></person-group>. <article-title>Nonsurgical chin and jawline augmentation using calcium hydroxylapatite and hyaluronic acid fillers</article-title>. <source>Facial Plast Surg</source>. <year>2019</year>;<volume>35</volume>:<fpage>140</fpage>&#8211;<lpage>148</lpage>. doi: <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1055/s-0039-1683854</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">30943558</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="ojaf081-B15"><label>15</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><string-name name-style="western"><surname>Callan</surname> &#160;<given-names>P</given-names></string-name>, <string-name name-style="western"><surname>Goodman</surname> &#160;<given-names>GJ</given-names></string-name>, <string-name name-style="western"><surname>Carlisle</surname> &#160;<given-names>I</given-names></string-name>, <etal>et al</etal></person-group> &#160;<article-title>Efficacy and safety of a hyaluronic acid filler in subjects treated for correction of midface volume deficiency: a 24 month study</article-title>. <source>Clin Cosmet Investig Dermatol</source>. <year>2013</year>;<volume>6</volume>:<fpage>81</fpage>&#8211;<lpage>89</lpage>. doi: <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.2147/CCID.S40581</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC3610404</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">23687448</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="ojaf081-B16"><label>16</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><string-name name-style="western"><surname>Jones</surname> &#160;<given-names>D</given-names></string-name>, <string-name name-style="western"><surname>Murphy</surname> &#160;<given-names>DK</given-names></string-name></person-group>. <article-title>Volumizing hyaluronic acid filler for midface volume deficit: 2-year results from a pivotal single-blind randomized controlled study</article-title>. <source>Dermatol Surg</source>. <year>2013</year>;<volume>39</volume>:<fpage>1602</fpage>&#8211;<lpage>1611</lpage>. doi: <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1111/dsu.12343</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">24093664</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="ojaf081-B17"><label>17</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><string-name name-style="western"><surname>Carruthers</surname> &#160;<given-names>J</given-names></string-name>, <string-name name-style="western"><surname>Carruthers</surname> &#160;<given-names>A</given-names></string-name>, <string-name name-style="western"><surname>Tezel</surname> &#160;<given-names>A</given-names></string-name>, <string-name name-style="western"><surname>Kraemer</surname> &#160;<given-names>J</given-names></string-name>, <string-name name-style="western"><surname>Craik</surname> &#160;<given-names>L</given-names></string-name></person-group>. <article-title>Volumizing with a 20-mg/mL smooth, highly cohesive, viscous hyaluronic acid filler and its role in facial rejuvenation therapy</article-title>. <source>Dermatol Surg</source>. <year>2010</year>;<volume>36</volume>:<fpage>1886</fpage>&#8211;<lpage>1892</lpage>. doi: <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1111/j.1524-4725.2010.01778.x</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">20969666</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="ojaf081-B18"><label>18</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><string-name name-style="western"><surname>Beer</surname> &#160;<given-names>K</given-names></string-name>, <string-name name-style="western"><surname>Kaufman-Janette</surname> &#160;<given-names>J</given-names></string-name>, <string-name name-style="western"><surname>Bank</surname> &#160;<given-names>D</given-names></string-name>, <etal>et al</etal></person-group> &#160;<article-title>Safe and effective chin augmentation with the hyaluronic acid injectable filler, VYC-20L</article-title>. <source>Dermatol Surg</source>. <year>2021</year>;<volume>47</volume>:<fpage>80</fpage>&#8211;<lpage>85</lpage>. doi: <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1097/dss.0000000000002795</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">33347003</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC7752233</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="ojaf081-B19"><label>19</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><string-name name-style="western"><surname>Vazirnia</surname> &#160;<given-names>A</given-names></string-name>, <string-name name-style="western"><surname>Braz</surname> &#160;<given-names>A</given-names></string-name>, <string-name name-style="western"><surname>Fabi</surname> &#160;<given-names>SG</given-names></string-name></person-group>. <article-title>Nonsurgical jawline rejuvenation using injectable fillers</article-title>. <source>J Cosmet Dermatol</source>. <year>2020</year>;<volume>19</volume>:<fpage>1940</fpage>&#8211;<lpage>1947</lpage>. doi: <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1111/jocd.13277</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">31889377</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="ojaf081-B20"><label>20</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><string-name name-style="western"><surname>Dover</surname> &#160;<given-names>JS</given-names></string-name>, <string-name name-style="western"><surname>Shridharani</surname> &#160;<given-names>SM</given-names></string-name>, <string-name name-style="western"><surname>Bloom</surname> &#160;<given-names>JD</given-names></string-name>, <string-name name-style="western"><surname>Somogyi</surname> &#160;<given-names>C</given-names></string-name>, <string-name name-style="western"><surname>Gallagher</surname> &#160;<given-names>CJ</given-names></string-name></person-group>. <article-title>Reduction of submental fat continues beyond 28 days after ATX-101 treatment: results from a post hoc analysis</article-title>. <source>Dermatol Surg</source>. <year>2018</year>;<volume>44</volume>:<fpage>1477</fpage>&#8211;<lpage>1479</lpage>. doi: <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1097/dss.0000000000001484</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">29419542</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC6221411</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="ojaf081-B21"><label>21</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><string-name name-style="western"><surname>Dayan</surname> &#160;<given-names>SH</given-names></string-name>, <string-name name-style="western"><surname>Schlessinger</surname> &#160;<given-names>J</given-names></string-name>, <string-name name-style="western"><surname>Beer</surname> &#160;<given-names>K</given-names></string-name>, <etal>et al</etal></person-group> &#160;<article-title>Efficacy and safety of ATX-101 by treatment session: pooled analysis of data from the phase 3 REFINE trials</article-title>. <source>Aesthet Surg J</source>. <year>2018</year>;<volume>38</volume>:<fpage>998</fpage>&#8211;<lpage>1010</lpage>. doi: <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1093/asj/sjy008</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">29401213</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC6094350</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="ojaf081-B22"><label>22</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><string-name name-style="western"><surname>Lupo</surname> &#160;<given-names>M</given-names></string-name>, <string-name name-style="western"><surname>Dover</surname> &#160;<given-names>JS</given-names></string-name>, <string-name name-style="western"><surname>Baradaran</surname> &#160;<given-names>S</given-names></string-name>, <string-name name-style="western"><surname>Patel</surname> &#160;<given-names>V</given-names></string-name>, <string-name name-style="western"><surname>Drinkwater</surname> &#160;<given-names>A</given-names></string-name></person-group>. <article-title>Development and validation of the Patient-Reported Submental Fat Rating Scale and the Patient-Reported Submental Fat Impact Scale</article-title>. <source>Dermatol Surg</source>. <year>2021</year>;<volume>47</volume>:<fpage>522</fpage>&#8211;<lpage>525</lpage>. doi: <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1097/dss.0000000000002908</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">33306491</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="ojaf081-B23"><label>23</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><string-name name-style="western"><surname>Klassen</surname> &#160;<given-names>AF</given-names></string-name>, <string-name name-style="western"><surname>Cano</surname> &#160;<given-names>SJ</given-names></string-name>, <string-name name-style="western"><surname>Schwitzer</surname> &#160;<given-names>JA</given-names></string-name>, <string-name name-style="western"><surname>Scott</surname> &#160;<given-names>AM</given-names></string-name>, <string-name name-style="western"><surname>Pusic</surname> &#160;<given-names>AL</given-names></string-name></person-group>. <article-title>FACE-Q scales for health-related quality of life, early life impact, satisfaction with outcomes, and decision to have treatment: development and validation</article-title>. <source>Plast Reconstr Surg</source>. <year>2015</year>;<volume>135</volume>:<fpage>375</fpage>&#8211;<lpage>386</lpage>. doi: <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1097/PRS.0000000000000895</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">25626785</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="ojaf081-B24"><label>24</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><string-name name-style="western"><surname>Swift</surname> &#160;<given-names>A</given-names></string-name>, <string-name name-style="western"><surname>Liew</surname> &#160;<given-names>S</given-names></string-name>, <string-name name-style="western"><surname>Weinkle</surname> &#160;<given-names>S</given-names></string-name>, <string-name name-style="western"><surname>Garcia</surname> &#160;<given-names>JK</given-names></string-name>, <string-name name-style="western"><surname>Silberberg</surname> &#160;<given-names>MB</given-names></string-name></person-group>. <article-title>The facial aging process from the &#8220;inside out&#8221;</article-title>. <source>Aesthet Surg J</source>. <year>2021</year>;<volume>41</volume>:<fpage>1107</fpage>&#8211;<lpage>1119</lpage>. doi: <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1093/asj/sjaa339</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">33325497</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC8438644</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="ojaf081-B25"><label>25</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><string-name name-style="western"><surname>M&#252;ller</surname> &#160;<given-names>D</given-names></string-name>, <string-name name-style="western"><surname>Prinz</surname> &#160;<given-names>V</given-names></string-name>, <string-name name-style="western"><surname>Sulovsky</surname> &#160;<given-names>M</given-names></string-name>, <etal>et al</etal></person-group> &#160;<article-title>Longevity and subject-reported satisfaction after minimally invasive jawline contouring</article-title>. <source>J Cosmet Dermatol</source>. <year>2022</year>;<volume>21</volume>:<fpage>199</fpage>&#8211;<lpage>206</lpage>. doi: <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1111/jocd.14410</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">34536051</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="ojaf081-B26"><label>26</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><string-name name-style="western"><surname>Calvisi</surname> &#160;<given-names>L</given-names></string-name>, <string-name name-style="western"><surname>Palazzolo</surname> &#160;<given-names>D</given-names></string-name>, <string-name name-style="western"><surname>Triolo</surname> &#160;<given-names>A</given-names></string-name></person-group>. <article-title>Nonsurgical reshaping of the nose, chin, and jawline: a retrospective analysis using experience-based eligibility criteria</article-title>. <source>J Cosmet Dermatol</source>. <year>2021</year>;<volume>21</volume>:<fpage>1436</fpage>&#8211;<lpage>1444</lpage>. doi: <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1111/jocd.14294</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">34129737</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="ojaf081-B27"><label>27</label><mixed-citation publication-type="other"><person-group person-group-type="author"><string-name name-style="western"><surname>Bertucci</surname> &#160;<given-names>V</given-names></string-name>, <string-name name-style="western"><surname>Rivers</surname> &#160;<given-names>JK</given-names></string-name>, <string-name name-style="western"><surname>Humphrey</surname> &#160;<given-names>S</given-names></string-name>, <etal>et al</etal></person-group> &#160;<comment>Canada HARMONY study: comprehensive panfacial approach to aesthetic treatment, including submental fullness, results in improved patient-reported outcomes [poster]. Presented at the Annual Meeting of the American Society for Dermatologic Surgery, November 19-21, 2021</comment>.</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="ojaf081-B28"><label>28</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><string-name name-style="western"><surname>Weinkle</surname> &#160;<given-names>SH</given-names></string-name>, <string-name name-style="western"><surname>Werschler</surname> &#160;<given-names>WP</given-names></string-name>, <string-name name-style="western"><surname>Teller</surname> &#160;<given-names>CF</given-names></string-name>, <etal>et al</etal></person-group> &#160;<article-title>Impact of comprehensive, minimally invasive, multimodal aesthetic treatment on satisfaction with facial appearance: the HARMONY study</article-title>. <source>Aesthet Surg J</source>. <year>2018</year>;<volume>38</volume>:<fpage>540</fpage>&#8211;<lpage>556</lpage>. doi: <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1093/asj/sjx179</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">29244069</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref></ref-list></back></article></pmc-articleset>