<?xml version="1.0"  ?><!DOCTYPE pmc-articleset PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD ARTICLE SET 2.0//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pmc/articleset/nlm-articleset-2.0.dtd"><pmc-articleset><article xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" xmlns:ali="http://www.niso.org/schemas/ali/1.0/" xml:lang="en" article-type="research-article" dtd-version="1.4"><processing-meta base-tagset="archiving" mathml-version="3.0" table-model="xhtml" tagset-family="jats"><restricted-by>pmc</restricted-by></processing-meta><front><journal-meta><journal-id journal-id-type="nlm-ta">Plast Reconstr Surg Glob Open</journal-id><journal-id journal-id-type="iso-abbrev">Plast Reconstr Surg Glob Open</journal-id><journal-id journal-id-type="pmc-domain-id">2522</journal-id><journal-id journal-id-type="pmc-domain">prsgo</journal-id><journal-id journal-id-type="publisher-id">GOX</journal-id><journal-title-group><journal-title>Plastic and Reconstructive Surgery Global Open</journal-title></journal-title-group><issn pub-type="epub">2169-7574</issn><publisher><publisher-name>Wolters Kluwer Health</publisher-name></publisher></journal-meta><article-meta><article-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC10836874</article-id><article-id pub-id-type="pmcid-ver">PMC10836874.1</article-id><article-id pub-id-type="pmcaid">10836874</article-id><article-id pub-id-type="pmcaiid">10836874</article-id><article-id pub-id-type="pmid">38313594</article-id><article-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1097/GOX.0000000000005579</article-id><article-version-alternatives><article-version article-version-type="pmc-version">1</article-version><article-version vocab="JAV" vocab-identifier="http://www.niso.org/publications/rp/RP-8-2008.pdf" article-version-type="Version of Record">3</article-version></article-version-alternatives><article-categories><subj-group subj-group-type="heading"><subject>Cosmetic</subject></subj-group><subj-group subj-group-type="heading"><subject>Original Article</subject></subj-group></article-categories><title-group><article-title>The Research Trend of Soft Tissue Filler Injection from 2000 to 2022: A Bibliometric and Visualized Analysis</article-title></title-group><contrib-group><contrib contrib-type="author" corresp="yes"><name name-style="western"><surname>Liao</surname><given-names initials="ZF">Zhi-Feng</given-names></name><degrees>MD, PhD</degrees><xref rid="aff1" ref-type="aff">*</xref></contrib><contrib contrib-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Cong</surname><given-names initials="LY">Li-Yao</given-names></name><degrees>DDS, PhD</degrees><xref rid="aff1" ref-type="aff">*</xref></contrib><contrib contrib-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Li</surname><given-names initials="FW">Fang-Wei</given-names></name><degrees>MD</degrees><xref rid="aff1" ref-type="aff">*</xref></contrib><contrib contrib-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Wang</surname><given-names initials="SW">Shi-Wei</given-names></name><degrees>MD, PhD</degrees><xref rid="aff2" ref-type="aff">&#8224;</xref></contrib><contrib contrib-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Liu</surname><given-names initials="FC">Fang-Cen</given-names></name><degrees>MD</degrees><xref rid="aff3" ref-type="aff">&#8225;</xref></contrib><contrib contrib-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Wang</surname><given-names initials="HB">Hai-Bin</given-names></name><degrees>MD, PhD</degrees><xref rid="aff1" ref-type="aff">*</xref></contrib><contrib contrib-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Luo</surname><given-names initials="SK">Sheng-Kang</given-names></name><degrees>MD, PhD</degrees><xref rid="aff1" ref-type="aff">*</xref></contrib><aff id="aff1">From the <label>*</label>Department of Plastic and Reconstructive Surgery, Guangdong Second Provincial General Hospital, Guangzhou, Guangdong, China</aff><aff id="aff2"><label>&#8224;</label>Department of Medical Affairs, Imeik Technology Development Co., Ltd, Beijing, China</aff><aff id="aff3"><label>&#8225;</label>Department of Injection, Guangzhou Bailiankai Medical Aesthetic Hospital, Guangzhou, Guangdong, China.</aff></contrib-group><author-notes><corresp id="c1">Prof. Sheng-Kang Luo, MD, PhD, Department of Plastic and Reconstructive Surgery, Guangdong Second Provincial General Hospital, Guangzhou, Guangdong, China, E-mail: <email xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xlink:href="luoshk@gd2h.org.cn">luoshk@gd2h.org.cn</email></corresp></author-notes><pub-date pub-type="collection"><month>2</month><year>2024</year></pub-date><pub-date pub-type="epub"><day>02</day><month>2</month><year>2024</year></pub-date><volume>12</volume><issue>2</issue><issue-id pub-id-type="pmc-issue-id">454866</issue-id><elocation-id>e5579</elocation-id><history><date date-type="received"><day>13</day><month>10</month><year>2023</year></date><date date-type="accepted"><day>11</day><month>12</month><year>2023</year></date></history><pub-history><event event-type="pmc-release"><date><day>02</day><month>02</month><year>2024</year></date></event><event event-type="pmc-live"><date><day>02</day><month>02</month><year>2024</year></date></event><event event-type="pmc-last-change"><date iso-8601-date="2024-10-22 17:25:33.850"><day>22</day><month>10</month><year>2024</year></date></event></pub-history><permissions><copyright-statement>Copyright &#169; 2024 The Authors. Published by Wolters Kluwer Health, Inc. on behalf of The American Society of Plastic Surgeons.</copyright-statement><copyright-year>2024</copyright-year><license><ali:license_ref specific-use="textmining" content-type="ccbyncndlicense">https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/4.0/</ali:license_ref><license-p>This is an open-access article distributed under the terms of the <ext-link xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" ext-link-type="uri" xlink:href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/4.0/">Creative Commons Attribution-Non Commercial-No Derivatives License 4.0 (CCBY-NC-ND)</ext-link>, where it is permissible to download and share the work provided it is properly cited. The work cannot be changed in any way or used commercially without permission from the journal.</license-p></license></permissions><self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" content-type="pmc-pdf" xlink:href="gox-12-e5579.pdf"/><self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xlink:href="gox-12-e5579.pdf"/><abstract><sec><title>Background:</title><p>The demand for soft tissue filler injections has experienced a significant increase in recent years. Therefore, this study used bibliometric analysis to identify prominent research areas and emerging trends within the field.</p></sec><sec><title>Methods:</title><p>Publications concerning research on soft tissue filler injections were collected from the Web of Science Core Collection database. Subsequently, VOSviewer 1.6.18 and CiteSpace 6.2.R4 software were used to analyze the co-authorship, co-occurrence, and citations of countries, institutions, authors, hotspot keywords, and journals associated with these studies.</p></sec><sec><title>Results:</title><p>A total of 1370 records pertaining to filler injection research conducted between 2000 and 2022 were identified. The United States (524 publications) emerged as the country with the highest number of publications in this field, with Mayo Clinic (37 publications) making the most substantial contribution. <italic toggle="yes">Dermatologic Surgery</italic> emerged as the leading journal in this field, publishing the highest number of research articles (151 publications) and also being the most frequently co-cited. Cotofana proved to be the most prolific author with 51 publications, and Lemperle emerged as the most frequently co-cited author with 628 citations (including total link strength: 6587). The most popular keywords, in descending order of popularity, were &#8220;dermal filler,&#8221; &#8220;injection,&#8221; &#8220;soft-tissue augmentation,&#8221; &#8220;complications,&#8221; and &#8220;hyaluronic acid.&#8221;</p></sec><sec><title>Conclusions:</title><p>The findings of this study offer a comprehensive overview of the main directions in filler injection research. Furthermore, they underscore the imperative of intensifying efforts to prevent complications linked to filler injections.</p></sec></abstract><custom-meta-group><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-status-qastatus</meta-name><meta-value>0</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-status-live</meta-name><meta-value>yes</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-status-embargo</meta-name><meta-value>no</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-status-released</meta-name><meta-value>yes</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-open-access</meta-name><meta-value>yes</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-olf</meta-name><meta-value>no</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-manuscript</meta-name><meta-value>no</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-legally-suppressed</meta-name><meta-value>no</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-has-pdf</meta-name><meta-value>yes</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-has-supplement</meta-name><meta-value>no</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-pdf-only</meta-name><meta-value>no</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-suppress-copyright</meta-name><meta-value>no</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-is-real-version</meta-name><meta-value>no</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-is-scanned-article</meta-name><meta-value>no</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-preprint</meta-name><meta-value>no</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-in-epmc</meta-name><meta-value>yes</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-license-ref</meta-name><meta-value>CC BY-NC-ND</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>OPEN-ACCESS</meta-name><meta-value>TRUE</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>COUNTRY</meta-name><meta-value>CHINA</meta-value></custom-meta></custom-meta-group></article-meta></front><body><boxed-text position="float" orientation="portrait"><sec><title>Takeaways</title><p><bold>Question:</bold> This study used bibliometric analysis to identify prominent research areas and emerging trends within the field of filler injection.</p><p><bold>Findings:</bold> The study analyzed the co-authorship, co-occurrence, and citations of countries, institutions, authors, hotspot keywords, and journals associated with filler injection.</p><p><bold>Meaning:</bold> The findings of this study offer a comprehensive overview of the main directions in filler injection research.</p></sec></boxed-text><sec sec-type="intro"><title>INTRODUCTION</title><p>Soft tissue filler injections are widely acknowledged as a safe and straightforward treatment for aesthetic purposes. These fillers are derived from various materials, including hyaluronic acid, calcium hydroxyapatite, and poly-L-lactic acid. Notably, the Food and Drug Administration has approved more than 30 dermal fillers.<sup><xref rid="R1" ref-type="bibr">1</xref>&#8211;<xref rid="R3" ref-type="bibr">3</xref></sup> According to the American Society for Aesthetic Plastic Surgery, an estimated 3,410,730 soft tissue filler injections were performed in the United States in 2020, ranking it as the second most common minimally invasive cosmetic procedure.<sup><xref rid="R4" ref-type="bibr">4</xref></sup> However, the growing popularity of these procedures has resulted in an increase in associated adverse events.<sup><xref rid="R5" ref-type="bibr">5</xref>,<xref rid="R6" ref-type="bibr">6</xref></sup> To enhance their efficacy and minimize such complications, novel fillers, techniques, and fundamental research have been introduced.<sup><xref rid="R7" ref-type="bibr">7</xref>&#8211;<xref rid="R11" ref-type="bibr">11</xref></sup> Thus, it is crucial to summarize the present research status in this field and identify areas for further investigation to facilitate the implementation of soft tissue filler injections.</p><p>Bibliometric analysis, a mathematical modeling tool, is used to monitor research trends in specific fields.<sup><xref rid="R12" ref-type="bibr">12</xref></sup> Although bibliometrics has found extensive applications in medicine, including pneumonia,<sup><xref rid="R13" ref-type="bibr">13</xref></sup> arthritis,<sup><xref rid="R14" ref-type="bibr">14</xref></sup> hypertension,<sup><xref rid="R15" ref-type="bibr">15</xref></sup> and human immunodeficiency virus disease,<sup><xref rid="R16" ref-type="bibr">16</xref></sup> as well as in plastic surgery,<sup><xref rid="R17" ref-type="bibr">17</xref>&#8211;<xref rid="R21" ref-type="bibr">21</xref></sup> no previous bibliometric study has specifically focused on soft tissue filler injections. This research topic holds a significant value for enhancing clinical treatment. The rapid development of fillers and techniques has resulted in a substantial increase in the number of published articles. Consequently, both researchers and nonresearchers can use this information to efficiently accomplish specific objectives within their respective areas of interest by studying highly influential research.</p><p>The objective of this study was to perform a bibliometric and visualization analysis in the field of soft tissue filler injections. The aim was to offer a comprehensive overview of the present research status and identify potential future perspectives in the field.</p></sec><sec sec-type="methods"><title>METHODS</title><sec><title>Search Strategy</title><p>On March 7, 2023, we performed a search in the Web of Science Core Collection (WoSCC) database using the search terms &#8220;TS=((soft tissue filler injection) OR (dermal filler injection))&#8221; to identify studies published in English between January 1, 2000 and December 31, 2022. Two authors independently screened data and excluded documents irrelevant to the search strategies. We only considered original articles and reviews, resulting in 1384 retrieved records. To ensure data quality, we preprocessed the data to eliminate duplicates or inconsistencies related to the topic. After screening by three researchers, we acquired 1370 valid documents (Fig. <xref rid="F1" ref-type="fig">1</xref>).</p><fig position="float" id="F1" orientation="portrait"><label>Fig. 1.</label><caption><p>Flowchart illustrating the article selection process for bibliometric mapping analysis and systematic review.</p></caption><graphic xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" position="float" orientation="portrait" xlink:href="gox-12-e5579-g001.jpg"/></fig></sec><sec><title>Analysis Tool</title><p>The data retrieved from WoSCC consisted of articles and citations, h-index, keywords, publication years, journals, authors, countries/regions, and affiliations. The articles were analyzed, and visual representation was created using VOSviewer and CiteSpace software. The bibliographic data were exported as a txt file from the WoSCC database and subsequently imported into VOSviewer and CiteSpace software to generate visualization maps. The basic metrics and visualization maps of countries,</p><p>institutions, authors, journals, and keywords were analyzed through VOSviewer and CiteSpace software. The basic metrics and visualization maps of countries, institutions, authors, journals, and keywords were analyzed through VOSviewer. A timeline view of co-cited reference was performed by CiteSpace. The size of the nodes and the thickness of the lines between the nodes represented the occurrence frequency and the degree of correlation of the relevant parameters, respectively. The nodes with the same color represented the same cluster in the visualization map.</p></sec></sec><sec sec-type="results"><title>RESULTS</title><sec><title>The Number of Articles in the Field of Soft Tissue Filler Injection</title><p>After applying the predetermined exclusion criteria, the study included 1370 papers authored by 4557 individuals affiliated with 1870 organizations in 64 countries. These papers were published in 284 journals and were subsequently subjected to further bibliometric analyses. In total, the publications received 26,320 citations, of which 18,166 were non&#8211;self-citations. The average citations per document were 19.21, and the h-index of the publications was 69.</p></sec><sec><title>Distribution of Publications from 2000 to 2022</title><p>Figure <xref rid="F2" ref-type="fig">2</xref> depicts the temporal distribution of publications in the field of soft tissue filler injection. Since 2017, the number of publications and citations in this field has shown a significant increase. It is noteworthy that there has been a substantial surge in publications and citations during this period, with the number of publications consistently surpassing 100, from 2018 to 2022. These findings indicate a growing interest among scholars in the research field of soft tissue filler injection, positioning it as a novel area of study within plastic and aesthetic research.</p><fig position="float" id="F2" orientation="portrait"><label>Fig. 2.</label><caption><p>Annual worldwide publication output.</p></caption><graphic xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" position="float" orientation="portrait" xlink:href="gox-12-e5579-g002.jpg"/></fig></sec><sec><title>The National/Regional Distribution of Global Publication</title><p>Figure <xref rid="F3" ref-type="fig">3</xref> illustrates the distribution of countries/regions with the highest number of global publications on soft tissue filler injection, whereas Table <xref rid="T1" ref-type="table">1</xref> provides a ranking of the top 10 most productive countries/regions. The top 10 countries accounted for 99.12% of the publications, with the United States leading in the number of published articles, followed by South Korea and Germany. Additionally, the United States, Germany, and South Korea had the highest numbers of citations, whereas France had the highest h-index. Spain and the United States tied for second and third place in terms of h-index. The distribution of countries/regions was analyzed using the VOSviewer software, focusing on those with at least five documents. This analysis identified 41 countries that met the criteria, and their relationships were visualized in a network diagram and a density map, as depicted in Figure <xref rid="F4" ref-type="fig">4</xref>.</p><table-wrap position="float" id="T1" orientation="portrait"><label>Table 1.</label><caption><p>The Top 10 Productive Countries/Regions</p></caption><table frame="hsides" rules="groups"><thead><tr><th align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Rank</th><th align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Country/Region</th><th align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Records</th><th align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Percentage (%)</th><th align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">H-index</th><th align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Citations</th><th align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Citations per Publication</th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">1</td><td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">USA</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">524</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">38.25%</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">57</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">12,672</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">24.18</td></tr><tr><td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">2</td><td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">South Korea</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">176</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">12.85%</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">22</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">1923</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">10.93</td></tr><tr><td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">3</td><td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Germany</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">141</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">10.29%</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">30</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">2809</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">19.92</td></tr><tr><td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">4</td><td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Italy</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">103</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">7.52%</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">21</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">1564</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">15.18</td></tr><tr><td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">5</td><td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">China</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">82</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">5.99%</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">18</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">858</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">10.46</td></tr><tr><td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">6</td><td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">England</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">81</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">5.91%</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">23</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">1622</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">20.02</td></tr><tr><td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">7</td><td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Brazil</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">74</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">5.40%</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">18</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">886</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">11.97</td></tr><tr><td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">8</td><td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Canada</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">66</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">4.82%</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">22</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">1524</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">23.09</td></tr><tr><td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">9</td><td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">France</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">66</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">4.82%</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">25</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">1741</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">26.38</td></tr><tr><td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">10</td><td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Spain</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">45</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">3.28%</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">20</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">1111</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">24.69</td></tr></tbody></table></table-wrap><fig position="float" id="F3" orientation="portrait"><label>Fig. 3.</label><caption><p>Top 10 productive countries/regions.</p></caption><graphic xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" position="float" orientation="portrait" xlink:href="gox-12-e5579-g003.jpg"/></fig><fig position="float" id="F4" orientation="portrait"><label>Fig. 4.</label><caption><p>Network visualization map of countries/regions.</p></caption><graphic xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" position="float" orientation="portrait" xlink:href="gox-12-e5579-g004.jpg"/></fig></sec><sec><title>Distribution of Affiliations</title><p>Table <xref rid="T2" ref-type="table">2</xref> presents the top 10 most productive affiliations. These affiliations represent three countries: the United States, South Korea, and Germany, with six of them originating from the United States. The leading affiliations were the Mayo Clinic (2.70%, 37 publications), the University of California, San Diego (2.55%, 35 publications), and the University of Munich (2.19%, 30 publications). Among them, the University of California, San Diego (USA) achieved the highest h-index (20), while the University of California, Los Angeles (USA) had the highest citation/publication ratio (41.24). To analyze the collaboration among different affiliations, a minimum threshold of 10 documents per affiliation was set, resulting in 39 affiliations meeting the criteria.</p><table-wrap position="float" id="T2" orientation="portrait"><label>Table 2.</label><caption><p>The Top 10 Productive Affiliations</p></caption><table frame="hsides" rules="groups"><thead><tr><th align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Rank</th><th align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Institution</th><th align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Location</th><th align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Records</th><th align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Percentage</th><th align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">H-index</th><th align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Citations</th><th align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Citations Per Publication</th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">1</td><td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Mayo Clinic</td><td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">USA</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">37</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">2.70%</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">11</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">288</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">7.78</td></tr><tr><td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">2</td><td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Univ Calif San Diego</td><td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">USA</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">35</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">2.55%</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">20</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">1320</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">37.71</td></tr><tr><td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">3</td><td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">University of Munich</td><td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Germany</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">30</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">2.19%</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">17</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">433</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">14.43</td></tr><tr><td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">4</td><td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Univ Calif Los Angeles</td><td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">USA</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">29</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">2.12%</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">18</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">1196</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">41.24</td></tr><tr><td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">5</td><td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Yonsei University</td><td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">South Korea</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">26</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">1.90%</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">11</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">348</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">13.38</td></tr><tr><td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">6</td><td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">University of Miami</td><td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">USA</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">23</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">1.68%</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">14</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">816</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">35.48</td></tr><tr><td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">7</td><td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Chung-Ang University</td><td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">South Korea</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">23</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">1.68%</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">8</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">137</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">5.96</td></tr><tr><td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">8</td><td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">University of British Columbia</td><td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">England</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">21</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">1.53%</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">12</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">813</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">38.71</td></tr><tr><td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">9</td><td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Albany Medical College</td><td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">USA</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">20</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">1.46%</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">13</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">437</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">21.85</td></tr><tr><td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">10</td><td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Northwestern University</td><td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">USA</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">20</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">1.46%</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">14</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">496</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">24.80</td></tr></tbody></table></table-wrap></sec><sec><title>Distribution of Journals and Co-cited Journals</title><p>Table <xref rid="T3" ref-type="table">3</xref> and Table <xref rid="T4" ref-type="table">4</xref> present the list of the top 10 productive and co-cited journals, respectively. <italic toggle="yes">Dermatologic Surgery</italic> ranked first with 151 publications, followed by the <italic toggle="yes">Journal of Cosmetic Dermatology</italic> (134 publications) and <italic toggle="yes">Plastic and Reconstructive Surgery</italic> (94 publications). Among the top 10 productive journals, <italic toggle="yes">Plastic and Reconstructive Surgery</italic> had the highest impact factor (IF; 5.169), h-index (36), and CPP (citations per publication; 42.50). Additionally, <italic toggle="yes">Dermatologic Surgery</italic> was the most frequently co-cited journal, with 5689 citations [total link strength (TLS): 134,521]. A co-citation analysis using VOSviewer was conducted to reveal the complex relationships among the journals. The analysis included 49 journals meeting the criteria of a minimum of 100 citations per source (Fig. <xref rid="F5" ref-type="fig">5</xref>).</p><table-wrap position="float" id="T3" orientation="portrait"><label>Table 3.</label><caption><p>The Top 10 Productive Journals</p></caption><table frame="hsides" rules="groups"><thead><tr><th align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Rank</th><th align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Journal</th><th align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Records</th><th align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Percentage</th><th align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Citations</th><th align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">CPP</th><th align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">H-index</th><th align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">IF (2021)</th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">1</td><td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">
<italic toggle="yes">Dermatologic Surgery</italic>
</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">151</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">11.02%</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">4177</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">27.66</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">36</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">2.914</td></tr><tr><td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">2</td><td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">
<italic toggle="yes">Journal of Cosmetic Dermatology</italic>
</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">134</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">9.78%</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">1182</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">8.82</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">20</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">2.189</td></tr><tr><td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">3</td><td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">
<italic toggle="yes">Plastic and Reconstructive Surgery</italic>
</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">94</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">6.86%</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">3995</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">42.50</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">42</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">5.169</td></tr><tr><td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">4</td><td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">
<italic toggle="yes">Aesthetic Plastic Surgery</italic>
</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">91</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">6.64%</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">1684</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">18.51</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">23</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">2.708</td></tr><tr><td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">5</td><td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">
<italic toggle="yes">Journal of Drugs in Dermatology</italic>
</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">82</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">5.99%</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">1141</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">13.91</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">20</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">1.608</td></tr><tr><td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">6</td><td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">
<italic toggle="yes">Aesthetic Surgery Journal</italic>
</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">75</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">5.47%</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">1675</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">22.33</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">20</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">4.485</td></tr><tr><td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">7</td><td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">
<italic toggle="yes">Journal of Cosmetic and Laser Therapy</italic>
</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">43</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">3.14%</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">713</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">16.58</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">14</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">1.982</td></tr><tr><td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">8</td><td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">
<italic toggle="yes">Facial Plastic Surgery</italic>
</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">36</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">2.63%</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">475</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">13.19</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">13</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">1.286</td></tr><tr><td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">9</td><td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">
<italic toggle="yes">Clinical Cosmetic and Investigational Dermatology</italic>
</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">36</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">2.63%</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">323</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">8.97</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">9</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">2.765</td></tr><tr><td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">10</td><td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">
<italic toggle="yes">Dermatologic Therapy</italic>
</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">26</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">1.90%</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">298</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">11.46</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">8</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">3.858</td></tr></tbody></table></table-wrap><table-wrap position="float" id="T4" orientation="portrait"><label>Table 4.</label><caption><p>Top 10 Co-cited Journals</p></caption><table frame="hsides" rules="groups"><thead><tr><th align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Rank</th><th align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Journal</th><th align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Citations</th><th align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">TLS</th><th align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">H-index</th><th align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">IF (2021)</th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">1</td><td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">
<italic toggle="yes">Dermatologic Surgery</italic>
</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">5689</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">134,521</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">36</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">2.91</td></tr><tr><td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">2</td><td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">
<italic toggle="yes">Plastic and Reconstructive Surgery</italic>
</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">4417</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">107,257</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">42</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">5.17</td></tr><tr><td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">3</td><td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">
<italic toggle="yes">Aesthetic Plastic Surgery</italic>
</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">1583</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">46,705</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">23</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">2.708</td></tr><tr><td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">4</td><td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">
<italic toggle="yes">Aesthetic Surgery Journal</italic>
</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">1502</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">41,293</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">20</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">4.485</td></tr><tr><td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">5</td><td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">
<italic toggle="yes">Journal of Drugs in Dermatology</italic>
</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">1078</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">29,899</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">20</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">1.608</td></tr><tr><td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">6</td><td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">
<italic toggle="yes">Journal of Cosmetic Dermatology</italic>
</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">873</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">22,284</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">20</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">2.189</td></tr><tr><td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">7</td><td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">
<italic toggle="yes">Journal of the American Academy of Dermatology</italic>
</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">773</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">28,630</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">10</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">15.49</td></tr><tr><td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">8</td><td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">
<italic toggle="yes">Facial Plastic Surgery</italic>
</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">648</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">18,524</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">13</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">1.286</td></tr><tr><td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">9</td><td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">
<italic toggle="yes">Journal of Cosmetic and Laser Therapy</italic>
</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">576</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">15,831</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">14</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">1.982</td></tr><tr><td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">10</td><td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">
<italic toggle="yes">Ophthalmic Plastic and Reconstructive Surgery</italic>
</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">474</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">14,738</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">9</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">2.01</td></tr></tbody></table></table-wrap><fig position="float" id="F5" orientation="portrait"><label>Fig. 5.</label><caption><p>Network visualization map of co-cited journals related to soft tissue filler injection.</p></caption><graphic xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" position="float" orientation="portrait" xlink:href="gox-12-e5579-g005.jpg"/></fig></sec><sec><title>Distribution of Authors and Co-cited Authors</title><p>Table <xref rid="T5" ref-type="table">5</xref> presents the top 10 authors who have made significant contributions to the field of soft tissue filler injection, with the majority of them affiliated with institutions in the USA and Germany. Collectively, their publications amount to 231 articles, representing 16.86% of all publications. Among them, Cotofana has the highest number of publications (51 articles), followed by Frank (44 articles), and Green (23 articles). Cotofana has the highest citation count and h-index, whereas Fagien leads in the CCP rankings (44.53), followed by Cohen (32.50), and Swift (21.27).</p><table-wrap position="float" id="T5" orientation="portrait"><label>Table 5.</label><caption><p>The Top 10 Productive and Co-cited Authors</p></caption><table frame="hsides" rules="groups"><thead><tr><th align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Rank</th><th align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Author</th><th align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Country</th><th align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Records</th><th align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Percentage</th><th align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">CCP</th><th align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Co-cited Author</th><th align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Citations</th><th align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">TLS</th><th align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Country</th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">1</td><td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Cotofana</td><td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">USA</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">51</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">3.72%</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">13.14</td><td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Lemperle</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">628</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">6587</td><td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">USA</td></tr><tr><td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">2</td><td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Frank</td><td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Germany</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">44</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">3.21%</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">12.39</td><td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Narins</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">373</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">4420</td><td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">USA</td></tr><tr><td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">3</td><td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Green</td><td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">USA</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">23</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">1.68%</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">11.91</td><td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Rohrich</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">276</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">3155</td><td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">USA</td></tr><tr><td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">4</td><td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Kim</td><td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">South Korea</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">19</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">1.39%</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">6.11</td><td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Delorenzi</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">221</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">2462</td><td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Canada</td></tr><tr><td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">5</td><td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Schenck</td><td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Germany</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">17</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">1.24%</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">20.35</td><td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Alijotas-Reig</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">214</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">3005</td><td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Spain</td></tr><tr><td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">6</td><td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Pavicic</td><td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Germany</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">16</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">1.17%</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">16.81</td><td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Carruthers</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">207</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">2288</td><td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Canada</td></tr><tr><td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">7</td><td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Cohen</td><td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">USA</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">16</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">1.17%</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">32.50</td><td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Lowe</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">205</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">2502</td><td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">USA</td></tr><tr><td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">8</td><td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Swift</td><td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Canada</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">15</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">1.09%</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">21.27</td><td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Cotofana</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">199</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">1441</td><td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">USA</td></tr><tr><td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">9</td><td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Fagien</td><td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">USA</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">15</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">1.09%</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">44.53</td><td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Alam</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">190</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">2475</td><td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">USA</td></tr><tr><td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">10</td><td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Sattler</td><td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Germany</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">15</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">1.09%</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">13.07</td><td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Carruthers</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">188</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">2378</td><td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Canada</td></tr></tbody></table></table-wrap><p>To examine the authors&#8217; cooperation, we conducted co-authorship analysis (Fig. <xref rid="F6" ref-type="fig">6</xref>) and co-citation analysis (Fig. <xref rid="F7" ref-type="fig">7</xref>). For co-authorship analysis, the minimum number of documents required for one affiliation was set at 5, and 117 affiliations fulfilled this criterion. In the case of co-citation analysis, the minimum number of documents required for one affiliation was set at 50, and 91 authors satisfied this criterion.</p><fig position="float" id="F6" orientation="portrait"><label>Fig. 6.</label><caption><p>Co-authorship network visualization of authors.</p></caption><graphic xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" position="float" orientation="portrait" xlink:href="gox-12-e5579-g006.jpg"/></fig><fig position="float" id="F7" orientation="portrait"><label>Fig. 7.</label><caption><p>Co-citation network visualization of authors.</p></caption><graphic xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" position="float" orientation="portrait" xlink:href="gox-12-e5579-g007.jpg"/></fig></sec><sec><title>Top 10 Highly Cited Articles</title><p>Table <xref rid="T6" ref-type="table">6</xref> presents a summary of the top 10 most-cited references, including the author, title, and year of publication. <italic toggle="yes">Dermatologic Surgery</italic> was the most prolific journal, with three publications, followed by <italic toggle="yes">Aesthetic Surgery Journal</italic> with two publications. The article titled &#8220;In vivo stimulation of de novo collagen production caused by cross-linked hyaluronic acid dermal filler injections in photodamaged human skin,&#8221; authored by Wang and published in <italic toggle="yes">Archives of Dermatology</italic>, received the highest number of citations (298). Among the top 10 most-cited articles, seven focused on complications associated with filler injections.</p><table-wrap position="float" id="T6" orientation="portrait"><label>Table 6.</label><caption><p>The Top 10 Articles with Most Total Citations</p></caption><table frame="hsides" rules="groups"><thead><tr><th align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Rank</th><th align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Title</th><th align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">First Author</th><th align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Journal</th><th align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Publication Time</th><th align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Citation</th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">1</td><td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">In vivo stimulation of de novo collagen production caused by cross-linked hyaluronic acid dermal filler injections in photodamaged human skin</td><td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Wang</td><td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">
<italic toggle="yes">Archives of Dermatology</italic>
</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">2007</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">298</td></tr><tr><td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">2</td><td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Avoiding and treating blindness from fillers: a review of the world literature</td><td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Beleznay</td><td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">
<italic toggle="yes">Dermatologic Surgery</italic>
</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">2015</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">286</td></tr><tr><td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">3</td><td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">The science of hyaluronic acid dermal fillers</td><td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Tezel</td><td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">
<italic toggle="yes">Journal of Cosmetic and Laser Therapy</italic>
</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">2008</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">226</td></tr><tr><td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">4</td><td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Adverse reactions to injectable soft tissue permanent fillers</td><td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Christensen</td><td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">
<italic toggle="yes">Aesthetic Plastic Surgery</italic>
</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">2005</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">215</td></tr><tr><td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">5</td><td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Adverse reactions to dermal fillers: review</td><td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Lowe</td><td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">
<italic toggle="yes">Dermatologic Surgery</italic>
</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">2005</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">206</td></tr><tr><td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">6</td><td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Complications of injectable fillers, part 2: vascular complications</td><td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">DeLorenzi</td><td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">
<italic toggle="yes">Aesthetic Surgery Journal</italic>
</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">2014</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">193</td></tr><tr><td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">7</td><td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Adverse reactions to injectable soft tissue fillers</td><td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Requena</td><td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">
<italic toggle="yes">Journal of The American Academy of Dermatology</italic>
</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">2011</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">189</td></tr><tr><td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">8</td><td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Hyaluronic acid, a promising skin rejuvenating biomedicine: a review of recent updates and preclinical and clinical investigations on cosmetic and nutricosmetic effects</td><td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Bukhari</td><td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">
<italic toggle="yes">International Journal of Biological Macromolecules</italic>
</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">2018</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">171</td></tr><tr><td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">9</td><td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Understanding, avoiding, and managing dermal filler complications</td><td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Cohen</td><td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">
<italic toggle="yes">Dermatologic Surgery</italic>
</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">2008</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">166</td></tr><tr><td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">10</td><td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Complications after injection of soft-tissue fillers</td><td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Ozturk</td><td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">
<italic toggle="yes">Aesthetic Surgery Journal</italic>
</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">2013</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">163</td></tr></tbody></table></table-wrap></sec><sec><title>Distribution of Research Hot Spots</title><p>To systematically identify the research hotspots and developmental direction of soft tissue filler injection, we performed a co-occurrence cluster analysis based on keywords using the VOSviewer software. After applying a threshold of 20, a total of 83 keywords were included for further visual analysis. A network map was created and is displayed in Figure <xref rid="F8" ref-type="fig">8</xref>A. The analysis of keyword citation counts revealed that the most frequently used keywords were &#8220;dermal filler,&#8221; &#8220;injection,&#8221; &#8220;soft-tissue augmentation,&#8221; &#8220;complications,&#8221; and &#8220;hyaluronic acid.&#8221; The temporal diagram indicated that the research trends centered around &#8220;hyaluronic acid,&#8221; &#8220;anatomy,&#8221; &#8220;blindness,&#8221; and &#8220;prevention&#8221; (Fig. <xref rid="F8" ref-type="fig">8</xref>B). Figure <xref rid="F9" ref-type="fig">9</xref> displays the top 25 co-occurring keywords with the strongest citation bursts. The results revealed that the keyword &#8220;skin&#8221; had the highest burst intensity (5.79), followed by &#8220;soft tissue augmentation&#8221; (22.9) and &#8220;artecoll&#8221; (8.09). Subsequently, a keyword clustering analysis was conducted to categorize the co-occurrence network of keywords into six different clusters, namely &#8220;blindness,&#8221; &#8220;double blind,&#8221; &#8220;artecoll,&#8221; &#8220;stem cells,&#8221; &#8220;dermal fillers,&#8221; and &#8220;hyaluronic acid&#8221; (Fig. <xref rid="F10" ref-type="fig">10</xref>).</p><fig position="float" id="F8" orientation="portrait"><label>Fig. 8.</label><caption><p>Network visualization map of keyword co-occurrence. A, Cluster analysis. B, Timing analysis.</p></caption><graphic xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" position="float" orientation="portrait" xlink:href="gox-12-e5579-g008.jpg"/></fig><fig position="float" id="F9" orientation="portrait"><label>Fig. 9.</label><caption><p>The top 25 keywords with the strongest citation bursts based on CiteSpace.</p></caption><graphic xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" position="float" orientation="portrait" xlink:href="gox-12-e5579-g009.jpg"/></fig><fig position="float" id="F10" orientation="portrait"><label>Fig. 10.</label><caption><p>Cluster analysis of keywords.</p></caption><graphic xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" position="float" orientation="portrait" xlink:href="gox-12-e5579-g010.jpg"/></fig></sec></sec><sec sec-type="discussion"><title>DISCUSSION</title><p>Soft-tissue filler injection is a frequently performed aesthetic procedure and an effective treatment for facial aging and contour deformities. However, due to the steady global increase in the number of soft tissue filler treatments performed, providing a comprehensive assessment of the topic has become increasingly challenging. Bibliometric analysis, a tool that uses mathematical models to track the overall research trends in a specific field, has recently been widely applied in the field of plastic surgery.<sup><xref rid="R14" ref-type="bibr">14</xref>,<xref rid="R18" ref-type="bibr">18</xref>&#8211;<xref rid="R20" ref-type="bibr">20</xref></sup> To the best of our knowledge, this is the first bibliometric study conducted on the topic of soft tissue filler injection. This study identified 1370 research articles on soft tissue filler injection from the WoSCC database. The articles were published between January 1, 2000, and December 31, 2022.</p><p>Our analysis showed that before 2004, there were limited publications on soft tissue filler injection, with only a small number of articles being published each year. However, the citations for these articles started increasing after 2004, indicating a growing interest among researchers in this field as a potential research hotspot (Fig. <xref rid="F2" ref-type="fig">2</xref>). Among the 41 countries/regions that have published at least five articles in this field, the United States ranked first in terms of publications, accounting for 38.25%. The United States emerged as the primary contributor in the field, holding a significant academic reputation in filler injection research. This is supported by the number of publications, h-index values, and total number of citations (Table <xref rid="T1" ref-type="table">1</xref>), which are closely linked to the country&#8217;s scientific research capacity, social development, economic status, and other factors.</p><p>Additionally, the Mayo Clinic emerged as the top publishing institution with 2.70% of total publications (37 articles). Moreover, the University of California San Diego (USA) achieved the highest h-index of 20 and garnered 1320 citations, while the University of California Los Angeles (USA) attained the highest citation/publication ratio of 41.24. These findings underscore the significant contributions of the USA to the advancement of this field.</p><p>Among the top 10 most productive journals, <italic toggle="yes">Dermatologic Surgery</italic>, <italic toggle="yes">Journal of Cosmetic Dermatology</italic>, and <italic toggle="yes">Plastic and Reconstructive Surgery</italic> stood out for publishing the highest number of articles in this field. <italic toggle="yes">Dermatologic Surgery</italic> emerged as the leading journal, boasting the highest number of publications and citations. It claimed the top spot among the most co-cited journals, showcasing its significant influence in the field of research. <italic toggle="yes">Plastic and Reconstructive Surgery</italic> served as a reliable source of up-to-date knowledge, covering the latest techniques and notable advancements in all areas of plastic and reconstructive surgery. Specifically, within the field of filler injection, it boasted the highest IF (5.169), h-index (36), and CPP (42.50), signifying the presence of high-quality research within its pages.</p><p>Of the top 10 articles with the highest total citations, seven focused on filler complications,<sup><xref rid="R22" ref-type="bibr">22</xref>&#8211;<xref rid="R28" ref-type="bibr">28</xref></sup> which continue to pose significant safety concerns for both cosmetic patients and physicians, highlighting the importance of this research field. Blindness is a rare and devastating complication, and possessing comprehensive anatomical knowledge is crucial for its prevention.<sup><xref rid="R29" ref-type="bibr">29</xref></sup> These publications offered promising avenues that warrant further in-depth studies. Since 2016, there has been a surge in research interest regarding facial anatomy and vascular complications such as necrosis and blindness, making them the focal points of investigation (Figs. <xref rid="F9" ref-type="fig">9</xref> and <xref rid="F11" ref-type="fig">11</xref>).</p><fig position="float" id="F11" orientation="portrait"><label>Fig. 11.</label><caption><p>Timeline visualization of keyword cluster analysis results from 2000 to 2022.</p></caption><graphic xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" position="float" orientation="portrait" xlink:href="gox-12-e5579-g011.jpg"/></fig><p>In this study, we conducted an analysis of articles pertaining to soft tissue filler injection by identifying them from the WoSCC database. We explored various aspects, including co-authorship, co-occurrence, and citation patterns among countries, institutions, authors, and hot spot keywords. Nevertheless, we restricted our analysis to English-language articles and solely relied on the WoSCC, which might not encompass all relevant databases. Consequently, the accuracy of our analysis may have been influenced.</p></sec><sec sec-type="conclusions"><title>CONCLUSIONS</title><p>Soft tissue filler injection has become a prominent subject in the realms of clinical and research domains within plastic and aesthetic surgery. Obtaining a comprehensive understanding of the trends and hotspots in this field is crucial to acquire valuable information. Our study offers a broad overview of the principal research directions in this field, emphasizing the contributions of the USA, as well as its affiliated institutions and authors. Prominent journals in this field include <italic toggle="yes">Plastic and Reconstructive Surgery</italic>, <italic toggle="yes">Dermatologic Surgery</italic>, and the <italic toggle="yes">Journal of Cosmetic Dermatology</italic>. Additionally, complications arising from filler injection and their prevention have garnered substantial attention and represent potential areas of future research focus. This study provides novel insights that can facilitate further research in this field.</p></sec><sec sec-type="COI-statement"><title>DISCLOSURE</title><p>The authors have no financial interest to declare in relation to the content of this article.</p></sec></body><back><fn-group><fn fn-type="other"><p>Published online 2 February 2024.</p></fn><fn fn-type="other"><p>
<italic toggle="yes">Disclosure statements are at the end of this article, following the correspondence information.</italic>
</p></fn></fn-group><ref-list><title>REFERENCES</title><ref id="R1"><label>1.</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Gutowski</surname><given-names>KA</given-names></name></person-group>. <article-title>Hyaluronic acid fillers: science and clinical uses.</article-title><source>Clin Plast Surg</source>. <year>2016</year>;<volume>43</volume>:<fpage>489</fpage>&#8211;<lpage>496</lpage>.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">27363762</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1016/j.cps.2016.03.016</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="R2"><label>2.</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Kadouch</surname><given-names>JA</given-names></name></person-group>. <article-title>Calcium hydroxylapatite: a review on safety and complications.</article-title><source>J Cosmet Dermatol</source>. <year>2017</year>;<volume>16</volume>:<fpage>152</fpage>&#8211;<lpage>161</lpage>.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">28247924</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1111/jocd.12326</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="R3"><label>3.</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Fitzgerald</surname><given-names>R</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Bass</surname><given-names>LM</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Goldberg</surname><given-names>DJ</given-names></name><etal/></person-group>. <article-title>Physiochemical characteristics of poly-L-Lactic acid (PLLA).</article-title><source>Aesthet Surg J</source>. <year>2018</year>;<volume>38</volume>:<fpage>S13</fpage>&#8211;<lpage>S17</lpage>.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">29897517</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1093/asj/sjy012</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="R4"><label>4.</label><mixed-citation publication-type="webpage"><article-title>American Society of Plastic Surgeons. 2020 plastic surgery statistics report.</article-title><comment>Available at <ext-link xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xlink:href="https://www.plasticsurgery.org/documents/News/Statistics/2020/plastic-surgery-statistics-full-report-2020.pdf" ext-link-type="uri">https://www.plasticsurgery.org/documents/News/Statistics/2020/plastic-surgery-statistics-full-report-2020.pdf</ext-link>. Accessed January 9, 2024</comment>.</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="R5"><label>5.</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Urdiales-G&#225;lvez</surname><given-names>F</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Delgado</surname><given-names>NE</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Figueiredo</surname><given-names>V</given-names></name><etal/></person-group>. <article-title>Treatment of soft tissue filler complications: expert consensus recommendations.</article-title><source>Aesthetic Plast Surg</source>. <year>2018</year>;<volume>42</volume>:<fpage>498</fpage>&#8211;<lpage>510</lpage>.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">29305643</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1007/s00266-017-1063-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC5840246</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="R6"><label>6.</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Arlette</surname><given-names>JP</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Froese</surname><given-names>AL</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Singh</surname><given-names>JK</given-names></name></person-group>. <article-title>Soft tissue filler therapy and informed consent: a Canadian review.</article-title><source>J Cutan Med Surg</source>. <year>2022</year>;<volume>26</volume>:<fpage>50</fpage>&#8211;<lpage>56</lpage>.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">34310242</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1177/12034754211032542</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC8750135</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="R7"><label>7.</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Bukhari</surname><given-names>SNA</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Roswandi</surname><given-names>NL</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Waqas</surname><given-names>M</given-names></name><etal/></person-group>. <article-title>Hyaluronic acid, a promising skin rejuvenating biomedicine: a review of recent updates and pre-clinical and clinical investigations on cosmetic and nutricosmetic effects.</article-title><source>Int J Biol Macromol</source>. <year>2018</year>;<volume>120</volume>:<fpage>1682</fpage>&#8211;<lpage>1695</lpage>.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">30287361</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1016/j.ijbiomac.2018.09.188</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="R8"><label>8.</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Attenello</surname><given-names>NH</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Maas</surname><given-names>CS</given-names></name></person-group>. <article-title>Injectable fillers: review of material and properties.</article-title><source>Facial Plast Surg</source>. <year>2015</year>;<volume>31</volume>:<fpage>29</fpage>&#8211;<lpage>34</lpage>.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">25763894</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1055/s-0035-1544924</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="R9"><label>9.</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Isaac</surname><given-names>J</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Walker</surname><given-names>L</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Ali</surname><given-names>SR</given-names></name><etal/></person-group>. <article-title>An illustrated anatomical approach to reducing vascular risk during facial soft tissue filler administration&#8212;a review.</article-title><source>JPRAS Open</source>. <year>2022</year>;<volume>36</volume>:<fpage>27</fpage>&#8211;<lpage>45</lpage>.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">37064503</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1016/j.jpra.2022.09.006</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC10102405</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="R10"><label>10.</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Liao</surname><given-names>ZF</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Cong</surname><given-names>LY</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Li</surname><given-names>FW</given-names></name><etal/></person-group>. <article-title>Positions of the glabellar arteries: implications for glabellar injection.</article-title><source>Aesthetic Plast Surg</source>. <year>2023</year>;<volume>47</volume>:<fpage>2037</fpage>&#8211;<lpage>2044</lpage>.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">36538055</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1007/s00266-022-03218-6</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="R11"><label>11.</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Liao</surname><given-names>ZF</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Cong</surname><given-names>LY</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Luo</surname><given-names>CE</given-names></name><etal/></person-group>. <article-title>New insight into glabellar arteries: a 3D CT and dissection study.</article-title><source>Plast Reconstr Surg</source>. <year>2023</year>;<volume>151</volume>:<fpage>979</fpage>&#8211;<lpage>987</lpage>.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">36729555</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1097/PRS.0000000000010075</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="R12"><label>12.</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Ellegaard</surname><given-names>O</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Wallin</surname><given-names>JA</given-names></name></person-group>. <article-title>The bibliometric analysis of scholarly production: how great is the impact?</article-title><source>Scientometrics</source>. <year>2015</year>;<volume>105</volume>:<fpage>1809</fpage>&#8211;<lpage>1831</lpage>.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">26594073</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1007/s11192-015-1645-z</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC4643120</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="R13"><label>13.</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Head</surname><given-names>MG</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Fitchett</surname><given-names>JR</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Newell</surname><given-names>ML</given-names></name><etal/></person-group>. <article-title>Mapping pneumonia research: a systematic analysis of UK investments and published outputs 1997</article-title>&#8211;<article-title>2013.</article-title><source>EBioMedicine</source>. <year>2015</year>;<volume>2</volume>:<fpage>1193</fpage>&#8211;<lpage>1199</lpage>.<pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1016/j.ebiom.2015.06.024</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC4588381</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">26501117</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="R14"><label>14.</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Deng</surname><given-names>P</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Wang</surname><given-names>S</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Sun</surname><given-names>X</given-names></name><etal/></person-group>. <article-title>Global trends in research of gouty arthritis over past decade: a bibliometric analysis.</article-title><source>Front Immunol</source>. <year>2022</year>;<volume>13</volume>:<fpage>910400</fpage>.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">35757713</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.3389/fimmu.2022.910400</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC9229989</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="R15"><label>15.</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Devos</surname><given-names>P</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Menard</surname><given-names>J</given-names></name></person-group>. <article-title>Bibliometric analysis of research relating to hypertension reported over the period 1997</article-title>&#8211;<article-title>2016.</article-title><source>J Hypertens</source>. <year>2019</year>;<volume>37</volume>:<fpage>2116</fpage>&#8211;<lpage>2122</lpage>.<pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1097/HJH.0000000000002143</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC6784761</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">31136459</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="R16"><label>16.</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Rosas</surname><given-names>SR</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Kagan</surname><given-names>JM</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Schouten</surname><given-names>JT</given-names></name><etal/></person-group>. <article-title>Evaluating research and impact: a bibliometric analysis of research by the NIH/NIAID HIV/AIDS clinical trials networks.</article-title><source>PLoS One</source>. <year>2011</year>;<volume>6</volume>:<fpage>e17428</fpage>.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">21394198</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1371/journal.pone.0017428</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC3048860</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="R17"><label>17.</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Ri</surname><given-names>C</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Ri</surname><given-names>H</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Yu</surname><given-names>J</given-names></name><etal/></person-group>. <article-title>Update on rhinoplasty research trends: a bibliometric analysis.</article-title><source>Aesthetic Plast Surg</source>. <year>2022</year>;<volume>46</volume>:<fpage>2950</fpage>&#8211;<lpage>2963</lpage>.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">35641688</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1007/s00266-022-02910-x</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="R18"><label>18.</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Mao</surname><given-names>J</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Ri</surname><given-names>C</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Li</surname><given-names>B</given-names></name><etal/></person-group>. <article-title>Research hotspots and emerging trends of facial rejuvenation: a bibliometric analysis.</article-title><source>Aesthetic Plast Surg</source>. <year>2023</year>;<volume>47</volume>:<fpage>1039</fpage>&#8211;<lpage>1058</lpage>.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">36376584</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1007/s00266-022-03099-9</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="R19"><label>19.</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Gao</surname><given-names>H</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Wu</surname><given-names>D</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Jie</surname><given-names>X</given-names></name><etal/></person-group>. <article-title>Global research trends and perspectives of blepharoplasty: a 20-year bibliometric analysis based on web of science.</article-title><source>Aesthetic Plast Surg</source>. <year>2023</year>;<volume>47</volume>:<fpage>654</fpage>&#8211;<lpage>665</lpage>.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">36203097</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1007/s00266-022-03116-x</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="R20"><label>20.</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Li</surname><given-names>TH</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Li</surname><given-names>ZM</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Qin</surname><given-names>XH</given-names></name><etal/></person-group>. <article-title>Global analyses and latest research hot spots of adipose-derived stem cells in fat grafting: a bibliometric and visualized review.</article-title><source>Aesthetic Plast Surg</source>. <year>2022</year>;<volume>47</volume>:<fpage>1192</fpage>&#8211;<lpage>1204</lpage>.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">36460771</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1007/s00266-022-03201-1</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC10229469</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="R21"><label>21.</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Zhou</surname><given-names>YC</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Zhu</surname><given-names>YL</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Cai</surname><given-names>Z</given-names></name><etal/></person-group>. <article-title>Top 100 highly cited articles on rhinoplasty between 2001 and 2020: a bibliometric and visualized analysis.</article-title><source>Plast Reconstr Surg</source>. <year>2023</year>;<volume>151</volume>:<fpage>581e</fpage>&#8211;<lpage>591e</lpage>.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">36729781</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1097/PRS.0000000000009989</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="R22"><label>22.</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Beleznay</surname><given-names>K</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Carruthers</surname><given-names>JD</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Humphrey</surname><given-names>S</given-names></name><etal/></person-group>. <article-title>Avoiding and treating blindness from fillers: a review of the world literature.</article-title><source>Dermatol Surg</source>. <year>2015</year>;<volume>41</volume>:<fpage>1097</fpage>&#8211;<lpage>1117</lpage>.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">26356847</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1097/DSS.0000000000000486</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="R23"><label>23.</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Christensen</surname><given-names>L</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Breiting</surname><given-names>V</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Janssen</surname><given-names>M</given-names></name><etal/></person-group>. <article-title>Adverse reactions to injectable soft tissue permanent fillers.</article-title><source>Aesthetic Plast Surg</source>. <year>2005</year>;<volume>29</volume>:<fpage>34</fpage>&#8211;<lpage>48</lpage>.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">15759096</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1007/s00266-004-0113-6</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="R24"><label>24.</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Lowe</surname><given-names>NJ</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Maxwell</surname><given-names>CA</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Patnaik</surname><given-names>R</given-names></name></person-group>. <article-title>Adverse reactions to dermal fillers: review.</article-title><source>Dermatol Surg</source>. <year>2005</year>;<volume>31</volume>:<fpage>1616</fpage>&#8211;<lpage>1625</lpage>.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">16416647</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="R25"><label>25.</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>DeLorenzi</surname><given-names>C</given-names></name></person-group>. <article-title>Complications of injectable fillers, part 2: vascular complications.</article-title><source>Aesthet Surg J</source>. <year>2014</year>;<volume>34</volume>:<fpage>584</fpage>&#8211;<lpage>600</lpage>.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">24692598</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1177/1090820X14525035</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="R26"><label>26.</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Requena</surname><given-names>L</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Requena</surname><given-names>C</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Christensen</surname><given-names>L</given-names></name><etal/></person-group>. <article-title>Adverse reactions to injectable soft tissue fillers [published correction appears in <italic toggle="yes">J Am Acad Dermatol.</italic> 2011 Jun;64(6):1178].</article-title><source>J Am Acad Dermatol</source>. <year>2011</year>;<volume>64</volume>:<fpage>1</fpage>&#8211;<lpage>34; quiz 35</lpage>.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">21167403</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1016/j.jaad.2010.02.064</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="R27"><label>27.</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Cohen</surname><given-names>JL</given-names></name></person-group>. <article-title>Understanding, avoiding, and managing dermal filler complications.</article-title><source>Dermatol Surg</source>. <year>2008</year>;<volume>34</volume>:<fpage>S92</fpage>&#8211;<lpage>S99</lpage>.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">18547189</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1111/j.1524-4725.2008.34249.x</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="R28"><label>28.</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Ozturk</surname><given-names>CN</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Li</surname><given-names>Y</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Tung</surname><given-names>R</given-names></name><etal/></person-group>. <article-title>Complications following injection of soft-tissue fillers.</article-title><source>Aesthet Surg J</source>. <year>2013</year>;<volume>33</volume>:<fpage>862</fpage>&#8211;<lpage>877</lpage>.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">23825309</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1177/1090820X13493638</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="R29"><label>29.</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Beleznay</surname><given-names>K</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Carruthers</surname><given-names>JDA</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Humphrey</surname><given-names>S</given-names></name><etal/></person-group>. <article-title>Update on avoiding and treating blindness from fillers: a recent review of the world literature.</article-title><source>Aesthet Surg J</source>. <year>2019</year>;<volume>39</volume>:<fpage>662</fpage>&#8211;<lpage>674</lpage>.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">30805636</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1093/asj/sjz053</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref></ref-list></back></article></pmc-articleset>