<?xml version="1.0"  ?><!DOCTYPE pmc-articleset PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD ARTICLE SET 2.0//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pmc/articleset/nlm-articleset-2.0.dtd"><pmc-articleset><article xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" xmlns:ali="http://www.niso.org/schemas/ali/1.0/" article-type="research-article" xml:lang="en" dtd-version="1.4"><processing-meta base-tagset="archiving" mathml-version="3.0" table-model="xhtml" tagset-family="jats"><restricted-by>pmc</restricted-by></processing-meta><front><journal-meta><journal-id journal-id-type="nlm-ta">Sci Rep</journal-id><journal-id journal-id-type="iso-abbrev">Sci Rep</journal-id><journal-id journal-id-type="pmc-domain-id">1579</journal-id><journal-id journal-id-type="pmc-domain">scirep</journal-id><journal-title-group><journal-title>Scientific Reports</journal-title></journal-title-group><issn pub-type="epub">2045-2322</issn><publisher><publisher-name>Nature Publishing Group</publisher-name></publisher></journal-meta><article-meta><article-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC11213947</article-id><article-id pub-id-type="pmcid-ver">PMC11213947.1</article-id><article-id pub-id-type="pmcaid">11213947</article-id><article-id pub-id-type="pmcaiid">11213947</article-id><article-id pub-id-type="pmid">38942920</article-id><article-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1038/s41598-024-64924-6</article-id><article-id pub-id-type="publisher-id">64924</article-id><article-version article-version-type="pmc-version">1</article-version><article-categories><subj-group subj-group-type="heading"><subject>Article</subject></subj-group></article-categories><title-group><article-title>Hyaluronidase inhibitor delphinidin inhibits cancer metastasis</article-title></title-group><contrib-group><contrib contrib-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>McGuire</surname><given-names initials="J">Jeremy</given-names></name><xref ref-type="aff" rid="Aff1">1</xref></contrib><contrib contrib-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Taguchi</surname><given-names initials="T">Taketo</given-names></name><xref ref-type="aff" rid="Aff2">2</xref></contrib><contrib contrib-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Tombline</surname><given-names initials="G">Gregory</given-names></name><xref ref-type="aff" rid="Aff3">3</xref></contrib><contrib contrib-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Paige</surname><given-names initials="V">Victoria</given-names></name><xref ref-type="aff" rid="Aff3">3</xref></contrib><contrib contrib-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Janelsins</surname><given-names initials="M">Michelle</given-names></name><xref ref-type="aff" rid="Aff1">1</xref><xref ref-type="aff" rid="Aff4">4</xref></contrib><contrib contrib-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Gilmore</surname><given-names initials="N">Nikesha</given-names></name><xref ref-type="aff" rid="Aff1">1</xref><xref ref-type="aff" rid="Aff4">4</xref></contrib><contrib contrib-type="author" corresp="yes"><name name-style="western"><surname>Seluanov</surname><given-names initials="A">Andrei</given-names></name><address><email>andrei.seluanov@rochester.edu</email></address><xref ref-type="aff" rid="Aff3">3</xref><xref ref-type="aff" rid="Aff5">5</xref></contrib><contrib contrib-type="author" corresp="yes"><name name-style="western"><surname>Gorbunova</surname><given-names initials="V">Vera</given-names></name><address><email>vera.gorbunova@rochester.edu</email></address><xref ref-type="aff" rid="Aff3">3</xref><xref ref-type="aff" rid="Aff5">5</xref></contrib><aff id="Aff1"><label>1</label><institution-wrap><institution-id institution-id-type="ROR">https://ror.org/00trqv719</institution-id><institution-id institution-id-type="GRID">grid.412750.5</institution-id><institution-id institution-id-type="ISNI">0000 0004 1936 9166</institution-id><institution>Supportive Care in Cancer, Department of Surgery, </institution><institution>University of Rochester Medical Center, </institution></institution-wrap>265 Crittenden Blvd., Box CU 420658, Rochester, NY 14642 USA </aff><aff id="Aff2"><label>2</label><institution-wrap><institution-id institution-id-type="ROR">https://ror.org/03xez1567</institution-id><institution-id institution-id-type="GRID">grid.250671.7</institution-id><institution-id institution-id-type="ISNI">0000 0001 0662 7144</institution-id><institution>Salk Institute for Biological Studies, </institution></institution-wrap>10010 N Torrey Pines Rd, La Jolla, CA 92037 USA </aff><aff id="Aff3"><label>3</label><institution-wrap><institution-id institution-id-type="ROR">https://ror.org/022kthw22</institution-id><institution-id institution-id-type="GRID">grid.16416.34</institution-id><institution-id institution-id-type="ISNI">0000 0004 1936 9174</institution-id><institution>Department of Biology, </institution><institution>University of Rochester, </institution></institution-wrap>Rochester, NY USA </aff><aff id="Aff4"><label>4</label><institution-wrap><institution-id institution-id-type="GRID">grid.412750.5</institution-id><institution-id institution-id-type="ISNI">0000 0004 1936 9166</institution-id><institution>James P. Wilmot Cancer Institute, </institution><institution>University of Rochester Medical Center, </institution></institution-wrap>Rochester, NY USA </aff><aff id="Aff5"><label>5</label><institution-wrap><institution-id institution-id-type="ROR">https://ror.org/022kthw22</institution-id><institution-id institution-id-type="GRID">grid.16416.34</institution-id><institution-id institution-id-type="ISNI">0000 0004 1936 9174</institution-id><institution>Department of Medicine, </institution><institution>University of Rochester, </institution></institution-wrap>Rochester, NY USA </aff></contrib-group><pub-date pub-type="epub"><day>28</day><month>6</month><year>2024</year></pub-date><pub-date pub-type="collection"><year>2024</year></pub-date><volume>14</volume><issue-id pub-id-type="pmc-issue-id">452196</issue-id><elocation-id>14958</elocation-id><history><date date-type="received"><day>26</day><month>1</month><year>2024</year></date><date date-type="accepted"><day>14</day><month>6</month><year>2024</year></date></history><pub-history><event event-type="pmc-release"><date><day>28</day><month>06</month><year>2024</year></date></event><event event-type="pmc-live"><date><day>29</day><month>06</month><year>2024</year></date></event><event event-type="pmc-last-change"><date iso-8601-date="2024-06-30 00:25:14.600"><day>30</day><month>06</month><year>2024</year></date></event></pub-history><permissions><copyright-statement>&#169; The Author(s) 2024</copyright-statement><license><ali:license_ref specific-use="textmining" content-type="ccbylicense">https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</ali:license_ref><license-p><bold>Open Access</bold> This article is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution 4.0 International License, which permits use, sharing, adaptation, distribution and reproduction in any medium or format, as long as you give appropriate credit to the original author(s) and the source, provide a link to the Creative Commons licence, and indicate if changes were made. The images or other third party material in this article are included in the article's Creative Commons licence, unless indicated otherwise in a credit line to the material. If material is not included in the article's Creative Commons licence and your intended use is not permitted by statutory regulation or exceeds the permitted use, you will need to obtain permission directly from the copyright holder. To view a copy of this licence, visit <ext-link xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" ext-link-type="uri" xlink:href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/">http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</ext-link>.</license-p></license></permissions><self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" content-type="pmc-pdf" xlink:href="41598_2024_Article_64924.pdf"/><abstract id="Abs1"><p id="Par1">Cancer remains a formidable global health challenge, with metastasis being a key contributor to its lethality. Abundant high molecular mass hyaluronic acid, a major non-protein component of extracellular matrix, protects naked mole rats from cancer and reduces cancer incidence in mice. Hyaluronidase plays a critical role in degrading hyaluronic acid and is frequently overexpressed in metastatic cancer. Here we investigated the potential of targeting hyaluronidases to reduce metastasis. A&#160;high throughput screen identified delphinidin, a natural plant compound found in fruits and vegetables, as a potent hyaluronidase inhibitor. Delphinidin-mediated inhibition of hyaluronidase activity led to an increase in high molecular weight hyaluronic acid in cell culture and in mouse tissues, and reduced migration and invasion behavior of breast, prostate, and melanoma cancer cells. Moreover, delphinidin treatment suppressed melanoma metastasis in mice. Our study provides a proof of principle that inhibition of hyaluronidase activity suppresses cancer cell migration, invasion and metastasis. Furthermore, we identified a natural compound delphinidin as a potential anticancer therapeutic. Thus, we have identified a path for clinical translation of the cancer resistance mechanism identified in the naked mole rat.</p></abstract><kwd-group kwd-group-type="npg-subject"><title>Subject terms</title><kwd>Drug development</kwd><kwd>Metastasis</kwd><kwd>Cell biology</kwd><kwd>Molecular biology</kwd><kwd>Cancer microenvironment</kwd></kwd-group><funding-group><award-group><funding-source><institution-wrap><institution-id institution-id-type="FundRef">http://dx.doi.org/10.13039/100000049</institution-id><institution>National Institute on Aging</institution></institution-wrap></funding-source><award-id>AG047200</award-id></award-group></funding-group><custom-meta-group><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-status-qastatus</meta-name><meta-value>0</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-status-live</meta-name><meta-value>yes</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-status-embargo</meta-name><meta-value>no</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-status-released</meta-name><meta-value>yes</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-open-access</meta-name><meta-value>yes</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-olf</meta-name><meta-value>no</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-manuscript</meta-name><meta-value>no</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-legally-suppressed</meta-name><meta-value>no</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-has-pdf</meta-name><meta-value>yes</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-has-supplement</meta-name><meta-value>yes</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-pdf-only</meta-name><meta-value>no</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-suppress-copyright</meta-name><meta-value>no</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-is-real-version</meta-name><meta-value>no</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-is-scanned-article</meta-name><meta-value>no</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-preprint</meta-name><meta-value>no</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-in-epmc</meta-name><meta-value>yes</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-license-ref</meta-name><meta-value>CC BY</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>issue-copyright-statement</meta-name><meta-value>&#169; Springer Nature Limited 2024</meta-value></custom-meta></custom-meta-group></article-meta></front><body><sec id="Sec1"><title>Introduction</title><p id="Par2">Metastasis, the spread of a primary cancer to a distant site, remains the primary cause of cancer mortality, observed in more than 90% of all cancer deaths<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR1">1</xref>&#8211;<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR3">3</xref></sup>. It is imperative that new treatment strategies aimed at preventing metastasis are explored to increase the survival rates for patients with cancer. Metastasis is a complex process that involves multiple steps known as the metastatic cascade, which begins with tumor cells detaching from the primary site, invading local stroma, intravasating into the circulatory or lymphatic system, extravasating at a distant site and growing to form a new tumor<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR4">4</xref>,<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR5">5</xref></sup>. Alteration of the primary tumor microenvironment may affect the initiation of the metastatic cascade and the ability of primary cancer cells to migrate and invade<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR6">6</xref>,<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR7">7</xref></sup>.</p><p id="Par3">Hyaluronic acid (HA), also known as hyaluronan, is a major non-protein component of the extracellular matrix<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR7">7</xref></sup>. HA is a polysaccharide of variable length depending on the number of repeating segments of D-glucuronic acid and <italic toggle="yes">N</italic>-acetyl-<sc>d</sc>-glucosamine. The role of HA in cancer progression can be described as a double-edge sword: in some instances, HA can be pro- tumorigenic, but can also be anti-tumorigenic. HA is implicated in cancer progression in multiple cancer types including prostate, bladder, breast and lung<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR8">8</xref>&#8211;<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR12">12</xref></sup>. On the other hand, HA is implicated in cancer resistance in the naked mole rat<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR13">13</xref></sup> as well in tumor suppression of human breast cancer cells<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR14">14</xref></sup>. We recently demonstrated that mice overexpressing hyaluronan synthase 2 from the naked mole-rat show reduced incidence of spontaneous and induced cancers<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR15">15</xref></sup>. An explanation for the dual nature of HA in cancer progression is that high molecular weight hyaluronic acid (HMW-HA) is tumor protective, while low molecular weight hyaluronic acid (LMW HA) is tumor promotive<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR16">16</xref>,<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR17">17</xref></sup>. LMW-HA promotes angiogenesis and inflammation which are all hallmarks of cancer metastasis<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR5">5</xref>,<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR18">18</xref></sup>. HMW-HA on the other hand is anti-inflammatory<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR19">19</xref></sup> and inhibits proliferation and migration of cancer cells<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR20">20</xref></sup>. Hence, a balance between HMW-HA and LMW-HA may control tumor progression and metastasis, with HMW-HA being inhibitory for tumor development and metastasis. In humans there is a family of six hyaluronidases (HYALs), HYAL 1-6<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR21">21</xref></sup>. HYAL 1 and 2 are the enzymes primarily responsible for degradation of HA in somatic tissues but HYAL 2 is predominately responsible for cleaving HMW-HAs-producing LMW-HAs that are often overexpressed in the tumor microenvironment<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR22">22</xref></sup>. An additional hyaluronidase transmembrane&#160;protein 2 (TMEM2) is a cell surface protein that possesses potent hyaluronidase activity and may be involved in degrading HA at the cell surface microenvironment<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR23">23</xref></sup>.</p><p id="Par4">We thus sought to identify small molecule inhibitors of hyaluronidases to increase the endogenous levels of HMW-HA that may inhibit cancer progression and metastasis. Since no potent small molecule inhibitors of hyaluronidase were commercially available, we designed an assay for identification of hyaluronidase inhibitors using fluorescence polarization (FP). We conducted a FP-based high-throughput screening assay and identified a natural plant compound, delphinidin, as an inhibitor of hyaluronidase. Delphinidin is the anthocyanidin that gives a dark blue color to many common fruits and vegetables including blueberries, pomegranates, black beans, black grapes, sweet potatoes, pigmented cabbages and some wines such as Cabernet Sauvignon<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR24">24</xref>&#8211;<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR26">26</xref></sup>. In our study we show that delphinidin inhibits hyaluronidase degradation of HA both in vitro and increases HA levels in vivo<italic toggle="yes">.</italic> When injected into tumor-bearing mice, delphinidin slowed the progression of metastasis. This combined with lack of adverse effects<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR27">27</xref></sup> makes delphinidin an attractive compound for prevention or treatment of metastatic cancer.</p></sec><sec id="Sec2"><title>Results</title><sec id="Sec3"><title>High throughput screening for hyaluronidase inhibitors using fluorescence polarization</title><p id="Par5">Increase in HMW-HA achieved by overexpression of naked mole-rat HAS2 gene reduces cancer incidence and extends lifespan in mice<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR15">15</xref></sup>. HMW-HA may confer antimetastatic effects on both lymphatic and vascular metastasis because it enhances lymphatic vessel integrity<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR28">28</xref></sup>. HMW-HA may also inhibit vascular metastasis when primary aortic smooth muscle vascular cells were treated with HA, LMW-HA promoted proliferation while HMW-HA stalled proliferation in the G1 phase<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR29">29</xref></sup>.&#8221; In addition, smaller HA oligomers that are generated during HA degradation appear to stimulate tumor invasion and metastasis and we propose that inhibition of hyaluronidases by delphinidin may also block this effect<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR30">30</xref>&#8211;<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR32">32</xref></sup>. To translate these benefits to human patients we set out to identify small molecule inhibitors of hyaluronidases which we hypothesized would slow the cleavage of endogenously produced HA and increase HMW-HA levels in tissues. As HMW-HA and LMW-HA differ only in length, we could not use conventional methods such as fluorescent intensity to detect the changes that hyaluronidases make. We applied the concept of FP measurement to detect the difference between the sizes of HA. Conventionally, FP is used to detect the binding of a fluorescent ligand to an enzyme of interest: When a fluorescent ligand is free-floating, it tumbles rapidly. When a polarized light is used to excite the fluorophore, the polarity of emission light would be different from that of excitation light because of the rapid molecular tumbling. On the other hand, when the fluorescent ligand binds to the enzyme of interest, large size of the enzyme prevents it from tumbling rapidly, and after excitation with a polarized light, the polarity of emission light stays close to that of the excitation light. FP measures this similarity between the polarities (the more similar the polarities are, the larger the FP values would be). Fluorescently labeled HMW-HA does not tumble rapidly because of its large size, thus giving large FP values. In contrast, fluorescein labeled LMW-HA tumbles more rapidly and gives smaller FP values. To fluorescently label HA, fluorescein was chosen as a fluorophore because of its appropriate fluorescent lifetime, and the Ugi reaction was used to link fluorescein to HA to achieve zero-length crosslinking and restrict molecular rotation of the fluorophore. By using fluorescent HA and FP, the hyaluronidase inhibitor assay produced reliable measurements with Z&#8242;-factor of 0.69 (Fig. <xref rid="Fig1" ref-type="fig">1</xref>A). Using this assay, about 3000 compounds from the National Cancer Institute (Approved Oncology Drugs Set, Diversity Set, Natural Products Set and Mechanistic Set) were screened (Fig. <xref rid="Fig1" ref-type="fig">1</xref>B), and Prodelphiniline (Fig. <xref rid="Fig1" ref-type="fig">1</xref>C) was selected as a hit compound. After studying the pharmacophores and structure-activity relationship, a much smaller compound, Delphinidin (Fig. <xref rid="Fig1" ref-type="fig">1</xref>D), was identified as a small molecule hyaluronidase inhibitor.<fig id="Fig1" position="float" orientation="portrait"><label>Figure 1</label><caption><p>High throughput screening (HTS) for HAase inhibitor using fluorescence polarization &amp; increases in HMW HA by delphinidin. (<bold>A</bold>) FP shows fluorescent HMW-HA at a higher FP value than LMW-HA (<bold>B</bold>) Representative data from HTS in a 384 well plate, red arrow indicates prodelphiniline. (<bold>C</bold>, <bold>D</bold>) Structures of Prodelphiniline and Delphinidin. (<bold>E</bold>) Equal numbers of human or mouse fibroblasts were incubated with increasing concentrations of Delphinidin for 24&#160;h. HA was separated on agarose gel (<bold>F</bold>) Quantification of HA in mouse and human samples.</p></caption><graphic xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" id="MO1" position="float" orientation="portrait" xlink:href="41598_2024_64924_Fig1_HTML.jpg"/></fig></p></sec><sec id="Sec4"><title>Delphinidin inhibits hyaluronidase activity and increases the levels and size of HMW-HA</title><p id="Par6">To test whether delphinidin increases the amount of HMW-HA in cultured cells, mouse and human fibroblasts were treated with delphinidin (0, 10 &#181;M, 20 &#181;M and 40 &#181;M) for 24&#160;h before hyaluronic acid (HA) was extracted from cell culture media and run on an agarose gel. The size and amount of HA increased in both mouse and human fibroblasts (Fig. <xref rid="Fig1" ref-type="fig">1</xref>E). The relative concentration of HA was quantitated showing a dose dependent increase in total HA concentration in the delphinidin treated fibroblasts with an increase in HMW HA between 4000 and 600&#160;kD observed in the gel image (Fig. <xref rid="Fig1" ref-type="fig">1</xref>F). We extracted HMW-HA from B16-F10 cell culture treated with and without delphinidin. Delphinidin was able to increase the size and amount of HA extracted after 48&#160;h of culture and when we repeated the experiment with a diluted sample of HAase delphinidin inhibited the degradation of HA (Supplemental Fig. <xref rid="MOESM1" ref-type="media">1</xref>).</p><p id="Par7">To test the efficacy of delphinidin in increasing HA levels in vivo we treated 3-months-old wild type C57BL/6 mice with vehicle (n&#8201;=&#8201;3) (10% DMSO/90% PBS) or with 50 mg/kg (n&#8201;=&#8201;4) or 100 mg/kg of delphinidin (n&#8201;=&#8201;3). Intraperitoneal (IP) injections of 100 &#181;l of vehicle or delphinidin were administered three times a week for 3&#160;weeks before the mice were sacrificed and skin, muscle, kidney, heart, lung, duodenum, jejunum and colon were collected. Previous studies have shown that IP injections of delphinidin provides reliable systemic distribution. There were no visible adverse effects in the mice, and they maintained weight comparable to the vehicle controls. Slides with paraffin embedded tissues from each of the samples collected from the mice were stained using hyaluronic acid binding protein (HABP) and a fluorescent streptavidin antibody to detect HA in the tissues. For each sample one section was treated overnight with hyaluronidase to degrade any HA before staining (Supplemental Fig. <xref rid="MOESM1" ref-type="media">2</xref>). Using fluorescent microscopy six representative images of each sample for all animals were captured (Fig. <xref rid="Fig2" ref-type="fig">2</xref>A). Imaris software version 9.8 Oxford Instruments (<ext-link xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" ext-link-type="uri" xlink:href="https://imaris.oxinst.com/">https://imaris.oxinst.com/</ext-link>) was used for the quantification of maximum fluorescent intensity, and any background fluorescence from the hyaluronidase control samples was subtracted. In skin, muscle, heart, kidney and intestines (duodenum, jejunum and colon) fluorescent intensity was significantly increased in animals treated with delphinidin compared to the vehicle control (Fig. <xref rid="Fig2" ref-type="fig">2</xref>B). Indicating that delphinidin inhibits hyaluronidases and increases HA levels in vivo. While we were not able to test the size of the HA in the tissues, the results from our in vitro experiments suggest that HA length is also increased.<fig id="Fig2" position="float" orientation="portrait"><label>Figure 2</label><caption><p>In vivo administration of delphinidin increased HA accumulation in mouse tissues: Mice were injected three times a week for three weeks with either vehicle, 50&#160;mg/kg delphinidin or 100&#160;mg/kg of delphinidin. Tissues were collected and embedded in paraffin before slide mounting and HABP staining. (<bold>A</bold>) Representative images (20X) showing HABP staining in mouse tissues. (<bold>B</bold>) Quantification of HABP staining in mouse tissue mean fluorescence intensity of 6 representative images (three biological replicates with two technical replicates from each tissue) using Imaris cell imaging software. Statistical analyses were generated from one-way ANOVA with multiple comparisons at 95% CI error bars are represented as mean with SEM.</p></caption><graphic xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" id="MO2" position="float" orientation="portrait" xlink:href="41598_2024_64924_Fig2_HTML.jpg"/></fig></p></sec><sec id="Sec5"><title>Delphinidin inhibits <italic toggle="yes">cancer</italic> cell proliferation</title><p id="Par8">We next tested the ability of delphinidin to inhibit proliferation of normal fibroblasts compared to the three cancer cell lines B16-F10, EO771 and RM1. The rationale for choosing the cell lines used in this study is that they are all metastatic cell lines derived from C57/Bl6 mice and can be used in syngeneic mouse models of metastasis. Mouse breast, prostate and melanoma cancer cells along with wild type mouse fibroblasts were treated with delphinidin or vehicle. Proliferation was quantified using Promega Cell Titer Glo assay 48&#160;h post treatment. Growth of all three cancer cell lines was inhibited by at least 50% compared to the control when treated with 15 &#181;M delphinidin, whereas 30 &#181;M delphinidin inhibited growth by at least 90%. Skin fibroblasts from wild type mice were not significantly inhibited by 15 &#181;M or 30 &#181;M delphinidin treatment (Fig. <xref rid="Fig3" ref-type="fig">3</xref>). Delphinidin specifically inhibited cancer cell growth while having little impact on the growth of the normal mouse cells. To test whether the effect of delphinidin is dependent on HA accumulation, the experiment was repeated with the addition of exogenous hyaluronidase (HAase). Cancer cells were treated with either delphinidin alone or delphinidin and exogenous HAase. When HAase was added in combination with delphinidin proliferation was partially restored to all three cancer cell lines (Fig. <xref rid="Fig3" ref-type="fig">3</xref>). These results taken together indicate that delphinidin is inhibiting cancer cell proliferation through the inhibition of HAase.<fig id="Fig3" position="float" orientation="portrait"><label>Figure 3</label><caption><p>Delphinidin inhibits proliferation of cancer cells. (<bold>A</bold>) Delphinidin had no significant effect on the growth of wildtype C57/Bl6 fibroblasts after 48&#160;h. Proliferation was assayed using Cell Titer Glo 2.0 (<bold>B</bold>&#8211;<bold>D</bold>) Delphinidin in a dose dependent manner significantly inhibited the growth of B16-F10, E0771 and RM1 after 48&#160;h. (<bold>E</bold>&#8211;<bold>G</bold>) When the cancer cells were treated with HAase in combination with delphinidin a reduction in growth inhibition was observed at 48&#160;h. All data was collected as technical triplicates and statistical analyses were generated from one-way ANOVA with multiple comparisons at 95% CI error bars are represented as mean with SEM.</p></caption><graphic xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" id="MO3" position="float" orientation="portrait" xlink:href="41598_2024_64924_Fig3_HTML.jpg"/></fig></p></sec><sec id="Sec6"><title>Delphinidin inhibits migration and invasion of <italic toggle="yes">cancer</italic> cells</title><p id="Par9">We next assessed if delphinidin has the ability to inhibit both migration and invasion of cancer cell lines in vitro. Cell migration was first assessed by wound healing assays. Silicone inserts were used to create a gap between the cancer cells so that when the inserts were removed the cells could migrate to fill in the gap. When the cells became confluent the inserts were removed and the cancer cells were treated either with 15 &#181;M delphinidin or control. The cells were then observed hourly over the next 8&#8211;20&#160;h to determine how long it took for the control cells to close approximately 80% of the gap. All three cancer cell lines were significantly inhibited in closing the gap compared to the control cells (Supplemental Fig. <xref rid="MOESM1" ref-type="media">3</xref>).</p><p id="Par10">Cell migration was assessed using a Boyden chamber assay. Cells were seeded in the top chamber, separated from the bottom chamber by a porous membrane. The bottom chambers contained 1% fetal bovine serum (FBS) as a chemoattractant. The top chambers were seeded with cancer cells with or without delphinidin. The addition of 15 &#181;M delphinidin inhibited the migration of all three cancer cell types (Fig. <xref rid="Fig4" ref-type="fig">4</xref>). Invasion was assessed using a similar Boyden chamber assay&#160;where the upper chamber is coated with a basement membrane that mimics the in vivo microenvironment that cancer cells encounter during the process of metastasis. Cancer cell lines were seeded for 24&#160;h in triplicate with and without delphinidin. Invasion by all three cancer cell types was significantly inhibited by the addition of 15 &#181;M delphinidin (Fig. <xref rid="Fig5" ref-type="fig">5</xref>). To test if delphinidin inhibits invasion by its inhibitory effect on HAase, we added delphinidin and HAase to the upper chamber with the cancer cells. The addition of HAase abrogated the inhibitory effect of delphinidin on invasion after 24&#160;h in all cell lines (Fig. <xref rid="Fig5" ref-type="fig">5</xref>). These results suggest that delphinidin inhibits invasion of cancer cells in part by inhibiting HAase.<fig id="Fig4" position="float" orientation="portrait"><label>Figure 4</label><caption><p>Delphinidin inhibits migration of cancer cells. (<bold>A</bold>) Representative images of membranes from Boyden chamber assay. Negative control was serum free media on both sides of the membrane and positive control was 1% FBS on the bottom well to promote chemotaxis delphinidin was added to top wells with cells and bottom wells contained 1% FBS (<bold>B</bold>&#8211;<bold>D</bold>) All three cancer cell lines had significant inhibition of migration when incubated with 15&#160;&#181;M delphinidin. (<bold>B</bold>) B16-F10 (<bold>C</bold>) E0771 (<bold>D</bold>) RM1. All data were collected as technical triplicates and statistical analyses were generated from one-way ANOVA with multiple comparisons at 95% CI error bars are represented as mean with SEM.</p></caption><graphic xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" id="MO4" position="float" orientation="portrait" xlink:href="41598_2024_64924_Fig4_HTML.jpg"/></fig><fig id="Fig5" position="float" orientation="portrait"><label>Figure 5</label><caption><p>Delphinidin inhibits invasion of cancer cell and HAase abrogates the effect of delphinidin. (<bold>A</bold>) Representative images of the membranes from the Boyden chamber invasion assay. The inside of the top membrane was coated with basement membrane to mimic metastatic invasion. Negative control was serum free media in top and bottom wells and positive control was 1% FBS on the bottom well to promote chemotaxis delphinidin and HAase was added to top wells with cells in serum free media and bottom wells contained 1% FBS. (<bold>B</bold>&#8211;<bold>D</bold>) 15&#160;&#181;M Delphinidin inhibited the invasion of all three cancer cell lines compared with 10 U/ml of HAase when cells were incubated with delphinidin in combination with 100 U/ml HAase the amount of inhibition was reduced. (<bold>B</bold>) B16-F10 (<bold>C</bold>) E0771 (<bold>D</bold>) RM1. All data was collected as technical triplicates and statistical analyses were generated from one-way ANOVA with multiple comparisons at 95% CI error bars are represented as mean with SEM.</p></caption><graphic xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" id="MO5" position="float" orientation="portrait" xlink:href="41598_2024_64924_Fig5_HTML.jpg"/></fig></p></sec><sec id="Sec7"><title>Delphinidin inhibits spontaneous melanoma metastasis in vivo</title><p id="Par11">To test whether delphinidin inhibits cancer cell metastasis in vivo, 8-months-old C57/BL6 mice were pretreated with either delphinidin 50 mg/kg or vehicle, 10% DMSO/90% PBS for 1&#160;week three times a week. Mouse melanoma B16-F10 luciferase expressing cells (5&#8201;&#215;&#8201;10<sup>5</sup>) were inoculated on the ears of the mice between the skin and the cartilage.This spontaneous metastasis model using ear inoculation of B16-F10 better mimics metastasis than the more commonly used tail vein metastasis model<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR28">28</xref>,<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR29">29</xref></sup>. A total of 12 of the delphinidin treated mice and 5 vehicle treated mice received successful injection as determined by observation of bioluminescent signal on the ear when imaging with the IVIS imager the day following the injections. In vivo imaging was performed weekly to monitor primary tumor growth and detection of metastases and delphinidin treatment was continued at three times a week for the duration of the study (Fig. <xref rid="Fig6" ref-type="fig">6</xref>A). Primary tumor growth was delayed in the delphinidin treated cohort, but the difference did not reach statistical significance (Fig. <xref rid="Fig6" ref-type="fig">6</xref>B,C). Detection of metastases to the sentinel lymph node was observed by week 3 in 80% of the vehicle treated mice and 25% of the delphinidin treated mice (Fig. <xref rid="Fig6" ref-type="fig">6</xref>B,D). These results indicate that delphinidin strongly inhibits metastatic growth. There was no evidence of any adverse events or side effects associated with systemic delphinidin administration compared to vehicle. There was no significant change in weight of the mice over the course of the experiment (Supplemental Fig. <xref rid="MOESM1" ref-type="media">4</xref>).<fig id="Fig6" position="float" orientation="portrait"><label>Figure 6</label><caption><p>B16-F10 Spontaneous Metastasis model: (<bold>A</bold>) Model design adapted from &#8220;Mouse Experimental Timeline&#8221;, by BioRender.com (2023). 50&#160;mg/kg of delphinidin administered by IP 3X a week starting one week before tumor cell (B16-F10) inoculation on the ear and continuing until tumor sizes reached endpoint (2 mm<sup>2</sup>). (<bold>B</bold>) Representative IVIS images of bioluminescence detection of primary tumor and metastases. (<bold>C</bold>) Primary tumor growth was not significant between delphinidin treated and vehicle mice. Statistical analysis was generated by unpaired t-test error bars are represented as mean with SEM. (<bold>D</bold>) At week three (Day 16) 80% (n&#8201;=&#8201;4/5) of vehicle treated mice had detectable metastases while only 25% (n&#8201;=&#8201;3/12) of delphinidin treated mice had detectable metastases.</p></caption><graphic xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" id="MO6" position="float" orientation="portrait" xlink:href="41598_2024_64924_Fig6_HTML.jpg"/></fig></p></sec></sec><sec id="Sec8"><title>Discussion</title><p id="Par12">While new cancer treatment options have increased survival rates over the past five decades, most cancer deaths are a result of metastatic disease. The metastatic cascade is a complex multistep process that begins with cancer cells invading local stroma and entering the lymphatic or circulatory system. If the initial steps of the metastatic cascade involving cancer cell migration and invasion can be halted, the lives of cancer patients can be extended.</p><p id="Par13">Transgenic overexpression of naked mole-rat HAS2 in mice reduced cancer incidence providing a proof of principle that HMW-HA inhibits cancer in vivo. However, the increase in HMW-HA levels achieved in nmrHAS2 expressing mice was modest due to very active hyaluronidase activity in mouse tissues<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR15">15</xref></sup>. As no potent small molecule inhibitors of HAases were available, we performed a chemical screen. One of the challenges in setting up the high- throughput screening assay was that the reactant (HMW-HA) and the product (LMW-HA) are both the same chemical compound: the difference is just its <italic toggle="yes">lengths</italic>. In other words, no chemicals were formed or consumed by the hyaluronidases reaction, and the same amount of &#8220;HA&#8221; continue to exist before and after the hyaluronidase reaction. We thus could not use conventional methods such as fluorescent intensity to detect the changes that hyaluronidases make. We applied the concept of FP measurement to detect the difference between the sizes of HA, if HA is fluorescently labeled: When HA is HMW-HA, it does not tumble rapidly because of its large size, thus it should give large FP values, whereas LMW-HA should tumble more rapidly and give smaller FP values. Indeed, this FP-based assay allowed us to identify several potential hyaluronidase inhibitors, and the subsequent studies in medicinal chemistry yielded delphinidin as a small molecule inhibitor for hyaluronidases.</p><p id="Par14">We have shown that delphinidin administered systemically to mice increases hyaluronic acid levels in multiple tissues and may increase levels of tumor protective HMW-HA while preventing the production of tumor supportive LMW-HA in the tumor microenvironment. Delphinidin inhibited proliferation, migration and invasion in melanoma, breast and prostate cancer cells but when delphinidin was administered in combination with exogenous hyaluronidase both proliferation and invasion of cancer cell lines were partially restored. While delphinidin treatment did not significantly impact primary tumor growth of B16-F10 melanoma it did inhibit the percentage of mice that developed spontaneous lymph node metastasis. The ability of delphinidin inhibiting metastasis in vivo needs to be confirmed pre-clinically using both spontaneous and experimental metastasis models.</p><p id="Par15">HMW-HA protects the naked mole-rat from cancer and naked mole-rat hyaluronan synthase 2 reduces cancer incidence in transgenic mice<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR13">13</xref>,<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR33">33</xref></sup>. However, elevated levels of HA are found in many cancer types including, lung, breast, prostate and ovary<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR34">34</xref>&#8211;<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR36">36</xref></sup>. These elevated HA levels are implicated in causing metastasis and poor prognosis for patients with cancer. This can be explained by concurrent increased hyaluronidase expression in the tumor microenvironment that converts HMW-HA to LMW-HA, giving rise to conflicting data on whether HA is tumor promotive or tumor protective. LMW-HA promotes tumor progression and metastasis while HMW-HA can protect against tumor progression and metastasis<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR20">20</xref></sup>. Elevated levels of hyaluronidase present in the serum of metastatic breast cancer patients compared to patients without metastatic disease may play a role in disease progression<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR36">36</xref>,<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR37">37</xref></sup>.HA can suppress prostate tumor growth when hyaluronidase is ablated but when HA and hyaluronidase are expressed simultaneously, the result is increased prostate cancer progression and metastasis<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR8">8</xref>,<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR37">37</xref>,<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR38">38</xref></sup>. Thus, the increased amounts of HA that has been associated with tumor progression and metastasis may be due to concurrent elevated levels of the enzyme hyaluronidase degrading HMW-HA to LWM-HA. It should be noted that delphinidin was able to induce apoptosis of the human prostate cancer cell line PC3<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR39">39</xref></sup>. We tested the ability of delphinidin to induce apoptosis of the mouse cell lines used in our experiments and we did not observe apoptosis using annexin 5 staining in any of the cell lines (Supplemental Fig. <xref rid="MOESM1" ref-type="media">5</xref>). This could be due to different mechanisms of action of delphinidin in human and mouse prostate cancer cells or it could be the concentration of delphinidin (120 and 180 &#181;M) used to induce activation of NF kappa B and apoptosis in the PC3 cell line was much higher than the 30 &#181;M concentration we used in our experiment.</p><p id="Par16">Interestingly, it was previously shown that tea leaf extract that contains delphinidin can inhibit hyaluronidase<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR38">38</xref>,<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR40">40</xref></sup>. As a natural compound delphinidin was reported to have several biological activities many of which may have antitumorigenic potential. Delphinidin was reported to have anti-inflammatory and antioxidant properties<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR40">40</xref>&#8211;<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR42">42</xref></sup>. Delphinidin also suppresses VEGF and VEGFR-2, showing anti-angiogenic potential<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR42">42</xref>&#8211;<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR44">44</xref></sup>. Delphinidin inhibited metastatic activity of human colorectal cancer cells by inhibiting integrin/FAK cascade<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR39">39</xref>,<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR44">44</xref></sup>, which is consistent with changes in the interaction with extracellular matrix and HA. Delphinidin induces programed cell death, apoptosis, and cell cycle arrest of human prostate cancer cells in vitro and in vivo<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR39">39</xref>,<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR45">45</xref></sup>. Delphinidin is also effective in causing apoptosis of human osteosarcoma cells<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR45">45</xref>,<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR46">46</xref></sup>. Thus, delphinidin was shown to inhibit metastasis of several cancer types in vitro and melanoma (this study) and prostate cancer in vivo<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR39">39</xref></sup>, in mouse models. Additional mouse models and human tumor xenografts may be useful to define which cancers are most responsive to delphinidin.</p><p id="Par17">While IP administration of delphinidin was well tolerated and effective in increasing HA levels in multiple tissues, it would be useful to show similar effects with oral administration of delphinidin. It was proposed that encapsulation of delphinidin in small extracellular vesicles could improve bioavailability and enhance its effects<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR18">18</xref></sup>. Another option is Delphinol, an extract from the maqui berry and contains 35% anthocyanins of which 25% is delphinidin. This nutraceutical could be used as an alternative to pure delphinidin for testing in pre-clinical models. Delphinol was used in a clinical trial for patients with glucose intolerance and was shown to lower blood glucose; importantly it had zero adverse effects<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR27">27</xref></sup>. Another clinical trial using Delphinol revealed that its antioxidant properties may reduce oxidized low-density lipoprotein<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR45">45</xref></sup>. In conclusion, pre-clinical mouse models demonstrating inhibition of metastasis by delphinidin together with good safety profile and potentially bioavailable oral administration of delphinidin make it a prime candidate for clinical trials for patients with cancer.</p></sec><sec id="Sec9"><title>Material and methods</title><sec id="Sec10"><title>Cell culture</title><p id="Par18">RM-1 (CRL-3310), E0771 (CRL-3461), B16-F10 Luc2 (CRL-6475-LUC2) were purchased from ATCC. B16-F10 is a sub clone of the murine melanoma cell line from a C57BL/6J mouse. It was generated by injecting mice with B16 tumor cells, collecting and culturing secondary tumor growths, and injecting them into fresh mice, a total of 10 times<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR47">47</xref></sup>. The RM1 cell line was generated he tumor from urogenital sinus Zipras/myc9 retrovirus-injected cells of C57BL/6 embryos<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR48">48</xref></sup>. The EO771 cell line was originally isolated from a spontaneous tumor in C57BL/6 mouse<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR49">49</xref></sup>. Primary C57BL6 skin fibroblasts were isolated as described previously<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR50">50</xref></sup>. All cell lines were cryopreserved within the first five passages and were used within the first 10 passages after thawing. Human fibroblasts are HCA2 originally isolated by Olivia Pereira-Smith, Baylor College of Medicine. All cell lines were cultured at 37 &#176;C, 5% CO<sub>2,</sub>, 3% O<sub>2</sub> on treated polystyrene culture dishes (Corning). Cancer cell lines were cultured in DMEM, high glucose, GlutaMAX (Gibco Cat # 10566016) supplemented with 10% Fetal Bovine Serum (FBS) (Gibco Cat #10437028) and 1% Penicillin-Streptomycin (Pen Strep) (Gibco Cat #15070063) Gibco. Mouse fibroblasts were culture in Eagle&#8217;s Minimum Essential Medium (EMEM) (ATCC Cat# 30-2003) supplemented with 15% FBS and 1% Pen Strep. Cell cultures were periodically tested for mycoplasma contamination with MycoAlert Mycoplasma Detection Kit (Lonza).</p></sec><sec id="Sec11"><title>Animals</title><p id="Par19">Wild type C57BL/6 mice were purchased from Charles River. All animal experiments were approved and performed in accordance with ARRIVE guidelines as well as guidelines set up by the University of Rochester Committee on Animal Resources (UCAR), which adheres to FDA and NIH animal care guidelines and reviews all animal protocols prior to approval (UCAR 2017-033). Animals were housed using microisolator technology in SPF conditions in a one-way facility.</p></sec><sec id="Sec12"><title>High-throughput screening for Hyaluronidase inhibitor</title><p id="Par20">Fluorescence polarization was utilized to screen hyaluronidase inhibitors. Hyaluronidase (Sigma H4272) and each compound of libraries were incubated in phosphate buffer (300&#160;mM, pH 5.35) in black walled black bottom 384 well plates. Fluorescein-labeled HA<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR51">51</xref></sup> was then added to each well, and the plates were incubated in the dark, humid containers to prevent drying. After 1&#160;h, fluorescent polarization was measured (TECAN Spark 20M). Compound libraries were obtained from the National Cancer Institute (Approved Oncology Drugs Set, Diversity Set, Natural Products Set and Mechanistic Set).</p></sec><sec id="Sec13"><title>HA analysis by gel electrophoresis</title><p id="Par21">HA was purified from conditioned media collected from mouse and human fibroblasts after 24&#160;h incubation with a dose range of delphinidin. Ten ml of conditioned media was treated with 1 ml Proteinase K (Promega Cat # V3021) in buffer (10 mM Tris-Cl pH8.0, .25 mM EDTA, 100&#160;mM NaCl, 0.5% SDS 1&#160;mg/ml proteinase K) (Roche Cat #03508838103) at 55 &#176;C for 4&#160;h to remove proteins. Samples then were mixed by inverting the tubes 60 times after adding 11&#160;ml of phenol:chloroform:Isoamyl Alchol (25:24:1) (ThermoFisher Cat# 15593049). Samples were centrifuged with swing rotor at 3500 rpm for 10&#160;min. The supernatant was transferred to a&#160;new tube and 25 ml of 100% ethyl alcohol (EtOH) was added and mixed by inversion. Samples were centrifuged with swing rotor at 4000 rpm for 1&#160;h. Supernatant was discarded and 20 ml of 70% EtOH was added and centrifuged for 10&#160;min at 4000 rpm. Supernatant was again removed and pellet was allowed to dry for 15&#160;min at room temperature. The pellet was dissolved in 2&#160;ml PBS and incubated overnight at 4&#160;&#176;C. The following day 20 &#181;l of Triton X- 114 was added to samples and they were vortexed for 5&#160;min cooling on ice every 30&#160;s. Samples were then incubated at 37&#160;&#176;C for 5&#160;min before centrifuging at 12,000&#160;g for 10&#160;min. Supernatant was collected and 5&#160;mls of 1&#160;M NaCl in 100% EtOH was added and centrifuged at 10,000&#160;g for 15&#160;min. Supernatant was then discarded and 5 ml of 70% EtOH was added to pellet and centrifuged at 10,000 g for 15&#160;min. Supernatant was then discarded and pellets were dried for 10&#160;min at room temperature before dissolving overnight at 4&#160;&#176;C&#160; in 600&#160;ul PBS. 20 ul of each sample was transferred to 2 new tubes and either treated with 1 U/ml of hyaluronidase from <italic toggle="yes">Streptomyces hyalurolyticus</italic> (Sigma-Aldrich Cat # H1136) or no treatment and then incubated overnight at 37&#160;&#176;C. This protocol was previously published<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR52">52</xref></sup>. For gel electrophoresis, a 0.8% Seakem Gold Agarose (Lonza Cat#50150) gel/TBE was kept at 55&#160;&#176;C for 15&#160;min before pouring into gel tray. After 2&#160;h, the gel was pre-run in TBE buffer at 35&#160;V for 2&#160;h. 10&#160;ul of each sample were then diluted in 6X loading buffer. Ladders and samples were then loaded and run at 23&#160;V for 30&#160;min and then 35&#160;V for 3&#160;h or until yellow dye runs out of gel. Gel was then stained overnight in the dark at room temperature in 0.005% Stains-All (Sigma Cat# E9379) prepared in 50% EtOH. The following day the gel was washed twice in 10% EtOH for 10&#160;min and then washed a third time for 4&#160;h or overnight. The gel was then imaged using digital photography. The gel was scanned using Bio Rad Gel Imager and quantitative analysis of HA was assessed using GelQuant.Net (<ext-link xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" ext-link-type="uri" xlink:href="http://biochemlabsolutions.com/GelQuantNET.html">http://biochemlabsolutions.com/GelQuantNET.html</ext-link>). The original gel image is no longer available as the bio rad gel imager had to be replaced and the stored images were lost. Only the top of the gel showing the wells was cropped out of the image used in Fig. <xref rid="Fig1" ref-type="fig">1</xref>. Full gel images from Supplemental Fig. <xref rid="MOESM1" ref-type="media">1</xref> are included in the supplemental data.</p></sec><sec id="Sec14"><title>In vivo delphinidin treatment</title><p id="Par22">Three to 6-month-old female C57Bl/6 (n&#8201;=&#8201;10) mice were treated with either 50 mg/kg (n&#8201;=&#8201;4) or 100 mg/kg (n&#8201;=&#8201;3) of delphinidin chloride (Cayman Cat# 11012). The delphinidin was dissolved in 10% Dimethyl sulfoxide (DMSO) and 90% sterile PBS that was used as a vehicle control (n&#8201;=&#8201;3). Intraperitoneal (IP) injections of either delphinidin or vehicle control (200 &#181;l) were administered three times a week (n&#8201;=&#8201;3 Vehicle, n&#8201;=&#8201;4 50&#160;mg/kg, and n&#8201;=&#8201;3 100 mg/kg) for 3&#160;weeks before the mice were sacrificed by CO2 euthanasia followed by secondary cervical dislocation. The following tissues, lung, kidney, spleen, heart, skin, muscle, duodenum, jejunum and colon were collected fixed in 10% formalin for 48&#160;h before being embedded in paraffin.</p></sec><sec id="Sec15"><title>Ear transplantation of B16F10 in vivo</title><p id="Par23">B16-F10 Luciferase expressing cells were suspended in PBS at 10&#8201;&#215;&#8201;10<sup>6</sup>/ml and 50 &#181;l of suspension were injected between the skin and cartilage on the dorsal side of the ear for a total of 5&#8201;&#215;&#8201;10<sup>5</sup> cells injected per mouse. C57/BL6 mice at approximately 8&#160;months of age were used. Male (n&#8201;=&#8201;20) and female (n&#8201;=&#8201;20) mice (C57/BL6, n&#8201;=&#8201;40) were anesthetized by isoflurane during transplantation. The tumor take was 60% and 25% for the delphinidin and vehicle groups respectively. One week prior to tumor cell inoculation one cohort of mice were treated with delphinidin 50 mg/kg diluted in 10% DMSO and 90% PBS by IP injection (200 &#181;l) three times a week. Treatment was continued 3 times a week for the duration of the experiment the other cohort of mice were injected with the vehicle for the delphinidin (200&#160;ul 90% PBS 10% DMSO). Outcome was defined as time to detectable metastasis. Endpoint was when primary tumor sizes reached (2 mm<sup>2</sup>) at which point mice were sacrificed by CO<sub>2</sub> euthanasia followed by secondary cervical dislocation. Due to the study design for treating and imaging the mice randomization and blinding was not possible and no confounders were controlled for. Bioluminescence was measured once weekly as a correlate of tumor growth and detection of metastases (IVIS, Perkin Elmer, Waltham, Massachusetts).</p></sec><sec id="Sec16"><title>HABP staining</title><p id="Par24">Slides with 2 sequential 5&#160;&#181;m paraffin sections (n&#8201;=&#8201;3 for each animal) washed two times with xylenes 10&#160;min each then rehydrated in ethanol 2&#160;min each (100%, 100%, 90%, 70% 50%). Rinsed in 1X PBS 3 times, 5&#160;min each. Tissue sections circled with PAP pen and incubated for an hour at room temperature in (100&#8211;200&#160;&#181;l) blocking solution (10% normal goat serum (NGS) (Fisher Cat# 50062Z) in 1X PBS). The blocking solution was discarded, and slides were incubated in biotinylated hyaluronic acid binding protein (HABP) (Amsbio Cat# AMS.HKD-BC41) at a 1:200 dilution in 10% NGS overnight at 4 C with gentle rocking in a humidified chamber. Negative controls consisted of two sections from each group that were incubated for 2&#160;h at 37 C with 1 mg/ml hyaluronidase (Sigma Cat# H3884) in 20 mM sodium phosphate buffer, with 77 mM sodium chloride, 0.01% BSA, pH 7.0 before HABP treatment. The following day slides were washed three times in 1X PBST (0.01% Tween 20) 10&#160;min each wash followed by 2 rinses in 1X PBS. Sections were incubated with streptavidin alexa fluor 488 (Invitrogen Cat # S32354) 1:1000 dilution in 10% NGS in the dark at room temperature for 1&#160;h. Slides were washed 3X in PBST 10&#160;min each and rinse 2X in 1X PBS 1&#160;min each. Cover slips were mounted with Vectashield plus antifade mounting medium with DAPI (Vector laboratories Cat#H2000). Slides were imaged with fluorescence microscopy (20X), three representative images were analyzed from each tissue section (2 tissue sections from each sample) using Imaris software version 9.8 Oxford Instruments (<ext-link xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" ext-link-type="uri" xlink:href="https://imaris.oxinst.com/">https://imaris.oxinst.com/</ext-link>) to determine maximum fluorescent intensity. Background fluorescence from negative control, hyaluronidase treatment, was subtracted from all samples.</p></sec><sec id="Sec17"><title>Proliferation assays</title><p id="Par25">Cells were seeded in triplicate at 2&#8201;&#215;&#8201;10<sup>4</sup>&#8211;5&#8201;&#215;&#8201;10<sup>4</sup> depending on the cell type in white walled white bottom 96 well plates and incubated overnight. On the following day cells were treated with 5 &#181;M delphinidin (stock 30 mg/ml) diluted in media before adding to cells. Hyaluronidase (Sigma Cat # H1136) was added with delphinidin in media before adding to cells. Plates were analyzed at 24 and 48&#160;h post delphinidin treatment with Cell Titer-Glo 2.0 cell viability assay. (Promega Cat#G9241). 100 &#181;l of cell titer-glo was added to each well and incubated shaking in the dark at room temperature for 10&#160;min before reading luminescence using a plate reader.</p></sec><sec id="Sec18"><title>Wound healing assay</title><p id="Par26">Three well silicone inserts (Ibidi Cat#80369) were placed with sterile forceps into individual wells of a 24 well plate and seeded with 70 &#181;l of cell suspension 5&#8201;&#215;&#8201;10<sup>5</sup> cells/ml. After 24&#8211;48&#160;h when the cells reached confluency the inserts are removed with sterile forceps and the wells were filled with 1 ml of cell culture media either with or without delphinidin. Cells are then immediately imaged and then imaged again at 8&#8211;20&#160;h depending on the cell type. Using image j the area of the gap is measured at time 0 and at 8&#8211;20&#160;h.</p></sec><sec id="Sec19"><title>Migration and invasion assays</title><p id="Par27">Cells were seeded and allowed to grow to 80% confluence then serum starved overnight. On the next day the cells were seeded (2&#8201;&#215;&#8201;10<sup>5</sup> cells) into upper chambers of 8 &#181;M 24-well transwell membrane assay system (Corning Cat#3428). Lower chambers were prepared either 650&#160;&#181;l serum free (&#8722;control), 1% serum (+control) or 1% serum with delphinidin or 1% serum with delphinidin and hyaluronidase. All conditions were performed in triplicate and incubated for 5&#160;h at 37&#160;&#176;C for migration assays. For invasion assays the upper chamber membranes were coated with Matrigel Basement Membrane Matrix (Corning Cat#354234). The Matrigel was thawed on ice, diluted with serum free media to a concentration of 200 &#181;g/ml, mixed by pipetting and 100 &#181;l added to each upper well and then incubated for at least 1&#160;h at 37&#160;&#176;C to let the gel form. The cells were then seeded in the Matrigel treated wells. After incubation, upper chambers were rinsed in DI water followed by 1&#8201;&#215;&#8201;PBS. Upper chambers then fixed in pure ice-cold methanol at &#8722;&#8201;20&#8201;&#176;C for 20&#160;min. The chambers were rinsed in DI water followed by 1&#8201;&#215;&#8201;PBS, and non-migrated cells removed from the inner membrane by gentle scrubbing 3X with cotton tip applicators. After scrubbing membranes are rinsed again in DI water before being stained with hematoxylin for 5&#160;min and incubated in 1X PBS to blue then cells. Upper chambers are then rinsed 3X in DI H20 before dehydrating in 100% ethanol for 3&#160;min. The chambers were allowed to air dry for 10&#160;min before using a scalpel to cut out the membrane. Membranes were fixed to microscope slides bottom up with permount (Fisher Cat# sp15100). Three fields of view from each membrane were acquired using brightfield microscopy (10X) and the number of migrated cells per field counted using image j.</p></sec><sec id="Sec20"><title>Statistical analysis</title><p id="Par28">T-tests or analysis of variance (ANOVA) and post hoc Tukey&#8217;s multiple comparison tests were used to calculate statistical significance (&#8804;&#8201;0.05) among groups. Samples sizes of n&#8201;&#8805;&#8201;3 was used for all statistical calculations. Error bars are shown as standard error from the mean (SEM). These statistical analyses were calculated with the Graph Pad Prisim 10.0, GraphPad Software, Boston, Massachusetts USA, (<ext-link xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" ext-link-type="uri" xlink:href="http://www.graphpad.com">www.graphpad.com</ext-link>).</p></sec></sec><sec sec-type="supplementary-material"><sec id="Sec21"><title>Supplementary Information</title><p>
<supplementary-material content-type="local-data" id="MOESM1" position="float" orientation="portrait"><media xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xlink:href="41598_2024_64924_MOESM1_ESM.pdf" position="float" orientation="portrait"><caption><p>Supplementary Figures.</p></caption></media></supplementary-material></p></sec></sec></body><back><fn-group><fn><p><bold>Publisher's note</bold></p><p>Springer Nature remains neutral with regard to jurisdictional claims in published maps and institutional affiliations.</p></fn></fn-group><sec><title>Supplementary Information</title><p>The online version contains supplementary material available at 10.1038/s41598-024-64924-6.</p></sec><ack><title>Acknowledgements</title><p>This work was supported by grants from US National Institutes on Aging to VG and AS and a Grant from VitaDao to V.G.</p></ack><notes notes-type="author-contribution"><title>Author contributions</title><p>V.G., A.S., T.T. and J.M. were responsible for the study conception as well as the design and development of methodology. J.M., T.T. and V.P. acquired data. V.G, A.S., T.T., G.T. and J.M. were responsible for analysis and interpretation of data. V.G., A.S., G.T., N.G., M.J., T.T. and J.M. were responsible for manuscript writing and editing.</p></notes><notes notes-type="data-availability"><title>Data availability</title><p>All the data generated or analyzed during this study is available from the corresponding author on reasonable request.</p></notes><notes id="FPar1" notes-type="COI-statement"><title>Competing interests</title><p id="Par29">VG is a co-founder of MatrixBio, leveraging the anti-cancer and pro-longevity effects of high molecular weight hyaluronic acid from naked mole rat to human. All other authors do not have any competing interest.</p></notes><ref-list id="Bib1"><title>References</title><ref id="CR1"><label>1.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Guan</surname><given-names>X</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>Cancer metastases: Challenges and opportunities</article-title><source>Acta Pharm. Sin. B</source><year>2015</year><volume>5</volume><fpage>402</fpage><lpage>418</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1016/j.apsb.2015.07.005</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">26579471</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC4629446</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR2"><label>2.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Chaffer</surname><given-names>CL</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Weinberg</surname><given-names>RA</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>A perspective on cancer cell metastasis</article-title><source>Science</source><year>2011</year><volume>331</volume><fpage>1559</fpage><lpage>1564</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1126/science.1203543</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">21436443</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR3"><label>3.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Kratzer</surname><given-names>TB</given-names></name><etal/></person-group><article-title>Progress against cancer mortality 50 years after passage of the national cancer act</article-title><source>JAMA Oncol.</source><year>2022</year><volume>8</volume><fpage>156</fpage><lpage>159</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1001/jamaoncol.2021.5668</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">34762103</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC8587226</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR4"><label>4.</label><mixed-citation publication-type="other">Welch, D. Defining a cancer metastasis. In <italic toggle="yes">AACR Education Book 2006</italic> 111&#8211;115 (2006).</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="CR5"><label>5.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Welch</surname><given-names>DR</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Hurst</surname><given-names>DR</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>Defining the hallmarks of metastasis</article-title><source>Cancer Res.</source><year>2019</year><volume>79</volume><fpage>3011</fpage><lpage>3027</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1158/0008-5472.Can-19-0458</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">31053634</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC6571042</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR6"><label>6.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Quail</surname><given-names>DF</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Joyce</surname><given-names>JA</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>Microenvironmental regulation of tumor progression and metastasis</article-title><source>Nat. Med.</source><year>2013</year><volume>19</volume><fpage>1423</fpage><lpage>1437</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1038/nm.3394</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">24202395</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC3954707</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR7"><label>7.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Fallacara</surname><given-names>A</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Baldini</surname><given-names>E</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Manfredini</surname><given-names>S</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Vertuani</surname><given-names>S</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>Hyaluronic acid in the third millennium</article-title><source>Polymers</source><year>2018</year><volume>10</volume><fpage>701</fpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.3390/polym10070701</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">30960626</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC6403654</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR8"><label>8.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Lokeshwar</surname><given-names>VB</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Lokeshwar</surname><given-names>BL</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Pham</surname><given-names>HT</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Block</surname><given-names>NL</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>Association of elevated levels of hyaluronidase, a matrix-degrading enzyme, with prostate cancer progression</article-title><source>Cancer Res.</source><year>1996</year><volume>56</volume><fpage>651</fpage><lpage>657</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">8564986</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR9"><label>9.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Matsui</surname><given-names>Y</given-names></name><etal/></person-group><article-title>Hyaluronic acid stimulates tumor-cell proliferation at wound sites</article-title><source>Gastrointest. Endosc.</source><year>2004</year><volume>60</volume><fpage>539</fpage><lpage>543</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1016/s0016-5107(04)01890-5</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">15472675</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR10"><label>10.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Kim</surname><given-names>PK</given-names></name><etal/></person-group><article-title>Hyaluronic acid fuels pancreatic cancer cell growth</article-title><source>eLife</source><year>2021</year><volume>10</volume><fpage>e62645</fpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.7554/eLife.62645</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">34951587</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC8730721</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR11"><label>11.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Wu</surname><given-names>W</given-names></name><etal/></person-group><article-title>Hyaluronic acid predicts poor prognosis in breast cancer patients: A protocol for systematic review and meta analysis</article-title><source>Medicine</source><year>2020</year><volume>99</volume><fpage>e20438</fpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1097/md.0000000000020438</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">32481447</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC12245377</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR12"><label>12.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Pirinen</surname><given-names>R</given-names></name><etal/></person-group><article-title>Prognostic value of hyaluronan expression in non-small-cell lung cancer: Increased stromal expression indicates unfavorable outcome in patients with adenocarcinoma</article-title><source>Int. J. Cancer</source><year>2001</year><volume>95</volume><fpage>12</fpage><lpage>17</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1002/1097-0215(20010120)95:1&amp;#x0003c;12::aid-ijc1002&amp;#x0003e;3.0.co;2-e</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">11241304</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR13"><label>13.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Tian</surname><given-names>X</given-names></name><etal/></person-group><article-title>High-molecular-mass hyaluronan mediates the cancer resistance of the naked mole rat</article-title><source>Nature</source><year>2013</year><volume>499</volume><fpage>346</fpage><lpage>349</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1038/nature12234</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">23783513</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC3720720</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR14"><label>14.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Ooki</surname><given-names>T</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Murata-Kamiya</surname><given-names>N</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Takahashi-Kanemitsu</surname><given-names>A</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Weida</surname><given-names>W</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Hatakeyama</surname><given-names>M</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>High-molecular-weight hyaluronan is a hippo pathway ligand directing cell density-dependent growth inhibition via PAR1b</article-title><source>Dev. Cell</source><year>2019</year><volume>49</volume><issue>4</issue><fpage>590</fpage><lpage>604</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1016/j.devcel.2019.04.018</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">31080060</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR15"><label>15.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Zhang</surname><given-names>Z</given-names></name><etal/></person-group><article-title>Increased hyaluronan by naked mole-rat Has2 improves healthspan in mice</article-title><source>Nature</source><year>2023</year><volume>621</volume><fpage>196</fpage><lpage>205</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1038/s41586-023-06463-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">37612507</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC10666664</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR16"><label>16.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Liu</surname><given-names>M</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Tolg</surname><given-names>C</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Turley</surname><given-names>E</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>Dissecting the dual nature of hyaluronan in the tumor microenvironment</article-title><source>Front. Immunol.</source><year>2019</year><volume>10</volume><fpage>947</fpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.3389/fimmu.2019.00947</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">31134064</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC6522846</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR17"><label>17.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Takasugi</surname><given-names>M</given-names></name><etal/></person-group><article-title>Naked mole-rat very-high-molecular-mass hyaluronan exhibits superior cytoprotective properties</article-title><source>Nat. Commun.</source><year>2020</year><volume>11</volume><fpage>2376</fpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1038/s41467-020-16050-w</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">32398747</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC7217962</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR18"><label>18.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Barkallah</surname><given-names>M</given-names></name><etal/></person-group><article-title>Enhancement of the anti-angiogenic effects of delphinidin when encapsulated within small extracellular vesicles</article-title><source>Nutrients</source><year>2021</year><volume>13</volume><issue>12</issue><fpage>4378</fpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.3390/nu13124378</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">34959929</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC8703615</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR19"><label>19.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Campo</surname><given-names>GM</given-names></name><etal/></person-group><article-title>Molecular size hyaluronan differently modulates toll-like receptor-4 in LPS-induced inflammation in mouse chondrocytes</article-title><source>Biochimie</source><year>2010</year><volume>92</volume><fpage>204</fpage><lpage>215</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1016/j.biochi.2009.10.006</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">19879319</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR20"><label>20.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Tavianatou</surname><given-names>AG</given-names></name><etal/></person-group><article-title>Hyaluronan: Molecular size-dependent signaling and biological functions in inflammation and cancer</article-title><source>FEBS J.</source><year>2019</year><volume>286</volume><fpage>2883</fpage><lpage>2908</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1111/febs.14777</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">30724463</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR21"><label>21.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Csoka</surname><given-names>AB</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Scherer</surname><given-names>SW</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Stern</surname><given-names>R</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>Expression analysis of six paralogous human hyaluronidase genes clustered on chromosomes 3p21 and 7q31</article-title><source>Genomics</source><year>1999</year><volume>60</volume><fpage>356</fpage><lpage>361</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1006/geno.1999.5876</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">10493834</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR22"><label>22.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Stern</surname><given-names>R</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Kogan</surname><given-names>G</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Jedrzejas</surname><given-names>MJ</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Solt&#233;s</surname><given-names>L</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>The many ways to cleave hyaluronan</article-title><source>Biotechnol. Adv.</source><year>2007</year><volume>25</volume><fpage>537</fpage><lpage>557</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1016/j.biotechadv.2007.07.001</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">17716848</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR23"><label>23.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Yamamoto</surname><given-names>H</given-names></name><etal/></person-group><article-title>A mammalian homolog of the zebrafish transmembrane protein 2 (TMEM2) is the long-sought-after cell-surface hyaluronidase</article-title><source>J. Biol. Chem.</source><year>2017</year><volume>292</volume><fpage>7304</fpage><lpage>7313</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1074/jbc.M116.770149</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">28246172</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC5418033</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR24"><label>24.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Ichiyanagi</surname><given-names>T</given-names></name><etal/></person-group><article-title>Nasunin from eggplant consists of cis-trans isomers of delphinidin 3-[4-(p-coumaroyl)-L-rhamnosyl (1&#8211;&gt;6)glucopyranoside]-5-glucopyranoside</article-title><source>J. Agric. Food Chem.</source><year>2005</year><volume>53</volume><fpage>9472</fpage><lpage>9477</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1021/jf051841y</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">16302764</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR25"><label>25.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Mojica</surname><given-names>L</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Berhow</surname><given-names>M</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Gonzalez de Mejia</surname><given-names>E</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>Black bean anthocyanin-rich extracts as food colorants: Physicochemical stability and antidiabetes potential</article-title><source>Food Chem.</source><year>2017</year><volume>229</volume><fpage>628</fpage><lpage>639</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1016/j.foodchem.2017.02.124</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">28372224</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR26"><label>26.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Thomas</surname><given-names>CR</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Evans</surname><given-names>JL</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Lowy</surname><given-names>C</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>The effect of alloxan induced diabetes in the rabbit on placental transfer of glucose and non-esterified fatty acids</article-title><source>Diabetes Res.</source><year>1989</year><volume>11</volume><fpage>55</fpage><lpage>60</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">2620485</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR27"><label>27.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Alvarado</surname><given-names>J</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Schoenlau</surname><given-names>F</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Leschot</surname><given-names>A</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Salgad</surname><given-names>AM</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Vigil Portales</surname><given-names>P</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>Delphinol(R) standardized maqui berry extract significantly lowers blood glucose and improves blood lipid profile in prediabetic individuals in three-month clinical trial</article-title><source>Panminerva Med.</source><year>2016</year><volume>58</volume><fpage>1</fpage><lpage>6</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">27820958</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR28"><label>28.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Yu</surname><given-names>M</given-names></name><etal/></person-group><article-title>Hyaluroan-regulated lymphatic permeability through S1P receptors is crucial for cancer metastasis</article-title><source>Med. Oncol.</source><year>2015</year><volume>32</volume><fpage>381</fpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1007/s12032-014-0381-1</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">25428387</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR29"><label>29.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Cuff</surname><given-names>CA</given-names></name><etal/></person-group><article-title>The adhesion receptor CD44 promotes atherosclerosis by mediating inflammatory cell recruitment and vascular cell activation</article-title><source>J. Clin. Invest.</source><year>2001</year><volume>108</volume><fpage>1031</fpage><lpage>1040</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1172/JCI12455</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">11581304</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC200948</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR30"><label>30.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Stern</surname><given-names>R</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Asari</surname><given-names>AA</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Sugahara</surname><given-names>KN</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>Hyaluronan fragments: An information-rich system</article-title><source>Eur. J. Cell Biol.</source><year>2006</year><volume>85</volume><fpage>699</fpage><lpage>715</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1016/j.ejcb.2006.05.009</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">16822580</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR31"><label>31.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Sugahara</surname><given-names>KN</given-names></name><etal/></person-group><article-title>Tumor cells enhance their own CD44 cleavage and motility by generating hyaluronan fragments</article-title><source>J. Biol. Chem.</source><year>2006</year><volume>281</volume><fpage>5861</fpage><lpage>5868</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1074/jbc.M506740200</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">16407205</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR32"><label>32.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Sugahara</surname><given-names>KN</given-names></name><etal/></person-group><article-title>Hyaluronan oligosaccharides induce CD44 cleavage and promote cell migration in CD44-expressing tumor cells</article-title><source>J. Biol. Chem.</source><year>2003</year><volume>278</volume><fpage>32259</fpage><lpage>32265</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1074/jbc.M300347200</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">12801931</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR33"><label>33.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Karousou</surname><given-names>E</given-names></name><etal/></person-group><article-title>Collagen VI and hyaluronan: the common role in breast cancer</article-title><source>BioMed Res. Int.</source><year>2014</year><volume>2014</volume><fpage>1</fpage><lpage>10</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1155/2014/606458</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC4121998</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">25126569</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR34"><label>34.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Rilla</surname><given-names>K</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Siiskonen</surname><given-names>H</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Tammi</surname><given-names>M</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Tammi</surname><given-names>R</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>Hyaluronan-coated extracellular vesicles&#8211;a novel link between hyaluronan and cancer</article-title><source>Adv. Cancer Res.</source><year>2014</year><volume>123</volume><fpage>121</fpage><lpage>148</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1016/b978-0-12-800092-2.00005-8</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">25081528</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR35"><label>35.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Theocharis</surname><given-names>AD</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Karamanos</surname><given-names>NK</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>Proteoglycans remodeling in cancer: Underlying molecular mechanisms</article-title><source>Matrix Biol.</source><year>2019</year><volume>75&#8211;76</volume><fpage>220</fpage><lpage>259</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1016/j.matbio.2017.10.008</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">29128506</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR36"><label>36.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Bertrand</surname><given-names>P</given-names></name><etal/></person-group><article-title>Increased hyaluronidase levels in breast tumor metastases</article-title><source>Int. J. Cancer</source><year>1997</year><volume>73</volume><fpage>327</fpage><lpage>331</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1002/(sici)1097-0215(19971104)73:3&amp;#x0003c;327::aid-ijc4&amp;#x0003e;3.0.co;2-1</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">9359477</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR37"><label>37.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Bharadwaj</surname><given-names>AG</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Rector</surname><given-names>K</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Simpson</surname><given-names>MA</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>Inducible hyaluronan production reveals differential effects on prostate tumor cell growth and tumor angiogenesis</article-title><source>J. Biol. Chem.</source><year>2007</year><volume>282</volume><fpage>20561</fpage><lpage>20572</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1074/jbc.M702964200</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">17502371</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR38"><label>38.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Maity</surname><given-names>N</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Nema</surname><given-names>NK</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Sarkar</surname><given-names>BK</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Mukherjee</surname><given-names>PK</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>Standardized Clitoria ternatea leaf extract as hyaluronidase, elastase and matrix-metalloproteinase-1 inhibitor</article-title><source>Indian J. Pharmacol.</source><year>2012</year><volume>44</volume><fpage>584</fpage><lpage>587</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.4103/0253-7613.100381</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">23112418</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC3480789</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR39"><label>39.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Hafeez</surname><given-names>BB</given-names></name><etal/></person-group><article-title>A dietary anthocyanidin delphinidin induces apoptosis of human prostate cancer PC3 cells in vitro and in vivo: Involvement of nuclear factor-kappaB signaling</article-title><source>Cancer Res.</source><year>2008</year><volume>68</volume><fpage>8564</fpage><lpage>8572</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1158/0008-5472.CAN-08-2232</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">18922932</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC3149885</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR40"><label>40.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Sogo</surname><given-names>T</given-names></name><etal/></person-group><article-title>Anti-inflammatory activity and molecular mechanism of delphinidin 3-sambubioside, a Hibiscus anthocyanin</article-title><source>Biofactors</source><year>2015</year><volume>41</volume><fpage>58</fpage><lpage>65</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1002/biof.1201</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">25728636</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR41"><label>41.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Masheta</surname><given-names>D</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Al-azzawi</surname><given-names>S</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>Antioxidant and anti-inflammatory effects of delphinidin on glial cells and lack of effect on secretase enzyme</article-title><source>IOP Conf. Ser. Mater. Sci. Eng.</source><year>2018</year><volume>454</volume><fpage>012061</fpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1088/1757-899X/454/1/012061</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR42"><label>42.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Lamy</surname><given-names>S</given-names></name><etal/></person-group><article-title>Delphinidin, a dietary anthocyanidin, inhibits vascular endothelial growth factor receptor-2 phosphorylation</article-title><source>Carcinogenesis</source><year>2006</year><volume>27</volume><fpage>989</fpage><lpage>996</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1093/carcin/bgi279</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">16308314</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR43"><label>43.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Kim</surname><given-names>MH</given-names></name><etal/></person-group><article-title>Delphinidin inhibits angiogenesis through the suppression of HIF-1alpha and VEGF expression in A549 lung cancer cells</article-title><source>Oncol. Rep.</source><year>2017</year><volume>37</volume><fpage>777</fpage><lpage>784</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.3892/or.2016.5296</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">27959445</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR44"><label>44.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Huang</surname><given-names>CC</given-names></name><etal/></person-group><article-title>Dietary delphinidin inhibits human colorectal cancer metastasis associating with upregulation of miR-204-3p and suppression of the integrin/FAK axis</article-title><source>Sci. Rep.</source><year>2019</year><volume>9</volume><fpage>18954</fpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1038/s41598-019-55505-z</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">31831830</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC6908670</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR45"><label>45.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Davinelli</surname><given-names>S</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Bertoglio</surname><given-names>JC</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Zarrelli</surname><given-names>A</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Pina</surname><given-names>R</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Scapagnini</surname><given-names>G</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>A randomized clinical trial evaluating the efficacy of an anthocyanin-maqui berry extract (Delphinol(R)) on oxidative stress biomarkers</article-title><source>J. Am. Coll. Nutr.</source><year>2015</year><volume>34</volume><issue>Suppl 1</issue><fpage>28</fpage><lpage>33</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1080/07315724.2015.1080108</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">26400431</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR46"><label>46.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Lee</surname><given-names>DY</given-names></name><etal/></person-group><article-title>Cytotoxic effects of delphinidin in human osteosarcoma cells</article-title><source>Acta Orthop. Traumatol. Turc.</source><year>2018</year><volume>52</volume><fpage>58</fpage><lpage>64</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1016/j.aott.2017.11.011</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">29290536</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC6136320</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR47"><label>47.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Hill</surname><given-names>RP</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Chambers</surname><given-names>AF</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Ling</surname><given-names>V</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Harris</surname><given-names>JF</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>Dynamic heterogeneity: Rapid generation of metastatic variants in mouse B16 melanoma cells</article-title><source>Science</source><year>1984</year><volume>224</volume><fpage>998</fpage><lpage>1001</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1126/science.6719130</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">6719130</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR48"><label>48.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Thompson</surname><given-names>TC</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Southgate</surname><given-names>J</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Kitchener</surname><given-names>G</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Land</surname><given-names>H</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>Multistage carcinogenesis induced by ras and myc oncogenes in a reconstituted organ</article-title><source>Cell</source><year>1989</year><volume>56</volume><fpage>917</fpage><lpage>930</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1016/0092-8674(89)90625-9</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">2538247</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR49"><label>49.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Le Naour</surname><given-names>A</given-names></name><etal/></person-group><article-title>EO771, the first luminal B mammary cancer cell line from C57BL/6 mice</article-title><source>Cancer Cell Int.</source><year>2020</year><volume>20</volume><fpage>328</fpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1186/s12935-020-01418-1</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">32699527</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC7372867</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR50"><label>50.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Seluanov</surname><given-names>A</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Vaidya</surname><given-names>A</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Gorbunova</surname><given-names>V</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>Establishing primary adult fibroblast cultures from rodents</article-title><source>J. Vis. Exp.</source><year>2010</year><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.3791/2033</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">20972406</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC3185624</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR51"><label>51.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Harada</surname><given-names>H</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Takahashi</surname><given-names>M</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>CD44-dependent intracellular and extracellular catabolism of hyaluronic acid by hyaluronidase-1 and -2</article-title><source>J Biol. Chem.</source><year>2007</year><volume>282</volume><fpage>5597</fpage><lpage>5607</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1074/jbc.M608358200</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">17170110</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR52"><label>52.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Zhao</surname><given-names>Y</given-names></name><etal/></person-group><article-title>Evolution of high-molecular-mass hyaluronic acid is associated with subterranean lifestyle</article-title><source>Nat. Commun.</source><year>2023</year><volume>14</volume><fpage>8054</fpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1038/s41467-023-43623-2</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">38052795</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC10698142</pub-id></element-citation></ref></ref-list></back></article></pmc-articleset>