<?xml version="1.0"  ?><!DOCTYPE pmc-articleset PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD ARTICLE SET 2.0//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pmc/articleset/nlm-articleset-2.0.dtd"><pmc-articleset><article xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" xmlns:ali="http://www.niso.org/schemas/ali/1.0/" article-type="case-report" xml:lang="en" dtd-version="1.4"><processing-meta base-tagset="archiving" mathml-version="3.0" table-model="xhtml" tagset-family="jats"><restricted-by>pmc</restricted-by></processing-meta><front><journal-meta><journal-id journal-id-type="nlm-ta">JAAD Case Rep</journal-id><journal-id journal-id-type="iso-abbrev">JAAD Case Rep</journal-id><journal-id journal-id-type="pmc-domain-id">2969</journal-id><journal-id journal-id-type="pmc-domain">jaadcr</journal-id><journal-title-group><journal-title>JAAD Case Reports</journal-title></journal-title-group><issn pub-type="epub">2352-5126</issn><publisher><publisher-name>Elsevier</publisher-name></publisher></journal-meta><article-meta><article-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC12059383</article-id><article-id pub-id-type="pmcid-ver">PMC12059383.1</article-id><article-id pub-id-type="pmcaid">12059383</article-id><article-id pub-id-type="pmcaiid">12059383</article-id><article-id pub-id-type="pmid">40353099</article-id><article-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1016/j.jdcr.2025.01.036</article-id><article-id pub-id-type="pii">S2352-5126(25)00061-X</article-id><article-version article-version-type="pmc-version">1</article-version><article-categories><subj-group subj-group-type="heading"><subject>Case Report</subject></subj-group></article-categories><title-group><article-title>Long-term management of recurrent biofilms in the tear trough regions following hyaluronic acid filler treatment</article-title></title-group><contrib-group><contrib contrib-type="author" id="au1"><name name-style="western"><surname>Enright</surname><given-names initials="KM">Kaitlyn M.</given-names></name><degrees>PhD</degrees><xref rid="aff1" ref-type="aff">a</xref></contrib><contrib contrib-type="author" id="au2"><name name-style="western"><surname>Khouri</surname><given-names initials="L">Lucie</given-names></name><degrees>MD</degrees><xref rid="aff2" ref-type="aff">b</xref></contrib><contrib contrib-type="author" id="au3"><name name-style="western"><surname>Nguyen</surname><given-names initials="Q">Quynh</given-names></name><degrees>MD</degrees><xref rid="aff2" ref-type="aff">b</xref><xref rid="aff3" ref-type="aff">c</xref></contrib><contrib contrib-type="author" id="au4"><name name-style="western"><surname>Zanetti</surname><given-names initials="K">Kiana</given-names></name><degrees>MSc</degrees><xref rid="aff1" ref-type="aff">a</xref></contrib><contrib contrib-type="author" id="au5"><name name-style="western"><surname>Bernstein</surname><given-names initials="S">Steven</given-names></name><degrees>MD</degrees><xref rid="aff3" ref-type="aff">c</xref></contrib><contrib contrib-type="author" id="au6"><name name-style="western"><surname>Nikolis</surname><given-names initials="A">Andreas</given-names></name><degrees>MD, PhD</degrees><email>research@vicpark.com</email><xref rid="aff1" ref-type="aff">a</xref><xref rid="aff3" ref-type="aff">c</xref><xref rid="aff4" ref-type="aff">d</xref><xref rid="cor1" ref-type="corresp">&#8727;</xref></contrib><aff id="aff1"><label>a</label>Erevna Innovations Inc, Clinical Research Unit, Westmount, Quebec, Canada</aff><aff id="aff2"><label>b</label>D&#233;partement d&#8217;ophtalmologie, Universit&#233; de Montr&#233;al, Montr&#233;al, Qu&#233;bec, Canada</aff><aff id="aff3"><label>c</label>Victoria Park Medispa, Westmount, Qu&#233;bec, Canada</aff><aff id="aff4"><label>d</label>Division of Plastic Surgery, McGill University, Montreal, Quebec, Canada</aff></contrib-group><author-notes><corresp id="cor1"><label>&#8727;</label>Correspondence to: Andreas Nikolis, MD, PhD, Erevna Innovations, 376 Victoria Ave, Suite 400A, Westmount, Qu&#233;bec H3Z 1C3, Canada. <email>research@vicpark.com</email></corresp></author-notes><pub-date pub-type="collection"><month>6</month><year>2025</year></pub-date><pub-date pub-type="epub"><day>04</day><month>3</month><year>2025</year></pub-date><volume>60</volume><issue-id pub-id-type="pmc-issue-id">488180</issue-id><fpage>7</fpage><lpage>10</lpage><pub-history><event event-type="pmc-release"><date><day>04</day><month>03</month><year>2025</year></date></event><event event-type="pmc-live"><date><day>09</day><month>05</month><year>2025</year></date></event><event event-type="pmc-last-change"><date iso-8601-date="2025-05-12 15:25:50.500"><day>12</day><month>05</month><year>2025</year></date></event></pub-history><permissions><copyright-statement>&#169; 2025 The Author(s)</copyright-statement><copyright-year>2025</copyright-year><license><ali:license_ref specific-use="textmining" content-type="ccbylicense">https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</ali:license_ref><license-p>This is an open access article under the CC BY license (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/).</license-p></license></permissions><self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" content-type="pmc-pdf" xlink:href="main.pdf"/><kwd-group id="kwrds0010"><title>Key words</title><kwd>adverse events</kwd><kwd>delayed complications</kwd><kwd>inflammatory reactions</kwd><kwd>periorbital injections</kwd><kwd>pharmacovigilance</kwd></kwd-group><custom-meta-group><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-status-qastatus</meta-name><meta-value>0</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-status-live</meta-name><meta-value>yes</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-status-embargo</meta-name><meta-value>no</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-status-released</meta-name><meta-value>yes</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-open-access</meta-name><meta-value>yes</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-olf</meta-name><meta-value>no</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-manuscript</meta-name><meta-value>no</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-legally-suppressed</meta-name><meta-value>no</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-has-pdf</meta-name><meta-value>yes</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-has-supplement</meta-name><meta-value>no</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-pdf-only</meta-name><meta-value>no</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-suppress-copyright</meta-name><meta-value>no</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-is-real-version</meta-name><meta-value>no</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-is-scanned-article</meta-name><meta-value>no</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-preprint</meta-name><meta-value>no</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-in-epmc</meta-name><meta-value>yes</meta-value></custom-meta></custom-meta-group></article-meta><def-list><title>Abbreviations used</title><def-item><term id="kwrd0040">AE</term><def><p>adverse event</p></def></def-item><def-item><term id="kwrd0050">CT</term><def><p>computerized tomography</p></def></def-item><def-item><term id="kwrd0060">HA</term><def><p>hyaluronic acid</p></def></def-item><def-item><term id="kwrd0070">SAE</term><def><p>serious adverse event</p></def></def-item></def-list></front><body><sec id="sec1"><title>Introduction</title><p id="p0010">Most adverse events associated with hyaluronic acid (HA) fillers are mild in severity, resolve spontaneously and promptly, and are associated with the injection technique rather than the product.<xref rid="bib1" ref-type="bibr"><sup>1</sup></xref><sup>,</sup><xref rid="bib2" ref-type="bibr"><sup>2</sup></xref> However, serious adverse events [eg, biofilms, foreign body granulomas] can arise months to years following treatment. Serious adverse events are more likely to be associated with the product itself.<xref rid="bib2" ref-type="bibr">2</xref>, <xref rid="bib3" ref-type="bibr">3</xref>, <xref rid="bib4" ref-type="bibr">4</xref> Similarities between clinical manifestations of infections and immune reactions can make proper diagnosis and treatment difficult. We present a rare case of recurrent masses in the bilateral tear trough regions following HA filler injections.</p></sec><sec id="sec2"><title>Case report</title><p id="p0015">The patient was a 50-year-old female with a history of cigarette smoking, slightly raised cholesterol levels, and seasonal allergies often accompanied by periorbital swelling. She remarked that her periorbital allergy symptoms had essentially resolved following an aesthetic lower lid blepharoplasty in 2006.</p><p id="p0020">Six months following the blepharoplasty, she noticed bilateral hollowing in the tear troughs. The operating surgeon was unable to propose a suitable solution. The patient consulted another surgeon who recommended a HA filler volumizing treatment. At that time, the patient was na&#239;ve to esthetic injections. The patient received a bilateral volume of 3.50&#160;mL HA injections in the tear troughs and malar regions. Days after the injections, the patient observed edema near the injection sites. She also felt pressure and tingling in the areas. There was no follow-up with the injecting nurse. The tingling sensation subsided after several weeks, but the edema persisted.</p><p id="p0025">After 1&#160;year of persistent edema, the patient consulted a dermatologist. The patient presented with firm, immobile, and painless masses (<xref rid="fig1" ref-type="fig">Fig 1</xref>) in the periorbital, sub-orbital and mid-cheek areas. The dermatologist attempted to dissolve the HA with intralesional hyaluronidase monthly for 6&#160;months, but the edema persisted. For almost 4&#160;years, the patient lived with abnormal masses increasing in size and number.<fig id="fig1" position="float" orientation="portrait"><label>Fig 1</label><caption><p>Recurrent masses in the bilateral tear troughs. <bold>A,</bold> Patient in 2016 upon presenting to the plastic surgeon. <bold>B,</bold> In July 2017 after the bilateral lower blepharoplasty. <bold>C,</bold> Appearance of new growths in September 2017. <bold>D,</bold> Patient in December 2020 following multiple excisions.</p></caption><graphic xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" position="float" orientation="portrait" xlink:href="gr1.jpg"/></fig></p><p id="p0030">She consulted an oculoplastic surgeon who attempted treatment with intralesional cortisone and prescribed a 1-month supply of antibiotics. The patient received regular cortisone injections for almost 2&#160;years. She remarked that the injections decreased the edema marginally. The clinician eventually discontinued this treatment as it caused the skin below the patient&#8217;s eyes to turn yellow. The oculoplastic surgeon consulted with her colleague, a plastic surgeon.</p><p id="p0035">As the edema and masses appeared years after the initial esthetic treatment, the plastic surgeon suspected the development of biofilms as a secondary effect of the original injections. He began a 3-month treatment regimen for the patient. He administered intralesional hyaluronidase 1500 units/mL &#215; 4 (to pursue removal of remnant HA) and intralesional clindamycin for 5&#160;days during the first month. During the second month, he administered intralesional hyaluronidase 1500 units/mL, 300 units per side. He prescribed a 7-day course of prednisone during the third month. While the appearance of the masses improved, some fullness persisted. Two months later, new masses appeared. The plastic surgeon sent the patient for a computerized tomography scan. The computerized tomography scan showed abnormal growths integrated into her skin (<xref rid="fig2" ref-type="fig">Fig 2</xref>).<fig id="fig2" position="float" orientation="portrait"><label>Fig 2</label><caption><p>Masses in the bilateral tear troughs on computed tomography scan. Sample image from the patient&#8217;s computed tomography scan. Masses (<italic toggle="yes">circled</italic>) are integrated into the skin in the regions injected with hyaluronic acid filler.</p></caption><graphic xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" position="float" orientation="portrait" xlink:href="gr2.jpg"/></fig></p><p id="p0040">In May 2017, the plastic surgeon performed a&#160;bilateral lower blepharoplasty to debulk the masses.&#160;He sent excisional biopsies to pathology (<xref rid="fig3" ref-type="fig">Fig&#160;3</xref>; <xref rid="tbl1" ref-type="table">Table I</xref>).<fig id="fig3" position="float" orientation="portrait"><label>Fig 3</label><caption><p>Periorbital mass excisions. <bold>A,</bold> Samples of masses excised with scale. <bold>B,</bold> The affected region.</p></caption><graphic xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" position="float" orientation="portrait" xlink:href="gr3.jpg"/></fig><table-wrap position="float" id="tbl1" orientation="portrait"><label>Table I</label><caption><p>Assessments conducted on the patient and/or her tissue samples and their corresponding results</p></caption><table frame="hsides" rules="groups"><thead><tr><th colspan="1" rowspan="1">Year</th><th colspan="1" rowspan="1">Assessment</th><th colspan="1" rowspan="1">Diagnosis and/or treatment</th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td colspan="1" rowspan="1">2007</td><td colspan="1" rowspan="1">Hollowing of the tear troughs assessed by a dermatologist</td><td colspan="1" rowspan="1">Attempted treatment with hyaluronic acid injections in the tear troughs</td></tr><tr><td colspan="1" rowspan="1">2008</td><td colspan="1" rowspan="1">Dermatologist assessed AEs caused by hyaluronic acid injections</td><td colspan="1" rowspan="1">Attempted treatment with hyaluronidase injections every mo for 6&#160;mo</td></tr><tr><td colspan="1" rowspan="1">2013</td><td colspan="1" rowspan="1">Persisting masses assessed by an oculoplastic surgeon</td><td colspan="1" rowspan="1">Attempted treatment with 1&#160;mo of antibiotics, 2&#160;y of cortisone</td></tr><tr><td colspan="1" rowspan="1">2016</td><td colspan="1" rowspan="1">Persisting masses assessed by an oculoplastic surgeon</td><td colspan="1" rowspan="1">Attempted treatment with intralesional antibiotics and hyaluronidase injections</td></tr><tr><td colspan="1" rowspan="1">2017</td><td colspan="1" rowspan="1">Surgical pathology report after infraorbital malar and cheek exploration</td><td colspan="1" rowspan="1">Excisions on both lower lids demonstrated florid histiocytic aggregates with foreign body-type giant cell reaction</td></tr><tr><td colspan="1" rowspan="1">2018</td><td colspan="1" rowspan="1">Specimen report from excisional biopsies of the bilateral lower lids</td><td colspan="1" rowspan="1">Florid histiocytic aggregates with foreign body-type giant cell reaction</td></tr><tr><td colspan="1" rowspan="1">2020</td><td colspan="1" rowspan="1">Surgical pathology report after excisions on the right lower lid</td><td colspan="1" rowspan="1">Florid histiocytic aggregates with foreign body-type giant cell reaction</td></tr></tbody></table></table-wrap></p><p id="p0045">Subsequent treatment efforts focused on serially excising the recurrent masses and the damaged tissue from the HA injections. The plastic surgeon performed 3 more serial excisions 6&#160;months later. In 2018, he performed 2 further excisions on the lower lid region. In 2019, he performed 2 bilateral excisions on the lower lids. In a final surgery in December 2020, he excised 2 masses and corrected an ectropion of the lower right eyelid. The surgeon&#160;sent masses from this surgery to pathology (<xref rid="tbl1" ref-type="table">Table I</xref>).</p><p id="p0050">By 2020, the excisions significantly improved the patient's condition. New masses appeared less frequently and were smaller, not exceeding 3&#160;mm&#160;&#215;&#160;5&#160;mm. Between December 2020 and May 2021, the patient returned monthly for follow-up. She received monthly fat injections for aesthetic improvement. Her condition remained stable as of her last visit in May 2021. The patient passed away in 2023 due to complications from amyotrophic lateral sclerosis.</p></sec><sec id="sec3"><title>Discussion</title><p id="p0055">Granulomas and implant nodules may form with delayed onset as the muscles of the face redistribute ill-positioned filler particles.<xref rid="bib5" ref-type="bibr"><sup>5</sup></xref><sup>,</sup><xref rid="bib6" ref-type="bibr"><sup>6</sup></xref> Nodules result from technical error and appear sooner than granulomas (1-2&#160;months after injection), after initial swelling subsides. Nodules remain small, while granulomas grow and may extend into surrounding tissues.<xref rid="bib6" ref-type="bibr"><sup>6</sup></xref> Histologically, granuloma particles are scattered. Nodule particles form aggregates. Given these clinical descriptions, some clinicians treated the masses as granulomas. However, granulomas are usually treated successfully with corticosteroids, which did not resolve the current case.<xref rid="bib7" ref-type="bibr"><sup>7</sup></xref> Biofilm formation was initially ruled out, given the negative bacterial culture. However, given reports of biofilms providing false negatives on bacterial cultures, this option was again considered.<xref rid="bib8" ref-type="bibr"><sup>8</sup></xref> Soft tissue fillers have been associated with biofilms. Suspected causes include non-sterile injection techniques that may have introduced bacteria into the injection sites via a contaminated needle.<xref rid="bib9" ref-type="bibr"><sup>9</sup></xref> External triggers such as a recent viral infection or immunization may also reactivate an existing, dormant biofilm.<xref rid="bib10" ref-type="bibr"><sup>10</sup></xref> Most cases of biofilms have been associated with the use of permanent fillers (eg polymethylmethacrylate), rather than HA, which is biocompatible and reversible.<xref rid="bib9" ref-type="bibr"><sup>9</sup></xref> Unfortunately, no systemic treatment exists for this condition. Surgical techniques remain the most suitable management strategy, although they may lead to secondary tissue deficits. Biofilm formation may also be stimulated by the surgical procedure itself. Management efforts should include aesthetic improvement. For this patient, such efforts included fat grafting and corrective blepharoplasty. To avoid adverse events, injectors should use a slow, aseptic injection technique, deposit small aliquots of product, and undertreat critical areas. The key takeaway from this case is that reinjecting HA in a region with a known biofilm present is not advisable. For these patients, surgeons should advise against further HA filler injections and instead consider microfat grafting.</p></sec><sec sec-type="COI-statement" id="coi0010"><title>Conflicts of interest</title><p id="p0060">None disclosed.</p></sec></body><back><ref-list id="cebib0010"><title>References</title><ref id="bib1"><label>1</label><element-citation publication-type="journal" id="sref1"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Abduljabbar</surname><given-names>M.H.</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Basendwh</surname><given-names>M.A.</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>Complications of hyaluronic acid fillers and their managements</article-title><source>J Dermatol Dermatol Surg</source><volume>20</volume><issue>2</issue><year>2016</year><fpage>100</fpage><lpage>106</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1016/j.jdds.2016.01.001</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="bib2"><label>2</label><element-citation publication-type="journal" id="sref2"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Lowe</surname><given-names>N.J.</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Maxwell</surname><given-names>C.A.</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Patnaik</surname><given-names>R.</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>Adverse reactions to dermal fillers: review</article-title><source>Dermatol Surg</source><volume>31</volume><issue>11 Pt 2</issue><year>2005</year><fpage>1616</fpage><lpage>1625</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">16416647</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="bib3"><label>3</label><element-citation publication-type="journal" id="sref3"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Philipp-Dormston</surname><given-names>W.G.</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Goodman</surname><given-names>G.J.</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>De Boulle</surname><given-names>K.</given-names></name><etal/></person-group><article-title>Global approaches to the prevention and management of delayed-onset adverse reactions with hyaluronic acid-based fillers</article-title><source>Plast Reconstr Surg Glob Open</source><volume>8</volume><issue>4</issue><year>2020</year><object-id pub-id-type="publisher-id">e2730</object-id><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1097/GOX.0000000000002730</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC7209845</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">32440404</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="bib4"><label>4</label><element-citation publication-type="journal" id="sref4"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Funt</surname><given-names>D.K.</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>Treatment of delayed-onset inflammatory reactions to hyaluronic acid filler: an algorithmic approach</article-title><source>Plast Reconstr Surg Glob Open</source><volume>10</volume><issue>6</issue><year>2022</year><object-id pub-id-type="publisher-id">e4362</object-id><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1097/GOX.0000000000004362</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC9208893</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">35747256</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="bib5"><label>5</label><element-citation publication-type="journal" id="sref5"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Orseth</surname><given-names>M.L.</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Lee</surname><given-names>N.</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Ibrahim</surname><given-names>O.</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Arndt</surname><given-names>K.A.</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Kaminer</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>Nodule formation following treatment with hyaluronic acid fillers: a report of two challenging cases</article-title><source>J Drugs Dermatol</source><volume>17</volume><issue>5</issue><year>2018</year><fpage>580</fpage><lpage>581</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">29742193</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="bib6"><label>6</label><element-citation publication-type="journal" id="sref6"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Lemperle</surname><given-names>G.</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Gauthier-Hazan</surname><given-names>N.</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Wolters</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Eisemann-Klein</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Zimmermann</surname><given-names>U.</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Duffy</surname><given-names>D.M.</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>Foreign body granulomas after all injectable dermal fillers: part 1. Possible causes</article-title><source>Plast Reconstr Surg</source><volume>123</volume><issue>6</issue><year>2009</year><fpage>1842</fpage><lpage>1863</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1097/PRS.0b013e31818236d7</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">19483587</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="bib7"><label>7</label><element-citation publication-type="journal" id="sref7"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Lemperle</surname><given-names>G.</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Gauthier-Hazan</surname><given-names>N.</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>Foreign body granulomas after all injectable dermal fillers: part 2. Treatment options</article-title><source>Plast Reconstr Surg</source><volume>123</volume><issue>6</issue><year>2009</year><fpage>1864</fpage><lpage>1873</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1097/PRS.0b013e3181858f4f</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">19483588</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="bib8"><label>8</label><element-citation publication-type="journal" id="sref8"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Parsa</surname><given-names>K.</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Schaudinn</surname><given-names>C.</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Gorur</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></name><etal/></person-group><article-title>Demonstration of bacterial biofilms in culture-negative silicone stent and jones tube</article-title><source>Ophthal Plast Reconstr Surg</source><volume>26</volume><issue>6</issue><year>2010</year><fpage>426</fpage><lpage>430</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1097/IOP.0b013e3181cff61f</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">20683273</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="bib9"><label>9</label><element-citation publication-type="journal" id="sref9"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Alhede</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Er</surname><given-names>&#214;.</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Eickhardt</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></name><etal/></person-group><article-title>Bacterial biofilm formation and treatment in soft tissue fillers</article-title><source>Pathog Dis</source><volume>70</volume><issue>3</issue><year>2014</year><fpage>339</fpage><lpage>346</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1111/2049-632X.12139</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">24482426</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="bib10"><label>10</label><element-citation publication-type="journal" id="sref10"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Sadashivaiah</surname><given-names>A.B.</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Mysore</surname><given-names>V.</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>Biofilms: their role in dermal fillers</article-title><source>J Cutan Aesthet Surg</source><volume>3</volume><issue>1</issue><year>2010</year><fpage>20</fpage><lpage>22</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.4103/0974-2077.63257</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">20606988</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC2890130</pub-id></element-citation></ref></ref-list><fn-group><fn id="d36e110"><p id="ntpara0010">Funding sources: None.</p></fn><fn id="d36e113"><p id="ntpara0015">Patient consent: The authors obtained written consent from patients for their photographs and medical information to be published in print and online and with the understanding that this information may be publicly available. Patient consent forms were not provided to the journal but are retained by the authors.</p></fn><fn id="d36e116"><p id="ntpara0020">IRB approval status: Not applicable.</p></fn></fn-group></back></article></pmc-articleset>