<?xml version="1.0"  ?><!DOCTYPE pmc-articleset PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD ARTICLE SET 2.0//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pmc/articleset/nlm-articleset-2.0.dtd"><pmc-articleset><article xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" xmlns:ali="http://www.niso.org/schemas/ali/1.0/" xml:lang="en" article-type="research-article" dtd-version="1.4"><processing-meta base-tagset="archiving" mathml-version="3.0" table-model="xhtml" tagset-family="jats"><restricted-by>pmc</restricted-by></processing-meta><front><journal-meta><journal-id journal-id-type="nlm-ta">Aesthet Surg J Open Forum</journal-id><journal-id journal-id-type="iso-abbrev">Aesthet Surg J Open Forum</journal-id><journal-id journal-id-type="pmc-domain-id">3943</journal-id><journal-id journal-id-type="pmc-domain">asjopen</journal-id><journal-id journal-id-type="publisher-id">asjopenforum</journal-id><journal-title-group><journal-title>Aesthetic Surgery Journal. Open Forum</journal-title></journal-title-group><issn pub-type="epub">2631-4797</issn><publisher><publisher-name>Oxford University Press</publisher-name></publisher></journal-meta><article-meta><article-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC11333964</article-id><article-id pub-id-type="pmcid-ver">PMC11333964.1</article-id><article-id pub-id-type="pmcaid">11333964</article-id><article-id pub-id-type="pmcaiid">11333964</article-id><article-id pub-id-type="pmid">39165914</article-id><article-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1093/asjof/ojae042</article-id><article-id pub-id-type="publisher-id">ojae042</article-id><article-version article-version-type="pmc-version">1</article-version><article-categories><subj-group subj-group-type="heading"><subject>Original Article</subject></subj-group><subj-group subj-group-type="category-taxonomy-collection"><subject>AcademicSubjects/MED00987</subject></subj-group><subj-group subj-group-type="category-taxonomy-collection"><subject>Asj/3</subject></subj-group></article-categories><title-group><article-title>Radiofrequency and Electrical Muscle Stimulation: A Synergistic Treatment That Achieves Lipolysis and Circumferential Waist Reduction in Noninvasive Body Contouring</article-title></title-group><contrib-group><contrib contrib-type="author" corresp="yes"><name name-style="western"><surname>Vranis</surname><given-names initials="NM">Neil M</given-names></name><degrees>MD</degrees><xref rid="FM1" ref-type="author-notes"/><xref rid="ojae042-cor1" ref-type="corresp"/></contrib><contrib contrib-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Ghavami</surname><given-names initials="A">Ashkan</given-names></name><degrees>MD</degrees><xref rid="FM2" ref-type="author-notes"/></contrib><contrib contrib-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Rohrich</surname><given-names initials="RJ">Rodney J</given-names></name><degrees>MD</degrees><xref rid="FM3" ref-type="author-notes"/></contrib><contrib contrib-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Theodorou</surname><given-names initials="S">Spero</given-names></name><degrees>MD</degrees><xref rid="FM4" ref-type="author-notes"/></contrib></contrib-group><author-notes><fn id="FM1"><p>Dr Vranis is a plastic surgeon in private practice, Beverly Hills, CA, USA.</p></fn><fn id="FM2"><p>Dr Ghavami is an assistant clinical professor, Department of Surgery, Division of Plastic and Reconstructive Surgery, David Geffen School of Medicine at UCLA, Los Angeles, CA, USA.</p></fn><fn id="FM3"><p>Dr Rohrich is a plastic surgeon in private practice, Dallas, TX, USA.</p></fn><fn id="FM4"><p>Dr Theodorou is a plastic surgeon in private practice, New York, NY, USA.</p></fn><corresp id="ojae042-cor1"><bold>Corresponding Author:</bold> Dr Neil M. Vranis, 433 N Camden Dr # 780, Beverly Hills, CA 90210, USA. E-mail: <email>drvranis@gmail.com</email></corresp></author-notes><pub-date pub-type="collection"><year>2024</year></pub-date><pub-date pub-type="epub" iso-8601-date="2024-05-28"><day>28</day><month>5</month><year>2024</year></pub-date><volume>6</volume><issue-id pub-id-type="pmc-issue-id">452404</issue-id><elocation-id>ojae042</elocation-id><history><date date-type="editorial-decision"><day>13</day><month>5</month><year>2024</year></date><date date-type="corrected-typeset"><day>24</day><month>7</month><year>2024</year></date></history><pub-history><event event-type="pmc-release"><date><day>28</day><month>05</month><year>2024</year></date></event><event event-type="pmc-live"><date><day>20</day><month>08</month><year>2024</year></date></event><event event-type="pmc-last-change"><date iso-8601-date="2024-08-29 00:25:24.453"><day>29</day><month>08</month><year>2024</year></date></event></pub-history><permissions><copyright-statement>&#169; The Author(s) 2024. Published by Oxford University Press on behalf of The Aesthetic Society.</copyright-statement><copyright-year>2024</copyright-year><license><ali:license_ref specific-use="textmining" content-type="ccbylicense">https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</ali:license_ref><license-p>This is an Open Access article distributed under the terms of the Creative Commons Attribution License (<ext-link xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" ext-link-type="uri" xlink:href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/">https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</ext-link>), which permits unrestricted reuse, distribution, and reproduction in any medium, provided the original work is properly cited.</license-p></license></permissions><self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" content-type="pmc-pdf" xlink:href="ojae042.pdf"/><self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xlink:href="ojae042.pdf"/><abstract><title>Abstract</title><sec id="s1"><title>Background</title><p>Surgeons and providers in aesthetic medicine seek noninvasive devices that can be utilized for safe, efficient, and effective body contouring. Patient demand has propelled the development of novel devices that can simultaneously improve skin laxity, adipolysis along with stimulation of muscle hypertrophy.</p></sec><sec id="s2"><title>Objectives</title><p>To determine the efficacy of body contouring after 3 treatments using the noninvasive Transform (InMode, Lake Forest, CA) device.</p></sec><sec id="s3"><title>Methods</title><p>A prospective, multicenter study was performed. Outcomes evaluated include: standardized caliper and ultrasound measurements of abdominal skin/soft-tissue thickness, waist circumference, histologic evaluation, patient comfort, and satisfaction assessments.</p></sec><sec id="s4"><title>Results</title><p>Forty-four patients were successfully enrolled in the study and completed the series of 3 treatments which involved combined electrical muscle stimulation (EMS) and noninvasive bipolar radiofrequency (RF). Abdominal ultrasound measurements reveal a decrease in soft-tissue thickness (average 3.1&#8197;mm; <italic toggle="yes">P</italic> = .001), there was a significant decrease in caliper measurements of periumbilical skin thickness (<italic toggle="yes">P</italic> &lt; .003), and the average reduction of abdominal circumference was 1.9&#8197;cm (<italic toggle="yes">P</italic> &lt; .0001) 3 months after the treatment series. Histology confirmed subcutaneous adipolysis without damaging the dermal layer. Patients reported a high degree of satisfaction with the overall result (<italic toggle="yes">P</italic> = .003) and that each of the 3 treatments were progressively more comfortable (<italic toggle="yes">P</italic> &lt; .005).</p></sec><sec id="s5"><title>Conclusions</title><p>This study demonstrates that a series of simultaneous noninvasive RF with EMS treatments to the abdomen decreases subcutaneous soft-tissue thickness of the treated area. These comfortable treatments ultimately result in a high degree of patient satisfaction at 3 months.</p></sec><sec id="s6"><title>Level of Evidence: 4</title><p>
<inline-graphic xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xlink:href="ojae042il1.jpg"/>
</p></sec></abstract><counts><page-count count="10"/></counts><custom-meta-group><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-status-qastatus</meta-name><meta-value>0</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-status-live</meta-name><meta-value>yes</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-status-embargo</meta-name><meta-value>no</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-status-released</meta-name><meta-value>yes</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-open-access</meta-name><meta-value>yes</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-olf</meta-name><meta-value>no</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-manuscript</meta-name><meta-value>no</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-legally-suppressed</meta-name><meta-value>no</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-has-pdf</meta-name><meta-value>yes</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-has-supplement</meta-name><meta-value>no</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-pdf-only</meta-name><meta-value>no</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-suppress-copyright</meta-name><meta-value>no</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-is-real-version</meta-name><meta-value>no</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-is-scanned-article</meta-name><meta-value>no</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-preprint</meta-name><meta-value>no</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-in-epmc</meta-name><meta-value>yes</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-license-ref</meta-name><meta-value>CC BY</meta-value></custom-meta></custom-meta-group></article-meta></front><body><p>The ideal aesthetic components of the abdomen and flank soft-tissue envelope include taught skin with minimal adiposity to highlight the well-defined underlaying muscle/bone contours.<sup><xref rid="ojae042-B1" ref-type="bibr">1</xref></sup> Noninvasive body contouring modalities traditionally addressed adipose reduction with minimal secondary impact on improving skin laxity or muscular hypertrophy. Numerous technologies have been used to improve lipodystrophy, with the most well-known example, including cryolipolysis (CoolSculpting, Allergan, Dublin, Ireland).<sup><xref rid="ojae042-B1" ref-type="bibr">1-4</xref></sup> Although studies demonstrate modest improvements in adiposity, issues of secondary skin laxity as well as the poorly understood phenomenon of paradoxical adipose hyperplasia that can occur limit its utility.<sup><xref rid="ojae042-B5" ref-type="bibr">5</xref></sup></p><p>In the mid-2000s, electrical muscle stimulation (EMS), a technology previously used exclusively in rehabilitation medicine,<sup><xref rid="ojae042-B6" ref-type="bibr">6-8</xref></sup> gained popularity within aesthetics because of the &#8220;effortless&#8221; development of muscle hypertrophy. Imaging studies confirm sustained improvements in muscle hypertrophy.<sup><xref rid="ojae042-B9" ref-type="bibr">9</xref>,<xref rid="ojae042-B10" ref-type="bibr">10</xref></sup> However, the aesthetic utility of EMS devices falls short because of the residual lipodystrophy in many patients.<sup><xref rid="ojae042-B6" ref-type="bibr">6</xref>,<xref rid="ojae042-B11" ref-type="bibr">11</xref></sup> Naturally, there has been a rise in patient and provider interest in a more comprehensive noninvasive body contouring solution. Radiofrequency (RF) technology in combination with EMS is of particular interest to simultaneously and synergistically address dermal laxity, adipose excess, and muscle tone.<sup><xref rid="ojae042-B12" ref-type="bibr">12</xref></sup></p><p>RF has been utilized in many medical fields. The use of electrical current to generate heat through Ohm's law (<italic toggle="yes">V</italic> = <italic toggle="yes">IR</italic>) in soft tissues, preferentially targeting collagen and adipose cells, has been successfully used for aesthetic purposes, such as fat reduction, dermal/subdermal tightening, and even improvements in the appearance of cellulite.<sup><xref rid="ojae042-B13" ref-type="bibr">13-17</xref></sup> The ability to safely and reproducibly deliver RF energy in a bipolar mechanism with precise real-time thermal control has significantly advanced the safety and use of RF over the past years.<sup><xref rid="ojae042-B13" ref-type="bibr">13-17</xref></sup> The capability to volumetrically heat tissues using RF is a favorable combination with EMS for 2 reasons: (1) heat acclimation (ie, preheating muscle) allows for a more efficient contraction and faster recovery and (2) simultaneous intensive muscle workload increases lipolysis efficiency.<sup><xref rid="ojae042-B18" ref-type="bibr">18</xref>,<xref rid="ojae042-B19" ref-type="bibr">19</xref></sup></p><p>The purpose of this study was to evaluate clinical and histologic results after a treatment series that used alternating bipolar RF and EMS. This comprehensive study was multicentered and prospective. Previous publications have used preliminary data to demonstrate basic safety of the Transform (InMode, Lake Forest, CA) device.<sup><xref rid="ojae042-B12" ref-type="bibr">12</xref>,<xref rid="ojae042-B20" ref-type="bibr">20</xref></sup> This study was appropriately powered with primary endpoints to objectively measure and assess adipose soft-tissue thickness, changes in waist circumference, and histologic changes of the skin and subcutaneous tissue. Secondary endpoints include subjective patient outcomes, such as overall satisfaction with body contouring and degree of comfort with each treatment session.</p><sec sec-type="methods" id="ojae042-s0"><title>METHODS</title><p>This IRB-approved study (Sterling Institutional Review Board; Clinical Trial Protocol Number: <ext-link xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" ext-link-type="pmc:clinical-trial" xlink:href="NCT05398159">NCT05398159</ext-link>) included 5 sites (TN, TX, PA, NC), with all patients independently presenting to each practice desiring noninvasive body contouring. They voluntarily consented to participation in this study. Data for this study were collected from March 2021 to September 2022. A power analysis (alpha &lt;0.05, power = 0.95) dictated that at least 43 (<italic toggle="yes">n</italic> = 43) patients needed to be included to detect a moderate effect.</p><p>The study included patients without any comorbidities, interested in noninvasive abdominal body contouring, and who were between the ages of 18 to 70 years with a BMI &#8804;30. They were excluded if they were pregnant, breastfeeding, had implantable electrical medical devices, history of cancer, or coagulopathy. All patients were required to return to clinic for the 3-month follow-up appointment. Patients with weight fluctuations &gt;3% of their baseline bodyweight were excluded from the study. To maintain consistency across treatments, a narrow window of settings was applied. Providers were instructed to set the device to with 41&#176;C gradually increasing to 43&#176;C according to patient comfort. The EMS power level was set according to the patient's tolerance, starting at intensity Level 5. Increase gradually to visible muscle contraction.</p><p>The efficacy of the Transform (InMode) treatment was assessed across numerous outcomes. Soft-tissue thickness was assessed using a caliper to measure the thickness of soft-tissue &#8220;pinch&#8221; as well as an ultrasound measurement (from dermis to rectus fascia) while soft tissue was in its native position. The location of these measurements was also recorded for each patient to minimize sampling error. Triangulation of &#8220;fixed points&#8221; (ie, umbilicus, moles, scars, tattoos, etc) was utilized. Torso circumference was recorded at the level of the widest diameter with a second measurement 2 inches above and a third measurement 2 inches below (both are parallel to the initial measurement). Subjective patient comfort ratings during the treatment as well as satisfaction with the overall results were collected and analyzed. One-sample <italic toggle="yes">t</italic>-test, paired samples <italic toggle="yes">t</italic>-test, or within-patients repeated measures analysis of variance was conducted. The analysis was carried out using R-4.3.1 (R Foundation for Statistical Computing, Vienna, Austria).</p><p>Waist circumference measurements were obtained at the widest point between xyphoid and pubis, and additional measurements were taken 2 inches above and below this point. All subsequent measurements taken for each patient were taken at the same distance from the floor to ensure uniformity. Caliper measurements were standardized by taking them from each side of the umbilicus. For the ultrasound measurements, 2 measurements were taken within the treatment area and recoded. The location of each probe was accurately triangulated according to fixed landmarks for each patient (ie, moles, scars, umbilicus, etc). Patient satisfaction and comfort scales were recorded in whole numbers from +2 to &#8722;2 with 0 being neutral (<xref rid="ojae042-T1" ref-type="table">Table 1</xref>).</p><table-wrap position="float" id="ojae042-T1" orientation="portrait"><label>Table 1.</label><caption><p>Rating scale to assess patient comfort for each treatment session and overall satisfaction with results at three months after completion of the treatment series.</p></caption><table frame="hsides" rules="groups"><colgroup span="1"><col align="left" span="1"/><col align="center" span="1"/></colgroup><thead><tr><th align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Comfort Rate</th><th align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Score</th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Very Comfortable</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">+2</td></tr><tr><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Comfortable</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">+1</td></tr><tr><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Indifferent</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">0</td></tr><tr><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Uncomfortable</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">-1</td></tr><tr><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Pain</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">-2</td></tr></tbody></table><table frame="hsides" rules="groups"><colgroup span="1"><col align="left" span="1"/><col align="center" span="1"/></colgroup><thead><tr><th align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Satisfaction Rate</th><th align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Score</th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Very Satisfied</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">+2</td></tr><tr><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Satisfied</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">+1</td></tr><tr><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Indifferent</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">0</td></tr><tr><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Disappointed</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">-1</td></tr><tr><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Very Disappointed</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">-2</td></tr></tbody></table></table-wrap><p>Biopsies from the treated areas were collected from the patients who consented to biopsy at baseline and at 3-month follow-up and stained for hematoxylin and eosin, elastin, and Masson's trichrome to assess for changes. Histological analysis was performed to assess changes in the subcutaneous tissue and the safety of the treatment in regards to dermal damage.</p></sec><sec sec-type="results" id="ojae042-s1"><title>RESULTS</title><p>Forty-four (<italic toggle="yes">n</italic> = 44) patients successfully completed the treatment series involving 3 noninvasive sessions of combined bipolar RF and EMS modalities (Videos 1 and 2). The enrolled cohort consisted of 39 females and 5 males. Average age was 47.6 years (range, 24-69 years; SD 12.9). The average height and weight were 5&#8242;6&#8243; and 150&#8197;lbs (SD 4.0, 21.5), respectively, with an average BMI of 24.2 (range, 18.7-30; SD 2.8). In terms of ethnic origin, the majority of patients were Caucasian (<italic toggle="yes">n</italic> = 33, 75%), followed by Hispanic (<italic toggle="yes">n</italic> = 4, 9.1%), African-American (<italic toggle="yes">n</italic> = 4, 9.1%), Asian (<italic toggle="yes">n</italic> = 2, 4.5%), and Middle-Eastern (<italic toggle="yes">n</italic> = 1, 2.3%).</p><sec id="ojae042-s1.1"><title>Skin and Adipose Tissue Thickness (Ultrasound Measurement)</title><p>Three months after treatment, the reduction in soft-tissue/adipose thickness was reduced by an average of 3.1&#8197;mm (<xref rid="ojae042-F1" ref-type="fig">Figure 1</xref>). The mean ultrasound measurements demonstrated a significant reduction at 3 months (mean = 21.4&#8197;mm) compared with baseline (mean = 24.5&#8197;mm; <italic toggle="yes">P</italic> &lt; .0001; <xref rid="ojae042-T2" ref-type="table">Table 2</xref>).</p><fig position="float" id="ojae042-F1" fig-type="figure" orientation="portrait"><label>Figure 1.</label><caption><p>Ultrasound fat thickness measurements at baseline (A) and 3-month after (B) completion of the treatment series. The yellow line depicts the measured adipose thickness with the calculated measurement displayed in yellow font on each image.</p></caption><graphic xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" position="float" orientation="portrait" xlink:href="ojae042f1.jpg"/></fig><table-wrap position="float" id="ojae042-T2" orientation="portrait"><label>Table 2.</label><caption><p>Ultrasound measured thickness (in mm) of abdominal skin and subcutaneous adiposity superficial to abdominal wall fascia measured before and 3-months after the completion of the treatment series.</p></caption><table frame="hsides" rules="groups"><colgroup span="1"><col align="left" span="1"/><col align="center" span="1"/><col align="center" span="1"/><col align="center" span="1"/><col align="center" span="1"/><col align="center" span="1"/></colgroup><thead><tr><th align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Outcome (Ultrasound)</th><th align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Pre-Treatment Mean (SD)</th><th align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">3-Month Mean (SD)</th><th align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Mean Diff (SD)</th><th align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">t-value</th><th align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">p-value</th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">1<sup>st</sup> Measurement</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">24.07 (7.76)</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">19.84 (6.75)</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">4.24 (7.35)</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">3.56</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">0.001</td></tr><tr><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">2<sup>nd</sup> Measurement</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">23.98 (7.64)</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">21.06 (6.02)</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">2.92 (4.21)</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">4.22</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">&lt;0.001</td></tr><tr><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Avg Ultrasound</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">24.28 (7.60)</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">20.77 (5.78)</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">3.51 (5.52)</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">3.82</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">0.001</td></tr></tbody></table></table-wrap></sec><sec id="ojae042-s1.2"><title>Skin and Adipose Tissue Thickness (Caliper Measurements)</title><p>A second method to assess and confirm a decrease in abdominal skin/soft-tissue thickness was utilizing caliper measurements. The omnibus test was statistically significant for caliper measurements #1, #2, and the average of 1 and 2 measured at 3 different time points: <italic toggle="yes">F</italic><sub>1</sub>(2, 72) = 7.99, <italic toggle="yes">P</italic> = .001, <italic toggle="yes">F</italic><sub>2</sub>(2, 72) = 6.42, <italic toggle="yes">P</italic> = .003, <italic toggle="yes">F</italic><sub>avg</sub>(2, 72) = 7.50, <italic toggle="yes">P</italic> = .001 respectively. A linear, negative correlation was demonstrated from baseline (<italic toggle="yes">m</italic><sub>1</sub> = 26.45; <italic toggle="yes">m</italic><sub>2</sub> = 26.41, <italic toggle="yes">m</italic><sub>avg</sub> = 26.43) to 1-month follow-up (<italic toggle="yes">m</italic><sub>1</sub> = 23.88; <italic toggle="yes">m</italic><sub>2</sub> = 24.18, <italic toggle="yes">m</italic><sub>avg</sub> = 24.03) to 3-month follow-up (<italic toggle="yes">m</italic><sub>1</sub> = 23.40; <italic toggle="yes">m</italic><sub>2</sub> = 24.18, <italic toggle="yes">m</italic><sub>avg</sub> = 23.47). Pairwise comparisons showed that the baseline measurement differed from both subsequent time points. However, there was no difference in measurement at the 1- and 3-month follow-ups. Thus, the improvement of soft-tissue thickness was maintained. <xref rid="ojae042-F2" ref-type="fig">Figure 2</xref> displays the mean values across the 3 time points for the 3 caliper outcome variables.</p><fig position="float" id="ojae042-F2" fig-type="figure" orientation="portrait"><label>Figure 2.</label><caption><p>A bar graft depicting the statistically significant improvement in caliper measurements of abdominal skin and soft-tissue thickness 1 month after completion of treatment series and the sustained improvement until the 3 month follow-up visit. Blue bars represent pre-treatment mean values and the orange/grey bars represent the 1 month and 3 month after treatment mean values, respectively.</p></caption><graphic xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" position="float" orientation="portrait" xlink:href="ojae042f2.jpg"/></fig></sec><sec id="ojae042-s1.3"><title>Waist Circumference Measurements</title><p>The mean circumference measurements demonstrated a significant reduction both at 1 and 3 months (1&#8197;month: mean = &#8722;1.5 and 3&#8197;month: mean = &#8722;1.9&#8197;cm, <italic toggle="yes">P</italic> = .0017 and <italic toggle="yes">P</italic> &lt; .0001, respectively) compared with baseline. Notably, improvement was apparent during the 1-month follow-up, and this positive trajectory persisted upon reaching the 3-month mark (<xref rid="ojae042-F3" ref-type="fig">Figure 3</xref>). These findings confirm the presence of a favorable trend in the reduction of circumference over the time following Transform treatment.</p><fig position="float" id="ojae042-F3" fig-type="figure" orientation="portrait"><label>Figure 3.</label><caption><p>A bar graft depicting that circumference measurements decreased from baseline (red), to 1-month (green), to 3-month (blue) post-treatment for all three measured locations and for their combined average. Pink, green and blue bars represent pre-treatment, 1 month after and 3 months after treatment value, respectively.</p></caption><graphic xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" position="float" orientation="portrait" xlink:href="ojae042f3.jpg"/></fig></sec><sec id="ojae042-s1.4"><title>Patient Comfort During Each Treatment</title><p>The 5-point scale for patient comfort was objectively evaluated in 2 ways: (1) each of the 3 measurements were compared with a value of 0 (hypothesized to be neutral/indifferent), and (2) comparing comfort scores at each of the 3 time points to one another. Two of the three 1 sample <italic toggle="yes">t</italic>-tests for each of the treatment sessions showed a statistically significant difference (<italic toggle="yes">P</italic><sub>1</sub> = .07, <italic toggle="yes">P</italic><sub>2</sub> &lt; .001, <italic toggle="yes">P</italic><sub>3</sub> &lt; .001). None of the treatments received a score of &#8722;2 (ie, were &#8220;painful&#8221;) for any of the patients (<xref rid="ojae042-T3" ref-type="table">Table 3</xref>).</p><table-wrap position="float" id="ojae042-T3" orientation="portrait"><label>Table 3.</label><caption><p>Patient comfort scores during each of the treatment sessions. (-2 = painful, 2 = very comfortable)</p></caption><table frame="hsides" rules="groups"><colgroup span="1"><col align="left" span="1"/><col align="center" span="1"/><col align="center" span="1"/><col align="center" span="1"/><col align="center" span="1"/><col align="right" span="1"/></colgroup><thead><tr><th align="left" colspan="2" rowspan="1">Outcome</th><th align="center" colspan="2" rowspan="1">Treatment Mean (SD)</th><th align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">t-value</th><th align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">p-value</th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td colspan="2" rowspan="1">
<underline>Subject Comfort Treatment 1</underline>
</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1"/><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">0.30 (1.07)</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">1.83</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">0.07</td></tr><tr><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Pain</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Uncomfortable</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Indifferent</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Comfortable</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Very Comfortable</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1"/></tr><tr><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">0 (0.0%)</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">8 (19.5%)</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">13 (31.7%)</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">14 (34.1%)</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">6 (14.6%)</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1"/></tr><tr><td colspan="2" rowspan="1">
<underline>Subject Comfort Treatment 2</underline>
</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1"/><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">0.71 (0.98)</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">4.78</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">&lt;0.001</td></tr><tr><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Pain</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Uncomfortable</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Indifferent</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Comfortable</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Very Comfortable</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1"/></tr><tr><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">0 (0.0%)</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">3 (7.0%)</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">10 (23.3%)</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">21 (48.8%)</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">9 (20.9%)</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1"/></tr><tr><td colspan="2" rowspan="1">
<underline>Subject Comfort Treatment 3</underline>
</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1"/><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">0.73 (1.02)</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">4.73</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">&lt;0.001</td></tr><tr><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Pain</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Uncomfortable</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Indifferent</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Comfortable</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Very Comfortable</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1"/></tr><tr><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">0 (0.0%)</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">6 (14.3%)</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">7 (23.3%)</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">21 (50.0%)</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">8 (19.0%)</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1"/></tr></tbody></table></table-wrap><p>The average patient comfort scores improved with each subsequent treatment session despite maintenance of the device settings/level of stimulation. The linear positive correlation was statistically significant, <italic toggle="yes">F</italic>(2, 86) = 5.76, <italic toggle="yes">P</italic> = .004. Pairwise comparisons reveal that each treatment was significantly less painful than the first treatment (<xref rid="ojae042-F4" ref-type="fig">Figure 4</xref>).</p><fig position="float" id="ojae042-F4" fig-type="figure" orientation="portrait"><label>Figure 4.</label><caption><p>A graphic representation of comfort scores (% of patients) reported for each treatment session. Light grey, teal, light blue and dark blue colors represent patient reported comfort as uncomfortable, indifferent, comfortable and very comfortable, respectively.</p></caption><graphic xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" position="float" orientation="portrait" xlink:href="ojae042f4.jpg"/></fig></sec><sec id="ojae042-s1.5"><title>Patient Satisfaction (3 Months Posttreatment)</title><p>Patient satisfaction after completion of the treatment series was measured on a 5-point scale that ranged from &#8722;2 (very disappointed) to 2 (very satisfied) with a score of 0 representing neutral and baseline for comparison (<xref rid="ojae042-T1" ref-type="table">Table 1</xref>). The mean of 0.66 (STD = 1.28) was statistically different from the hypothesized mean, <italic toggle="yes">t</italic>(37) = 3.17, <italic toggle="yes">P</italic> = .003, suggesting that the patients were more satisfied 3 months after the treatment compared with a hypothesized neutral satisfaction level (<xref rid="ojae042-F5" ref-type="fig">Figure 5</xref>). Clinical photographs highlight the contour changes of the abdomen and flanks after completion of the treatment series (<xref rid="ojae042-F6" ref-type="fig">Figures 6</xref>, <xref rid="ojae042-F7" ref-type="fig">7</xref>).</p><fig position="float" id="ojae042-F5" fig-type="figure" orientation="portrait"><label>Figure 5.</label><caption><p>Pie chart depicting the level of patient satisfaction with the clinical outcome after a three-series treatment protocol with the Transform device (InMode, Lake Forest, CA). The dark blue, red, green, purple and light blue sections of the pie-chart represent the proportion of patients who were very satisfied, satisfied, neutral, disappointed and very disappointed with the treatment results, respectively.</p></caption><graphic xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" position="float" orientation="portrait" xlink:href="ojae042f5.jpg"/></fig><fig position="float" id="ojae042-F6" fig-type="figure" orientation="portrait"><label>Figure 6.</label><caption><p>Clinical profile torso photographs of a 36-year old female patient showing the before (A) and six months after (B) treatment series. Improvement in the abdomen and flank is demonstrated in these photographs.</p></caption><graphic xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" position="float" orientation="portrait" xlink:href="ojae042f6.jpg"/></fig><fig position="float" id="ojae042-F7" fig-type="figure" orientation="portrait"><label>Figure 7.</label><caption><p>Clinical photographs of a 44-year-old female patient showing the before (A) and six months after (B) treatment series. Adipose reduction and overall contour improvement of the flanks is demonstrated in these photographs.</p></caption><graphic xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" position="float" orientation="portrait" xlink:href="ojae042f7.jpg"/></fig></sec><sec id="ojae042-s1.6"><title>Histology</title><p>Abdominal skin/soft-tissue biopsies from within the treatment area were obtained from 2 patients. Biopsies were obtained from each patient before and 3 months after completion of the treatment series. Histologic evaluation of the posttreatment biopsies demonstrated soft-tissue adipocytes surrounded by inflammatory cells (macrophages, neutrophils, and lymphocytes) in addition to fibrous tissue and fibrocytes. Fat necrosis and volumetric loss of subcutaneous adipocytes characterized by clear spaces surrounded by variable amounts of foamy histiocytes and occasional eosinophils and lymphocytes in all treatment sites. Most importantly, the epidermis and dermis were noted to be intact and of appropriate thickness/appearance. Histologically, they appeared to be within normal limits on all evaluated slides (<xref rid="ojae042-F8" ref-type="fig">Figures 8</xref>, <xref rid="ojae042-F9" ref-type="fig">9</xref>).</p><fig position="float" id="ojae042-F8" fig-type="figure" orientation="portrait"><label>Figure 8.</label><caption><p>Histology from Patient 1 post-treatment biopsy. An irregularly shaped foci located 4mm below the epidermis (A: 1x magnification, B: 2x magnification). Adipocytes within this focus are separated by inflammatory cells along with fibrous tissue consistent with sub-acute focal panniculitis (C: 10x magnification). The green lines in A represent the area that is further magnified in B and C.</p></caption><graphic xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" position="float" orientation="portrait" xlink:href="ojae042f8.jpg"/></fig><fig position="float" id="ojae042-F9" fig-type="figure" orientation="portrait"><label>Figure 9.</label><caption><p>Histology from Patient 2 post-treatment biopsy on high magnification. A clear space of subcutaneous adipocytes volumetric loss (large black star) surrounded by numerous, foamy histiocytes (blue arrows) and lymphocytes (green arrows). A multi-nucleated giant cell with foamy cytoplasm (orange area) is visualized in the adjacent area of inflammation (small black stars).</p></caption><graphic xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" position="float" orientation="portrait" xlink:href="ojae042f9.jpg"/></fig></sec></sec><sec sec-type="discussion" id="ojae042-s2"><title>DISCUSSION</title><p>The results of this study and previous report<sup><xref rid="ojae042-B12" ref-type="bibr">12</xref></sup> demonstrate that combining EMS and bipolar RF modalities using the Transform device (InMode), during a single treatment session is safe and effective for mild noninvasive body contouring. This was the first study to demonstrate that this combination of therapies led to a significant reduction in abdominal circumferential girth. The radiographic and histologic findings aligned with this clinical observation. Noninvasive aesthetic treatments have become increasingly popular over the past 20 years. Both of these modalities have been independently used with different tissue targets and mechanisms of action. Logically, the next frontier involves safely combining synergistic treatments into a single device/treatment in order to optimize treatments for patients and clinicians.</p><p>Numerous studies have shown that heating dermal tissue to 42&#176;C triggers a downstream healing cascade that initiates neocollagenesis and elastin formation.<sup><xref rid="ojae042-B21" ref-type="bibr">21</xref></sup> In animal studies, after 10&#8197;min of exposure to temperatures of 39&#176;C to 43&#176;C, the amount of collagen increased from an average of 9% before therapy to 25.9% after 3-month follow-up compared with no change in untreated areas.<sup><xref rid="ojae042-B22" ref-type="bibr">22</xref>,<xref rid="ojae042-B23" ref-type="bibr">23</xref></sup> Other studies have similarly shown through electron microscopy that collagen fibrils had a greater diameter after treatment with a single RF session.<sup><xref rid="ojae042-B24" ref-type="bibr">24</xref></sup> Optimizing these forms of noninvasive thermal-inducing treatments is a delicate balance between achieving temperatures that trigger a nonablative wound healing response to remodel collagen as opposed to higher temperatures that may ablate collagen and soft tissue.<sup><xref rid="ojae042-B13" ref-type="bibr">13</xref></sup> RF has been shown to result in skin tightening and reducing adipocytes. Studies investigating the use of RF for subcutaneous fat reduction have ranged from 4.9% to 29.0% in fat reduction.<sup><xref rid="ojae042-B25" ref-type="bibr">25-27</xref></sup> The histologic evaluation in this study affirms these findings, as there was evidence of adipolysis/adipose necrosis at the cellular level which also translated to clinical findings (decreased soft-tissue thickness on ultrasound and skin pinch measurements). It has been shown that with a minimal 15&#8197;min exposure time, apoptosis can be initiated with temperatures of 42&#176;C, and exposure time to trigger apoptosis decreases as the temperature rises.<sup><xref rid="ojae042-B23" ref-type="bibr">23</xref></sup> Apoptosis is achieved with temperatures of up to 25&#176;C, whereas higher temperatures may result in immediate cell death or necrosis.<sup><xref rid="ojae042-B23" ref-type="bibr">23</xref></sup></p><p>EMS combined with RF provides additional synergistic benefits compared with EMS treatment on its own. It has been well documented that natural, as well as, induced heat acclimatization improves muscle contractility as well as recovery.<sup><xref rid="ojae042-B28" ref-type="bibr">28</xref>,<xref rid="ojae042-B29" ref-type="bibr">29</xref></sup> The EMS functions to produce supraphysiologic muscle contractions through direct stimulation of neuromuscular pathways. This effect not only improves the tone and volume of muscle but also impacts lipolysis because of local energy consumption leading to breakdown to triglycerides stored in fat cells to glycerol and free fatty acids.<sup><xref rid="ojae042-B23" ref-type="bibr">23</xref></sup> As shown in prior studies, the combination of heat and mechanical stimulation of muscle induces significantly higher expression of heat shock proteins as well a myosatellite cells that ultimately lead to muscle hypertrophy and myofiber development.<sup><xref rid="ojae042-B29" ref-type="bibr">29</xref>,<xref rid="ojae042-B30" ref-type="bibr">30</xref></sup> On its own, EMS has been shown to produce an average subcutaneous fat reduction of 19.6% (17.5%-23.3%),<sup><xref rid="ojae042-B31" ref-type="bibr">31</xref>,<xref rid="ojae042-B32" ref-type="bibr">32</xref></sup> an average muscle thickening of 15.1% (14.8%-15.4%),<sup><xref rid="ojae042-B31" ref-type="bibr">31</xref>,<xref rid="ojae042-B33" ref-type="bibr">33</xref></sup> and an average reduction in abdominal separation of 9.95%.<sup><xref rid="ojae042-B31" ref-type="bibr">31</xref>,<xref rid="ojae042-B32" ref-type="bibr">32</xref></sup></p><p>Although objective measurements are paramount to affirming the validity of gross clinical observation, patient outcomes are the ultimate endpoint in the fields of aesthetic plastic surgery and body contouring. Less than 10% of patients treated (<xref rid="ojae042-F9" ref-type="fig">Figure 9</xref>) were disappointed or very disappointed with their results 3 months after the last treatment session. In fact, the majority of the patients were satisfied or very satisfied with their results. There were no adverse effects, highlighting the safety element of this treatment modality. No patient reported the treatment as &#8220;painful&#8221; in any of the 3 sessions. Given the high degree of patient satisfaction coupled with the safety profile and noninvasive nature of the device, there is a cohort of patients who can benefit from these treatments in the realm of body contouring.</p><p>Although this was a multicenter, prospective study, it does have a number of limitations. Despite the adequate sample size (<italic toggle="yes">n</italic> = 44), the use of a control group for comparison&#8212;RF alone, EMS alone&#8212;may have helped to elucidate the degree of contribution of each technology independently and quantified the synergistic effect of the combination treatment. Optimally, the use of more objective imaging such as computed tomography/MRI would have been preferred to objectively quantify fat vs muscle components of the patient's treatment; however, the unnecessary radiation and diagnostic expense are not warranted, and thus, ultrasound was selected as the preferred imaging modality. As with many body contouring studies, it would have also been optimal to control for possible lifestyle (diet/exercise) confounding variables; however, our strict exclusion criteria of weight maintenance within 3% of baseline was an attempt to mitigate the influence of this confounding variable. Lastly, longer follow-up times will be needed to determine the longevity of treatment efficacy and resolution of subcutaneous inflammation/fat necrosis at a cellular level. Although this study demonstrates a positive response in the subacute time period, additional studies will be needed to assess long-term viability of results or the need for additional maintenance treatment sessions at specific time intervals.</p></sec><sec sec-type="conclusions" id="ojae042-s3"><title>CONCLUSIONS</title><p>Using the Transform device (InMode), we were able to demonstrate a significant reduction in torso circumference and abdominal soft-tissue thickness with high patient satisfaction scores as early as 3 months after completion of the treatment series. Histologic review of the biopsies obtained from the treated areas confirms adipolysis, which aligns with the hypothesized physiologic response after treatment. Most importantly, there were no adverse effects as a result from the simultaneous combination of EMS and RF treatment.</p></sec></body><back><sec id="ojae042-s4"><title>Disclosures</title><p>There are no disclosures for Dr Vranis. Dr Ghavami receives book royalties from Thieme Medical Publishing (Leipzig, Germany) and QMP Inc. (St. Louis, MO). Dr Rohrich received instrument royalties from Eriem Surgical, Inc. (Lake Forest, IL), and book royalties from Thieme Medical Publishing. Dr Theodorou received royalties from Thieme Medical Publishing and is a consultant for InMode Ltd (Lake Forest, CA).</p></sec><sec id="ojae042-s5"><title>Funding</title><p>InMode Ltd provided the device for patient use and the article processing charge. The authors received no financial support for the research and authorship.</p></sec><ref-list id="ref1"><title>REFERENCES</title><ref id="ojae042-B1"><label>1</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><string-name name-style="western"><surname>Lee</surname><given-names>NY</given-names></string-name>, <string-name name-style="western"><surname>Robinson</surname><given-names>DM</given-names></string-name></person-group>. <article-title>Noninvasive body contouring</article-title>. <source>Semin Cutan Med Surg</source>. <year>2017</year>;<volume>36</volume>(<issue>4</issue>):<fpage>170</fpage>&#8211;<lpage>178</lpage>. doi: <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.12788/j.sder.2017.043</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">29224034</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="ojae042-B2"><label>2</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><string-name name-style="western"><surname>Hedayati</surname><given-names>B</given-names></string-name>, <string-name name-style="western"><surname>Juh&#225;sz</surname><given-names>M</given-names></string-name>, <string-name name-style="western"><surname>Chu</surname><given-names>S</given-names></string-name>, <string-name name-style="western"><surname>Mesinkovska</surname><given-names>NA</given-names></string-name></person-group>. <article-title>Adverse events associated with cryolipolysis: a systematic review of the literature</article-title>. <source>Dermatol Surg</source>. <year>2020</year>;<volume>46</volume>(<issue>1</issue>):<fpage>S8</fpage>&#8211;<lpage>S13</lpage>. doi: <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1097/DSS.0000000000002524</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">32976167</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="ojae042-B3"><label>3</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><string-name name-style="western"><surname>Altmann</surname><given-names>J</given-names></string-name>, <string-name name-style="western"><surname>Burns</surname><given-names>AJ</given-names></string-name>, <string-name name-style="western"><surname>Kilmer</surname><given-names>SL</given-names></string-name>, <etal>et al</etal></person-group><article-title>Global expert opinion on cryolipolysis treatment recommendations and considerations: a modified Delphi study</article-title>. <source>Aesthet Surg J Open Forum</source>. <year>2022</year>:<volume>4</volume>:<fpage>ojac008</fpage>. doi: <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1093/asjof/ojac008</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">35592181</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC9113840</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="ojae042-B4"><label>4</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><string-name name-style="western"><surname>Few</surname><given-names>J</given-names></string-name>, <string-name name-style="western"><surname>Saltz</surname><given-names>R</given-names></string-name>, <string-name name-style="western"><surname>Beaty</surname><given-names>M</given-names></string-name>, <etal>et al</etal></person-group><article-title>Cryolipolysis: clinical best practices and other nonclinical considerations</article-title>. <source>Aesthet Surg J Open Forum</source>. <year>2020</year>;<volume>2</volume>(<issue>2</issue>):<fpage>ojaa010</fpage>. doi: <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1093/asjof/ojaa010</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">33791637</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC7671251</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="ojae042-B5"><label>5</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><string-name name-style="western"><surname>Khan</surname><given-names>M</given-names></string-name></person-group>. <article-title>Complications of cryolipolysis: paradoxical adipose hyperplasia (PAH) and beyond</article-title>. <source>Aesthet Surg J</source>. <year>2019</year>;<volume>39</volume>(<issue>8</issue>):<fpage>334&#8211;</fpage><lpage>3342</lpage>. doi: <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1093/asj/sjy282</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">30346468</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="ojae042-B6"><label>6</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><string-name name-style="western"><surname>Manudhane</surname><given-names>AP</given-names></string-name>, <string-name name-style="western"><surname>Wang</surname><given-names>S</given-names></string-name>, <string-name name-style="western"><surname>Ezaldein</surname><given-names>HH</given-names></string-name>, <string-name name-style="western"><surname>Scott</surname><given-names>JF</given-names></string-name></person-group>. <article-title>Powered muscle stimulators: an investigation into newly FDA 510(k) approved devices marketed for muscle toning and esthetic benefit</article-title>. <source>J Dermatolog Treat</source>. <year>2020</year>;<volume>31</volume>(<issue>2</issue>):<fpage>200</fpage>&#8211;<lpage>203</lpage>. doi: <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1080/09546634.2019.1587148</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">30799667</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="ojae042-B7"><label>7</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><string-name name-style="western"><surname>Enoka</surname><given-names>RM</given-names></string-name>, <string-name name-style="western"><surname>Amiridis</surname><given-names>IG</given-names></string-name>, <string-name name-style="western"><surname>Duchateau</surname><given-names>J</given-names></string-name></person-group>. <article-title>Electrical stimulation of muscle: electrophysiology and rehabilitation</article-title>. <source>Physiology (Bethesda)</source>. <year>2020</year>;<volume>35</volume>(<issue>1</issue>):<fpage>40</fpage>&#8211;<lpage>56</lpage>. doi: <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1152/physiol.00015.2019</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">31799910</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="ojae042-B8"><label>8</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><string-name name-style="western"><surname>Wade</surname><given-names>RC</given-names></string-name>, <string-name name-style="western"><surname>Gorgey</surname><given-names>AS</given-names></string-name></person-group>. <article-title>Skeletal muscle conditioning may be an effective rehabilitation intervention preceding functional electrical stimulation cycling</article-title>. <source>Neural Regen Res</source>. <year>2016</year>;<volume>11</volume>(<issue>8</issue>):<fpage>1232</fpage>&#8211;<lpage>1233</lpage>. doi: <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.4103/1673-5374.189174</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">27651764</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC5020815</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="ojae042-B9"><label>9</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><string-name name-style="western"><surname>Cook</surname><given-names>J</given-names></string-name>, <string-name name-style="western"><surname>Pozner</surname><given-names>JN</given-names></string-name></person-group>. <article-title>Commentary on: noninvasive induction of muscle fiber hypertrophy and hyperplasia: effects of high-intensity focused electromagnetic field evaluated in an in-vivo porcine model: a pilot study</article-title>. <source>Aesthet Surg J</source>. <year>2020</year>;<volume>40</volume>(<issue>5</issue>):<fpage>575</fpage>&#8211;<lpage>576</lpage>. doi: <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1093/asj/sjz314</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">31904822</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="ojae042-B10"><label>10</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><string-name name-style="western"><surname>Duncan</surname><given-names>D</given-names></string-name>, <string-name name-style="western"><surname>Dinev</surname><given-names>I</given-names></string-name></person-group>. <article-title>Noninvasive induction of muscle fiber hypertrophy and hyperplasia: effects of high-intensity focused electromagnetic field evaluated in an in-vivo porcine model: a pilot study</article-title>. <source>Aesthet Surg J</source>. <year>2020</year>;<volume>40</volume>(<issue>5</issue>):<fpage>568</fpage>&#8211;<lpage>574</lpage>. doi: <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1093/asj/sjz244</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">31665217</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC7154795</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="ojae042-B11"><label>11</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><string-name name-style="western"><surname>Zachary</surname><given-names>CB</given-names></string-name>, <string-name name-style="western"><surname>Burns</surname><given-names>AJ</given-names></string-name>, <string-name name-style="western"><surname>Pham</surname><given-names>LD</given-names></string-name>, <string-name name-style="western"><surname>Jimenez Lozano</surname><given-names>JN</given-names></string-name></person-group>. <article-title>Clinical study demonstrates that electromagnetic muscle stimulation does not cause injury to fat cells</article-title>. <source>Lasers Surg Med</source>. <year>2021</year>;<volume>53</volume>(<issue>1</issue>):<fpage>70</fpage>&#8211;<lpage>78</lpage>. doi: <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1002/lsm.23259</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">32383824</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC7891655</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="ojae042-B12"><label>12</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><string-name name-style="western"><surname>Dayan</surname><given-names>E</given-names></string-name>, <string-name name-style="western"><surname>Chilukuri</surname><given-names>S</given-names></string-name>, <string-name name-style="western"><surname>Bucky</surname><given-names>L</given-names></string-name>, <string-name name-style="western"><surname>Bharti</surname><given-names>G</given-names></string-name>, <string-name name-style="western"><surname>Gold</surname><given-names>MH</given-names></string-name>, <string-name name-style="western"><surname>Rohrich</surname><given-names>R</given-names></string-name></person-group>. <article-title>Combination non-invasive radiofrequency and electrical muscle stimulation: a synergistic combination for body contouring</article-title>. <source>J Cosmet Dermatol</source>. <year>2022</year>;<volume>21</volume>(<issue>S1</issue>):<fpage>S29</fpage>&#8211;<lpage>S36</lpage>. doi: <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1111/jocd.15393</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">36164965</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="ojae042-B13"><label>13</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><string-name name-style="western"><surname>Dayan</surname><given-names>E</given-names></string-name>, <string-name name-style="western"><surname>Chapas</surname><given-names>A</given-names></string-name>, <string-name name-style="western"><surname>Marte</surname><given-names>J</given-names></string-name>, <string-name name-style="western"><surname>Chia</surname><given-names>C</given-names></string-name>, <string-name name-style="western"><surname>Theodorou</surname><given-names>S</given-names></string-name></person-group>. <article-title>A prospective trial: handsfree thermoregulated bipolar radiofrequency for face and neck contouring</article-title>. <source>Plast Reconstr Surg Glob Open</source>. <year>2022</year>;<volume>10</volume>(<issue>3</issue>):<fpage>e4194</fpage>. doi: <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1097/GOX.0000000000004194</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">35492231</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC9038493</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="ojae042-B14"><label>14</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><string-name name-style="western"><surname>Dayan</surname><given-names>E</given-names></string-name>, <string-name name-style="western"><surname>Theodorou</surname><given-names>S</given-names></string-name></person-group>. <article-title>Not all radiofrequency devices are created equal: a thermal assessment</article-title>. <source>Plast Reconstr Surg Glob Open</source>. <year>2022</year>;<volume>10</volume>(<issue>2</issue>):<fpage>e4077</fpage>. doi: <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1097/GOX.0000000000004077</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">35141101</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC8820913</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="ojae042-B15"><label>15</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><string-name name-style="western"><surname>Dayan</surname><given-names>E</given-names></string-name></person-group>. <article-title>Commentary on: temperature-controlled monopolar radiofrequency in the treatment of submental skin laxity: a prospective study</article-title>. <source>Aesthet Surg J</source>. <year>2021</year>;<volume>41</volume>(<issue>11</issue>):<fpage>NP1657</fpage>&#8211;<lpage>NP1658</lpage>. doi: <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1093/asj/sjab131</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">33728438</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="ojae042-B16"><label>16</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><string-name name-style="western"><surname>Cohen</surname><given-names>S</given-names></string-name>, <string-name name-style="western"><surname>Dominsky</surname><given-names>O</given-names></string-name>, <string-name name-style="western"><surname>Artzi</surname><given-names>O</given-names></string-name>, <string-name name-style="western"><surname>Dayan</surname><given-names>E</given-names></string-name>, <string-name name-style="western"><surname>Eckstein</surname><given-names>J</given-names></string-name></person-group>. <article-title>Deep layer radiofrequency thermo-coagulative technology for cervicofacial contouring: sonographic and clinical results</article-title>. <source>Plast Reconstr Surg Glob Open</source>. <year>2020</year>;<volume>8</volume>(<issue>12</issue>):<fpage>e3286</fpage>. doi: <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1097/GOX.0000000000003286</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">33425598</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC7787293</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="ojae042-B17"><label>17</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><string-name name-style="western"><surname>Dayan</surname><given-names>E</given-names></string-name>, <string-name name-style="western"><surname>Theodorou</surname><given-names>S</given-names></string-name>, <string-name name-style="western"><surname>Rohrich</surname><given-names>RJ</given-names></string-name>, <string-name name-style="western"><surname>Jay Burns</surname><given-names>A</given-names></string-name></person-group>. <article-title>Aesthetic applications of radiofrequency: lymphatic and perfusion assessment</article-title>. <source>Plast Reconstr Surg Glob Open</source>. <year>2020</year>;<volume>8</volume>(<issue>10</issue>):<fpage>e3193</fpage>. doi: <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1097/GOX.0000000000003193</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">33173697</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC7647541</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="ojae042-B18"><label>18</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><string-name name-style="western"><surname>Waldron</surname><given-names>M</given-names></string-name>, <string-name name-style="western"><surname>Fowler</surname><given-names>R</given-names></string-name>, <string-name name-style="western"><surname>Heffernan</surname><given-names>S</given-names></string-name>, <string-name name-style="western"><surname>Tallent</surname><given-names>J</given-names></string-name>, <string-name name-style="western"><surname>Kilduff</surname><given-names>L</given-names></string-name>, <string-name name-style="western"><surname>Jeffries</surname><given-names>O</given-names></string-name></person-group>. <article-title>Effects of heat acclimation and acclimatisation on maximal aerobic capacity compared to exercise alone in both thermoneutral and hot environments: a meta-analysis and meta-regression</article-title>. <source>Sports Med</source>. <year>2021</year>;<volume>51</volume>(<issue>7</issue>):<fpage>1509</fpage>&#8211;<lpage>1525</lpage>. doi: <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1007/s40279-021-01445-6</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">33811616</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC8222027</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="ojae042-B19"><label>19</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><string-name name-style="western"><surname>Sekiguchi</surname><given-names>Y</given-names></string-name>, <string-name name-style="western"><surname>Benjamin</surname><given-names>CL</given-names></string-name>, <string-name name-style="western"><surname>Manning</surname><given-names>CN</given-names></string-name>, <etal>et al</etal></person-group><article-title>Effects of heat acclimatization, heat acclimation, and intermittent exercise heat training on time-trial performance</article-title>. <source>Sports Health</source>. <year>2022</year>;<volume>14</volume>(<issue>5</issue>):<fpage>694</fpage>&#8211;<lpage>701</lpage>. doi: <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1177/19417381211050643</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">34706597</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC9460081</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="ojae042-B20"><label>20</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><string-name name-style="western"><surname>Novak</surname><given-names>M</given-names></string-name>, <string-name name-style="western"><surname>Weir</surname><given-names>D</given-names></string-name>, <string-name name-style="western"><surname>Rohrich</surname><given-names>RJ</given-names></string-name></person-group>. <article-title>Safety and efficacy of transform for noninvasive lipolysis and circumference reduction of the abdomen</article-title>. <source>Plast Reconstr Surg Glob Open</source>. <year>2022</year>;<volume>10</volume>(<issue>7</issue>):<fpage>e4446</fpage>. doi: <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1097/GOX.0000000000004446</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">35923978</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC9298471</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="ojae042-B21"><label>21</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><string-name name-style="western"><surname>Dayan</surname><given-names>E</given-names></string-name>, <string-name name-style="western"><surname>Chia</surname><given-names>C</given-names></string-name>, <string-name name-style="western"><surname>Burns</surname><given-names>AJ</given-names></string-name>, <string-name name-style="western"><surname>Theodorou</surname><given-names>S</given-names></string-name></person-group>. <article-title>Adjustable depth fractional radiofrequency combined with bipolar radiofrequency: a minimally invasive combination treatment for skin laxity</article-title>. <source>Aesthet Surg J</source>. <year>2019</year>;<volume>39</volume>(Supplement_3):<fpage>S112</fpage>&#8211;<lpage>S119</lpage>. doi: <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1093/asj/sjz055</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">30958550</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC6460431</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="ojae042-B22"><label>22</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><string-name name-style="western"><surname>Fritz</surname><given-names>K</given-names></string-name>, <string-name name-style="western"><surname>Salavastru</surname><given-names>C</given-names></string-name></person-group>. <article-title>Ways of noninvasive facial skin tightening and fat reduction</article-title>. <source>Facial Plast Surg</source>. <year>2016</year>;<volume>32</volume>(<issue>3</issue>):<fpage>276</fpage>&#8211;<lpage>282</lpage>. doi: <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1055/s-0036-1584214</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">27248025</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="ojae042-B23"><label>23</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><string-name name-style="western"><surname>Weiss</surname><given-names>R</given-names></string-name>, <string-name name-style="western"><surname>Weiss</surname><given-names>M</given-names></string-name>, <string-name name-style="western"><surname>Beasley</surname><given-names>K</given-names></string-name>, <string-name name-style="western"><surname>Vrba</surname><given-names>J</given-names></string-name>, <string-name name-style="western"><surname>Bernardy</surname><given-names>J</given-names></string-name></person-group>. <article-title>Operator independent focused high frequency ISM band for fat reduction: porcine model</article-title>. <source>Lasers Surg Med</source>. <year>2013</year>;<volume>45</volume>(<issue>4</issue>):<fpage>235</fpage>&#8211;<lpage>239</lpage>. doi: <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1002/lsm.22134</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">23619902</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC3664404</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="ojae042-B24"><label>24</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><string-name name-style="western"><surname>Zelickson</surname><given-names>BD</given-names></string-name>, <string-name name-style="western"><surname>Kist</surname><given-names>D</given-names></string-name>, <string-name name-style="western"><surname>Bernstein</surname><given-names>E</given-names></string-name>, <etal>et al</etal></person-group><article-title>Histological and ultrastructural evaluation of the effects of a radiofrequency-based nonablative dermal remodeling device: a pilot study</article-title>. <source>Arch Dermatol</source>. <year>2004</year>;<volume>140</volume>(<issue>2</issue>):<fpage>204</fpage>&#8211;<lpage>209</lpage>. doi: <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1001/archderm.140.2.204</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">14967794</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="ojae042-B25"><label>25</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><string-name name-style="western"><surname>Boisnic</surname><given-names>S</given-names></string-name>, <string-name name-style="western"><surname>Divaris</surname><given-names>M</given-names></string-name>, <string-name name-style="western"><surname>Nelson</surname><given-names>AA</given-names></string-name>, <string-name name-style="western"><surname>Gharavi</surname><given-names>NM</given-names></string-name>, <string-name name-style="western"><surname>Lask</surname><given-names>GP</given-names></string-name></person-group>. <article-title>A clinical and biological evaluation of a novel, noninvasive radiofrequency device for the long-term reduction of adipose tissue</article-title>. <source>Lasers Surg Med</source>. <year>2014</year>;<volume>46</volume>(<issue>2</issue>):<fpage>94</fpage>&#8211;<lpage>103</lpage>. doi: <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1002/lsm.22223</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">24535760</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="ojae042-B26"><label>26</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><string-name name-style="western"><surname>Jacob</surname><given-names>C</given-names></string-name>, <string-name name-style="western"><surname>Kent</surname><given-names>D</given-names></string-name>, <string-name name-style="western"><surname>Ibrahim</surname><given-names>O</given-names></string-name></person-group>. <article-title>Efficacy and safety of simultaneous application of HIFEM and synchronized radiofrequency for abdominal fat reduction and muscle toning: a multicenter magnetic resonance imaging evaluation study</article-title>. <source>Dermatol Surg</source>. <year>2021</year>;<volume>47</volume>(<issue>7</issue>):<fpage>969</fpage>&#8211;<lpage>973</lpage>. doi: <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1097/DSS.0000000000003086</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">34001694</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="ojae042-B27"><label>27</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><string-name name-style="western"><surname>Hayre</surname><given-names>N</given-names></string-name>, <string-name name-style="western"><surname>Palm</surname><given-names>M</given-names></string-name>, <string-name name-style="western"><surname>Jenkin</surname><given-names>P</given-names></string-name></person-group>. <article-title>A clinical evaluation of a next generation, non-invasive, selective radiofrequency, hands-free, body-shaping device</article-title>. <source>J Drugs Dermatol</source>. <year>2016</year>;<volume>15</volume>(<issue>12</issue>):<fpage>1557</fpage>&#8211;<lpage>1561</lpage>.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">28095578</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="ojae042-B28"><label>28</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><string-name name-style="western"><surname>Racinais</surname><given-names>S</given-names></string-name>, <string-name name-style="western"><surname>Alonso</surname><given-names>JM</given-names></string-name>, <string-name name-style="western"><surname>Coutts</surname><given-names>AJ</given-names></string-name>, <etal>et al</etal></person-group><article-title>Consensus recommendations on training and competing in the heat</article-title>. <source>Sports Med</source>. <year>2015</year>;<volume>45</volume>(<issue>7</issue>):<fpage>925</fpage>&#8211;<lpage>938</lpage>. doi: <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1007/s40279-015-0343-6</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">26002286</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC4473280</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="ojae042-B29"><label>29</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><string-name name-style="western"><surname>Daanen</surname><given-names>HAM</given-names></string-name>, <string-name name-style="western"><surname>Racinais</surname><given-names>S</given-names></string-name>, <string-name name-style="western"><surname>P&#233;riard</surname><given-names>JD</given-names></string-name></person-group>. <article-title>Heat acclimation decay and re-induction: a systematic review and meta-analysis</article-title>. <source>Sports Med</source>. <year>2018</year>;<volume>48</volume>(<issue>2</issue>):<fpage>409</fpage>&#8211;<lpage>430</lpage>. doi: <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1007/s40279-017-0808-x</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">29129022</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC5775394</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="ojae042-B30"><label>30</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><string-name name-style="western"><surname>Yoshihara</surname><given-names>T</given-names></string-name>, <string-name name-style="western"><surname>Naito</surname><given-names>H</given-names></string-name>, <string-name name-style="western"><surname>Kakigi</surname><given-names>R</given-names></string-name>, <etal>et al</etal></person-group><article-title>Heat stress activates the Akt/mTOR signalling pathway in rat skeletal muscle</article-title>. <source>Acta Physiol (Oxf)</source>. <year>2013</year>;<volume>207</volume>(<issue>2</issue>):<fpage>416</fpage>&#8211;<lpage>426</lpage>. doi: <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1111/apha.12040</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">23167446</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="ojae042-B31"><label>31</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><string-name name-style="western"><surname>Kent</surname><given-names>DE</given-names></string-name>, <string-name name-style="western"><surname>Jacob</surname><given-names>CI</given-names></string-name></person-group>. <article-title>Simultaneous changes in abdominal adipose and muscle tissues following treatments by high-intensity focused electromagnetic (HIFEM) technology-based device: computed tomography evaluation</article-title>. <source>J Drugs Dermatol</source>. <year>2019</year>;<volume>18</volume>(<issue>11</issue>):<fpage>1098</fpage>&#8211;<lpage>1102</lpage>.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">31738500</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="ojae042-B32"><label>32</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><string-name name-style="western"><surname>Kinney</surname><given-names>BM</given-names></string-name>, <string-name name-style="western"><surname>Lozanova</surname><given-names>P</given-names></string-name></person-group>. <article-title>High intensity focused electromagnetic therapy evaluated by magnetic resonance imaging: safety and efficacy study of a dual tissue effect based non-invasive abdominal body shaping</article-title>. <source>Lasers Surg Med</source>. <year>2019</year>;<volume>51</volume>(<issue>1</issue>):<fpage>40</fpage>&#8211;<lpage>46</lpage>. doi: <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1002/lsm.23024</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">30302767</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC6585690</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="ojae042-B33"><label>33</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><string-name name-style="western"><surname>Halevy</surname><given-names>O</given-names></string-name>, <string-name name-style="western"><surname>Krispin</surname><given-names>A</given-names></string-name>, <string-name name-style="western"><surname>Leshem</surname><given-names>Y</given-names></string-name>, <string-name name-style="western"><surname>McMurtry</surname><given-names>JP</given-names></string-name>, <string-name name-style="western"><surname>Yahav</surname><given-names>S</given-names></string-name></person-group>. <article-title>Early-age heat exposure affects skeletal muscle satellite cell proliferation and differentiation in chicks</article-title>. <source>Am J Physiol Regul Integr Comp Physiol</source>. <year>2001</year>;<volume>281</volume>(<issue>1</issue>):<fpage>R302</fpage>&#8211;<lpage>R309</lpage>. doi: <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1152/ajpregu.2001.281.1.R302</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">11404306</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref></ref-list></back></article></pmc-articleset>