<?xml version="1.0"  ?><!DOCTYPE pmc-articleset PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD ARTICLE SET 2.0//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pmc/articleset/nlm-articleset-2.0.dtd"><pmc-articleset><article xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" xmlns:ali="http://www.niso.org/schemas/ali/1.0/" xml:lang="en" article-type="research-article" dtd-version="1.4"><processing-meta base-tagset="archiving" mathml-version="3.0" table-model="xhtml" tagset-family="jats"><restricted-by>pmc</restricted-by></processing-meta><front><journal-meta><journal-id journal-id-type="nlm-ta">Cureus</journal-id><journal-id journal-id-type="iso-abbrev">Cureus</journal-id><journal-id journal-id-type="pmc-domain-id">2757</journal-id><journal-id journal-id-type="pmc-domain">cureus</journal-id><journal-title-group><journal-title>Cureus</journal-title></journal-title-group><issn pub-type="epub">2168-8184</issn><publisher><publisher-name>Cureus Inc.</publisher-name></publisher></journal-meta><article-meta><article-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC11665833</article-id><article-id pub-id-type="pmcid-ver">PMC11665833.1</article-id><article-id pub-id-type="pmcaid">11665833</article-id><article-id pub-id-type="pmcaiid">11665833</article-id><article-id pub-id-type="pmid">39717328</article-id><article-id pub-id-type="doi">10.7759/cureus.74297</article-id><article-version article-version-type="pmc-version">1</article-version><article-categories><subj-group subj-group-type="heading"><subject>Plastic Surgery</subject></subj-group><subj-group><subject>Dermatology</subject></subj-group><subj-group><subject>Medical Education</subject></subj-group></article-categories><title-group><article-title>Combined Application of Hyaluronidase and Collagenase for Late-Onset Edema in Periocular Area After Hyaluronic Acid Volume Repositioning: A Six-Case Retrospective Review</article-title></title-group><contrib-group><contrib contrib-type="editor"><name name-style="western"><surname>Muacevic</surname><given-names initials="A">Alexander</given-names></name></contrib><contrib contrib-type="editor"><name name-style="western"><surname>Adler</surname><given-names initials="JR">John R</given-names></name></contrib></contrib-group><contrib-group><contrib contrib-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Castelanich</surname><given-names initials="DG">Desiree Giselle</given-names></name><xref rid="aff-1" ref-type="aff">1</xref></contrib><contrib contrib-type="author" corresp="yes"><name name-style="western"><surname>Parra Hernand&#233;z</surname><given-names initials="LA">Luis A</given-names></name><xref rid="aff-2" ref-type="aff">2</xref></contrib><contrib contrib-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Martinez Amado</surname><given-names initials="A">Andreina</given-names></name><xref rid="aff-3" ref-type="aff">3</xref></contrib><contrib contrib-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Acevedo</surname><given-names initials="DA">Diana A</given-names></name><xref rid="aff-4" ref-type="aff">4</xref></contrib><contrib contrib-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Vel&#225;squez</surname><given-names initials="L">Lina</given-names></name><xref rid="aff-5" ref-type="aff">5</xref></contrib><contrib contrib-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Dicker</surname><given-names initials="V">Valentina</given-names></name><xref rid="aff-6" ref-type="aff">6</xref></contrib><contrib contrib-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Parra Hernandez</surname><given-names initials="AM">Andrea M</given-names></name><xref rid="aff-7" ref-type="aff">7</xref></contrib></contrib-group><aff id="aff-1">
<label>1</label>
Dermatology, Argentine Society of Dermatology, Buenos Aires, ARG </aff><aff id="aff-2">
<label>2</label>
Aesthetic Medicine, Sociedad Internacional de Rejuvenecimiento Facial No Quir&#250;rgico (SIRF), Barranquilla, COL </aff><aff id="aff-3">
<label>3</label>
Aesthetic Medicine and Clinical Research, Universidad Militar Nueva Granada, Bogota, COL </aff><aff id="aff-4">
<label>4</label>
Aesthetic Medicine, Universidad del Rosario, Cali, COL </aff><aff id="aff-5">
<label>5</label>
Dermatology, Colombian Society of Dermatology, Cali, COL </aff><aff id="aff-6">
<label>6</label>
Aesthetic Medicine, Universidad del Rosario, Bogota, COL </aff><aff id="aff-7">
<label>7</label>
Oculoplastic Surgery, Sociedad Internacional de Rejuvenecimiento Facial No Quir&#250;rgico (SIRF), Barranquilla, COL </aff><author-notes><corresp id="cor1">
Luis A. Parra Hernand&#233;z <email>info@encefalo.org</email></corresp></author-notes><pub-date date-type="pub" publication-format="electronic"><day>23</day><month>11</month><year>2024</year></pub-date><pub-date date-type="collection" publication-format="electronic"><month>11</month><year>2024</year></pub-date><volume>16</volume><issue>11</issue><issue-id pub-id-type="pmc-issue-id">474082</issue-id><elocation-id>e74297</elocation-id><history><date date-type="accepted"><day>23</day><month>11</month><year>2024</year></date></history><pub-history><event event-type="pmc-release"><date><day>23</day><month>11</month><year>2024</year></date></event><event event-type="pmc-live"><date><day>23</day><month>12</month><year>2024</year></date></event><event event-type="pmc-last-change"><date iso-8601-date="2024-12-24 10:25:53.443"><day>24</day><month>12</month><year>2024</year></date></event></pub-history><permissions><copyright-statement>Copyright &#169; 2024, Castelanich et al.</copyright-statement><copyright-year>2024</copyright-year><copyright-holder>Castelanich et al.</copyright-holder><license><ali:license_ref specific-use="textmining" content-type="ccbylicense">https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</ali:license_ref><license-p>This is an open access article distributed under the terms of the Creative Commons Attribution License CC-BY 4.0., which permits unrestricted use, distribution, and reproduction in any medium, provided the original author and source are credited.</license-p></license></permissions><self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" content-type="pmc-pdf" xlink:href="cureus-0016-00000074297.pdf"/><self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xlink:href="https://www.cureus.com/articles/317852-combined-application-of-hyaluronidase-and-collagenase-for-late-onset-edema-in-periocular-area-after-hyaluronic-acid-volume-repositioning-a-six-case-retrospective-review">This article is available from https://www.cureus.com/articles/317852-combined-application-of-hyaluronidase-and-collagenase-for-late-onset-edema-in-periocular-area-after-hyaluronic-acid-volume-repositioning-a-six-case-retrospective-review</self-uri><abstract><p>Background and objective: Although generally low-risk, hyaluronic acid (HA) dermal fillers can lead to late-onset edema, particularly in the periocular region. This condition typically manifests three to four months post-injection and requires specialized management, usually with hyaluronidase. However, increased use of hyaluronidase has resulted in instances of post-hyaluronidase syndrome, leading to unaesthetic outcomes. This study presents a retrospective case series that utilizes a novel technique combining two enzymes to improve late-onset edema and prevent post-hyaluronidase syndrome development.</p><p>Methods: From 2019 to 2024, six patients in our aesthetic clinic received a novel therapeutic approach involving co-administration of 1,500 IU of hyaluronidase and collagenase with a cannula to address late-onset edema in the periocular area.</p><p>Results: The combination of high-dose hyaluronidase and low-dose collagenase improved late-onset edema in all patients after a single treatment. Statistical analysis showed a significant improvement in aesthetic scores (P &lt; 0.05), with effect sizes of 0.89 for Hirmand, 1.3 for the Teoxane Infraorbital Hollows Scale (TIOHS), and 1.2 for O'Mahoney&#8217;s photo-numeric scale. No post-hyaluronidase syndrome or complications were observed.</p><p>Conclusions: This combined technique utilizing 1,500 IU of hyaluronidase and collagenase GH PB220 from Pbserum (Madrid, Spain) effectively achieves significant aesthetic improvements with a high safety profile, offering a promising alternative for managing late-onset edema after HA dermal filler treatments.</p></abstract><kwd-group kwd-group-type="author"><kwd>case report</kwd><kwd>collagenase</kwd><kwd>hyaluronic acid</kwd><kwd>hyaluronidase</kwd><kwd>late onset edema</kwd></kwd-group><custom-meta-group><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-status-qastatus</meta-name><meta-value>0</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-status-live</meta-name><meta-value>yes</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-status-embargo</meta-name><meta-value>no</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-status-released</meta-name><meta-value>yes</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-open-access</meta-name><meta-value>yes</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-olf</meta-name><meta-value>no</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-manuscript</meta-name><meta-value>no</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-legally-suppressed</meta-name><meta-value>no</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-has-pdf</meta-name><meta-value>yes</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-has-supplement</meta-name><meta-value>no</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-pdf-only</meta-name><meta-value>no</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-suppress-copyright</meta-name><meta-value>no</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-is-real-version</meta-name><meta-value>no</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-is-scanned-article</meta-name><meta-value>no</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-preprint</meta-name><meta-value>no</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-in-epmc</meta-name><meta-value>yes</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-license-ref</meta-name><meta-value>CC BY</meta-value></custom-meta></custom-meta-group></article-meta></front><body><sec sec-type="intro"><title>Introduction</title><p>The aging process around the eyes involves sagging upper eyelids, noticeable under-eye depressions, and changes in facial bone structure [<xref rid="REF1" ref-type="bibr">1</xref>]. Cosmetic procedures to refresh the eyelids are well-known for achieving a youthful appearance. However, the periorbital area has a complex anatomy and high vascular risk [<xref rid="REF2" ref-type="bibr">2</xref>,<xref rid="REF3" ref-type="bibr">3</xref>]. Hyaluronic acid (HA) fillers are a minimally invasive cosmetic injectable procedure used globally, with a favorable safety profile in most cases. Nevertheless, complications can occur, classified as early, late, or delayed reactions. Based on symptom onset, management options include oral antibiotics (mainly macrolides), incision/drainage, and hyaluronidase injection [<xref rid="REF2" ref-type="bibr">2</xref>].&#160;Hyaluronidase injection is the gold standard for treating HA complications [<xref rid="REF4" ref-type="bibr">4</xref>,<xref rid="REF5" ref-type="bibr">5</xref>]. Periorbital complications can be severe, including blindness, embolism, ptosis, visual alterations, pain, diplopia, ophthalmoplegia, dryness, overfilled syndrome, and the Tyndall effect [<xref rid="REF2" ref-type="bibr">2</xref>,<xref rid="REF4" ref-type="bibr">4</xref>]. Less severe complications include bruising (10-75%), color changes (4-7%), contour irregularities (11%), and swelling, fluid, or edema due to mediated or delayed hypersensitivity or hyaluronic acid degradation (15-26%) [<xref rid="REF6" ref-type="bibr">6</xref>-<xref rid="REF8" ref-type="bibr">8</xref>].</p><p>Hyaluronidase has become a crucial medication in every physician's emergency kit for filler treatments, as it is a soluble enzyme that degrades hyaluronic acid (HA) by hydrolyzing &#946; 1,4-N-acetylglucosaminidic bonds [<xref rid="REF5" ref-type="bibr">5</xref>,<xref rid="REF9" ref-type="bibr">9</xref>]. In aesthetics, physicians can use commercial formulations of hyaluronidase, including bovine (bovine testicular hyaluronidase), ovine (ovine testicular hyaluronidase), and human recombinant or bacterial recombinant enzymes, such as Pbserum (Pbserum, Madrid, Spain) from <italic toggle="yes">Streptococcus pyogenes</italic> [<xref rid="REF5" ref-type="bibr">5</xref>]. Based on their action targets, hyaluronidases can be categorized into three groups: (i) those that manipulate structural tissue characteristics through targeted degradation of hyaluronan [<xref rid="REF10" ref-type="bibr">10</xref>], (ii) those that modify tissue diffusion properties through targeted hyaluronan degradation [<xref rid="REF10" ref-type="bibr">10</xref>], and (iii)&#160;those that utilize metabolic effects through targeted reduction of hyaluronan chain lengths&#160;[<xref rid="REF10" ref-type="bibr">10</xref>].</p><p>The established guidelines recommend a 1:1 ratio of hyaluronidase to the volume of edema in the periocular area. Fifteen hundred units of hyaluronidase are typically diluted in 5 ml of sodium chloride (NaCl) and administered at 500 units per affected area [<xref rid="REF11" ref-type="bibr">11</xref>]. However, research has demonstrated that the sensitivity of an HA to degradation varies according to the type of reticular product utilized or its molecular weight. Additionally, the brand of hyaluronidase and its origin can cause the volume required to facilitate the complication to vary up to three-fold from one to another. Consequently, it has been challenging to establish a precise quantity or volume of hyaluronidase to employ in all cases necessitating it [<xref rid="REF12" ref-type="bibr">12</xref>].</p><p>While hyaluronidase has a high effectiveness profile in resolving HA-related complications, concerns have recently arisen regarding undesirable outcomes after its application, including pain, irreversible volume loss, and adverse changes in skin appearance. This condition is known as "post-hyaluronidase syndrome" [<xref rid="REF13" ref-type="bibr">13</xref>]. This condition is reported in approximately 18% of hyaluronidase applications [<xref rid="REF13" ref-type="bibr">13</xref>]. However, this syndrome's exact mechanism of action is not yet fully understood, and some authors suggest it may be related to the volume and duration of the previously injected filler [<xref rid="REF13" ref-type="bibr">13</xref>,<xref rid="REF14" ref-type="bibr">14</xref>]. Enzymatic saturation may occur, replacing HA in the extracellular matrix. Repeated hyaluronidase applications can cause enzymatic saturation, negatively impacting skin quality in the affected area [<xref rid="REF10" ref-type="bibr">10</xref>]. This risk is particularly significant in the periocular region, where the skin is thinner and more sensitive to volume loss and changes in the extracellular matrix. External factors such as pH, ambient temperature, and tissue type can also influence this risk [<xref rid="REF15" ref-type="bibr">15</xref>].</p><p>This article presents a retrospective case series of six patients who experienced late-onset edema in the periocular area between 2019 and 2024. They were treated with a new technique: applying a higher dose of hyaluronidase in a single session and combining it with collagenase to minimize post-hyaluronidase risk and improve edema.</p></sec><sec sec-type="materials|methods"><title>Materials and methods</title><p>While hyaluronidase has a high effectiveness profile in resolving HA-related complications, concerns have recently arisen regarding undesirable outcomes after its application, including pain, irreversible volume loss, and adverse changes in skin appearance. This condition is known as "post-hyaluronidase syndrome" (Figure <xref rid="FIG1" ref-type="fig">1</xref>), which can manifest as Hollowing and volume loss, reduced skin elasticity, and skin pigmentation that worsens the appearance compared to pre-treatment [<xref rid="REF13" ref-type="bibr">13</xref>].&#160;Written informed consent to include all the images in the published article was obtained from the patients.</p><fig position="anchor" fig-type="figure" id="FIG1" orientation="portrait"><label>Figure 1</label><caption><title> Post-hyaluronidase syndrome.</title><p>A 31-year-old female patient was treated with 500 IU of hyaluronidase (PB3000, Pbserum, Madrid, Spain) to remove the previous hyaluronic acid on the left infraorbital side. (A) Before treatment photos, (B) after five days of the treatment. The red arrow indicates where the skin has lost volume, changed coloration, and experienced skin atrophy.</p></caption><graphic xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" position="float" orientation="portrait" xlink:href="cureus-0016-00000074297-i01.jpg"/></fig><p>This condition is reported in approximately 18% of hyaluronidase applications [<xref rid="REF13" ref-type="bibr">13</xref>]. However, this syndrome's exact mechanism of action is not yet fully understood, and some authors suggest it may be related to the volume and duration of the previously injected filler [<xref rid="REF13" ref-type="bibr">13</xref>,<xref rid="REF14" ref-type="bibr">14</xref>]. Enzymatic saturation may occur, replacing HA in the extracellular matrix. Repeated hyaluronidase applications can cause enzymatic saturation, negatively impacting skin quality in the affected area [<xref rid="REF10" ref-type="bibr">10</xref>]. This risk is particularly significant in the periocular region, where the skin is thinner and more sensitive to volume loss and changes in the extracellular matrix. External factors such as pH, ambient temperature, and tissue type can also influence this risk [<xref rid="REF15" ref-type="bibr">15</xref>].</p><p>We present a case series of six patients who exhibited periocular edema following injections of HA fillers, specifically Juv&#233;derm Volbella (Vycross-Allergan, Irvine, CA) in patients 1 and 3 and Juv&#233;derm Volite (Vycross-Allergan, Irvine, CA) in patients 2 and 6 (see Figure <xref rid="FIG2" ref-type="fig">2</xref>). Patients 4 and 5 were unable to identify the specific HA option administered.&#160;Written informed consent to include these images in the published article was obtained from the patient(s).</p><fig position="anchor" fig-type="figure" id="FIG2" orientation="portrait"><label>Figure 2</label><caption><title>Before treatment photos from all patients.</title><p>Edema is shown in all six patients (1-6) due to the application of HA at the tear trough level to enhance the periocular area.</p><p>Patient #1: A 47-year-old female patient treated with Juv&#233;derm Volbella (Vycross-Allergan, Irvine, CA); 0.3 ml was applied on each side, and edema remained two months later.</p><p>Patient #2: A 50-year-old female patient treated with Juv&#233;derm Volite (Vycross-Allergan, Irvine, CA); approximately 0.25 ml was applied on each side, presenting edema three months later.</p><p>Patient #3: A 37-year-old female patient treated with Juv&#233;derm Volbella (Vycross-Allergan, Irvine, CA); 0.2 ml was applied on each side, with edema present one month later.</p><p>Patient #4: A 42-year-old female patient whose specific HA treatment was unknown; edema was observed four and a half months later.</p><p>Patient #5: A 30-year-old female patient whose specific HA treatment was unknown; edema was present two months later.</p><p>Patient #6: A 42-year-old male patient treated with Juv&#233;derm Volite (Vycross-Allergan, Irvine, CA); approximately 0.35 ml was applied on each side, and edema was noted five months later.</p></caption><graphic xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" position="float" orientation="portrait" xlink:href="cureus-0016-00000074297-i02.jpg"/></fig><p>Desiree Castelanich conceptualized the technique in her private clinic in Buenos Aires, Argentina, where aesthetic medicine procedures are performed. She collaborated with Andrea Marcela Parra, an oculoplastic surgeon, and Luis Alberto Parra, an aesthetic physician. Together, the three practitioners treated the first three patients in Buenos Aires.</p><p>The remaining three patients were treated in various cities in Colombia by specialists who replicated the technique, adhering to the same dilution and application protocol.</p><p>All patients were classified as non-serious adverse events due to late-onset edema, and we applied Hirmand&#8217;s classification system&#160;[<xref rid="REF16" ref-type="bibr">16</xref>], Teoxane Infraorbital Hollows Scale (TIOHS) [<xref rid="REF17" ref-type="bibr">17</xref>], and O&#8217;Mahoney&#8217;s photo numeric scale [<xref rid="REF18" ref-type="bibr">18</xref>]&#160;to evaluate the cosmetic outcome two months after management.</p><p>Hyaluronidase was recommended for the skin around the lower eyelid. However, using hyaluronidase in this area can lead to significant skin quality deterioration, including atrophy and changes in skin color, all of which are symptoms associated with "post-hyaluronidase syndrome&#8221; [<xref rid="REF13" ref-type="bibr">13</xref>]. To mitigate this issue, we have developed an alternative treatment protocol that combines high-dose hyaluronidase with collagenase.</p><p>Description of technique</p><p>A comprehensive knowledge of the peri-orbicular anatomy is essential to deliver a safe treatment. The anatomy involves the skin measuring less than 1 mm with minimal subdermal fat&#160;[<xref rid="REF19" ref-type="bibr">19</xref>,<xref rid="REF20" ref-type="bibr">20</xref>]. The excessive swelling after injection in this area is believed to be due to tight ligament connections and restricted lymphatic drainage [<xref rid="REF20" ref-type="bibr">20</xref>].</p><p>After a very detailed review of the location of edema in each patient, we decided to perform a combination of hyaluronidase with collagenase. &#8203;&#8203;&#8203;&#8203;&#8203;&#8203;Diluted hyaluronidase and collagenase<italic toggle="yes">&#160;</italic>can be mixed as follows: (i) Start by diluting 1,500 IU of hyaluronidase (PB3000, PBSerum, Madrid, Spain) in 1.5 mL of 0.9% sodium chloride; (ii) dilute collagenase GH PB220 (Pbserum, Madrid, Spain) in 1.5 mL of standard saline solution containing 0.9% sodium chloride; (iii) mix 1.5 mL of hyaluronidase with 0.5 mL of collagenase to make 2 mL after dilution; (iv) apply this 2 mL combination to the area where the skin's appearance is targeted for improvement after the HA application. Depending on each patient's dermal thickness, you can administer it using a 27G x 50 mm or 25G x 50 mm cannula.</p><p>Chlorhexidine was used to cleanse the skin, and it was then left to air dry. The procedure was performed in small amounts using retrograde movements&#160;to cover the entire area, and one session was performed for all patients.</p></sec><sec sec-type="results"><title>Results</title><p>Two months after the enzymatic treatment (Figures <xref rid="FIG3" ref-type="fig">3</xref>, <xref rid="FIG4" ref-type="fig">4</xref>), no additional application of hyaluronidase was necessary. The results were satisfactory and aesthetically pleasing for the area, with no visible edema, loss of volume, or changes associated with post-hyaluronidase syndrome.&#160;Written informed consent to include these images in the published article was obtained from the patient(s).</p><fig position="anchor" fig-type="figure" id="FIG3" orientation="portrait"><label>Figure 3</label><caption><title>Follow-up photos for patients 1, 2, and 3.</title><p>The photos&#160;show&#160;the before-and-after protocols for patients 1, 2, and 3 treated with the hyaluronidase + collagenase protocol; (A) before, and (B)&#160;two months after the treatment.</p></caption><graphic xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" position="float" orientation="portrait" xlink:href="cureus-0016-00000074297-i03.jpg"/></fig><fig position="anchor" fig-type="figure" id="FIG4" orientation="portrait"><label>Figure 4</label><caption><title>Follow-up photos for patients 4, 5, and 6.</title><p>The photos&#160;show&#160;the before-and-after protocols for patients 4, 5, and 6 treated with the hyaluronidase + collagenase protocol; (A) before, and (B)&#160;two months after the treatment.</p></caption><graphic xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" position="float" orientation="portrait" xlink:href="cureus-0016-00000074297-i04.jpg"/></fig><p>The outcomes were evaluated using Hirmand&#8217;s classification system [<xref rid="REF16" ref-type="bibr">16</xref>], the Teoxane Infraorbital Hollows Scale (TIOHS) [<xref rid="REF17" ref-type="bibr">17</xref>], and O&#8217;Mahoney&#8217;s photo-numeric scale [<xref rid="REF18" ref-type="bibr">18</xref>] to evaluate changes in the patients, and these results are presented in Table <xref rid="TAB1" ref-type="table">1</xref>.</p><table-wrap position="float" id="TAB1" orientation="portrait"><label>Table 1</label><caption><title>Before and after Hirmand&#8217;s classification system [<xref rid="REF16" ref-type="bibr">16</xref>], Teoxane Infraorbital Hollows Scale (TIOHS) [<xref rid="REF17" ref-type="bibr">17</xref>], and O&#8217;Mahoney&#8217;s photo numeric scale [<xref rid="REF18" ref-type="bibr">18</xref>] to evaluate the cosmetic outcome two months after management.</title></caption><table frame="hsides" rules="groups"><tbody><tr style="background-color:#ccc"><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Patient</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Before Hirmand&#8217;s classification system &#160;[<xref rid="REF16" ref-type="bibr">16</xref>]</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">After Hirmand&#8217;s classification system [<xref rid="REF16" ref-type="bibr">16</xref>]</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Before Teoxane Infraorbital Hollows Scale (TIOHS) [<xref rid="REF17" ref-type="bibr">17</xref>]</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">After Teoxane Infraorbital Hollows Scale (TIOHS) [<xref rid="REF17" ref-type="bibr">17</xref>]</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Before O&#8217;Mahoney&#8217;s photo numeric scale [<xref rid="REF18" ref-type="bibr">18</xref>]</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">After O&#8217;Mahoney&#8217;s photo numeric scale [<xref rid="REF18" ref-type="bibr">18</xref>]</td></tr><tr><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">1</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Class III</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Class II</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">4</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">2</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">8</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">3</td></tr><tr style="background-color:#ccc"><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">2</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Class III</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Class I</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">5</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">1</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">8</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">4</td></tr><tr><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">3</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Class II</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Class II</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">3</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">2</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">5</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">3</td></tr><tr style="background-color:#ccc"><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">4</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Class II</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Class I</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">3</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">2</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">5</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">2</td></tr><tr><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">5</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Class III</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Class I</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">4</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">2</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">7</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">3</td></tr><tr style="background-color:#ccc"><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">6</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Class II</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Class I</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">3</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">1</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">5</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">2</td></tr></tbody></table></table-wrap><p>Statistical analysis was conducted using IBM SPSS Statistics, version 30.0 (IBM Corp., Armonk, NY, USA). The Paired-Samples T-test was employed to evaluate and compare changes in Hirmand's&#160;classification system, Teoxane Infraorbital Hollows Scale (TIOHS) classification, and O'Mahoney's photo-numeric scale. The results indicate that all three interventions (Hirmand, TIOHS, and O'Mahoney) resulted in a statistically significant improvement in scores when comparing post-intervention to pre-intervention measurements (P &lt; 0.05 for all scales and classifications). The effect size varied among the interventions, with O'Mahoney demonstrating the most substantial effect. The Hedges correction provided a more precise effect size estimate by accounting for sample size, resulting in 0.89 for Hirmand's, 1.3 for TIOHS, and 1.2 for O'Mahoney (Table <xref rid="TAB2" ref-type="table">2</xref>). Consequently, the pre-and post-intervention results demonstrated a statistically significant difference in the aesthetic appearance of the&#160;patients' faces following treatment, as determined by four blinded evaluators who assessed the photographs.</p><table-wrap position="float" id="TAB2" orientation="portrait"><label>Table 2</label><caption><title>Effect sizes of paired samples. Results show all interventions (Hirmand, TIOHS, and O'Mahoney) significantly improve scores from &#8216;Before&#8217; to &#8216;After&#8217; (P &lt; 0.05). Effect sizes differ, with O'Mahoney having the largest. Hedges correction, accounting for sample size, estimates effect sizes as 0.89 for Hirmand, 1.3 for TIOHS, and 1.2 for O'Mahoney.</title><p>a: The denominator used in the estimation of effect sizes is the sample standard deviation of the mean difference, along with a correction factor provided by the Hedges correction.</p><p>Hirmand&#8217;s classification system [<xref rid="REF16" ref-type="bibr">16</xref>], Teoxane Infraorbital Hollows Scale (TIOHS) [<xref rid="REF17" ref-type="bibr">17</xref>], and O&#8217;Mahoney&#8217;s photo numeric scale [<xref rid="REF18" ref-type="bibr">18</xref>].</p></caption><table frame="hsides" rules="groups"><tbody><tr style="background-color:#ccc"><td colspan="2" rowspan="2">&#160;</td><td colspan="2" rowspan="1">95% confidence interval of difference</td><td rowspan="2" colspan="1">P value</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">&#160;</td></tr><tr><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Inf.</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Sup.</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Hedges correction<sup>a</sup>
</td></tr><tr style="background-color:#ccc"><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Par 1</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Before_Hirmand - After_Hirmand</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">.377</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">1.957</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">.013</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">.895</td></tr><tr><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Par 2</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Before_TIOHS - After_TIOHS</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">.850</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">3.150</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">.007</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">1.303</td></tr><tr style="background-color:#ccc"><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Par 3</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Before_O&#8217;Mahoney&#8217;s - After_O&#8217;Mahoney&#8217;s</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">2.399</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">4.601</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">&lt; .001</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">1.247</td></tr></tbody></table></table-wrap></sec><sec sec-type="discussion"><title>Discussion</title><p>Injectable fillers are gaining popularity but may require dissolution for various reasons, primarily due to swelling or the Tyndall effect in the periorbital area. Distinguishing between overfill and swelling can be challenging. However, it is generally accepted that swelling is more pronounced in the morning, indicating edema caused by the filler's hydrophilic properties and daily fluctuations in body fluid distribution [<xref rid="REF13" ref-type="bibr">13</xref>].</p><p>Wilde et al. (2024) first described "post-hyaluronidase syndrome," which involves hollowing and loss of volume, decreased skin elasticity, or skin pigmentation exceeding the appearance before the initial treatment [<xref rid="REF13" ref-type="bibr">13</xref>]. According to their data, this syndrome could be found in 18% of patients who received hyaluronidase [<xref rid="REF13" ref-type="bibr">13</xref>]. These findings were already evident to the authors in previous applications of hyaluronidase to remove HA previously positioned in the periocular area. Despite using low doses (approximately 500 IU of hyaluronidase per treatment), patients presented irreversible loss of natural volume and skin quality in the area (Figure <xref rid="FIG1" ref-type="fig">1</xref>).</p><p>After this experience, we evaluated a method to prevent post-hyaluronidase complications when removing HA from the periocular area. According to scientific literature, hyaluronidase can manage various complications and restore the effects of injected fillers. Recent studies have described the successful treatment of epidermoid cysts with recombinant hydrolytic enzymes by mixing hyaluronidase with other components [<xref rid="REF21" ref-type="bibr">21</xref>].</p><p>Based on this evidence, we combined hyaluronidase with collagenases GH PB220 (Pbserum, Madrid, Spain). These collagenases break down collagen and offer benefits beyond their primary function, including promoting dermal cell regeneration, protecting against cell death and inflammation, and accelerating wound healing [<xref rid="REF22" ref-type="bibr">22</xref>]. Bacterial-origin collagenases show significant effectiveness in breaking down collagen, promoting granulation tissue development, reducing inflammation, aiding epithelial cell regrowth, and speeding up wound healing. This highlights collagenase's potential in skin rejuvenation, scar management, and surgery preparation [<xref rid="REF21" ref-type="bibr">21</xref>,<xref rid="REF23" ref-type="bibr">23</xref>].</p><p>Varani et al. and similar literature suggest that dermal fibroblasts are connected to undamaged collagen fibrils and apply pulling forces to maintain standard cell structure and mechanical tension [<xref rid="REF24" ref-type="bibr">24</xref>]. With aging, collagen fibrils become fragmented, leading to decreased fibroblast binding and reduced mechanical stability. These changes hinder fibroblasts' spreading, mechanical forces, and functions [<xref rid="REF24" ref-type="bibr">24</xref>,<xref rid="REF25" ref-type="bibr">25</xref>]. A critical feature of dermal fibroblasts in aged skin is diminished spreading and interaction with collagen fibrils, leading to a collapsed appearance. The cells deviate from their usual elongated spindle-like shape and become shorter, taking on a rounded and collapsed form [<xref rid="REF24" ref-type="bibr">24</xref>].</p><p>Our technique represents a shift in the understanding of hyaluronidase usage. We propose administering a significantly higher dose in a single session, combining 1,500 IU of hyaluronidase (hyaluronidase PB3000, Pbserum, Madrid, Spain) diluted in 1.5 ml of 0.9% normal saline with 0.5 ml of a prepared dilution of collagenase GH PB220 (Pbserum, Madrid, Spain). We invite injectors to consider this combination to stimulate fibroblastic activity, thereby preventing skin retraction by altering fibroblast tension and the structure of the extracellular matrix, which can trigger the recovery of the entire extracellular matrix.</p><p>Four blinded assessors with extensive injectable experience reviewed before-and-after photographs using three scales to measure aesthetic improvement. Although these scales do not specifically assess complications, we suggested they evaluate the overall enhancement of these cases. The changes were then compared statistically using the paired t-test and Hedges' correction to determine effect size and correct for estimation bias. These tests indicated a statistically significant decrease in adverse outcomes, with a positive mean difference in both cases, suggesting improvement after treatment. According to the confidence interval results and Hedges' correction in a small sample, we can conclude that the management successfully enhanced the aesthetic appearance of the treated patients.</p><p>A fundamental limitation of our study is the small number of patients treated; the technique has only been tested on six patients. Despite this limitation, the results appear promising and suggest that practitioners in various countries could easily replicate this approach regardless of patients' skin types. This is one of the main strengths of our study, as three patients were treated in Argentina and three in Colombia, demonstrating the technique's adaptability and replication potential. In the future, we hope to continue accumulating data to validate these findings further.</p></sec><sec sec-type="conclusions"><title>Conclusions</title><p>We propose a novel technique combining 1,500 IU of hyaluronidase (hyaluronidase PB3000, Pbserum, Madrid, Spain) with collagenase GH PB220 (Pbserum, Madrid, Spain) in the same syringe to correct late-onset edema in the periocular region after HA applications. This approach demonstrates a high safety profile in the four patients studied. It provides evidence of improved edema in a single session using an average of 1,500 IU of hyaluronidase without triggering symptoms of post-hyaluronidase syndrome.</p><p>Statistical analysis revealed a significant improvement in aesthetic scores, with a positive mean difference observed in the paired t-test results (P &lt; 0.05) across all scales used. The Hedges correction indicated effect sizes of 0.89 for Hirmand, 1.3 for TIOHS, and 1.2 for O'Mahoney, further supporting the efficacy of our approach. Although the study's limited sample size may preclude definitive conclusions, exploring alternative solutions for managing HA complications that require fewer applications while preserving the extracellular matrix and skin quality is essential. This study may pave the way for future histological and cellular function analyses to confirm the product's positive effects.</p></sec></body><back><ack><p>The authors would like to thank Dr. Karina Ravera, a radiologist and specialist in aesthetic medicine at the University of Buenos Aires, Argentina, for performing an ultrasound on one of the patients treated with this technique.</p></ack><fn-group content-type="conflict"><title>Disclosures</title><fn fn-type="COI-statement"><p><bold>Human subjects:</bold> Consent for treatment and open access publication was obtained or waived by all participants in this study.</p><p><bold>Animal subjects:</bold> All authors have confirmed that this study did not involve animal subjects or tissue.</p><p><bold>Conflicts of interest:</bold> In compliance with the ICMJE uniform disclosure form, all authors declare the following:</p><p><bold>Payment/services info:</bold> All authors have declared that no financial support was received from any organization for the submitted work.</p><p><bold>Financial relationships:</bold> All authors have declared that they have no financial relationships at present or within the previous three years with any organizations that might have an interest in the submitted work.</p><p><bold>Other relationships:</bold> All authors have declared that there are no other relationships or activities that could appear to have influenced the submitted work.</p></fn></fn-group><fn-group content-type="other"><title>Author Contributions</title><fn fn-type="other"><p><bold>Concept and design:</bold>&#160; Luis A. Parra Hernand&#233;z, Desiree Giselle Castelanich, Diana A. Acevedo, Lina Vel&#225;squez, Valentina Dicker, Andrea M. Parra Hernandez, Andreina Martinez Amado</p><p><bold>Acquisition, analysis, or interpretation of data:</bold>&#160; Luis A. Parra Hernand&#233;z, Desiree Giselle Castelanich, Diana A. Acevedo, Lina Vel&#225;squez, Valentina Dicker, Andrea M. Parra Hernandez, Andreina Martinez Amado</p><p><bold>Drafting of the manuscript:</bold>&#160; Luis A. Parra Hernand&#233;z, Desiree Giselle Castelanich, Diana A. Acevedo, Lina Vel&#225;squez, Valentina Dicker, Andrea M. Parra Hernandez, Andreina Martinez Amado</p><p><bold>Critical review of the manuscript for important intellectual content:</bold>&#160; Luis A. Parra Hernand&#233;z, Desiree Giselle Castelanich, Diana A. Acevedo, Lina Vel&#225;squez, Valentina Dicker, Andrea M. Parra Hernandez, Andreina Martinez Amado</p><p><bold>Supervision:</bold>&#160; Luis A. Parra Hernand&#233;z, Desiree Giselle Castelanich, Diana A. Acevedo, Lina Vel&#225;squez, Valentina Dicker, Andrea M. Parra Hernandez, Andreina Martinez Amado</p></fn></fn-group><ref-list><title>References</title><ref id="REF1"><label>1</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><article-title>Fat or fillers: the dilemma in eyelid surgery</article-title><source>World J Clin Cases</source><person-group><name name-style="western"><surname>Miotti</surname><given-names>G</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>De Marco</surname><given-names>L</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Quaglia</surname><given-names>D</given-names></name><etal/></person-group><fpage>2951</fpage><lpage>2965</lpage><volume>12</volume><year>2024</year><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">38898854</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.12998/wjcc.v12.i17.2951</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC11185368</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="REF2"><label>2</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><article-title>Ocular complications post-cosmetic periocular hyaluronic acid injections: a systematic review</article-title><source>Aesthetic Plast Surg</source><person-group><name name-style="western"><surname>Mortada</surname><given-names>H</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Seraj</surname><given-names>H</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Barasain</surname><given-names>O</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Bamakhrama</surname><given-names>B</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Alhindi</surname><given-names>NI</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Arab</surname><given-names>K</given-names></name></person-group><fpage>760</fpage><lpage>773</lpage><volume>46</volume><year>2022</year><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">35091771</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1007/s00266-021-02730-5</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="REF3"><label>3</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><article-title>Vision loss associated with hyaluronic acid fillers: a systematic review of literature</article-title><source>Aesthetic Plast Surg</source><person-group><name name-style="western"><surname>Kapoor</surname><given-names>KM</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Kapoor</surname><given-names>P</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Heydenrych</surname><given-names>I</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Bertossi</surname><given-names>D</given-names></name></person-group><fpage>929</fpage><lpage>944</lpage><volume>44</volume><year>2020</year><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">31822960</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1007/s00266-019-01562-8</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="REF4"><label>4</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><article-title>Hyaluronic acid gel injection for the treatment of tear trough deformity: a multicenter, observational, single-blind study</article-title><source>Aesthetic Plast Surg</source><person-group><name name-style="western"><surname>Diaspro</surname><given-names>A</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Calvisi</surname><given-names>L</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Sito</surname><given-names>G</given-names></name></person-group><fpage>1860</fpage><lpage>1867</lpage><volume>46</volume><year>2022</year><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">35478038</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1007/s00266-022-02887-7</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="REF5"><label>5</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><article-title>Hyaluronidase injection for the treatment of eyelid edema: a retrospective analysis of 20 patients</article-title><source>Eur J Med Res</source><person-group><name name-style="western"><surname>Hilton</surname><given-names>S</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Schrumpf</surname><given-names>H</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Buhren</surname><given-names>BA</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>B&#246;lke</surname><given-names>E</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Gerber</surname><given-names>PA</given-names></name></person-group><fpage>30</fpage><volume>19</volume><year>2014</year><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">24886711</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1186/2047-783X-19-30</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC4063423</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="REF6"><label>6</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><article-title>Filling the periorbital hollows with hyaluronic acid gel: initial experience with 244 injections</article-title><source>Ophthalmic Plast Reconstr Surg</source><person-group><name name-style="western"><surname>Goldberg</surname><given-names>RA</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Fiaschetti</surname><given-names>D</given-names></name></person-group><fpage>335</fpage><lpage>341</lpage><volume>22</volume><year>2006</year><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">16985414</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1097/01.iop.0000235820.00633.61</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="REF7"><label>7</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><article-title>Brighter eyes: combined upper cheek and tear trough augmentation: a systematic approach utilizing two complementary hyaluronic acid fillers</article-title><source>J Drugs Dermatol</source><person-group><name name-style="western"><surname>Tung</surname><given-names>R</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Ruiz de Luzuriaga</surname><given-names>AM</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Park</surname><given-names>K</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Sato</surname><given-names>M</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Dubina</surname><given-names>M</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Alam</surname><given-names>M</given-names></name></person-group><fpage>1094</fpage><lpage>1097</lpage><volume>11</volume><year>2012</year><uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xlink:href="https://jddonline.com/articles/p-classarticles-case-article-headlinebrighter-eyes-combined-upper-cheek-and-tear-trough-augmentation-S1545961612P1094X/">https://jddonline.com/articles/p-classarticles-case-article-headlinebrighter-eyes-combined-upper-cheek-and-tear-trough-augmentation-S1545961612P1094X/</uri><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">23135653</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="REF8"><label>8</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><article-title>Static and dynamic filler-associated tear trough deformities: manifestations and treatment algorithm</article-title><source>Aesthetic Plast Surg</source><person-group><name name-style="western"><surname>Kang</surname><given-names>Y</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Wang</surname><given-names>S</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Xia</surname><given-names>Z</given-names></name><etal/></person-group><fpage>2642</fpage><lpage>2650</lpage><volume>48</volume><year>2024</year><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">38727846</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1007/s00266-024-04089-9</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="REF9"><label>9</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><article-title>Hyaluronidase in the office: a necessity for every dermasurgeon that injects hyaluronic acid</article-title><source>J Cosmet Laser Ther</source><person-group><name name-style="western"><surname>Hirsch</surname><given-names>RJ</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Brody</surname><given-names>HJ</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Carruthers</surname><given-names>JD</given-names></name></person-group><fpage>182</fpage><lpage>185</lpage><volume>9</volume><year>2007</year><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">17763028</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1080/14764170701291674</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="REF10"><label>10</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><article-title>Hyaluronidase: An overview of its properties, applications, and side effects</article-title><source>Arch Plast Surg</source><person-group><name name-style="western"><surname>Jung</surname><given-names>H</given-names></name></person-group><fpage>297</fpage><lpage>300</lpage><volume>47</volume><year>2020</year><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">32718106</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.5999/aps.2020.00752</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC7398804</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="REF11"><label>11</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><article-title>Updated filler emergency kit: next-generation emergency solution</article-title><source>Aesthetic Plast Surg</source><person-group><name name-style="western"><surname>Fakih-Gomez</surname><given-names>N</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Porcar Plana</surname><given-names>CA</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Verano-Garcia</surname><given-names>A</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Mu&#241;oz-Gonzalez</surname><given-names>C</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Kadouch</surname><given-names>J</given-names></name></person-group><fpage>1174</fpage><lpage>1180</lpage><volume>48</volume><year>2024</year><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">37957396</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1007/s00266-023-03722-3</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="REF12"><label>12</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><article-title>Durability, behavior, and tolerability of 5 hyaluronidase products</article-title><source>Dermatol Surg</source><person-group><name name-style="western"><surname>Casabona</surname><given-names>G</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Marchese</surname><given-names>PB</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Montes</surname><given-names>JR</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Hornfeldt</surname><given-names>CS</given-names></name></person-group><fpage>0</fpage><lpage>50</lpage><volume>44 Suppl 1</volume><year>2018</year><pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1097/DSS.0000000000001562</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">29894436</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="REF13"><label>13</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><article-title>The posthyaluronidase syndrome: dosing strategies for hyaluronidase in the dissolving of facial filler and independent predictors of poor outcomes</article-title><source>Plast Reconstr Surg Glob Open</source><person-group><name name-style="western"><surname>Wilde</surname><given-names>CL</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Jiang</surname><given-names>K</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Lee</surname><given-names>S</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Ezra</surname><given-names>DG</given-names></name></person-group><fpage>0</fpage><volume>12</volume><year>2024</year><pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1097/GOX.0000000000005765</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC11037726</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">38655103</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="REF14"><label>14</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><article-title>Expansion and delivery of adipose-derived mesenchymal stem cells on three microcarriers for soft tissue regeneration</article-title><source>Tissue Eng Part A</source><person-group><name name-style="western"><surname>Zhou</surname><given-names>Y</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Yan</surname><given-names>Z</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Zhang</surname><given-names>H</given-names></name><etal/></person-group><fpage>2981</fpage><lpage>2997</lpage><volume>17</volume><year>2011</year><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">21875329</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1089/ten.tea.2010.0707</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="REF15"><label>15</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><article-title>Late-onset reactions after hyaluronic acid dermal fillers: a consensus recommendation on etiology, prevention and management</article-title><source>Dermatol Ther (Heidelb)</source><person-group><name name-style="western"><surname>Baranska-Rybak</surname><given-names>W</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Lajo-Plaza</surname><given-names>JV</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Walker</surname><given-names>L</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Alizadeh</surname><given-names>N</given-names></name></person-group><fpage>1767</fpage><lpage>1785</lpage><volume>14</volume><year>2024</year><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">38907876</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1007/s13555-024-01202-3</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC11265052</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="REF16"><label>16</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><article-title>Anatomy and nonsurgical correction of the tear trough deformity</article-title><source>Plast Reconstr Surg</source><person-group><name name-style="western"><surname>Hirmand</surname><given-names>H</given-names></name></person-group><fpage>699</fpage><lpage>708</lpage><volume>125</volume><year>2010</year><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">20124855</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1097/PRS.0b013e3181c82f90</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="REF17"><label>17</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><article-title>Creation and validation of a photonumeric scale for assessment of infraorbital hollows</article-title><source>Dermatol Surg</source><person-group><name name-style="western"><surname>Carey</surname><given-names>W</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Tr&#233;vidic</surname><given-names>P</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Benedetto</surname><given-names>AV</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Maffert</surname><given-names>P</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Antunes</surname><given-names>S</given-names></name></person-group><fpage>777</fpage><lpage>782</lpage><volume>49</volume><year>2023</year><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">37523595</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1097/DSS.0000000000003851</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC10377239</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="REF18"><label>18</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><article-title>A validated photonumeric scale for infraorbital dark circles and its application in evaluating the efficacy of a cosmetic treatment product in a split-face randomized clinical trial</article-title><source>Int J Cosmet Sci</source><person-group><name name-style="western"><surname>O'Mahony</surname><given-names>MM</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Sladen</surname><given-names>C</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Crone</surname><given-names>M</given-names></name><etal/></person-group><fpage>48</fpage><lpage>56</lpage><volume>43</volume><year>2021</year><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">33038017</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1111/ics.12668</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC7898348</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="REF19"><label>19</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><article-title>Anatomical study of the dorsal nasal artery to prevent visual complications during dorsal nasal augmentation</article-title><source>Plast Reconstr Surg Glob Open</source><person-group><name name-style="western"><surname>Tansatit</surname><given-names>T</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Jitaree</surname><given-names>B</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Uruwan</surname><given-names>S</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Rungsawang</surname><given-names>C</given-names></name></person-group><fpage>0</fpage><volume>9</volume><year>2021</year><pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1097/GOX.0000000000003924</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC8594662</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">34796083</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="REF20"><label>20</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><article-title>Cannula Versus Needle for Rejuvenation of the Perioribital Region</article-title><source>Adv Cosmet Surg</source><person-group><name name-style="western"><surname>Safran</surname><given-names>T</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Nikolis</surname><given-names>A</given-names></name></person-group><fpage>39</fpage><lpage>47</lpage><volume>7</volume><year>2024</year></element-citation></ref><ref id="REF21"><label>21</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><article-title>Successfully nonsurgical epidermoid cyst management with recombinant hydrolytic enzymes: a case report</article-title><source>Clin Cosmet Investig Dermatol</source><person-group><name name-style="western"><surname>Castelanich</surname><given-names>DG</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Parra Hern&#225;ndez</surname><given-names>LA</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Chac&#237;n</surname><given-names>M</given-names></name></person-group><fpage>1815</fpage><lpage>1822</lpage><volume>17</volume><year>2024</year><uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xlink:href="https://doi.org/10.2147/CCID.S442955">https://doi.org/10.2147/CCID.S442955</uri><pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.2147/CCID.S442955</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC11321352</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">39139846</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="REF22"><label>22</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><article-title>Targeting matrix metalloproteases to improve cutaneous wound healing</article-title><source>Expert Opin Ther Targets</source><person-group><name name-style="western"><surname>Xue</surname><given-names>M</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Le</surname><given-names>NT</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Jackson</surname><given-names>CJ</given-names></name></person-group><fpage>143</fpage><lpage>155</lpage><volume>10</volume><year>2006</year><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">16441234</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1517/14728222.10.1.143</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="REF23"><label>23</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><article-title>Increased inflammation delays wound healing in mice deficient in collagenase-2 (MMP-8)</article-title><source>FASEB J</source><person-group><name name-style="western"><surname>Guti&#233;rrez-Fern&#225;ndez</surname><given-names>A</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Inada</surname><given-names>M</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Balb&#237;n</surname><given-names>M</given-names></name><etal/></person-group><fpage>2580</fpage><lpage>2591</lpage><volume>21</volume><year>2007</year><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">17392479</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1096/fj.06-7860com</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC2575772</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="REF24"><label>24</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><article-title>Reduced fibroblast interaction with intact collagen as a mechanism for depressed collagen synthesis in photodamaged skin</article-title><source>J Invest Dermatol</source><person-group><name name-style="western"><surname>Varani</surname><given-names>J</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Schuger</surname><given-names>L</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Dame</surname><given-names>MK</given-names></name><etal/></person-group><fpage>1471</fpage><lpage>1479</lpage><volume>122</volume><year>2004</year><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">15175039</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1111/j.0022-202X.2004.22614.x</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="REF25"><label>25</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><article-title>Age-associated reduction of cellular spreading/mechanical force up-regulates matrix metalloproteinase-1 expression and collagen fibril fragmentation via c-Jun/AP-1 in human dermal fibroblasts</article-title><source>Aging Cell</source><person-group><name name-style="western"><surname>Qin</surname><given-names>Z</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Voorhees</surname><given-names>JJ</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Fisher</surname><given-names>GJ</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Quan</surname><given-names>T</given-names></name></person-group><fpage>1028</fpage><lpage>1037</lpage><volume>13</volume><year>2014</year><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">25201474</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1111/acel.12265</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC4326925</pub-id></element-citation></ref></ref-list></back></article></pmc-articleset>