<?xml version="1.0"  ?><!DOCTYPE pmc-articleset PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD ARTICLE SET 2.0//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pmc/articleset/nlm-articleset-2.0.dtd"><pmc-articleset><article xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" xmlns:ali="http://www.niso.org/schemas/ali/1.0/" article-type="case-report" xml:lang="en" dtd-version="1.4"><processing-meta base-tagset="archiving" mathml-version="3.0" table-model="xhtml" tagset-family="jats"><restricted-by>pmc</restricted-by></processing-meta><front><journal-meta><journal-id journal-id-type="nlm-ta">Acta Neurochir (Wien)</journal-id><journal-id journal-id-type="iso-abbrev">Acta Neurochir (Wien)</journal-id><journal-id journal-id-type="pmc-domain-id">365</journal-id><journal-id journal-id-type="pmc-domain">springeropen</journal-id><journal-title-group><journal-title>Acta Neurochirurgica</journal-title></journal-title-group><issn pub-type="ppub">0001-6268</issn><issn pub-type="epub">0942-0940</issn><custom-meta-group><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-is-collection-domain</meta-name><meta-value>yes</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-collection-title</meta-name><meta-value>Springer</meta-value></custom-meta></custom-meta-group></journal-meta><article-meta><article-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC12488740</article-id><article-id pub-id-type="pmcid-ver">PMC12488740.1</article-id><article-id pub-id-type="pmcaid">12488740</article-id><article-id pub-id-type="pmcaiid">12488740</article-id><article-id pub-id-type="pmid">41032126</article-id><article-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1007/s00701-025-06674-6</article-id><article-id pub-id-type="publisher-id">6674</article-id><article-version article-version-type="pmc-version">1</article-version><article-categories><subj-group subj-group-type="heading"><subject>Case Report</subject></subj-group></article-categories><title-group><article-title>A case of hypertension due to iatrogenic glossopharyngeal neuropathy after aesthetic procedure</article-title></title-group><contrib-group><contrib contrib-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>TUN&#199;</surname><given-names initials="E">Erdin&#231;</given-names></name><xref ref-type="aff" rid="Aff1">1</xref></contrib><contrib contrib-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Turan</surname><given-names initials="T">Tansel</given-names></name><xref ref-type="aff" rid="Aff2">2</xref></contrib><contrib contrib-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Acu</surname><given-names initials="&#x130;H">&#304;rem Hengirmen</given-names></name><xref ref-type="aff" rid="Aff2">2</xref></contrib><contrib contrib-type="author" corresp="yes"><name name-style="western"><surname>Aygun</surname><given-names initials="H">Hatice</given-names></name><address><email>hatice_5aygun@hotmail.com</email></address><xref ref-type="aff" rid="Aff3">3</xref><xref ref-type="aff" rid="Aff4">4</xref></contrib><aff id="Aff1"><label>1</label><institution-wrap><institution-id institution-id-type="ROR">https://ror.org/01nkhmn89</institution-id><institution-id institution-id-type="GRID">grid.488405.5</institution-id><institution-id institution-id-type="ISNI">0000 0004 4673 0690</institution-id><institution>Faculty of Medicine, Department of Anatomy, </institution><institution>Biruni University, </institution></institution-wrap>Istanbul, Turkey </aff><aff id="Aff2"><label>2</label>Reborn Clinics Academy, Tesikiye Mah. Hakk&#305; Yeten Cad. No:11, Istanbul, Turkey </aff><aff id="Aff3"><label>3</label>K&#305;z&#305;l&#305;rmak, 1071 Plaza B Blok Kat:28 No:180, 1443. Cd., Ankara, 06510 Turkey </aff><aff id="Aff4"><label>4</label><institution-wrap><institution-id institution-id-type="ROR">https://ror.org/01nkhmn89</institution-id><institution-id institution-id-type="GRID">grid.488405.5</institution-id><institution-id institution-id-type="ISNI">0000 0004 4673 0690</institution-id><institution>Neuroscience Laboratory, </institution><institution>BAMER, Biruni University, </institution></institution-wrap>Istanbul, Turkey </aff></contrib-group><pub-date pub-type="epub"><day>1</day><month>10</month><year>2025</year></pub-date><pub-date pub-type="ppub"><year>2025</year></pub-date><volume>167</volume><issue>1</issue><issue-id pub-id-type="pmc-issue-id">498144</issue-id><elocation-id>262</elocation-id><history><date date-type="received"><day>8</day><month>4</month><year>2025</year></date><date date-type="accepted"><day>7</day><month>9</month><year>2025</year></date></history><pub-history><event event-type="pmc-release"><date><day>01</day><month>10</month><year>2025</year></date></event><event event-type="pmc-live"><date><day>03</day><month>10</month><year>2025</year></date></event><event event-type="pmc-last-change"><date iso-8601-date="2025-10-03 00:25:14.440"><day>03</day><month>10</month><year>2025</year></date></event></pub-history><permissions><copyright-statement>&#169; The Author(s) 2025</copyright-statement><copyright-year>2025</copyright-year><license><ali:license_ref specific-use="textmining" content-type="ccbyncndlicense">https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/4.0/</ali:license_ref><license-p><bold>Open Access</bold> This article is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-NoDerivatives 4.0 International License, which permits any non-commercial use, sharing, distribution and reproduction in any medium or format, as long as you give appropriate credit to the original author(s) and the source, provide a link to the Creative Commons licence, and indicate if you modified the licensed material. You do not have permission under this licence to share adapted material derived from this article or parts of it. The images or other third party material in this article are included in the article&#8217;s Creative Commons licence, unless indicated otherwise in a credit line to the material. If material is not included in the article&#8217;s Creative Commons licence and your intended use is not permitted by statutory regulation or exceeds the permitted use, you will need to obtain permission directly from the copyright holder. To view a copy of this licence, visit <ext-link xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" ext-link-type="uri" xlink:href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/4.0/">http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/4.0/</ext-link>.</license-p></license></permissions><self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" content-type="pmc-pdf" xlink:href="701_2025_Article_6674.pdf"/><abstract id="Abs1"><p id="Par1">In our case, we report a previously unreported complication of a thread lift procedure in the jowl region. This complication was caused by damage to the glossopharyngeal nerve through compression. The case also illustrates the diagnostic and therapeutic aspects of iatrogenic injury to the glossopharyngeal nerve. The widespread use of thread lift in aesthetic medicine has increased the variety and frequency of complications. The thread lift procedure is an blind intervention in which critical anatomical structures are not directly visualised. Therefore, the risk of damage to various structures is also high. Damage to the nerves in the application area is manifested by specific symptoms such as sensory deficits, pain, swallowing impairment, and autonomic dysfunction. We describe the diagnosis and treatment of a glossopharyngeal nerve injury caused by compression of the nerve trunk following a facial thread lift procedure.</p></abstract><kwd-group xml:lang="en"><title>Keywords</title><kwd>Thread lift procedure</kwd><kwd>Jowl region</kwd><kwd>Aesthetic medicine</kwd><kwd>Glossopharyngeal</kwd></kwd-group><custom-meta-group><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-status-qastatus</meta-name><meta-value>0</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-status-live</meta-name><meta-value>yes</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-status-embargo</meta-name><meta-value>no</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-status-released</meta-name><meta-value>yes</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-open-access</meta-name><meta-value>yes</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-olf</meta-name><meta-value>no</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-manuscript</meta-name><meta-value>no</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-legally-suppressed</meta-name><meta-value>no</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-has-pdf</meta-name><meta-value>yes</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-has-supplement</meta-name><meta-value>no</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-pdf-only</meta-name><meta-value>no</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-suppress-copyright</meta-name><meta-value>no</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-is-real-version</meta-name><meta-value>no</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-is-scanned-article</meta-name><meta-value>no</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-preprint</meta-name><meta-value>no</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-in-epmc</meta-name><meta-value>yes</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>issue-copyright-statement</meta-name><meta-value>&#169; Springer-Verlag GmbH Austria, part of Springer Nature 2025</meta-value></custom-meta></custom-meta-group></article-meta></front><body><sec id="Sec1"><title>Case</title><p id="Par2">A 52-year-old woman patient presented with complaints following a thread lift procedure performed at a private aesthetic clinic. The patient had sought treatment for facial contour correction and sagging of the submental region. The procedure was initiated from the right side without complications, with the thread anchored to the mastoid process in the posterior auricular region. However, during the procedure on the left side, the patient experienced sudden, sharp pain radiating from the throat and tongue root toward the left palatine tonsil. Following the completion of the procedure, the patient developed hypotension (80/45&#160;mmHg) and bradycardia (50&#160;bpm), along with a sensation of impending fainting.</p><p id="Par3">Despite resting at the clinic, her complaints persisted. Over the next week, the patient repeatedly visited the clinic, complaining of dysphagia, pain radiating toward the left ear, persistent pain localized to the left tonsillar region, dizziness, and episodes of near-fainting. The clinic provided only symptomatic treatments, and did not conduct further investigations.</p><p id="Par4">During the ongoing complaints, intermittent blood pressure measurements revealed fluctuations from an initial 120/85&#160;mmHg to 140/95&#160;mmHg and later 150/100&#160;mmHg. The patient was referred to an internal medicine specialist with a preliminary diagnosis of hypertension. No organic pathology was detected, but due to intermittent palpitations and elevated blood pressure, treatment with metoprolol tartrate 25&#160;mg was initiated for presumed essential hypertension.</p><p id="Par5">Concerned that her symptoms coincided with the thread lift procedure, the patient sought a second opinion from an the author regarding the patient&#8217;s complaints. Based on the clinical presentation, damage to the glossopharyngeal and vagus nerves was suspected, and referral to neurology was recommended.</p><p id="Par6">Neurological examination identified sensory deficits in the left oropharynx, tongue root, palate, and tonsil. Additional findings included edema in the floor of the mouth and periauricular region, ageusia in the posterior third of the tongue, and xerostomia. These findings confirmed a glossopharyngeal nerve injury. Brain MRI revealed edema localized in the posterior-inferior aspect of the left parotid gland. After otolaryngology consultation, surgical exploration and removal of the threads were performed. The patient underwent surgical revision, and her symptoms gradually resolved within 20&#160;days postoperatively. Full sensory recovery was documented at the end of four months.</p></sec><sec id="Sec2"><title>Discussion</title><p id="Par7">The glossopharyngeal nerve (cranial nerve IX) serves both motor, sensory, and parasympathetic functions. It exits the posterior cranial fossa via the jugular foramen with cranial nerves X and XI. The nerve courses superficially alongside the internal carotid artery and jugular vein, passing under the palatine tonsil toward the tongue base. Within the parapharyngeal space, it supplies motor fibers to the stylopharyngeus muscle, parasympathetic fibers to the parotid gland, and sensory fibers to the pharynx, tonsils, and posterior one-third of the tongue. Taste fibers from this region terminate in the nucleus tractus solitarius (NTS), and general sensory fibers from the tongue and middle ear terminate in the spinal trigeminal nucleus [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR3">3</xref>, <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR8">8</xref>].</p><p id="Par8">Of particular importance in this case is the glossopharyngeal nerve&#8217;s role in the baroreflex mechanism. Baroreceptors in the carotid sinus detect changes in blood pressure and transmit these signals via the glossopharyngeal nerve to the brainstem. Here, the signals synapse in the NTS to coordinate appropriate autonomic responses. Increased baroreceptor firing in response to elevated blood pressure leads to enhanced parasympathetic output via the vagus nerve, slowing heart rate and reducing cardiac output, alongside decreased sympathetic activity that results in vasodilation and lowered blood pressure. In our patient, the sequence of blood pressure changes provides mechanistic insight. The initial hypotension with bradycardia can be attributed to excessive afferent firing of the glossopharyngeal nerve due to acute compression, resembling the mechanism described in glossopharyngeal neuralgia with vascular compression. Enhanced carotid baroreceptor input to the nucleus tractus solitarius (NTS) transiently increased parasympathetic outflow via the vagus nerve while suppressing sympathetic tone, leading to hypotension and bradycardia. As the compression-induced neuropathy progressed, afferent conduction was reduced, leading to loss of baroreflex buffering. This allowed unopposed sympathetic drive from the rostral ventrolateral medulla (RVLM), resulting in sustained hypertension. This dual-phase response highlights the paradoxical cardiovascular manifestations of glossopharyngeal nerve dysfunction&#160;(Fig.&#160;<xref rid="Fig1" ref-type="fig">1</xref>) [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR4">4</xref>, <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR5">5</xref>, <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR9">9</xref>&#8211;<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR12">12</xref>, <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR14">14</xref>].<fig id="Fig1" position="float" orientation="portrait"><label>Fig.&#160;1</label><caption><p>Anatomical course and baroreflex role of the glossopharyngeal nerve (CN IX) and its relation to thread lift application sites. Abbreviations: CN IX &#8211; glossopharyngeal nerve; CN X &#8211; vagus nerve; NTS &#8211; nucleus tractus solitarius; IJV &#8211; internal jugular vein; ICA &#8211; internal carotid artery. VMN&#8201;=&#8201;Ventromedial nucleus, DNV&#8201;=&#8201;Dorsal nucleus of vagus, TP&#8201;=&#8201;Transverse process, TB&#8201;=&#8201;Tympanic bone, MB&#8201;=&#8201;Mastoid bone, MP&#8201;=&#8201;Mastoid process, L&#8201;=&#8201;Stylohyoid ligament (likely), CB&#8201;=&#8201;Carotid body.A and B are facial landmark reference lines (A&#8201;=&#8201;along mandible, B&#8201;=&#8201;along zygomatic arch&#8211;masseter line)</p></caption><graphic xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" id="MO1" position="float" orientation="portrait" xlink:href="701_2025_6674_Fig1_HTML.jpg"/></fig></p><p id="Par9">Thread lift is a minimally invasive aesthetic procedure for correcting facial and submental sagging. The technique involves the placement of dissolvable or long-lasting threads under the skin using thin cannulas, fixed at strategic points to achieve lifting effects. Although the threads are intended to pass superficially, above the superficial musculoaponeurotic system (SMAS), placement depth and direction deviations can occur. Excessive tension or incorrect anatomical placement can lead to complications, including nerve injury, as described in previous case series [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR1">1</xref>, <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR6">6</xref>, <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR13">13</xref>, <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR16">16</xref>].</p><p id="Par10">In clinical literature, glossopharyngeal nerve damage has been described in association with tonsillectomy [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR15">15</xref>], carotid endarterectomy [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR2">2</xref>], and endotracheal intubation [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR7">7</xref>]. In the presented case, excessive traction or improper placement of the thread near the mandible likely compressed the glossopharyngeal nerve. The patient&#8217;s specific symptoms pain radiating to the ear, taste disturbances, and localized tonsillar pain are characteristic of glossopharyngeal neuralgia and nerve dysfunction.</p><p id="Par11">Notably, hypertension has rarely been reported as a complication of bilateral glossopharyngeal nerve damage, mainly in the context of tonsillectomy [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR15">15</xref>]. To the best of our knowledge, this case represents the first documented instance of glossopharyngeal nerve injury and resultant hypertension following an aesthetic thread lift procedure.</p><p id="Par12">This case highlights the importance of anatomical awareness and careful planning during thread lift procedures. The superficial nature of thread passage does not eliminate the risk of injury to deeper structures, especially in the submental and parapharyngeal regions. The patient&#8217;s specific symptoms should be carefully evaluated, and consultation with neurology and otolaryngology specialists is strongly advised. Early recognition and intervention may prevent permanent nerve damage and systemic complications.</p></sec><sec id="Sec3"><title>Conclusion</title><p id="Par13">Thread lift procedures, though minimally invasive, carry risks of serious complications if anatomical planes are not respected. Glossopharyngeal nerve damage may present with oropharyngeal pain, sensory deficits, and blood pressure dysregulation. In such a case, surgical revision and removal of the threads should be considered for recovery. This case emphasizes the importance of clinician awareness regarding rare but significant complications of aesthetic procedures and the need for multidisciplinary evaluation in the presence of neurological symptoms.</p><p id="Par14">Beyond its relevance for aesthetic surgeons, this case underlines the crucial physiological role of the glossopharyngeal nerve in cardiovascular regulation. Injury to this nerve may paradoxically present with either hypotension or hypertension, depending on whether afferent firing is excessive or absent. Such cases should raise awareness among neurosurgeons and neurologists regarding the autonomic consequences of glossopharyngeal neuropathy.</p></sec></body><back><fn-group><fn><p><bold>Publisher's Note</bold></p><p>Springer Nature remains neutral with regard to jurisdictional claims in published maps and institutional affiliations.</p></fn></fn-group><notes notes-type="author-contribution"><title>Author&#8217;s contribution
</title><p>ET: Concept, Design; TT: Materials, Data Collection; &#304;HA; Materials, Literature Review; HA: Writing, Critical Review. All authors reviewed the manuscript.</p></notes><notes notes-type="funding-information"><title>Funding</title><p>None.</p></notes><notes notes-type="data-availability"><title>Data availability
</title><p>The data presented in this study are available on request from the corresponding author.</p></notes><notes><title>Declarations</title><notes id="FPar1"><title>Consent to publish declaration</title><p id="Par15">Not applicable.</p></notes><notes id="FPar2"><title>Informed consent</title><p id="Par16">Informed consent was obtained from the patient.</p></notes><notes id="FPar3" notes-type="COI-statement"><title>Conflict of interest</title><p id="Par17">The authors declare no competing interests.</p></notes></notes><ref-list id="Bib1"><title>References</title><ref id="CR1"><label>1.</label><citation-alternatives><element-citation id="ec-CR1" publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Abraham</surname><given-names>RF</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>DeFatta</surname><given-names>RJ</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Williams</surname><given-names>EF</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>Thread-lift for facial rejuvenation: assessment of long-term results</article-title><source>Arch Facial Plast Surg</source><year>2009</year><volume>11</volume><issue>3</issue><fpage>178</fpage><lpage>183</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1001/archfaci.2009.10</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">19451452</pub-id></element-citation><mixed-citation id="mc-CR1" publication-type="journal">Abraham RF, DeFatta RJ, Williams EF 3rd (2009) Thread-lift for facial rejuvenation: assessment of long-term results. Arch Facial Plast Surg 11(3):178&#8211;183<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">19451452</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1001/archfacial.2009.10</pub-id></mixed-citation></citation-alternatives></ref><ref id="CR2"><label>2.</label><citation-alternatives><element-citation id="ec-CR2" publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>AbuRahma</surname><given-names>AF</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Choueiri</surname><given-names>MA</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>Cranial and cervical nerve injuries after recurrent carotid endarterectomy</article-title><source>J Vasc Surg</source><year>2000</year><volume>32</volume><fpage>649</fpage><lpage>654</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1067/mva.2000.109751</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">11013026</pub-id></element-citation><mixed-citation id="mc-CR2" publication-type="journal">AbuRahma AF, Choueiri MA (2000) Cranial and cervical nerve injuries after recurrent carotid endarterectomy. J Vasc Surg 32:649&#8211;654<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">11013026</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1067/mva.2000.109751</pub-id></mixed-citation></citation-alternatives></ref><ref id="CR3"><label>3.</label><mixed-citation publication-type="other"> Agur AMR, Dalley AF. Grant's Atlas of Anatomy. 12th ed. Lippincott Williams &amp; Wilkins; 2009:643&#8211;787, 835.</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="CR4"><label>4.</label><citation-alternatives><element-citation id="ec-CR4" publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Averill</surname><given-names>DB</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Diz</surname><given-names>DI</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>Angiotensin peptides and baroreflex control of sympathetic outflow: pathways and mechanisms of the medulla oblongata</article-title><source>Brain Res Bull</source><year>2000</year><volume>51</volume><issue>2</issue><fpage>119</fpage><lpage>128</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1016/S0361-9230(99)00237-3</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">10709957</pub-id></element-citation><mixed-citation id="mc-CR4" publication-type="journal">Averill DB, Diz DI (2000) Angiotensin peptides and baroreflex control of sympathetic outflow: pathways and mechanisms of the medulla oblongata. Brain Res Bull 51(2):119&#8211;128<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">10709957</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1016/s0361-9230(99)00237-3</pub-id></mixed-citation></citation-alternatives></ref><ref id="CR5"><label>5.</label><citation-alternatives><element-citation id="ec-CR5" publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Dampney</surname><given-names>RAL</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Coleman</surname><given-names>MJ</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Fontes</surname><given-names>MAP</given-names></name><etal/></person-group><article-title>Central mechanisms underlying short-term and long-term regulation of the cardiovascular system</article-title><source>Proc Aust Physiol Pharmacol Soc</source><year>2001</year><volume>32</volume><issue>1</issue><fpage>111</fpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1046/j.1440-1681.2002.03640.x</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">11985533</pub-id></element-citation><mixed-citation id="mc-CR5" publication-type="journal">Dampney RAL, Coleman MJ, Fontes MAP et al (2001) Central mechanisms underlying short-term and long-term regulation of the cardiovascular system. Proc Aust Physiol Pharmacol Soc 32(1):111<pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1046/j.1440-1681.2002.03640.x</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">11985533</pub-id></mixed-citation></citation-alternatives></ref><ref id="CR6"><label>6.</label><citation-alternatives><element-citation id="ec-CR6" publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Diaspro</surname><given-names>A</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Rossini</surname><given-names>G</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>Thread lifting of the midface: a pilot study for quantitative evaluation</article-title><source>Dermatol Ther</source><year>2021</year><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1111/dth.14958</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">33840127</pub-id></element-citation><mixed-citation id="mc-CR6" publication-type="journal">Diaspro A, Rossini G (2021) Thread lifting of the midface: a pilot study for quantitative evaluation. Dermatol Ther. 10.1111/dth.14958<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">33840127</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1111/dth.14958</pub-id></mixed-citation></citation-alternatives></ref><ref id="CR7"><label>7.</label><citation-alternatives><element-citation id="ec-CR7" publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Laffon</surname><given-names>M</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Ferrandi&#232;re</surname><given-names>M</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Mercier</surname><given-names>C</given-names></name><etal/></person-group><article-title>Transient lingual and glossopharyngeal nerve injury: a complication of the clamped oropharyngeal airway</article-title><source>Anesthesiology</source><year>2001</year><volume>94</volume><fpage>719</fpage><lpage>720</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1097/00000542-200104000-00041</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">11379704</pub-id></element-citation><mixed-citation id="mc-CR7" publication-type="journal">Laffon M, Ferrandi&#232;re M, Mercier C et al (2001) Transient lingual and glossopharyngeal nerve injury: a complication of the clamped oropharyngeal airway. Anesthesiology 94:719&#8211;720<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">11379704</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1097/00000542-200104000-00041</pub-id></mixed-citation></citation-alternatives></ref><ref id="CR8"><label>8.</label><mixed-citation publication-type="other"> Martini FH, Timmons MJ. Human Anatomy. 7th ed. Student edition. Pearson; 2012:444.</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="CR9"><label>9.</label><citation-alternatives><element-citation id="ec-CR9" publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Miura</surname><given-names>M</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Reis</surname><given-names>DJ</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>Terminations and secondary projections of the carotid sinus nerve in the cat brain stem</article-title><source>Am J Physiol</source><year>1969</year><volume>217</volume><fpage>142</fpage><lpage>153</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1152/ajplegacy.1969.217.1.142</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">5785872</pub-id></element-citation><mixed-citation id="mc-CR9" publication-type="journal">Miura M, Reis DJ (1969) Terminations and secondary projections of the carotid sinus nerve in the cat brain stem. Am J Physiol 217:142&#8211;153<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">5785872</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1152/ajplegacy.1969.217.1.142</pub-id></mixed-citation></citation-alternatives></ref><ref id="CR10"><label>10.</label><mixed-citation publication-type="other"> Zanutto BS, Valentinuzzi ME, Segura ET. Neural set point for the control of arterial pressure: role of the nucleus tractus solitarius. Biomed Eng Online. 2010;9(4).<pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1186/1475-925X-9-4</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC3224897</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">20064256</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="CR11"><label>11.</label><citation-alternatives><element-citation id="ec-CR11" publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Olufsen</surname><given-names>M</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Tran</surname><given-names>H</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Ottesen</surname><given-names>J</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>Modelling cerebral blood flow control during posture change from sitting to standing</article-title><source>Cardiovasc Eng</source><year>2004</year><volume>4</volume><issue>1</issue><fpage>47</fpage><lpage>58</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1023/B:CARE.0000025122.46013.1a</pub-id></element-citation><mixed-citation id="mc-CR11" publication-type="journal">Olufsen M, Tran H, Ottesen J (2004) Modelling cerebral blood flow control during posture change from sitting to standing. Cardiovasc Eng 4(1):47&#8211;58</mixed-citation></citation-alternatives></ref><ref id="CR12"><label>12.</label><citation-alternatives><element-citation id="ec-CR12" publication-type="book"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Spyer</surname><given-names>KM</given-names></name></person-group><person-group person-group-type="editor"><name name-style="western"><surname>Bannister</surname><given-names>R</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Mathias</surname><given-names>C</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>Central nervous control of the cardiovascular system</article-title><source>Autonomic Failure</source><year>1992</year><publisher-name>Oxford University Press</publisher-name><fpage>54</fpage><lpage>77</lpage></element-citation><mixed-citation id="mc-CR12" publication-type="book">Spyer KM (1992) Central nervous control of the cardiovascular system. In: Bannister R, Mathias C (eds) Autonomic Failure. Oxford University Press, pp 54&#8211;77</mixed-citation></citation-alternatives></ref><ref id="CR13"><label>13.</label><citation-alternatives><element-citation id="ec-CR13" publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Sulamanidze</surname><given-names>M</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Sulamanidze</surname><given-names>G</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>Facial lifting with Aptos methods</article-title><source>J Cutan Aesthet Surg</source><year>2008</year><volume>1</volume><issue>1</issue><fpage>7</fpage><lpage>11</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.4103/0974-2077.41149</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">20300331</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC2840891</pub-id></element-citation><mixed-citation id="mc-CR13" publication-type="journal">Sulamanidze M, Sulamanidze G (2008) Facial lifting with Aptos methods. J Cutan Aesthet Surg 1(1):7&#8211;11<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">20300331</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.4103/0974-2077.41149</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC2840891</pub-id></mixed-citation></citation-alternatives></ref><ref id="CR14"><label>14.</label><citation-alternatives><element-citation id="ec-CR14" publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Sved</surname><given-names>AF</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Ito</surname><given-names>S</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>Pharmacological profile of the depressor response elicited by injection of SarThran into the rat rostral ventrolateral medulla</article-title><source>FASEB J</source><year>1999</year><volume>13</volume><fpage>A213</fpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1152/ajpheart.2000.279.6.H2961</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">11087253</pub-id></element-citation><mixed-citation id="mc-CR14" publication-type="journal">Sved AF, Ito S (1999) Pharmacological profile of the depressor response elicited by injection of SarThran into the rat rostral ventrolateral medulla. FASEB J 13:A213<pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1152/ajpheart.2000.279.6.H2961</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">11087253</pub-id></mixed-citation></citation-alternatives></ref><ref id="CR15"><label>15.</label><citation-alternatives><element-citation id="ec-CR15" publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Trinidade</surname><given-names>A</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Philpott</surname><given-names>CM</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>Bilateral glossopharyngeal nerve palsy after tonsillectomy: an infrequent and difficult complication of a common procedure</article-title><source>J Laryngol Otol</source><year>2015</year><volume>129</volume><fpage>392</fpage><lpage>394</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1017/S0022215115000080</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">25697260</pub-id></element-citation><mixed-citation id="mc-CR15" publication-type="journal">Trinidade A, Philpott CM (2015) Bilateral glossopharyngeal nerve palsy after tonsillectomy: an infrequent and difficult complication of a common procedure. J Laryngol Otol 129:392&#8211;394<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">25697260</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1017/S0022215115000080</pub-id></mixed-citation></citation-alternatives></ref><ref id="CR16"><label>16.</label><mixed-citation publication-type="other"> Sulamanidze M, Sulamanidze G, Kadzhaya A. New Method of Face Elastic Thread Lift. InTech Open. 2013.</mixed-citation></ref></ref-list></back></article></pmc-articleset>