<?xml version="1.0"  ?><!DOCTYPE pmc-articleset PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD ARTICLE SET 2.0//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pmc/articleset/nlm-articleset-2.0.dtd"><pmc-articleset><article xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" xmlns:ali="http://www.niso.org/schemas/ali/1.0/" article-type="review-article" xml:lang="en" dtd-version="1.4"><front><journal-meta><journal-id journal-id-type="nlm-ta">Aesthetic Plast Surg</journal-id><journal-id journal-id-type="iso-abbrev">Aesthetic Plast Surg</journal-id><journal-id journal-id-type="pmc-domain-id">365</journal-id><journal-id journal-id-type="pmc-domain">springeropen</journal-id><journal-title-group><journal-title>Aesthetic Plastic Surgery</journal-title></journal-title-group><issn pub-type="ppub">0364-216X</issn><issn pub-type="epub">1432-5241</issn><custom-meta-group><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-is-collection-domain</meta-name><meta-value>yes</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-collection-title</meta-name><meta-value>Springer</meta-value></custom-meta></custom-meta-group></journal-meta><article-meta><article-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC5440530</article-id><article-id pub-id-type="pmcid-ver">PMC5440530.1</article-id><article-id pub-id-type="pmcaid">5440530</article-id><article-id pub-id-type="pmcaiid">5440530</article-id><article-id pub-id-type="pmid">28411354</article-id><article-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1007/s00266-017-0798-y</article-id><article-id pub-id-type="publisher-id">798</article-id><article-version article-version-type="pmc-version">1</article-version><article-categories><subj-group subj-group-type="heading"><subject>Original Article</subject></subj-group></article-categories><title-group><article-title>Preventing the Complications Associated with the Use of Dermal Fillers in Facial Aesthetic Procedures: An Expert Group Consensus Report</article-title></title-group><contrib-group><contrib contrib-type="author" corresp="yes"><contrib-id contrib-id-type="orcid" authenticated="false">http://orcid.org/0000-0003-1479-9733</contrib-id><name name-style="western"><surname>Urdiales-G&#225;lvez</surname><given-names initials="F">Fernando</given-names></name><address><phone>+ 34 952 06 14 10</phone><email>info@institutomedicomiramar.com</email></address><xref ref-type="aff" rid="Aff1">1</xref></contrib><contrib contrib-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Delgado</surname><given-names initials="NE">Nuria Escoda</given-names></name><xref ref-type="aff" rid="Aff2">2</xref></contrib><contrib contrib-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Figueiredo</surname><given-names initials="V">Vitor</given-names></name><xref ref-type="aff" rid="Aff3">3</xref></contrib><contrib contrib-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Lajo-Plaza</surname><given-names initials="JV">Jos&#233; V.</given-names></name><xref ref-type="aff" rid="Aff4">4</xref></contrib><contrib contrib-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Mira</surname><given-names initials="M">Mar</given-names></name><xref ref-type="aff" rid="Aff5">5</xref></contrib><contrib contrib-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Ort&#237;z-Mart&#237;</surname><given-names initials="F">Francisco</given-names></name><xref ref-type="aff" rid="Aff6">6</xref></contrib><contrib contrib-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>del Rio-Reyes</surname><given-names initials="R">Rosa</given-names></name><xref ref-type="aff" rid="Aff7">7</xref></contrib><contrib contrib-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Romero-&#193;lvarez</surname><given-names initials="N">Nazaret</given-names></name><xref ref-type="aff" rid="Aff8">8</xref></contrib><contrib contrib-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>del Cueto</surname><given-names initials="SR">Sof&#237;a Ruiz</given-names></name><xref ref-type="aff" rid="Aff5">5</xref></contrib><contrib contrib-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Segurado</surname><given-names initials="MA">Mar&#237;a A.</given-names></name><xref ref-type="aff" rid="Aff9">9</xref><xref ref-type="aff" rid="Aff10">10</xref></contrib><contrib contrib-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Rebenaque</surname><given-names initials="CV">Cristina Villanueva</given-names></name><xref ref-type="aff" rid="Aff11">11</xref></contrib><aff id="Aff1"><label>1</label>Instituto M&#233;dico Miramar, Paseo de Miramar 21, 29016 M&#225;laga, Spain </aff><aff id="Aff2"><label>2</label>Centro de Medicina Est&#233;tica Dra Escoda, Rambla de Catalunya 60, Barcelona, Spain </aff><aff id="Aff3"><label>3</label>Cl&#237;nica Mil&#233;nio, R. Manuel da Silva Leal 11C, Lisbon, Portugal </aff><aff id="Aff4"><label>4</label>Centro M&#233;dico Lajo-Plaza, Calle Moreto 10, Madrid, Spain </aff><aff id="Aff5"><label>5</label>Cl&#237;nica Mira + Cueto, Av. de Concha Espina 53, Madrid, Spain </aff><aff id="Aff6"><label>6</label>Teknobell M&#233;dicina Est&#233;tica, Av. Pdte Carrero Blanco 14, Seville, Spain </aff><aff id="Aff7"><label>7</label>Grupo de Dermatolog&#237;a Pedro Ja&#233;n, Calle Cinca 30, Madrid, Spain </aff><aff id="Aff8"><label>8</label>Cl&#237;nica de Medicina Est&#233;tica Dra Nazaret Romero, Paseo Castellana 123, Madrid, Spain </aff><aff id="Aff9"><label>9</label>SClinic, Claudio Coello 92, Madrid, Spain </aff><aff id="Aff10"><label>10</label>Hospital del Sureste V&#237;a Verde, Ronda del Sur 10, Arganda del Rey, Madrid, Spain </aff><aff id="Aff11"><label>11</label>Cl&#237;nica de Medicina Est&#233;tica Dra Villanueva, Carrer de Calvet 10, Barcelona, Spain </aff></contrib-group><pub-date pub-type="epub"><day>14</day><month>4</month><year>2017</year></pub-date><pub-date pub-type="ppub"><year>2017</year></pub-date><volume>41</volume><issue>3</issue><issue-id pub-id-type="pmc-issue-id">292869</issue-id><fpage>667</fpage><lpage>677</lpage><history><date date-type="received"><day>10</day><month>10</month><year>2016</year></date><date date-type="accepted"><day>5</day><month>1</month><year>2017</year></date></history><pub-history><event event-type="pmc-release"><date><day>14</day><month>04</month><year>2017</year></date></event><event event-type="pmc-live"><date><day>08</day><month>06</month><year>2017</year></date></event><event event-type="pmc-last-change"><date iso-8601-date="2017-06-09 00:08:23.617"><day>09</day><month>06</month><year>2017</year></date></event></pub-history><permissions><copyright-statement>&#169; The Author(s) 2017</copyright-statement><license license-type="OpenAccess"><ali:license_ref specific-use="textmining" content-type="ccbylicense">https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</ali:license_ref><license-p>
<bold>Open Access</bold>This article is distributed under the terms of the Creative Commons Attribution 4.0 International License (<ext-link xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" ext-link-type="uri" xlink:href="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/">http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</ext-link>), which permits unrestricted use, distribution, and reproduction in any medium, provided you give appropriate credit to the original author(s) and the source, provide a link to the Creative Commons license, and indicate if changes were made.</license-p></license></permissions><self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" content-type="pmc-pdf" xlink:href="266_2017_Article_798.pdf"/><abstract id="Abs1"><sec><title>Background</title><p>The use of dermal fillers in minimally invasive facial aesthetic procedures has become increasingly popular of late, yet as the indications and the number of procedures performed increase, the number of complications is also likely to increase. Paying special attention to specific patient characteristics and to the technique used can do much to avoid these complications. Indeed, a well-trained physician can also minimize the impact of such problems when they do occur.</p></sec><sec><title>Methods</title><p>A multidisciplinary group of experts in aesthetic treatments reviewed the main factors associated with the complications that arise when using dermal fillers. A search of English, French and Spanish language articles in PubMed was performed using the terms &#8220;complications&#8221; OR &#8220;soft filler complications&#8221; OR &#8220;injectable complications&#8221; AND &#8220;dermal fillers&#8221;. An initial document was drafted that reflected the complications identified and recommendations as to how they should be handled. This document was then reviewed and modified by the expert panel, until a final text was agreed upon and validated.</p></sec><sec><title>Results</title><p>The panel addressed consensus recommendations about the preparation, the procedure and the post-procedural care. The panel considered it crucial to obtain an accurate medical history to prevent potential complications. An additional clinical assessment, including standardized photography, is also crucial to evaluate the outcomes and prevent potential complications. Furthermore, the state of the operating theatre, the patient&#8217;s health status and the preparation of the skin are critical to prevent superficial soft tissue infections. Finally, selecting the appropriate technique, based on the physician&#8217;s experience, as well as the characteristics of the patient and filler, helps to ensure successful outcomes and limits the complications.</p></sec><sec><title>Conclusions</title><p>This consensus document provides key elements to help clinicians who are starting to use dermal fillers to employ standard procedures and to understand how best to prevent potential complications of the treatment.</p></sec><sec><title>Level of Evidence V</title><p>This journal requires that authors assign a level of evidence to each article. For a full description of these Evidence-Based Medicine ratings, please refer to the Table of Contents or the online Instructions to Authors <ext-link xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" ext-link-type="uri" xlink:href="http://www.springer.com/00266">www.springer.com/00266</ext-link>.</p></sec></abstract><kwd-group xml:lang="en"><title>Keywords</title><kwd>Aesthetic procedures</kwd><kwd>Dermal fillers</kwd><kwd>Complications</kwd><kwd>Prevention</kwd></kwd-group><custom-meta-group><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-status-qastatus</meta-name><meta-value>0</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-status-live</meta-name><meta-value>yes</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-status-embargo</meta-name><meta-value>no</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-status-released</meta-name><meta-value>yes</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-open-access</meta-name><meta-value>yes</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-olf</meta-name><meta-value>no</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-manuscript</meta-name><meta-value>no</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-legally-suppressed</meta-name><meta-value>no</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-has-pdf</meta-name><meta-value>yes</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-has-supplement</meta-name><meta-value>no</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-pdf-only</meta-name><meta-value>no</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-suppress-copyright</meta-name><meta-value>no</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-is-real-version</meta-name><meta-value>no</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-is-scanned-article</meta-name><meta-value>no</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-preprint</meta-name><meta-value>no</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-in-epmc</meta-name><meta-value>yes</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-license-ref</meta-name><meta-value>CC BY</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>issue-copyright-statement</meta-name><meta-value>&#169; Springer Science+Business Media New York and International Society of Aesthetic Plastic Surgery 2017</meta-value></custom-meta></custom-meta-group></article-meta></front><body><sec id="Sec1"><title>Introduction</title><p>In recent years, the popularity of minimally invasive cosmetic procedures has experienced unprecedented growth, including the use of dermal fillers. According to the American Society for Aesthetic Plastic Surgery, the use of cosmetic surgery increased nearly 5% between 2011 and 2012 [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR1">1</xref>]. As the use of dermal fillers becomes more established, the size of the market grows and there are now an estimated 160 products currently available worldwide, supplied by more than 50 companies [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR2">2</xref>]. These products are mainly used to create volume or to reverse any soft tissue loss due to disease or age [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR3">3</xref>]. As such, they are used in volume replacement and enhancement procedures that include cheek and chin augmentation, tear trough correction, nose reshaping, mid-facial volumization, lip enhancement, hand rejuvenation and the correction of facial asymmetry [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR3">3</xref>].</p><p>Dermal fillers vary in their composition, duration of effect, palpability, ease of administration, potential complications and other factors, all of which affect the therapeutic results [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR4">4</xref>, <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR5">5</xref>]. Hence, achieving desirable outcomes with dermal fillers depends critically on understanding their different characteristics, capabilities, methods of injection, risks and the limitations of the fillers available. In addition, there is a learning curve associated with the administration of dermal fillers, which requires practice to achieve consistently desirable results. Perhaps the most important issue to prevent complications with dermal fillers, more than selecting the appropriate patients, is probably not to treat inappropriate ones.</p><p>Because of the large number of dermal fillers currently available in the market and their increasing popularity, not only among patients but also among dermatologists and aesthetic physicians, it is of interest to provide recommendations that might help clinicians in their decision-making. Additionally, the lack of randomized control trials underlines the need to gather consensus views from experienced injectors who have treated many patients.</p><p>This manuscript aims to provide a summary of the different factors that might influence the results of dermal fillers in aesthetic procedures and how to prevent them.</p><p>Thus, in this article we establish consensus-based recommendations to provide dermatologists and practitioners of aesthetic medicine a reference framework based on available data, and the group&#8217;s clinical experience.</p></sec><sec id="Sec2"><title>Materials and Methods</title><p>On 21 May 2016, a multidisciplinary group of experts in aesthetic treatments convened to discuss the main factors that influence the complications associated with dermal filler use. Different subjects emerged as core topics of concerns including patient selection, injection technique and post-procedural cares. The authors developed this consensus paper based on those discussions and a review of the current literature.</p><p>A PubMed literature search for English, French and Spanish language articles published to date was performed using the terms &#8220;complications&#8221; OR &#8220;soft filler complications&#8221; OR &#8220;injectable complications&#8221; AND &#8220;dermal fillers&#8221;. References cited in selected articles were also reviewed to identify additional relevant reports. Additionally, relevant published national and international guidelines were also scrutinized.</p><p>Because the aesthetic procedures are usually elective processes, clinical trials are complex to organize and conduct. There are few prospective trials, but these are often not randomized or controlled. Therefore, our knowledge base mainly comprises case reports and summaries of individual practitioner&#8217;s experience.</p><p>An initial document was drafted by the Coordinating Committee, and it was reviewed by the expert panel members. The Coordinating Committee evaluated the panel&#8217;s comments and modified the draft as they considered necessary. Subsequent revisions were based on feedback from the other authors until a consensus was achieved, and the final text was then validated (Fig.&#160;<xref rid="Fig1" ref-type="fig">1</xref>).<fig id="Fig1" position="float" orientation="portrait"><label>Fig.&#160;1</label><caption><p>Flow diagram of the consensus process</p></caption><graphic xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" id="MO1" position="float" orientation="portrait" xlink:href="266_2017_798_Fig1_HTML.jpg"/></fig>
</p></sec><sec id="Sec3"><title>Results</title><sec id="Sec4"><title>Pre-procedure Care</title><sec id="Sec5"><title>How the Skin Ages: Facial Ageing</title><p>Facial ageing is a multifactorial, complex, three-dimensional (3D), dynamic and generally not uniform process, with anatomical, biochemical and genetic correlates [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR6">6</xref>&#8211;<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR8">8</xref>]. Many of the facial manifestations of ageing reflect the combined effects of gravity, progressive bone resorption, decreased tissue elasticity and the redistribution of subcutaneous fullness [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR6">6</xref>&#8211;<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR8">8</xref>]. Facial ageing is also associated with the loss of soft tissue fullness in certain areas (periorbital, forehead, malar, temporal, mandibular, mental, glabella and perioral sites) and the persistence or hypertrophy of fat in others (submental, lateral nasolabial fold, labiomental crease, jowls, infraorbital fat pouches and malar fat pad) [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR6">6</xref>, <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR9">9</xref>]. All people age differently as a result of the imbalance, disharmony and disproportion of the ageing process between the overlying soft tissue and the underlying bony frameworks. Moreover, each individual compartment ages at a different pace in the same individual. Hence, it is recommended that when correcting the ageing face, the individual compartments should be considered and corrected separately.</p></sec><sec id="Sec6"><title>Knowledge of the Fillers</title><p>There are a host of fillers currently available in Spain and Portugal. Before and after opening the filler, it is imperative to be aware of their constituents, particle concentration (per mg), cross-linking, monophasic or biphasic nature, additives (e.g. lidocaine) and shelf life. Any contraindications detailed in the instructions for the use of the chosen filler should be closely adhered to. The suitability of different fillers needs to be discussed, and the patient must be given an indication of the likely value expected to be gained from the treatment [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR10">10</xref>, <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR11">11</xref>]. Although the panel considers that the perfect filler has yet to be described, the characteristics of an optimal filler are listed in Table&#160;<xref rid="Tab1" ref-type="table">1</xref>. The choice of fillers depends upon diverse factors, such as the defect to be corrected, the desired duration of the effect and the constituents of the filler.<table-wrap id="Tab1" position="float" orientation="portrait"><label>Table&#160;1</label><caption><p>Optimal dermal filler characteristics</p></caption><table frame="hsides" rules="groups"><thead><tr><th align="left" colspan="2" rowspan="1">Dermal filler characteristics check list</th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Long duration/persistence<break/>Performance promise<break/>Painless<break/>Reasonable cost<break/>Non toxic<break/>Non inflammatory<break/>Non carcinogenic<break/>No migration</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Non-animal origin<break/>Easy to store<break/>Easy to inject<break/>Easy of learning how to inject<break/>Minimal side effects<break/>Biodegradable (in case of temporary or semi-permanent fillers)<break/>Biocompatibility </td></tr></tbody></table></table-wrap>
</p></sec><sec id="Sec7"><title>Injection Technique and Injection Patterns</title><p>Selecting the appropriate injection technique for each patient helps to ensure a successful outcome and limits the risk of undesired effects. The techniques and injection patterns used to administer dermal fillers in clinical practice vary according to physician&#8217;s preferences and experience [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR12">12</xref>]. Several patterns have been described for the appropriate placement of different fillers: fanning, serial puncture, cross-hatching and linear threading. The most popular is the linear threading method, either retrograde or anterograde. Beginners are advised to start with this technique rather than using other methods like the depot or fern method, which can produce lumps if administered inappropriately.</p></sec></sec><sec id="Sec8"><title>Preparative Care</title><sec id="Sec9"><title>Patient Interview</title><p>Although the grievance the patients express is extremely important, clinicians must be aware that patients may have difficulties in conveying their reasons for seeking advice or treatment. Hence, an exhaustive consultation is essential prior to any treatment to determine the reasons why the patient wants to undergo cosmetic therapy, and to establish &#8220;realistic&#8221; goals for the treatment. The clinician&#8217;s first goal is to determine whether facial ageing exists and, if so, whether the patient&#8217;s perception of the deformity ties in with the clinician&#8217;s assessment.</p><p>The patient&#8217;s motivation for undergoing treatment is very important. Patients who have &#8220;external&#8221; (extrinsic) motivations, for example involving the desire to please others or to have a more successful career, are less likely to be happy with the results of the treatment than patients who have &#8220;internal&#8221; (intrinsic) motivations and want to look better for themselves [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR13">13</xref>]. In addition, it is extremely important for patients to have realistic expectations. The goal to look like a top model or the most fashionable film star is, in most cases, not realistic. On the other hand, it is also vital for the clinician to not create unrealistic expectations. The patient must fully understand the results that can be realistically achieved, the approximate length of the treatment and also the likely complications. At this point it is crucial to establish good communications with the patient [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR13">13</xref>]. Moreover, some prudence should be exercised when deciding about a patient who exhibits signs of any underlying mental disturbance or dysmorphophobic tendency.</p></sec><sec id="Sec10"><title>Medical History</title><p>Obtaining a complete medical history is crucial to prevent potential complications. The medical history should scour for any medical illnesses, allergies, medications used and prior aesthetic procedures. For instance, the risk of bruising is greater when patients have bleeding disorders, uncontrolled hypertension or when anticoagulants like aspirin, clopidogrel or warfarin are being taken. Similarly, we must check for hypersensitivity to lidocaine. Anti-ds DNA antibodies cross-react with collagen and, hence, collagen-based fillers should not be used in patients with systemic lupus erythematosus [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR14">14</xref>]. When evaluating patients with cardiovascular diseases or those who take anticoagulant medication, it is important to determine the time frame during which the patient will be taking the medication and the risk associated with temporary discontinuation of the medication [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR15">15</xref>].</p><p>Although there have only occasionally been reports of adverse events or suboptimal results, caution is advised when injecting hyaluronic acid-based fillers derived from <italic toggle="yes">Streptococcus</italic> species in patients with any prior streptococcal disease. Indeed, this may be a source of delayed reactions [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR12">12</xref>]. It should be noted that some of the currently available non-animal hyaluronic acid-based fillers contain trace amounts of gram-positive bacterial proteins and, therefore, they are contraindicated for patients with a history of allergies to such material [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR16">16</xref>]. Finally, it is extremely important to check for any signs of inflammation in the area to be treated. Active inflammation will provoke degradation of the filler [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR10">10</xref>].</p><p>Table&#160;<xref rid="Tab2" ref-type="table">2</xref> summarizes the minimum requirements in terms of the information that should be gleaned from the patient&#8217;s medical records for aesthetic procedures.<table-wrap id="Tab2" position="float" orientation="portrait"><label>Table&#160;2</label><caption><p>Minimum requirements demanded to the medical records in aesthetic procedures</p></caption><table frame="hsides" rules="groups"><thead><tr><th align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Minimal information collected in the medical record</th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Patient identification</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">&#160;Number of clinical record</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">&#160;Name and surname</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">&#160;Date of birth</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">&#160;Address</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">&#160;Telephone number</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Reason for the visit</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">&#160;Main reason for consultation</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">&#160;Duration of the problem</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Family history</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Psychosocial history</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">&#160;Patient motivation</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">&#160;Patient expectations</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">&#160;Level of education</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">&#160;Kind of work</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">&#160;Hygiene conditions</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Medical history</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">&#160;Allergies*, immunological diseases, herpes</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">&#160;Previous and current diseases</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">&#160;Previous surgeries</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">&#160;Previous aesthetic treatments**</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">&#160;Prior infections (pay special attention on this point as most of filler complications are related to this issue)</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">&#160;Dental history***</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">&#160;Active skin infections or inflammations</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Clinical assessment</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">&#160;To determine whether a facial ageing process exists</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">&#160;Well-focused pre-treatment photographs</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">&#160;&#160;Assessment of treatment effects</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">&#160;&#160;Assessment of adverse effects</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">&#160;&#160;Medicolegal purposes</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">&#160;Ultrasonography</td></tr></tbody></table><table-wrap-foot><p>*&#160;The panel recommends to pay special attention for asking about allergy/hypersensitivity reactions to lidocaine (information may be obtained from previous dental procedures)</p><p>**&#160;According to the panel recommendations, previous aesthetic procedures must be thoroughly assessed. The physician must be sure about the filler/fillers injected</p><p>***&#160;After a dental procedure, such as dental removal, dental cleaning or drilling the panel recommends to wait, at least, 1&#160;month before injecting the fillers</p></table-wrap-foot></table-wrap>
</p></sec><sec id="Sec11"><title>Informed Consent</title><p>It is mandatory that the patient receives adequate information about the filler, the technique that will be used for its administration, the potential outcomes, the possible side effects, the post-procedural care, the need for maintenance or any other additional procedures required to achieve optimum results.</p><p>The panel recommends that this informed consent:<list list-type="order"><list-item><p>Should be as complete as possible, such that it could serve as a guide to obtain and impart all the necessary information at the first visit.</p></list-item><list-item><p>Should include a specific paragraph regarding the potential problems when the patient also suffers from an immune disease.</p></list-item></list>
</p><p>In addition to the informed consent, it is recommended that the patient fills out a questionnaire in which any previous treatments with fillers are recorded, as well as the type of filler and their response.</p></sec><sec id="Sec12"><title>Clinical Assessment</title><p>As Claude Bernard said: &#8220;Who doesn&#8217;t know what he&#8217;s looking for, doesn&#8217;t understand what he finds&#8221;. Every face has its disproportions and asymmetries, and they are essentially normal. Therefore, a clinician must employ an educated eye if the correct diagnosis is to be made. To analyse an individual&#8217;s facial proportions, their head position must be natural. A natural head position is defined as a standardized and reproducible position of the head when the subject focuses on a distant point at eye level [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR13">13</xref>].</p><p>Many linear and angular measures of the soft tissue profile, and a variety of cephalometric analyses, have been developed to determine the ideal facial proportions [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR17">17</xref>&#8211;<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR20">20</xref>]. Beauty is not an exact science, but according to some plastic surgeons, there is a specific proportion system that takes into account facial height, width and symmetry. Furthermore, the definition of an attractive and beautiful face is subjective, associated with many factors that include social, cultural and ethnic aspects, as well as age [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR21">21</xref>]. The face may be divided into vertical fifths (Fig.&#160;<xref rid="Fig2" ref-type="fig">2</xref>a) and horizontal thirds (Fig.&#160;<xref rid="Fig2" ref-type="fig">2</xref>b) [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR20">20</xref>]. To evaluate facial proportions, several soft tissue points can be used to obtain linear distances (Fig.&#160;<xref rid="Fig3" ref-type="fig">3</xref>) and, in fact, these facial measurements may be strongly related to attractiveness [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR20">20</xref>, <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR22">22</xref>] (the different parameters measured to assess beauty are shown in Fig.&#160;<xref rid="Fig4" ref-type="fig">4</xref>).<fig id="Fig2" position="float" orientation="portrait"><label>Fig.&#160;2</label><caption><p>Different divisions of the face. <bold>a</bold> Division of the face into <italic toggle="yes">vertical</italic> fifths. 1: Pa right&#8211;Ex right, 2: Ex right&#8211;En right, 3: En right&#8211;En left, 4: En left&#8211;Ex left, 5: Ex left&#8211;Pa left. <bold>b</bold> Division of the face into <italic toggle="yes">horizontal</italic> thirds. 1 upper third: Tr&#8211;Gl, 2 middle third: Gl&#8211;subN, 3 lower third: subN&#8211;Me. <italic toggle="yes">Pa</italic> postaurale, <italic toggle="yes">Ex</italic> exocanthion, <italic toggle="yes">En</italic> endocanthion, <italic toggle="yes">Tr</italic> trichion, <italic toggle="yes">Gl</italic> glabella, <italic toggle="yes">Me</italic> menton, <italic toggle="yes">SubN</italic> subnasale</p></caption><graphic xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" id="MO2" position="float" orientation="portrait" xlink:href="266_2017_798_Fig2_HTML.jpg"/></fig>
<fig id="Fig3" position="float" orientation="portrait"><label>Fig.&#160;3</label><caption><p>Soft tissue points that can be used to obtain face measurements (adapted from Milutinovic et al. [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR20">20</xref>]). Soft tissue points from <italic toggle="yes">top</italic> to <italic toggle="yes">bottom</italic>: trichion (Tr): the beginning of the forehead when one lifts the eyebrow, glabella (Gl): the most prominent point of the forehead at the superior aspect of the eyebrows, postaurale (Pa): the most posterior point on the helix (outer rim of the ear), lateral canthus (LC): lateral canthus of the eye, exocanthion (Ex): the most lateral point of the palpebral fissure at the outer canthus of the eye, endocanthion (En): the most medial point of the palpebral fissure at the inner canthus of the eye, lateral cheek (Lchk): lateral border of the cheeks, lateral nose (Ln): lateral side of the nose, subnasale (SubN): the point in the midsagittal plane where the nasal septum merges into the upper lip, stomion (Sto): the midpoint of the intralabial fissure, cheilion (Ch): the corner of the mouth, menton (Me): the most inferior point on the soft tissue chin</p></caption><graphic xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" id="MO3" position="float" orientation="portrait" xlink:href="266_2017_798_Fig3_HTML.jpg"/></fig>
<fig id="Fig4" position="float" orientation="portrait"><label>Fig.&#160;4</label><caption><p>Different parameters to calculate the length of the face (adapted from Milutinovic et al. [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR20">20</xref>]). Facial measures (Fig.&#160;<xref rid="Fig1" ref-type="fig">1</xref>a, b): (Tr&#8211;Me): height of the face. (Lchk right&#8211;Lchk left): width of the face. (Me&#8211;Sto): the lowest point on the chin, and the point where the upper and lower lip merge. (Sto&#8211;LC): the point where the upper and lower lip merge, and corner of the eye. (Me&#8211;Ln): the lowest point on the chin and the outer edge of the nostril. (Ln&#8211;Tr): the outer edge of the nostril and highest point of the forehead</p></caption><graphic xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" id="MO4" position="float" orientation="portrait" xlink:href="266_2017_798_Fig4_HTML.jpg"/></fig>
</p><p>The panel members considered it extremely important to evaluate the quality of the skin, assessing the presence of nevus or other skin irregularities that could reflect systemic illnesses or predict potential skin complications after filler injection.</p><sec id="Sec13"><title>Ultrasound Examination</title><p>Ultrasonography may be a useful tool to evaluate the surface topography of the skin and to assess what may happen to the filler beneath the surface of the skin [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR22">22</xref>, <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR23">23</xref>]. Ultrasonography was used to ascertain the site, quantity and type of filler that should be injected into the soft tissue of the face in a cohort of 80 subjects who underwent facial filler augmentation [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR24">24</xref>]. High-frequency sonography was able to identify and quantify the presence of the filler in the soft tissue of almost all patients. Moreover, it was possible to detect inflammatory reactions (many of which were silent) and granulomas and to detect the presence of diverse fillers in the same area [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR24">24</xref>]. Additionally, ultrasonography may facilitate the selection and application of rejuvenation agents and procedures (such as lower eyelid blepharoplasty), the dynamic analysis of hyaluronic acid within the elevator plane for upper eyelid retraction, and the serial distribution and integration of autologous fat injection in the lower lid compartments [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR25">25</xref>].</p></sec><sec id="Sec14"><title>Standardized Photographic Scales</title><p>Among the different methods used to analyse craniofacial morphology and to establish facial profiles, standardized photographs occupy a prominent place in facial analysis and they are used routinely by most aesthetic specialists. Additionally, high&#8208;quality standardized photographs &#8220;before and after&#8221; provide a compelling demonstration of the possible results of treatment and they are a crucial tool that aid quality consultations [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR26">26</xref>]. Although scales have been published that permit intra-study comparisons, many of them are yet to be validated, and their heterogeneity makes comparisons across studies impossible. A set of validated, objective and quantitative scales now exists that allows the key signs of the ageing that causes individuals to seek cosmetic procedures to be evaluated [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR27">27</xref>&#8211;<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR32">32</xref>]. Each scale is a five-point photo-numeric scale based on computer-simulated photographs incorporating each of the aspects to be evaluated in a stepwise manner. Other methods have also been proposed as valuable tools in aesthetics, such as the VISIA Complexion Analysis System (Canfield Imaging Systems, Fairfield, NJ) [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR33">33</xref>] or the Vectra 3D imaging software (Canfield Scientific, Inc. Fairfield, New Jersey) [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR34">34</xref>]. The Mid-Face Volume Deficit Scale (MVDS) is an Allergan&#174; specific scale that uses a six-point photo-numeric instrument specifically developed as a physician&#8217;s assessment tool to evaluate overall degree of the volume deficit of the mid-face, from 0 (none) through to 6 or severe (Fig.&#160;<xref rid="Fig4" ref-type="fig">4</xref>).</p><p>The panel&#8217;s recommendation is that photographs should be taken at 0 degrees, at 45&#176; (right and left) and at 90&#176; (right and left). Additionally, it is thought to be extremely important to take dynamic photographs in order to detect asymmetries and the degree of skin sagging on neck flexion (Fig.&#160;<xref rid="Fig5" ref-type="fig">5</xref>).
<fig id="Fig5" position="float" orientation="portrait"><label>Fig.&#160;5</label><caption><p>The Mid-Face Volume Deficit Scale was designed to evaluate the overall volume deficit of the mid-face, from 0 [none] to 6 or severe</p></caption><graphic xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" id="MO5" position="float" orientation="portrait" xlink:href="266_2017_798_Fig5_HTML.jpg"/></fig>
</p></sec></sec></sec><sec id="Sec15"><title>Procedure Care</title><sec id="Sec16"><title>Patient and Theatre Preparation</title><p>It is essential to standardize the surgical procedures to achieve the most desirable outcomes. In the panel&#8217;s opinion, there are different aspects that need to be taken into consideration when preparing the patient and the operating theatre for treatment. Table&#160;<xref rid="Tab3" ref-type="table">3</xref> shows the expert panel&#8217;s recommendations regarding these issues.<table-wrap id="Tab3" position="float" orientation="portrait"><label>Table&#160;3</label><caption><p>Expert panel members&#8217; recommendations for preparing the patient and the theatre for the aesthetic procedure</p></caption><table frame="hsides" rules="groups"><thead><tr><th align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Recommendations for patient and material management</th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">To have an auxiliary table</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">&#160;That helps us to maintain the aseptic conditions of the surgical materials</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">An assistant for opening the drawers</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">&#160;If not possible, it is mandatory to change or clean the gloves every time the surgeon touch something outside the sterile field</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">The patient bed should be foldable</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Use of mask is recommended</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Sterile gauzes should be opened starting the procedure*</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">&#160;It is recommended to leave them inside the plastic bag, especially when an assistant is not available</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">The physician should wash his/her hands thoroughly and remove their watch and rings</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Patient must wash their hands with an alcohol-based gel hand disinfectant**</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">It is recommended to use sterile gloves</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">&#160;Always for cannulas</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">&#160;Recommended for needle***</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Sharpen the pencils and clean them after each use</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">In order to avoid demarcation lines and skin pigmentation, it is mandatory to clean the skin that has been drawn before injecting</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">When needed, the lip must to be done at the end of the process</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">&#160;Surgeon must put special attention about do not touch any other part of the face after having touched the mucosa</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">&#160;If the surgeon needs to touch the face after handling the lip, it will be advisable to change the gloves</td></tr></tbody></table><table-wrap-foot><p>*&#160;Non-sterile gauzes can be used, but they should be damped with an antiseptic and kept on a clean surface throughout the procedure</p><p>**&#160;A specified quantity an alcohol-based gel hand disinfectant is placed in a subject&#8217;s cupped palms, and the subject rubbed the product onto all surfaces of the hands up to the wrists &#8220;until the patient felt their hands dry&#8221;</p><p>***&#160;As syringes are not sterile, in such a case, the expert panel recommends to wear surgical gloves, although not necessarily sterile</p></table-wrap-foot></table-wrap>
</p></sec><sec id="Sec17"><title>Preparation of the Treatment Area</title><p>Although the incidence of infection following soft tissue injections is quite low [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR35">35</xref>&#8211;<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR39">39</xref>], adequate skin preparation is critical to prevent superficial soft tissue infection [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR40">40</xref>]. Thus, patients with an ongoing skin infection in the area to be treated, or in close proximity, should not be treated [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR41">41</xref>]. Different commercially available antiseptic solutions have been used to prepare the skin for dermal filler procedures, yet no differences in terms of the rate of contaminated blood cultures were described with 10% povidone-iodine, 70% isopropyl alcohol, tincture of iodine, or povidone-iodine with 70% ethyl alcohol [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR40">40</xref>]. The panel recommends the combined use of a quaternary ammonium compound with 70% ethyl alcohol, or of chlorhexidine and 70% ethyl alcohol. However, it is important to note that chlorhexidine should be avoided in the periocular area due to the potential risk of keratitis and possible ocular damage [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR11">11</xref>].</p><p>There is no evidence that fillers trigger recurrent herpes infection, and thus, there is no reason to use anti-herpetic prophylaxis with every patient. Nevertheless, patients who have a history of developing cold sores after filler injection could benefit from such an approach. Hence, in patients with a history of recurrent herpes the panel recommends a prophylactic treatment with valacyclovir (1&#160;g) for 3&#8211;4&#160;days prior to treatment and for 3&#8211;4&#160;days after.</p><p>Table&#160;<xref rid="Tab4" ref-type="table">4</xref> summarizes the panel&#8217;s recommendations regarding the preparation of the treatment area.<table-wrap id="Tab4" position="float" orientation="portrait"><label>Table&#160;4</label><caption><p>Recommendations for preparing the area for filler administration</p></caption><table frame="hsides" rules="groups"><thead><tr><th align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Preparing the area for filler administration</th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">A surgical cap should be used</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">&#160;If it is not possible, at least, the hair should be correctly put up with a headband</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">It is highly recommended that the sink be located in the surgical room<sup>a</sup>
</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Clean the make-up properly<sup>b</sup>
</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">&#160;Not to apply make-up since the day before the treatment.</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">&#160;If the patient comes made-up to the clinic, apply chlorhexidine at least for three minutes after removing the making-up</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">To use an antiseptic solution</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">&#160;The combination of a quaternary ammonium compound&#160;+&#160;70% ethyl alcohol</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">&#160;The combination of chlorhexidine&#160;+&#160;70% ethyl alcohol</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">&#160;Always disinfect all the skin and not only the area to be treated since most of the times, for example when handling cannulas, we touch different parts</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">To use disposable towels with antiseptic solution</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">&#160;They should be used before and after each injection at the injection point<sup>c</sup>
</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">It is recommended to put antiseptic solution in the cover of the cannula</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">To regularly check that the needle is in perfect shape<sup>d</sup>
</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">&#160;In terms of its sterile condition</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">&#160;To assess that it is not blunt</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Do not refill the chlorhexidine bottles</td></tr></tbody></table><table-wrap-foot><p>
<sup>a</sup>In some Spanish regions is mandatory</p><p>
<sup>b</sup>As some kinds of make-up are indeed hard to remove in office, the panel recommends not to apply make-up since the day before the treatment</p><p>
<sup>c</sup>This should never be a substitute of the antiseptic solution used before the procedure</p><p>
<sup>d</sup>The panel recommends to change the needle after every 3&#8211;4 punctures</p></table-wrap-foot></table-wrap>
</p></sec><sec id="Sec18"><title>Anaesthesia</title><p>One of the main concerns of the patients with regard to the injection of the filler injections is the pain and discomfort associated, especially for the first-time patient. Whereas topical anaesthetics alone can provide adequate anaesthesia for some procedures, others require the injection of a local anaesthetic. However, while anaesthesia that blocks the nerves is effective against the pain, it may distort the area to be treated, as well as lengthen and complicate the procedure. Indeed, lidocaine injected in the infraorbital region distorts the local anatomy and may result in suboptimal correction [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR12">12</xref>]. Furthermore, there is a possibility that patients may experience an allergic reaction to lidocaine. However, a review of the literature showed that the incidence of true allergic reactions to local anaesthetic agents (including lidocaine and other products) was &lt;1% [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR41">41</xref>].</p></sec><sec id="Sec19"><title>Injection Technique</title><p>Selecting the appropriate technique for administration, based on the physician&#8217;s experience, the patient and the characteristics of the filler, helps to ensure successful outcomes and limits the incidence of complications. To identify and react to any adverse reaction, injections must be performed slowly and with caution. In terms of the filler, that amount administered should be adapted to each individual and injected in small quantities at multiple points to avoid overfilling [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR42">42</xref>]. Before injecting, aspiration should be performed as a prophylactic measure, particularly in highly vascularized areas, and a new needle without filler should be used prior to deep bolus injections [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR11">11</xref>].</p><p>For needle treatment, the panel recommends that adequate suctioning should be employed before injecting, at least 0.1&#8211;0.2&#160;cc of air, and waiting for at least 4&#160;s. Additionally, the experts also recommend changing the needle every 3 or 4 punctures. If the treatment is going to be administered using a blunt tip cannula, the panel recommends paying special attention to maintaining it sterile:<list list-type="bullet"><list-item><p>The cannula should not be touched.</p></list-item><list-item><p>Non-sterile areas should not be touched with the cannula.</p></list-item><list-item><p>The cannula should be kept in its cap when not in use (it is recommended that antiseptic solution is put into the cannula cap).</p></list-item></list>
</p></sec></sec><sec id="Sec20"><title>Post-procedural Care</title><p>Post-procedural care plays a vital role in achieving optimal results, and hence, the panel considers it is essential to inform patients as to how they should act after treatment.</p><p>Patients should be asked to comply with the following recommendations:<list list-type="order"><list-item><p>Avoid extreme cold or heat for 48&#160;h.</p></list-item><list-item><p>Avoid massaging the treated area.</p></list-item><list-item><p>Avoid strenuous physical activity.</p></list-item><list-item><p>Sleep with their heads elevated for one night.</p></list-item><list-item><p>A skin care routine may be followed only once 24&#160;h have passed.</p></list-item><list-item><p>Patients should not undergo dental procedures that might lead to gum bleeding in the 3&#8211;4&#160;weeks following facial filler treatment.</p></list-item><list-item><p>In those patients with a predisposition to bruising, a vitamin K cream or arnica gel may be useful to speed up its resolution.</p></list-item></list>
</p><sec id="Sec21"><title>Documentation</title><p>To trace untoward effects that might arise from manufacturing discrepancies, the batch number sticker provided with the filler should be attached to the patient&#8217;s consent form or medical chart. Indeed, the entire process should be exhaustively documented, including the injection pattern and technique, the name and amount of the filler injected, and the area(s) treated. The panel considers it extremely useful to use a diagnostic/treatment code tool.</p></sec></sec></sec><sec id="Sec22"><title>Conclusions</title><p>Aesthetic medical procedures with dermal fillers are becoming increasingly popular. For this reason, aesthetic clinicians must become aware of how to prevent and how to manage any potential complications. The panel agrees that the adequate selection of the patient, technique and filler will help to ensure a desirable outcome. Moreover, to prevent future undesirable outcomes and serious adverse events, it will be important to carefully document the procedure, technique and the filler administered. A diagnostic/treatment code tool may be suitable to achieve this. This consensus highlights key elements that will help clinicians who are just starting to use dermal filler procedures, and it could serve as a basis to standardize the process and to establish how to prevent potential complications of this treatment.
</p></sec></body><back><ack><title>Acknowledgements</title><p>The authors wish to thank Allergan Laboratories for their collaboration with the logistics of the meetings and the assistance with the medical writing. The authors thank Dr Antonio Martinez of Ciencia y Deporte S.L. and Mark Sefton of Biomedred S.L. for providing medical writing and editorial assistance. It should be noted that Allergan S.A. was not involved in the preparation of the recommendations nor did the company influence in any way the scientific consensus reached.</p></ack><notes notes-type="COI-statement"><title>Compliance with Ethical Standards</title><sec id="FPar1"><title>Conflict of interest</title><p>None.</p></sec></notes><ref-list id="Bib1"><title>References</title><ref id="CR1"><label>1.</label><mixed-citation publication-type="other">2012 Plastic Surgery Procedural Statistics (2012) <ext-link xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" ext-link-type="uri" xlink:href="http://www.plasticsurgery.org/Documents/news-resources/statistics/2012-Plastic-Surgery-Statistics/plastic-surgery-trends-quick-facts.pdf">http://www.plasticsurgery.org/Documents/news-resources/statistics/2012-Plastic-Surgery-Statistics/plastic-surgery-trends-quick-facts.pdf</ext-link>. Accessed on 13 June 16</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="CR2"><label>2.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Funt</surname><given-names>D</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Pavicic</surname><given-names>T</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>Dermal fillers in aesthetics: an overview of adverse events and treatment approaches</article-title><source>Clin Cosmet Investig Dermatol</source><year>2013</year><volume>6</volume><fpage>295</fpage><lpage>316</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">24363560</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.2147/CCID.S50546</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC3865975</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR3"><label>3.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Rzany</surname><given-names>B</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Hilton</surname><given-names>S</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Prager</surname><given-names>W</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Hartmann</surname><given-names>V</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Brandl</surname><given-names>G</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Fischer</surname><given-names>TC</given-names></name><etal/></person-group><article-title>Expert guideline on the use of porcine collagen in aesthetic medicine</article-title><source>J Dtsch Dermatol Ges</source><year>2010</year><volume>8</volume><issue>3</issue><fpage>210</fpage><lpage>217</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1111/j.1610-0387.2009.07321_supp.x</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">20030742</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR4"><label>4.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Johl</surname><given-names>SS</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Burgett</surname><given-names>RA</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>Dermal filler agents: a practical review</article-title><source>Curr Opin Ophthalmol</source><year>2006</year><volume>17</volume><issue>5</issue><fpage>471</fpage><lpage>479</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1097/01.icu.0000243021.20499.4b</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">16932063</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR5"><label>5.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Eppley</surname><given-names>BL</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Dadvand</surname><given-names>B</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>Injectable soft-tissue fillers: clinical overview</article-title><source>Plast Reconstr Surg</source><year>2006</year><volume>118</volume><issue>4</issue><fpage>98e</fpage><lpage>106e</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1097/01.prs.0000232436.91409.30</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">16980841</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR6"><label>6.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Coleman</surname><given-names>SR</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Grover</surname><given-names>R</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>The anatomy of the aging face: volume loss and changes in 3-dimensional topography</article-title><source>Aesthet Surg J</source><year>2006</year><volume>26</volume><issue>1S</issue><fpage>S4</fpage><lpage>S9</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1016/j.asj.2005.09.012</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">19338976</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR7"><label>7.</label><element-citation publication-type="book"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Wulc</surname><given-names>AE</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Sharma</surname><given-names>P</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Czyz</surname><given-names>CN</given-names></name><etal/></person-group><person-group person-group-type="editor"><name name-style="western"><surname>Hartstein</surname><given-names>ME</given-names></name><etal/></person-group><article-title>The anatomic basis of midfacial aging</article-title><source>Midfacial rejuvenation</source><year>2012</year><publisher-loc>Berlin</publisher-loc><publisher-name>Springer</publisher-name></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR8"><label>8.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Macierzy&#324;ska</surname><given-names>A</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Pierzcha&#322;a</surname><given-names>E</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Placek</surname><given-names>W</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>Volumetric techniques: three-dimensional midface modeling</article-title><source>Postepy Dermatol Alergol</source><year>2014</year><volume>31</volume><issue>6</issue><fpage>388</fpage><lpage>391</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.5114/pdia.2014.40981</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">25610354</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC4293387</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR9"><label>9.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Gosain</surname><given-names>AK</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Klein</surname><given-names>MH</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Sudhakar</surname><given-names>PV</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Prost</surname><given-names>RW</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>A volumetric analysis of soft-tissue changes in the aging midface using high-resolution MRI: implications for facial rejuvenation</article-title><source>Plast Reconstr Surg</source><year>2005</year><volume>115</volume><fpage>1143</fpage><lpage>1152</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1097/01.PRS.0000156333.57852.2F</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">15793457</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR10"><label>10.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>De Boulle</surname><given-names>K</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>Management of complications after implantation of fillers</article-title><source>J Cosmet Dermatol</source><year>2004</year><volume>3</volume><fpage>2</fpage><lpage>15</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1111/j.1473-2130.2004.00058.x</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">17163941</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR11"><label>11.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Bailey</surname><given-names>SH</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Cohen</surname><given-names>JL</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Kenkel</surname><given-names>JM</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>Etiology, prevention and treatment of dermal filler complications</article-title><source>Aesthet Surg J</source><year>2011</year><volume>31</volume><fpage>110</fpage><lpage>121</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1177/1090820X10391083</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">21239678</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR12"><label>12.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Vedamurthy</surname><given-names>M</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Vedamurthy</surname><given-names>A</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Nischal</surname><given-names>K</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>Dermal fillers: do&#8217;s and dont&#8217;s</article-title><source>J Cutan Aesthet Surg</source><year>2010</year><volume>3</volume><issue>1</issue><fpage>11</fpage><lpage>15</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.4103/0974-2077.63221</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">20606986</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC2890128</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR13"><label>13.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Naini</surname><given-names>FB</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Gill</surname><given-names>DS</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>Facial aesthetics: 2. Clinical assessment</article-title><source>Dent Update</source><year>2008</year><volume>35</volume><issue>3</issue><fpage>159</fpage><lpage>162</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">18507224</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.12968/denu.2008.35.3.159</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR14"><label>14.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Faaber</surname><given-names>P</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Capel</surname><given-names>PJ</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Rijke</surname><given-names>GP</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Vierwinden</surname><given-names>G</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>van de Putte</surname><given-names>LB</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Koene</surname><given-names>RA</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>Cross-reactivity of anti-DNA antibodies with proteoglycans</article-title><source>Clin Exp Immunol</source><year>1984</year><volume>55</volume><fpage>502</fpage><lpage>508</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">6608423</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC1535916</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR15"><label>15.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Khalifeh</surname><given-names>MR</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Redett</surname><given-names>RJ</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>The management of patients on anticoagulants prior to cutaneous surgery: case report of a thromboembolic complication, review of the literature, and evidence-based recommendations</article-title><source>Plast Reconstr Surg</source><year>2006</year><volume>118</volume><fpage>110e</fpage><lpage>117e</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1097/01.prs.0000221114.01290.85</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">17016167</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR16"><label>16.</label><mixed-citation publication-type="other">
Juvederm Ultra. Package insert (2016). <ext-link xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" ext-link-type="uri" xlink:href="http://www.allergan.com/miscellaneous-pages/allergan-pdf-files/juvederm_ultra_xc_dfu">http://www.allergan.com/miscellaneous-pages/allergan-pdf-files/juvederm_ultra_xc_dfu</ext-link>. Last visit June 2016</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="CR17"><label>17.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Milosevi&#263;</surname><given-names>SA</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Varga</surname><given-names>ML</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Slaj</surname><given-names>M</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>Analysis of the soft tissue facial profile of Croatians using of linear measurements</article-title><source>J Craniofac Surg</source><year>2008</year><volume>19</volume><issue>1</issue><fpage>251</fpage><lpage>258</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1097/scs.0b013e31815c9446</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">18216697</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR18"><label>18.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Ani&#263;-Milosevi&#263;</surname><given-names>S</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Lapter-Varga</surname><given-names>M</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Slaj</surname><given-names>M</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>Analysis of the soft tissue facial profile by means of angular measurements</article-title><source>Eur J Orthod</source><year>2008</year><volume>30</volume><issue>2</issue><fpage>135</fpage><lpage>140</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1093/ejo/cjm116</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">18263886</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR19"><label>19.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Hockley</surname><given-names>A</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Weinstein</surname><given-names>M</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Borislow</surname><given-names>AJ</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Braitman</surname><given-names>LE</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>Photos vs silhouettes for evaluation of African American profile esthetics</article-title><source>Am J Orthod Dentofac Orthop</source><year>2012</year><volume>141</volume><issue>2</issue><fpage>161</fpage><lpage>168</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1016/j.ajodo.2011.06.041</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">22284283</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR20"><label>20.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Milutinovic</surname><given-names>J</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Zelic</surname><given-names>K</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Nedeljkovic</surname><given-names>N</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>Evaluation of facial beauty using anthropometric proportions</article-title><source>Sci World J</source><year>2014</year><volume>2014</volume><fpage>428250</fpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1155/2014/428250</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC3951104</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">24701166</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR21"><label>21.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>McKnight</surname><given-names>A</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Momoh</surname><given-names>AO</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Bullocks</surname><given-names>JM</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>Variations of structural components: specific intercultural differences in facial morphology, skin type, and structures</article-title><source>Semin Plast Surg</source><year>2009</year><volume>23</volume><issue>3</issue><fpage>163</fpage><lpage>167</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1055/s-0029-1224794</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">20676309</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC2884921</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR22"><label>22.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Mommaerts</surname><given-names>MY</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Moerenhout</surname><given-names>BA</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>Ideal proportions in full face front view, contemporary versus antique</article-title><source>J Craniomaxillofac Surg</source><year>2011</year><volume>39</volume><issue>2</issue><fpage>107</fpage><lpage>110</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1016/j.jcms.2010.04.012</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">20542444</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR23"><label>23.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Young</surname><given-names>SR</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Bolton</surname><given-names>PA</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Downie</surname><given-names>J</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>Use of high-frequency ultrasound in the assessment of injectable dermal fillers</article-title><source>Skin Res Technol</source><year>2008</year><volume>14</volume><issue>3</issue><fpage>320</fpage><lpage>323</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1111/j.1600-0846.2008.00297.x</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">19159378</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR24"><label>24.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Grippaudo</surname><given-names>FR</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Mattei</surname><given-names>M</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>The utility of high-frequency ultrasound in dermal filler evaluation</article-title><source>Ann Plast Surg</source><year>2011</year><volume>67</volume><issue>5</issue><fpage>469</fpage><lpage>473</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1097/SAP.0b013e318203ebf6</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">21346530</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR25"><label>25.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Papageorgiou</surname><given-names>K</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Chang</surname><given-names>HS</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Isaacs</surname><given-names>D</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Fiaschetti</surname><given-names>D</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Ang</surname><given-names>M</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Goldberg</surname><given-names>R</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>Refining the goals of oculofacial rejuvenation with dynamic ultrasonography</article-title><source>Aesthet Surg J</source><year>2012</year><volume>32</volume><issue>2</issue><fpage>207</fpage><lpage>219</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1177/1090820X11434523</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">22328690</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR26"><label>26.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Schlickmann</surname><given-names>IAC</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Moro</surname><given-names>A</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Anjos</surname><given-names>A</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>Facial profile analysis of esthetically harmonious young male adults in standardized photographs: comparison of manual versus computerized measurements</article-title><source>Rev Dental Press Ortod Ortop Facial</source><year>2008</year><volume>13</volume><issue>6</issue><fpage>98</fpage><lpage>107</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1590/S1415-54192008000600012</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR27"><label>27.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Carruthers</surname><given-names>A</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Carruthers</surname><given-names>J</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Hardas</surname><given-names>B</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Kaur</surname><given-names>M</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Goertelmeyer</surname><given-names>R</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Jones</surname><given-names>D</given-names></name><etal/></person-group><article-title>A validated grading scale for forehead lines</article-title><source>Dermatol Surg</source><year>2008</year><volume>34</volume><issue>Suppl 2</issue><fpage>S155</fpage><lpage>S160</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">19021673</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1111/j.1524-4725.2008.34364.x</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR28"><label>28.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Carruthers</surname><given-names>A</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Carruthers</surname><given-names>J</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Hardas</surname><given-names>B</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Kaur</surname><given-names>M</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Goertelmeyer</surname><given-names>R</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Jones</surname><given-names>D</given-names></name><etal/></person-group><article-title>A validated lip fullness grading scale</article-title><source>Dermatol Surg</source><year>2008</year><volume>34</volume><issue>Suppl 2</issue><fpage>S161</fpage><lpage>S166</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">19021674</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1111/j.1524-4725.2008.34365.x</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR29"><label>29.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Carruthers</surname><given-names>A</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Carruthers</surname><given-names>J</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Hardas</surname><given-names>B</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Kaur</surname><given-names>M</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Goertelmeyer</surname><given-names>R</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Jones</surname><given-names>D</given-names></name><etal/></person-group><article-title>A validated grading scale for crow&#8217;s feet</article-title><source>Dermatol Surg</source><year>2008</year><volume>34</volume><issue>Suppl 2</issue><fpage>S173</fpage><lpage>S178</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">19021676</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1111/j.1524-4725.2008.34367.x</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR30"><label>30.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Carruthers</surname><given-names>A</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Carruthers</surname><given-names>J</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Hardas</surname><given-names>B</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Kaur</surname><given-names>M</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Goertelmeyer</surname><given-names>R</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Jones</surname><given-names>D</given-names></name><etal/></person-group><article-title>A validated brow positioning grading scale</article-title><source>Dermatol Surg</source><year>2008</year><volume>34</volume><issue>Suppl 2</issue><fpage>S150</fpage><lpage>S154</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">19021672</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1111/j.1524-4725.2008.34363.x</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR31"><label>31.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Narins</surname><given-names>RS</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Carruthers</surname><given-names>J</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Flynn</surname><given-names>TC</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Geister</surname><given-names>TL</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>G&#246;rtelmeyer</surname><given-names>R</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Hardas</surname><given-names>B</given-names></name><etal/></person-group><article-title>Validated assessment scales for the lower face</article-title><source>Dermatol Surg</source><year>2012</year><volume>38</volume><issue>2 Spec No.</issue><fpage>333</fpage><lpage>342</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1111/j.1524-4725.2011.02247.x</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">22316189</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR32"><label>32.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Carruthers</surname><given-names>A</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Carruthers</surname><given-names>J</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>A validated facial grading scale: the future of facial ageing measurement tools?</article-title><source>J Cosmet Laser Ther</source><year>2010</year><volume>12</volume><issue>5</issue><fpage>235</fpage><lpage>241</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.3109/14764172.2010.514920</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">20825260</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR33"><label>33.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Goldsberry</surname><given-names>A</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Hanke</surname><given-names>CW</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Hanke</surname><given-names>KE</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>VISIA system: a possible tool in the cosmetic practice</article-title><source>J Drugs Dermatol</source><year>2014</year><volume>13</volume><issue>11</issue><fpage>1312</fpage><lpage>1314</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">25607694</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR34"><label>34.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Jacono</surname><given-names>AA</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Malone</surname><given-names>MH</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Talei</surname><given-names>B</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>Three-dimensional analysis of long-term midface volume change after vertical vector deep-plane rhytidectomy</article-title><source>Aesthet Surg J</source><year>2015</year><volume>35</volume><issue>5</issue><fpage>491</fpage><lpage>503</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1093/asj/sju171</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">26063830</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR35"><label>35.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Brian</surname><given-names>R</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Toy</surname><given-names>PJF</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>Outbreak of mycobacterium abscessus infection after soft tissue augmentation</article-title><source>Dermatol Surg</source><year>2003</year><volume>29</volume><fpage>971</fpage><lpage>973</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">12930343</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1046/j.1524-4725.2003.29262.x</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR36"><label>36.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>DeLorenzi</surname><given-names>C</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>Complications of injectable fillers, part I</article-title><source>Aesthet Surg J</source><year>2013</year><volume>33</volume><issue>4</issue><fpage>561</fpage><lpage>575</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1177/1090820X13484492</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">23636629</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR37"><label>37.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Lucey</surname><given-names>P</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Goldberg</surname><given-names>DJ</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>Complications of collagen fillers</article-title><source>Facial Plast Surg</source><year>2014</year><volume>30</volume><issue>6</issue><fpage>615</fpage><lpage>622</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1055/s-0034-1396904</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">25536127</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR38"><label>38.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Heppt</surname><given-names>M</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Hartmann</surname><given-names>D</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Reinholz</surname><given-names>M</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Feller-Heppt</surname><given-names>G</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Ruzicka</surname><given-names>T</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Gauglitz</surname><given-names>GG</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>Fillers and associated side effects</article-title><source>HNO</source><year>2015</year><volume>63</volume><issue>7</issue><fpage>472</fpage><lpage>480</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1007/s00106-015-0030-9</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">26148563</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR39"><label>39.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Wagner</surname><given-names>RD</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Fakhro</surname><given-names>A</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Cox</surname><given-names>JA</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Izaddoost</surname><given-names>SA</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>Etiology, prevention, and management of infectious complications of dermal fillers</article-title><source>Semin Plast Surg</source><year>2016</year><volume>30</volume><issue>2</issue><fpage>83</fpage><lpage>86</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1055/s-0036-1580734</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">27152101</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC4856531</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR40"><label>40.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Calfee</surname><given-names>DP</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Farr</surname><given-names>BM</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>Comparison of four antiseptic preparations for skin in the prevention of contamination of percutaneously drawn blood cultures: a randomized trial</article-title><source>J Clin Microbiol</source><year>2002</year><volume>40</volume><fpage>1660</fpage><lpage>1665</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1128/JCM.40.5.1660-1665.2002</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">11980938</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC130950</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR41"><label>41.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Lafaille</surname><given-names>P</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Benedetto</surname><given-names>A</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>Fillers: contraindications, side effects and precautions</article-title><source>J Cutan Aesthet Surg</source><year>2010</year><volume>3</volume><issue>1</issue><fpage>16</fpage><lpage>19</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.4103/0974-2077.63222</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">20606987</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC2890129</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR42"><label>42.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Bhole</surname><given-names>MV</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Manson</surname><given-names>AL</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Seneviratne</surname><given-names>SL</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Misbah</surname><given-names>SA</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>IgE-mediated allergy to local anaesthetics: separating fact from perception: a UK perspective</article-title><source>Br J Anaesth</source><year>2012</year><volume>108</volume><issue>6</issue><fpage>903</fpage><lpage>911</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1093/bja/aes162</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">22593127</pub-id></element-citation></ref></ref-list></back></article></pmc-articleset>