<?xml version="1.0"  ?><!DOCTYPE pmc-articleset PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD ARTICLE SET 2.0//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pmc/articleset/nlm-articleset-2.0.dtd"><pmc-articleset><article xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" xmlns:ali="http://www.niso.org/schemas/ali/1.0/" article-type="case-report" xml:lang="en" dtd-version="1.4"><front><journal-meta><journal-id journal-id-type="nlm-ta">JAAD Case Rep</journal-id><journal-id journal-id-type="iso-abbrev">JAAD Case Rep</journal-id><journal-id journal-id-type="pmc-domain-id">2969</journal-id><journal-id journal-id-type="pmc-domain">jaadcr</journal-id><journal-title-group><journal-title>JAAD Case Reports</journal-title></journal-title-group><issn pub-type="epub">2352-5126</issn><publisher><publisher-name>Elsevier</publisher-name></publisher></journal-meta><article-meta><article-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC6558264</article-id><article-id pub-id-type="pmcid-ver">PMC6558264.1</article-id><article-id pub-id-type="pmcaid">6558264</article-id><article-id pub-id-type="pmcaiid">6558264</article-id><article-id pub-id-type="pmid">31205997</article-id><article-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1016/j.jdcr.2019.02.034</article-id><article-id pub-id-type="publisher-id">S2352-5126(19)30120-1</article-id><article-version article-version-type="pmc-version">1</article-version><article-categories><subj-group subj-group-type="heading"><subject>Case Series</subject></subj-group></article-categories><title-group><article-title>Selection criteria and techniques for improved cosmesis and predictable outcomes in laser hair removal treatment of acne keloidalis nuchae</article-title></title-group><contrib-group><contrib contrib-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Umar</surname><given-names initials="S">Sanusi</given-names></name><degrees>MD</degrees><email>drumar@dru.com</email><xref rid="cor1" ref-type="corresp">&#8727;</xref></contrib></contrib-group><aff id="aff1">Department of Medicine, Dermatology Division, University of California at Los Angeles, Los Angeles, California</aff><aff id="aff2">Dr U Hair and Skin Clinic, Redondo Beach, California</aff><aff id="aff3">Harbor-UCLA Department of Medicine, Dermatology Division, Torrance, California</aff><author-notes><corresp id="cor1"><label>&#8727;</label>Correspondence to: Sanusi Umar, MD, Dr U Hair and Skin Clinic, 510 N. Prospect Avenue, Suite 209, Redondo Beach, CA 90277. <email>drumar@dru.com</email></corresp></author-notes><pub-date pub-type="collection"><month>6</month><year>2019</year></pub-date><pub-date pub-type="epub"><day>08</day><month>6</month><year>2019</year></pub-date><volume>5</volume><issue>6</issue><issue-id pub-id-type="pmc-issue-id">335139</issue-id><fpage>529</fpage><lpage>534</lpage><pub-history><event event-type="pmc-release"><date><day>08</day><month>06</month><year>2019</year></date></event><event event-type="pmc-live"><date><day>14</day><month>06</month><year>2019</year></date></event><event event-type="pmc-last-change"><date iso-8601-date="2024-07-17 04:25:15.510"><day>17</day><month>07</month><year>2024</year></date></event></pub-history><permissions><copyright-statement>&#169; 2019 by the American Academy of Dermatology, Inc. Published by Elsevier, Inc.</copyright-statement><copyright-year>2019</copyright-year><copyright-holder>American Academy of Dermatology, Inc.</copyright-holder><license xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" license-type="CC BY-NC-ND" xlink:href="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/4.0/"><ali:license_ref specific-use="textmining" content-type="ccbyncndlicense">https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/4.0/</ali:license_ref><license-p>This is an open access article under the CC BY-NC-ND license (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/4.0/).</license-p></license></permissions><self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" content-type="pmc-pdf" xlink:href="main.pdf"/><related-article xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" related-article-type="correction-forward" xml:lang="en" xlink:title="correction" vol="5" journal-id="JAAD Case Rep" journal-id-type="nlm-ta" ext-link-type="pmc" xlink:href="PMC6728734"><article-title>Correction</article-title><volume>5</volume><issue>9</issue><date><day>29</day><month>8</month><year>2019</year></date><fpage>809</fpage><lpage>809</lpage><source>JAAD Case Reports</source><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC6728734</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">31517004</pub-id></related-article><kwd-group id="kwrds0010"><title>Key words</title><kwd>acne keloidalis nuchae</kwd><kwd>hairline</kwd><kwd>laser hair removal</kwd><kwd>outcome</kwd><kwd>selection criteria</kwd></kwd-group><kwd-group id="kwrds0015"><title>Abbreviations used</title><kwd>AKN, acne keloidalis nuchae</kwd><kwd>Nd-YAG, neodymium-doped yttrium aluminum garnet</kwd></kwd-group><custom-meta-group><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-status-qastatus</meta-name><meta-value>0</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-status-live</meta-name><meta-value>yes</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-status-embargo</meta-name><meta-value>no</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-status-released</meta-name><meta-value>yes</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-open-access</meta-name><meta-value>yes</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-olf</meta-name><meta-value>no</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-manuscript</meta-name><meta-value>no</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-legally-suppressed</meta-name><meta-value>no</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-has-pdf</meta-name><meta-value>yes</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-has-supplement</meta-name><meta-value>no</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-pdf-only</meta-name><meta-value>no</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-suppress-copyright</meta-name><meta-value>no</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-is-real-version</meta-name><meta-value>no</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-is-scanned-article</meta-name><meta-value>no</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-preprint</meta-name><meta-value>no</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-in-epmc</meta-name><meta-value>yes</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-license-ref</meta-name><meta-value>CC BY-NC-ND</meta-value></custom-meta></custom-meta-group></article-meta></front><body><sec id="sec1"><title>Introduction</title><p id="p0010">A common denominator for successful, long-term treatment of acne keloidalis nuchae (AKN) with low recurrence is elimination of hair in the lesions, which can be achieved by surgical means or laser hair removal.<xref rid="bib1" ref-type="bibr">1</xref>, <xref rid="bib2" ref-type="bibr">2</xref>, <xref rid="bib3" ref-type="bibr">3</xref>, <xref rid="bib4" ref-type="bibr">4</xref>, <xref rid="bib5" ref-type="bibr">5</xref>, <xref rid="bib6" ref-type="bibr">6</xref>, <xref rid="bib7" ref-type="bibr">7</xref>, <xref rid="bib8" ref-type="bibr">8</xref> Although laser hair removal typically improves AKN,<xref rid="bib5" ref-type="bibr">5</xref>, <xref rid="bib6" ref-type="bibr">6</xref>, <xref rid="bib7" ref-type="bibr">7</xref>, <xref rid="bib8" ref-type="bibr">8</xref> not all lesions are equally responsive to treatment.<xref rid="bib5" ref-type="bibr"><sup>5</sup></xref> Furthermore, although studies generally report favorable outcomes from laser hair removal in treating AKN, they have also described variability in outcomes<xref rid="bib5" ref-type="bibr">5</xref>, <xref rid="bib6" ref-type="bibr">6</xref>, <xref rid="bib7" ref-type="bibr">7</xref> and the need for a standardized scoring system.<xref rid="bib8" ref-type="bibr"><sup>8</sup></xref></p><p id="p0015">This report describes a methodology for selecting patients for laser AKN treatment based on height of individual folliculocentric lesions and a laser treatment classification system to maximize patient outcomes and expectations.</p></sec><sec id="sec2"><title>Methods</title><sec id="sec2.1"><title>Selection criteria</title><p id="p0020">The author restricted laser treatments to patients with folliculocentric lesions that were either discrete follicular papules or nodules, or papules and nodules that coalesce to form follicular plaques. Plaques with smooth bald plaques were excluded. Lesions must also have a preferred vertical height (above the skin surface) of 2 to 3&#160;mm, because the neodymium-doped yttrium aluminum garnet (Nd-YAG) laser penetrates 5 to 7&#160;mm,<xref rid="bib9" ref-type="bibr"><sup>9</sup></xref> and average scalp hair follicle length is 2 to 4&#160;mm, with the coarsest averaging 5&#160;mm.<xref rid="bib6" ref-type="bibr"><sup>6</sup></xref> Keeping lesions to less than 3&#160;mm also ensured a higher likelihood of penetration depth equivalent to the entire length of the hair follicle (<xref rid="fig1" ref-type="fig">Fig&#160;1</xref>).<fig id="fig1" position="float" orientation="portrait"><label>Fig 1</label><caption><p>Schematic explaining why a &#8804;2-mm vertical height limit for AKN lesions is preferred for optimal treatment response. The depth which laser waves must penetrate to kill hair should include the length of the hair follicle from the epidermal surface to the hair bulb plus the vertical height of the AKN lesion. &#169; 2018 MediVisuals, Inc.</p></caption><graphic xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" position="float" orientation="portrait" xlink:href="gr1.jpg"/></fig></p></sec><sec id="sec2.2"><title>Zone of laser treatment and classification</title><p id="p0025">Treating lesions alone will result in the appearance of patchy areas of hair loss. Additionally, neighboring hair follicles are a potential source of new AKN lesions through which the disease propagates. By treating adjacent areas, the chance of disease spread is minimized. Additionally, the zone of treatment was chosen to deliberately result in an area of alopecia that caused shifting of the posterior hairline superiorly (<xref rid="fig2" ref-type="fig">Figs 2</xref> and <xref rid="fig3" ref-type="fig">3</xref>). The result was areas below the superior border of the treated area appearing as hairless skin contiguous with hairless neck skin. With this scenario, alopecia induced by the laser is camouflaged.<fig id="fig2" position="float" orientation="portrait"><label>Fig 2</label><caption><p><bold>A</bold>, Level I candidacy. These are patients in whom the qualifying primary lesions are predominantly located in the lower half of the sagittal distance between the occipital notch (superiorly) and the posterior hairline (inferiorly). A new hairline would be created that is cosmetically indistinguishable from normal posterior hairlines. <bold>B</bold>, Level II candidacy. These are patients whose distribution of AKN lesions are predominantly in the upper half of the area described above but below the level of the occipital notch. Minor breaches in the line that do not exceed the level of the occipital notch can be tolerated. A new posterior hairline would be created that is higher than typical hairlines. &#169; 2018 MediVisuals, Inc.</p></caption><graphic xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" position="float" orientation="portrait" xlink:href="gr2.jpg"/></fig><fig id="fig3" position="float" orientation="portrait"><label>Fig 3</label><caption><p><bold>A</bold>, Level III candidacy. This classification describes a patient whose predominant lesions extend to the level of the occipital notch or slightly above it. Laser treatment is performed with the goal of creating a very high posterior hairline at the level of the occipital notch or complete elimination of the posterior hairline if lesions exceed the level of the occipital notch. Significantly thinned hair in the treated zone is accepted in lieu of complete baldness if lesion improvement is achieved. <bold>B</bold>, Level IV candidacy. There is widespread scalp involvement in these patients. The entire scalp is treated to eliminate AKN lesions and cause wholesale reduction or elimination of scalp hair. The patient is reconciled to being completely bald or severely thinned in the treated area. &#169; 2018 MediVisuals, Inc.</p></caption><graphic xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" position="float" orientation="portrait" xlink:href="gr3.jpg"/></fig></p><p id="p0030">Next, because alopecia is an expected effect of laser hair removal in AKN, the author adopted a severity-based classification system for predicting esthetic outcome using recommended laser treatment protocols. The severity classification, which extends from level I to IV is based on the scope of AKN lesion spread relative to the occipital notch. A detailed description of the classification system and treatment zones is illustrated in <xref rid="fig2" ref-type="fig">Figs 2</xref> and <xref rid="fig3" ref-type="fig">3</xref>.</p></sec><sec id="sec2.3"><title>The process</title><p id="p0035">The zone to be treated (level I-IV) was chosen according to the aforementioned classification system. Next, after clean shaving the designated zone, a topical anesthetic (benzocaine/lidocaine/tetracaine or lidocaine/prilocaine) was applied. Optionally, after a 30- to 45-minute interval, an epinephrine/lidocaine HCl 1% 1:1000,000 mix injection diluted with saline in 1:10 ratio was used to infiltrate the area.</p><p id="p0040">After waiting about 15&#160;minutes, lesions and nonlesion hair-bearing areas were treated with long-pulsed ND-YAG 1064&#160;nm (GentleYAG by Candela; Syneron, Inc, Irvine, CA). Treatment conditions used pulse durations of 30 to 40&#160;ms, spot size of 18&#160;mm, an energy fluence of 18 to 22&#160;mJ, as well as prepulse and postpulse dynamic epidermal cooling.</p><p id="p0045">If the skin tone is found to be significantly dark either preoperatively or during the treatment sessions because of natural skin tone or AKN-induced postinflammatory hyperpigmentation, hydroquinone 4% twice daily is prescribed. This treatment lightens the skin so the laser is better able to discern and target darker hair shafts more effectively with less possibility of skin burns.</p><p id="p0050">A minimum of four treatments at intervals of 6 to 8&#160;weeks was prescribed and is acceptable for good long-term results if no lesion recurrence is noted approximately 6&#160;months after treatment in the absence of any ancillary treatments (eg, steroids).</p></sec></sec><sec id="sec3"><title>Case 1</title><p id="p0055">A 52-year-old African-American man presented with follicular papules each of less than 3&#160;mm vertical height spread in an area below the halfway line between the occipital notch and posterior hairline. His papules were determined to be level I (<xref rid="fig4" ref-type="fig">Fig 4</xref>, <italic toggle="yes">A</italic>) after not responding to topical and intralesional steroid treatments. Before the initiation of laser treatment, patients with level I lesions are given the option of having rounded or sharp patterns at the lateral end corners of their new posterior hairlines. He chose sharp lateral corners for his proposed new posterior hairline, which was made to blend with the periauricular hairline. Four ND:YAG laser treatments were administered at 6- to 8-week intervals using methods recommended for level 1 lesion spread (<xref rid="fig2" ref-type="fig">Fig&#160;2</xref>, <italic toggle="yes">A</italic>). Permanent resolution of all AKN lesions occurred with excellent posterior hairline cosmesis (<xref rid="fig4" ref-type="fig">Fig 4</xref>, <italic toggle="yes">B</italic>).<fig id="fig4" position="float" orientation="portrait"><label>Fig 4</label><caption><p>Case 1, before (<bold>A</bold>) and 6&#160;months after (<bold>B</bold>) 4 sessions of ND-YAG laser treatments. Shows well camouflaged treated area the baldness of which blends with the bald neck. Minor hairline relocation with squared out lateral corners look very natural.</p></caption><graphic xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" position="float" orientation="portrait" xlink:href="gr4.jpg"/></fig></p></sec><sec id="sec4"><title>Case 2</title><p id="p0060">A 40-year-old Asian-American man with AKN did not respond to topical and intralesional steroid treatments and presented with follicular papules, each less than 3&#160;mm of vertical height spread in an area that extended above the halfway line between the occipital notch and posterior hairline (level II). A few satellite lesions extended to the occipital notch (<xref rid="fig5" ref-type="fig">Fig 5</xref>, <italic toggle="yes">A</italic>). Complete and permanent resolution was&#160;observed after 5 sessions of ND-YAG laser treatments at 6- to 8-week intervals using methods recommended for level II lesion spread (<xref rid="fig2" ref-type="fig">Fig 2</xref>, <italic toggle="yes">B</italic>). The patient was satisfied with a new posterior hairline comparable to an individual with naturally developed retrograde alopecia (<xref rid="fig5" ref-type="fig">Fig 5</xref>, <italic toggle="yes">B</italic>). Before treatment, the outcome was discussed and accepted by the patient who was also given the option of patchily treating the affected area by laser<xref rid="bib5" ref-type="bibr">5</xref>, <xref rid="bib6" ref-type="bibr">6</xref>, <xref rid="bib7" ref-type="bibr">7</xref>, <xref rid="bib8" ref-type="bibr">8</xref> or by surgical excision.<xref rid="bib1" ref-type="bibr">1</xref>, <xref rid="bib2" ref-type="bibr">2</xref>, <xref rid="bib3" ref-type="bibr">3</xref>, <xref rid="bib4" ref-type="bibr">4</xref><fig id="fig5" position="float" orientation="portrait"><label>Fig 5</label><caption><p>Case 2, before (<bold>A</bold>) and 1&#160;year after (<bold>B</bold>) 5 sessions of ND-YAG laser treatments.</p></caption><graphic xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" position="float" orientation="portrait" xlink:href="gr5.jpg"/></fig></p></sec><sec id="sec5"><title>Case 3</title><p id="p0065">A 24-year-old African-American man with AKN did not respond to topical steroid treatment and presented with follicular papules and nodules, each of less than 3&#160;mm vertical height spread in the entire back of the head extending from the posterior hairline to above the occipital notch line His lesions&#160;were determined to be level III (<xref rid="fig6" ref-type="fig">Fig 6</xref>, <italic toggle="yes">A</italic>). After 2 sessions of ND-YAG laser treatments using methods described for level III candidate (<xref rid="fig3" ref-type="fig">Fig 3</xref>, <italic toggle="yes">B</italic>) at 6- to 8-week intervals, the AKN lesions largely resolved with significant hair thinning in the entire treated zone. This patient preferred a thinning zone&#160;to complete baldness to have the option of grooming to mimic a tight crew-shaved appearance (<xref rid="fig6" ref-type="fig">Fig 6</xref>, <italic toggle="yes">B</italic>).<fig id="fig6" position="float" orientation="portrait"><label>Fig 6</label><caption><p>Case 3, before (<bold>A</bold>) and 3&#160;months after (<bold>B</bold>) 2 sessions of ND-YAG laser treatments.</p></caption><graphic xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" position="float" orientation="portrait" xlink:href="gr6.jpg"/></fig></p></sec><sec id="sec6"><title>Discussion</title><p id="p0070">Currently, the only treatments with curative possibility for AKN are surgical and laser hair removal.<xref rid="bib1" ref-type="bibr">1</xref>, <xref rid="bib2" ref-type="bibr">2</xref>, <xref rid="bib3" ref-type="bibr">3</xref>, <xref rid="bib4" ref-type="bibr">4</xref>, <xref rid="bib5" ref-type="bibr">5</xref>, <xref rid="bib6" ref-type="bibr">6</xref>, <xref rid="bib7" ref-type="bibr">7</xref>, <xref rid="bib8" ref-type="bibr">8</xref> A common feature of both treatments is the elimination of hair follicles at the center of the lesion. However, recurrent surgical removals may be necessary if the excisions are not carried to depths exceeding levels of the hair follicles. Although cure by radiation treatment has been used, in the single reported case, all lesional tufted hair was permanently lost at 20&#160;months after therapy.<xref rid="bib10" ref-type="bibr"><sup>10</sup></xref> The success of laser hair removal underscores the folliculocentric nature of the disease.<xref rid="bib5" ref-type="bibr">5</xref>, <xref rid="bib6" ref-type="bibr">6</xref>, <xref rid="bib7" ref-type="bibr">7</xref>, <xref rid="bib8" ref-type="bibr">8</xref></p><p id="p0075">Histologic studies have shown that hair follicles play a central role in both triggering the disease and perpetuating it into papules, indurated plaques, and masses.<xref rid="bib11" ref-type="bibr"><sup>11</sup></xref> It follows that hair follicle killing should occur for laser hair removal to be effective in AKN lesion treatment.<xref rid="bib7" ref-type="bibr"><sup>7</sup></xref></p><p id="p0080">Generally, long-pulse, long-wave lasers are favored, including the long-pulsed Alexandrite 755&#160;nm,<xref rid="bib7" ref-type="bibr"><sup>7</sup></xref> the long-pulsed Diode 800&#160;nm,<xref rid="bib6" ref-type="bibr"><sup>6</sup></xref> and the long-pulsed Nd-YAG 1064&#160;nm.<xref rid="bib5" ref-type="bibr">5</xref>, <xref rid="bib8" ref-type="bibr">8</xref> These lasers can penetrate deeply enough to target the entire dermal expanse of the average follicular length of 2 to 4&#160;mm (<xref rid="fig1" ref-type="fig">Fig 1</xref>) because of their longer wavelengths.</p><p id="p0085">Of these lasers, Nd-YAG is favored by the author because it penetrates the deepest of the 3 lasers (5-7&#160;mm)<xref rid="bib9" ref-type="bibr"><sup>9</sup></xref> and is the least absorbed by melanin, resulting in lesser skin damage for the most affected demographic (men of color). The safety profile is additionally enhanced by contact or the dynamic cooling of the epidermis.</p><p id="p0090">The advantage of the laser hair removal approach, especially in level I and II patients, is that the reward is immense&#8212;patients are rid of their disease permanently and with a very natural cosmetic outcome. Even level III patients have shown immense satisfaction and good outcomes. Furthermore, no wound is created in the process, so issues related to wound care and complications such as scarring are avoided. The drawback is that for some level II and III patients, the higher posterior hairline is not as natural looking. Patients whose lesions are more widespread (level III and IV) are typically unwilling to completely sacrifice their hair on a permanent basis. For this reason, they are first given the option to have fewer laser treatment sessions so that improvement or clearance of AKN lesions in the background of significant hair thinning rather than complete hair elimination in the treated zone is considered a satisfactory outcome. These patients have often preferred having significant hair thinning instead of complete baldness in the treated zones (<xref rid="fig5" ref-type="fig">Fig 5</xref>, <italic toggle="yes">B</italic>). Patients still have the option of getting more laser treatment sessions to eliminate hair permanently should new lesions develop after a waiting period of 6&#160;months.</p><p id="p0095">Laser hair removal also carries all the known risks&#160;of laser hair treatment, such as first- and second-degree burns. These latter complications are generally self-limiting and easily treatable. Because the treated area is often already inflamed from AKN diseased tissue, it is especially susceptible to developing burns. For this reason, cautionary measures should be taken, including use of melanin-sparing laser hair removal wavelengths (ND-YAG), lower energy settings, longer pulse durations, skin precooling, and avoiding double pulsing. Finally, multiple office visits over a period of at least 24&#160;weeks are required.</p></sec><sec id="sec7"><title>Conclusion</title><p id="p0100">Using the above methodology and selection criteria, laser hair removal can be an effective cure for AKN with good cosmesis.</p></sec></body><back><ref-list id="cebib0010"><title>References</title><ref id="bib1"><label>1</label><element-citation publication-type="journal" id="sref1"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Kanthak</surname><given-names>F.F.</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Cullen</surname><given-names>M.L.</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>Skin graft in the treatment of chronic furunculosis of the posterior surface of the neck (folliculitis keloidalis)</article-title><source>South Med J</source><volume>44</volume><year>1951</year><fpage>1154</fpage><lpage>1157</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">14884029</pub-id></element-citation><mixed-citation id="srct0025">Kanthak FF, Cullen ML. Skin graft in the treatment of chronic furunculosis of the posterior surface of the neck (folliculitis keloidalis). South Med J. 1951:44:1154-1157.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">14884029</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="bib2"><label>2</label><element-citation publication-type="journal" id="sref2"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Glenn</surname><given-names>J.M.</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Bennett</surname><given-names>R.G.</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Kelly</surname><given-names>A.P.</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>Acne keloidalis nuchae: treatment with excision and second-intention healing</article-title><source>J Am Acad Dermatol</source><volume>33</volume><issue>2 Pt 1</issue><year>1995</year><fpage>243</fpage><lpage>246</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">7622651</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1016/0190-9622(95)90242-2</pub-id></element-citation><mixed-citation id="srct0030">Glenn JM, Bennett RG, Kelly AP. Acne keloidalis nuchae: treatment with excision and second-intention healing. J Am Acad Dermatol. 1995;33(2 Pt 1):243-246.<pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1016/0190-9622(95)90242-2</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">7622651</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="bib3"><label>3</label><element-citation publication-type="journal" id="sref3"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Umar</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>David</surname><given-names>C.V.</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Castillo</surname><given-names>J.R.</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Queller</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>Innovative surgical approaches and selection criteria of large acne keloidalis nuchae lesions</article-title><source>Plast Reconstr Surg Glob Open</source><year>2019</year><comment>In press</comment><pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1097/GOX.0000000000002215</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC6571336</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">31333947</pub-id></element-citation><mixed-citation id="srct0035">Umar S, David CV, Castillo JR, Queller J et&#160;al. Innovative surgical approaches and selection criteria of large acne keloidalis nuchae lesions. Plast Reconstr Surgery Glob Open; In press.<pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1097/GOX.0000000000002215</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC6571336</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">31333947</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="bib4"><label>4</label><element-citation publication-type="journal" id="sref4"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Umar</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Castillo</surname><given-names>J.R.</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>David</surname><given-names>C.V.</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Sandhu</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>Patient selection criteria and innovative techniques for improving outcome and cosmesis in acne keloidalis nuchae lesion excision and primary closure</article-title><source>JAAD Case Rep</source><volume>5</volume><year>2018</year><fpage>24</fpage><lpage>28</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">30555880</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1016/j.jdcr.2018.10.002</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC6280636</pub-id></element-citation><mixed-citation id="srct0040">Umar S, Castillo JR, David CV, Sandhu S. Patient selection criteria and innovative techniques for improving outcome and cosmesis in acne keloidalis nuchae lesion excision and primary closure. JAAD Case Rep. 2018;5:24-28.<pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1016/j.jdcr.2018.10.002</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC6280636</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">30555880</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="bib5"><label>5</label><element-citation publication-type="journal" id="sref5"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Esmat</surname><given-names>S.M.</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Abdel Hay</surname><given-names>R.M.</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Abu Zeid</surname><given-names>O.M.</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Hosni</surname><given-names>H.N.</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>The efficacy of laser assisted hair removal in the treatment of acne keloidalis nuchae; a pilot study</article-title><source>Eur J Dermatol</source><volume>22</volume><year>2012</year><fpage>645</fpage><lpage>650</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">23018044</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1684/ejd.2012.1830</pub-id></element-citation><mixed-citation id="srct0045">Esmat SM, Abdel Hay RM, Abu Zeid OM, Hosni HN. The efficacy of laser assisted hair removal in the treatment of acne keloidalis nuchae; a pilot study. Eur J Dermatol. 2012;22:645-650.<pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1684/ejd.2012.1830</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">23018044</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="bib6"><label>6</label><element-citation publication-type="journal" id="sref6"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Shah</surname><given-names>G.K.</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>Efficacy of diode laser for treating acne keloidalis nuchae</article-title><source>Indian J Dermatol Venereol Leprol</source><volume>71</volume><year>2005</year><fpage>31</fpage><lpage>34</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">16394358</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.4103/0378-6323.13783</pub-id></element-citation><mixed-citation id="srct0050">Shah GK. Efficacy of diode laser for treating acne keloidalis nuchae. Indian J Dermatol Venereol Leprol. 2005;71:31-34.<pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.4103/0378-6323.13783</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">16394358</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="bib7"><label>7</label><element-citation publication-type="journal" id="sref7"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Tawfik</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Osman</surname><given-names>M.A.</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Rashwan</surname><given-names>I.</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>A novel treatment of acne keloidalis nuchae by long-pulsed Alexandrite laser</article-title><source>Dermatol Surg</source><volume>44</volume><year>2018</year><fpage>413</fpage><lpage>420</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">29016541</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1097/DSS.0000000000001336</pub-id></element-citation><mixed-citation id="srct0055">Tawfik A, Osman MA, Rashwan I. A novel treatment of acne keloidalis nuchae by long-pulsed Alexandrite laser. Dermatol Surg. 2018;44:413-420.<pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1097/DSS.0000000000001336</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">29016541</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="bib8"><label>8</label><element-citation publication-type="journal" id="sref8"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Woo</surname><given-names>D.K.</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Treyger</surname><given-names>G.</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Henderson</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Huggins</surname><given-names>R.H.</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Jackson-Richards</surname><given-names>D.</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Hamzavi</surname><given-names>I.</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>Prospective controlled trial for the treatment of acne keloidalis nuchae with a long-pulsed neodymium-doped yttrium-aluminum-garnet laser</article-title><source>J Cutan Med Surg</source><volume>22</volume><year>2018</year><fpage>236</fpage><lpage>238</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">29587518</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1177/1203475417739846</pub-id></element-citation><mixed-citation id="srct0060">Woo DK, Treyger G, Henderson M, Huggins RH, et&#160;al. Prospective controlled trial for the treatment of acne keloidalis nuchae with a long-pulsed neodymium-doped yttrium-aluminum-garnet laser. J Cutan Med Surg. 2018;22:236-238.<pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1177/1203475417739846</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">29587518</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="bib9"><label>9</label><element-citation publication-type="journal" id="sref9"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Alster</surname><given-names>T.S.</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Bryan</surname><given-names>H.</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Williams</surname><given-names>C.M.</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>Long-pulsed Nd:YAG laser-assisted hair removal in pigmented skin: a clinical and histological evaluation</article-title><source>Arch Dermatol</source><volume>137</volume><year>2001</year><fpage>885</fpage><lpage>889</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">11453807</pub-id></element-citation><mixed-citation id="srct0065">Alster TS, Bryan H, Williams CM. Long-pulsed Nd:YAG laser-assisted hair removal in pigmented skin: a clinical and histological evaluation. Arch Dermatol. 2001;137:885-889.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">11453807</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="bib10"><label>10</label><element-citation publication-type="journal" id="sref10"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Millan-Cayetano</surname><given-names>J.F.</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Repiso-Jimenez</surname><given-names>J.B.</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Del Boz</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>de Troya-Martin</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>Refractory acne keloidalis nuchae treated with radiotherapy</article-title><source>Australas J Dermatol</source><volume>58</volume><year>2017</year><fpage>e11</fpage><lpage>e13</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">26223375</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1111/ajd.12380</pub-id></element-citation><mixed-citation id="srct0070">Millan-Cayetano JF, Repiso-Jimenez JB, Del Boz J, de Troya-Martin M. Refractory acne keloidalis nuchae treated with radiotherapy. Australas J Dermatol. 2015. doi:10.1111/ajd.12380.<pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1111/ajd.12380</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">26223375</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="bib11"><label>11</label><element-citation publication-type="journal" id="sref11"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Herzberg</surname><given-names>A.J.</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Dinehart</surname><given-names>S.M.</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Kerns</surname><given-names>B.J.</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Pollack</surname><given-names>S.V.</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>Acne keloidalis. Transverse microscopy, immunohistochemistry, and electron microscopy</article-title><source>Am J Dermatopathol</source><volume>12</volume><year>1990</year><fpage>109</fpage><lpage>121</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">2331046</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1097/00000372-199004000-00001</pub-id></element-citation><mixed-citation id="srct0075">Herzberg AJ, Dinehart SM, Kerns BJ, Pollack SV. Acne keloidalis. Transverse microscopy, immunohistochemistry, and electron microscopy. Am J Dermatopathol. 1990;12:109-121.<pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1097/00000372-199004000-00001</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">2331046</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref></ref-list><fn-group><fn id="d31e85"><p id="ntpara0010">Funding sources: None.</p></fn><fn id="d31e88"><p id="ntpara0015">Conflicts of interest: None disclosed.</p></fn></fn-group></back></article></pmc-articleset>