<?xml version="1.0"  ?><!DOCTYPE pmc-articleset PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD ARTICLE SET 2.0//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pmc/articleset/nlm-articleset-2.0.dtd"><pmc-articleset><article xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" xmlns:ali="http://www.niso.org/schemas/ali/1.0/" article-type="case-report" xml:lang="en" dtd-version="1.4"><front><journal-meta><journal-id journal-id-type="nlm-ta">J Dent (Shiraz)</journal-id><journal-id journal-id-type="iso-abbrev">J Dent (Shiraz)</journal-id><journal-id journal-id-type="pmc-domain-id">2317</journal-id><journal-id journal-id-type="pmc-domain">jdentshiraz</journal-id><journal-title-group><journal-title>Journal of Dentistry</journal-title></journal-title-group><issn pub-type="ppub">2345-6485</issn><issn pub-type="epub">2345-6418</issn><publisher><publisher-name>Shiraz University of Medical Sciences</publisher-name></publisher></journal-meta><article-meta><article-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC6092459</article-id><article-id pub-id-type="pmcid-ver">PMC6092459.1</article-id><article-id pub-id-type="pmcaid">6092459</article-id><article-id pub-id-type="pmcaiid">6092459</article-id><article-id pub-id-type="pmid">30175196</article-id><article-id pub-id-type="publisher-id">JDS-19-3</article-id><article-version article-version-type="pmc-version">1</article-version><article-categories><subj-group subj-group-type="heading"><subject>Case Reports</subject></subj-group></article-categories><title-group><article-title>Gummy Smile Correction Using Botulinum Toxin With Respective Gingival Surgery
</article-title></title-group><contrib-group><contrib contrib-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Pedron</surname><given-names initials="IG">Irineu Gregnanin</given-names></name><xref ref-type="aff" rid="aff1">1</xref></contrib><contrib contrib-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Mangano</surname><given-names initials="A">Alessandro</given-names></name><xref ref-type="aff" rid="aff2">2</xref></contrib></contrib-group><aff id="aff1">
<label>1</label> Dept. of Stomatology, College of Dentistry, University of S&#227;o Paulo, Brazil.
</aff><aff id="aff2">
<label>2</label> Private Practice in Gravedona ed Uniti, Como, Italy.
</aff><author-notes><corresp id="cor1"><bold>Correspondence: </bold>Irineu Gregnanin Pedron
Rua Flores do Piau&#237;, 508- S&#227;o Paulo- Brazil.
Zip Code: 08210-200. <bold> Tel:</bold>+55-11-2944-4067</corresp><corresp id="cor2">E-mail : <email>igpedron@alumni.usp.br</email></corresp></author-notes><pub-date pub-type="ppub"><month>9</month><year>2018</year></pub-date><volume>19</volume><issue>3</issue><issue-id pub-id-type="pmc-issue-id">318831</issue-id><fpage>248</fpage><lpage>252</lpage><history><date date-type="rev-recd"><month>6</month><year>2017</year></date><date date-type="accepted"><month>4</month><year>2018</year></date><date date-type="received"><month>4</month><year>2017</year></date></history><pub-history><event event-type="pmc-release"><date><day>01</day><month>09</month><year>2018</year></date></event><event event-type="pmc-live"><date><day>01</day><month>09</month><year>2018</year></date></event><event event-type="pmc-last-change"><date iso-8601-date="2018-09-05 00:17:53.640"><day>05</day><month>09</month><year>2018</year></date></event></pub-history><permissions><copyright-statement>Copyright: &#169; Journal of Dentistry Shiraz University of Medical Sciences</copyright-statement><license xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" license-type="open-access" xlink:href="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0"><ali:license_ref specific-use="textmining" content-type="ccbyncsalicense">https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</ali:license_ref><license-p>This is an open-access article distributed under the terms of the Creative Commons Attribution-Noncommercial-Share Alike 3.0 Unported, which permits unrestricted use, distribution, and reproduction in any medium, provided the original work is properly cited.</license-p></license></permissions><self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" content-type="pmc-pdf" xlink:href="JDS-19-248.pdf"/><abstract><p>The pursuit of esthetic excellence has become a major goal in the dental treatment and orthodontic treatment. The beauty of the smile is not only constituted by the shape, position, and size of the teeth, but also based on the characteristics of the gingival tissue and conformation of the lips, which should be as harmonious as teeth. Gummy smile is one of the complaints of the patients, since such a situation can influence self-esteem and social relationships. The development of new more conservative techniques may provide a better therapeutic option than surgical procedures, such as the application of botulinum toxin, in the treatment of gummy smile. The purpose of this article is to present the case of a patient who presented dentogingival discrepancy and gummy smile, treated by resective gingival surgery and by application of botulinum toxin, optimizing smile harmony, and achieving improved self-esteem and quality of life. The application of botulinum toxin is an alternative less invasive, faster, safer, and more effective. Moreover, it produces harmonics and pleasing results when applied in target muscles, respecting the appropriate dose and type of smile. Therefore, the technique is a useful adjunct in the esthetic improvement of the smile and provides better results when combined with resective gingival surgery.
</p></abstract><kwd-group><kwd>Gingival overgrowth </kwd><kwd> Botulinum toxins type A </kwd><kwd> Gummy smile </kwd><kwd> Gingivectomy </kwd><kwd> Dental esthetics</kwd></kwd-group><custom-meta-group><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-status-qastatus</meta-name><meta-value>0</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-status-live</meta-name><meta-value>yes</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-status-embargo</meta-name><meta-value>no</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-status-released</meta-name><meta-value>yes</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-open-access</meta-name><meta-value>yes</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-olf</meta-name><meta-value>no</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-manuscript</meta-name><meta-value>no</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-legally-suppressed</meta-name><meta-value>no</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-has-pdf</meta-name><meta-value>yes</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-has-supplement</meta-name><meta-value>no</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-pdf-only</meta-name><meta-value>no</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-suppress-copyright</meta-name><meta-value>no</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-is-real-version</meta-name><meta-value>no</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-is-scanned-article</meta-name><meta-value>no</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-preprint</meta-name><meta-value>no</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-in-epmc</meta-name><meta-value>yes</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-license-ref</meta-name><meta-value>CC BY-NC-SA</meta-value></custom-meta></custom-meta-group></article-meta></front><body><sec sec-type="Introduction" id="sec1-1"><title>Introduction</title><p>Currently, the demand for cosmetic procedures has grown exponentially. Dental procedures, as well as medical ones, besides working to obtain the principle of health promotion, seek smile esthetics, as the smile is a form of communication and socialization that expresses many feelings.[<xref rid="ref1" ref-type="bibr">1</xref>-<xref rid="ref2" ref-type="bibr">2</xref>]</p><p>Facial esthetic harmony correlates directly with the smile and this, in turn, is formed by the union of three components: teeth, gum, and lips.[<xref rid="ref1" ref-type="bibr">1</xref>-<xref rid="ref3" ref-type="bibr">3</xref>] The smile becomes esthetically pleasing when these elements are disposed in suitable proportion, and exposure of the gingival tissue is limited to 3mm. When the gingival exposure is greater than 3 mm, it is characterized the non-esthetic condition called gummy smile, which affects some patients psychologically.[<xref rid="ref1" ref-type="bibr">1</xref>,<xref rid="ref4" ref-type="bibr">4</xref>-<xref rid="ref7" ref-type="bibr">7</xref>]</p><p>Several therapeutic modalities have been proposed for the correction of gummy smile including gingivectomy or gingivoplasty,[<xref rid="ref1" ref-type="bibr">1</xref>,<xref rid="ref2" ref-type="bibr">2</xref>,<xref rid="ref4" ref-type="bibr">4</xref>-<xref rid="ref5" ref-type="bibr">5</xref>,<xref rid="ref7" ref-type="bibr">7</xref>] myectomy, [<xref rid="ref5" ref-type="bibr">5</xref>,<xref rid="ref7" ref-type="bibr">7</xref>] and orthognathic surgery.[<xref rid="ref5" ref-type="bibr">5</xref>,<xref rid="ref7" ref-type="bibr">7</xref>-<xref rid="ref8" ref-type="bibr">8</xref>] While the last two procedures are more invasive and associated with high morbidity,[<xref rid="ref6" ref-type="bibr">6</xref>] in contrast, the use of botulinum toxin resulted to be more conservative, more effective, faster, and safer, as compared to surgical procedures.[<xref rid="ref4" ref-type="bibr">4</xref>,<xref rid="ref9" ref-type="bibr">9</xref>] Thus, the application of botulinum toxin can be considered as a therapeutic option to a surgical approach.[<xref rid="ref4" ref-type="bibr">4</xref>,<xref rid="ref6" ref-type="bibr">6</xref>]</p><p>Botulinum toxin is synthesized by gram-positive anaerobic bacterium Clostridium botulinum.[<xref rid="ref5" ref-type="bibr">5</xref>,<xref rid="ref7" ref-type="bibr">7</xref>-<xref rid="ref8" ref-type="bibr">8</xref>] It inhibits the release of acetylcholine at the neuromuscular junction, which prevents muscle contraction. There are seven distinct serotypes of toxins (A, B, C1, D, E, F and G). However, the subtype A is the most frequently used clinically and the most powerful.[<xref rid="ref5" ref-type="bibr">5</xref>] Currently, botulinum toxin has been shown effective in the treatment of gummy smile in patients with hyperfunction of the muscles involved in smiling, as well as in patients with other disorders such as temporomandibular disorders (hypertrophy of the masseter muscle, bruxism, clenching) and myofacial pain.[<xref rid="ref5" ref-type="bibr">5</xref>,<xref rid="ref8" ref-type="bibr">8</xref>] The purpose of this paper was to report a case of a patient who presented gummy smile and was treated by associating resective gingival surgery (gingivectomy) and application of botulinum toxin.
</p></sec><sec id="sec1-2"><title>Case Report</title><p>An 18-years-old Caucasian female referred to the practice with complaint of excessive gum display while smiling (<xref ref-type="fig" rid="JDS-19-248-g001.tif">Figures 1</xref> and <xref ref-type="fig" rid="JDS-19-248-g002.tif">2</xref>). </p><fig id="JDS-19-248-g001.tif" position="float" orientation="portrait"><label>Figure1</label><caption><p>Exposure of evident gum, featuring the gummy smile
</p></caption><graphic xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" position="float" orientation="portrait" xlink:href="JDS-19-248-g001.jpg"/></fig><fig id="JDS-19-248-g002.tif" position="float" orientation="portrait"><label>Figure2</label><caption><p>Gummy smile: closer view
</p></caption><graphic xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" position="float" orientation="portrait" xlink:href="JDS-19-248-g002.jpg"/></fig><p>The patient presented a good general health and absence of active periodontal disease. Clinically, the patient had short clinical crowns and a gummy smile showing gingival exposure greater than 3mm (<xref ref-type="fig" rid="JDS-19-248-g003.tif">Figure 3</xref>). </p><fig id="JDS-19-248-g003.tif" position="float" orientation="portrait"><label>Figure3</label><caption><p>Initial clinical appearance showing an anatomical discrepancy between the lengths of teeth
</p></caption><graphic xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" position="float" orientation="portrait" xlink:href="JDS-19-248-g003.jpg"/></fig><p>No periapical radiolucency at radiographic examination was detected, the periodontal ligament was within normal limit, and the crown-to-root ratio was about 1&#8201;:&#8201;3. At clinical examination,
attached gingiva band was 6 to 7mm in width, and periodontal pocket depth was 3mm or less.
</p><p>The primary treatment plan proposed was a combined orthodontic-surgical approach by mean of LeFort I osteotomy in order to affect the maxilla and reduce the gingival exposure. The patient refused the
surgical approach. A second treatment plan was developed and proposed consisting of a preliminary gingival surgery (gingivectomy) followed by injection of botulinum toxin type A. The patient was informed
about the recurrence of gummy smile after 6 months of application because of temporary results of the botulinum toxin. The patient read and signed a written consent form prior to treatment. Under local
infiltrative anesthesia, bleeding points were determined with the aid of a millimetered- probe and the union of these points were performed with the electrocautery.[<xref rid="ref2" ref-type="bibr">2</xref>]
The length of the teeth was increased, characterizing the dental zenith. Subsequently, the scraping was performed, resembling the technique of external bevel, in order to enhance issue healing
(<xref ref-type="fig" rid="JDS-19-248-g004.tif">Figures 4</xref> and <xref ref-type="fig" rid="JDS-19-248-g005.tif">5</xref>). There was no need of the use of surgical cement, given that the process of the wound occurs by secondary
intention. The patient reported no complaints or complications after surgery.
</p><fig id="JDS-19-248-g004.tif" position="float" orientation="portrait"><label>Figure4</label><caption><p>Post-surgical: upper left side</p></caption><graphic xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" position="float" orientation="portrait" xlink:href="JDS-19-248-g004.jpg"/></fig><fig id="JDS-19-248-g005.tif" position="float" orientation="portrait"><label>Figure5</label><caption><p>Post-surgical: upper right side</p></caption><graphic xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" position="float" orientation="portrait" xlink:href="JDS-19-248-g005.jpg"/></fig><p>After 30 days, at the subsequent consultation, satisfactory tissue repair was observed (<xref ref-type="fig" rid="JDS-19-248-g006.tif">Figure 6</xref>), and no changes or complaints were reported by the patient.
However, the persistence of complaint of gummy smile was reported by the patient (<xref ref-type="fig" rid="JDS-19-248-g007.tif">Figures 7</xref> and <xref ref-type="fig" rid="JDS-19-248-g008.tif">8</xref>). </p><fig id="JDS-19-248-g006.tif" position="float" orientation="portrait"><label>Figure6</label><caption><p>Post-surgical (30 days): observed satisfactory tissue repair</p></caption><graphic xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" position="float" orientation="portrait" xlink:href="JDS-19-248-g006.jpg"/></fig><fig id="JDS-19-248-g007.tif" position="float" orientation="portrait"><label>Figure7</label><caption><p>Post-surgical (30 days): persistence of gummy smile complaint.</p></caption><graphic xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" position="float" orientation="portrait" xlink:href="JDS-19-248-g007.jpg"/></fig><fig id="JDS-19-248-g008.tif" position="float" orientation="portrait"><label>Figure8</label><caption><p>Persistence of gummy smile complaint: closer view
</p></caption><graphic xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" position="float" orientation="portrait" xlink:href="JDS-19-248-g008.jpg"/></fig><p>In the same consultation, botulinum toxin was applied. Prior to application of botulinum toxin, the surface of the skin was disinfected with ethyl alcohol 70% and the oils from the area were removed, in order to avoid local infection. The points of application were marked, beside each nostril. Then, local anesthetic (EmlaTM, Astra, S&#227;o Paulo, Brazil) was applied with the aim of promoting comfort during the procedure. Botulinum toxin type A (DysportTM, Ipsen Biopharm Ltd, Wrexham, UK) was diluted in 1.7ml of saline according to the manufacturer's instructions, and two units was injected in the recommended site, laterally to each nostril. After application, the patient was advised not to bow their head during the first four hours and not engage in physical activity during the first 24 hours after the procedure.
</p><p>After 10 days, the patient was examined. She presented a uniform dehiscence of the upper lip and reduction and attenuation of gummy smile (<xref ref-type="fig" rid="JDS-19-248-g009.tif">Figure 9</xref> and <xref ref-type="fig" rid="JDS-19-248-g010.tif">Figure 10</xref>). Side effects or complaints were not reported.
</p><fig id="JDS-19-248-g009.tif" position="float" orientation="portrait"><label>Figure9</label><caption><p>Aesthetic results after 10 days of application of botulinum toxin.</p></caption><graphic xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" position="float" orientation="portrait" xlink:href="JDS-19-248-g009.jpg"/></fig><fig id="JDS-19-248-g010.tif" position="float" orientation="portrait"><label>Figure10</label><caption><p>Aesthetic results: closer view
</p></caption><graphic xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" position="float" orientation="portrait" xlink:href="JDS-19-248-g010.jpg"/></fig></sec><sec sec-type="Discussion" id="sec1-3"><title>Discussion</title><p>The gummy smile is conceptualized by the exposure of more than 3 mm of gingival tissue during smiling,[<xref rid="ref1" ref-type="bibr">1</xref>,<xref rid="ref4" ref-type="bibr">4</xref>,<xref rid="ref6" ref-type="bibr">6</xref>] and it is often found in women.[<xref rid="ref9" ref-type="bibr">9</xref>] The predominance of females can be explained by the fact that male patients present lower smile line.[<xref rid="ref3" ref-type="bibr">3</xref>-<xref rid="ref4" ref-type="bibr">4</xref>]</p><p>Several etiologies have been suggested to gummy smile, as vertical maxillary excess,[<xref rid="ref3" ref-type="bibr">3</xref>-<xref rid="ref5" ref-type="bibr">5</xref>,<xref rid="ref7" ref-type="bibr">7</xref>-<xref rid="ref8" ref-type="bibr">8</xref>] delayed passive eruption,3,5-6,8 [<xref rid="ref3" ref-type="bibr">3</xref>,<xref rid="ref5" ref-type="bibr">5</xref>-<xref rid="ref6" ref-type="bibr">6</xref>,<xref rid="ref8" ref-type="bibr">8</xref>] hyperfunction of the muscles involved in smiling[<xref rid="ref5" ref-type="bibr">5</xref>-<xref rid="ref6" ref-type="bibr">6</xref>,<xref rid="ref8" ref-type="bibr">8</xref>] and reduced length of the clinical crown of the teeth[<xref rid="ref1" ref-type="bibr">1</xref>-<xref rid="ref2" ref-type="bibr">2</xref>,<xref rid="ref6" ref-type="bibr">6</xref>] which can occur separately or together, and determine the type of treatment to be used. </p><p>In gummy smile caused by overactive muscle, botulinum toxin was indicated. It is the treatment of first choice for the ease and security of applications, fast effect, besides being a more conservative approach when compared to surgical procedures (myectomy or Le Fort I osteotomy).[<xref rid="ref3" ref-type="bibr">3</xref>-<xref rid="ref10" ref-type="bibr">10</xref>]</p><p>The activity of the smile is determined by several facial muscles, like the elevator of the upper lip and wing of the nose, the zygomatic major and minor, the angle of the mouth, orbicularis oris, and risorius.[<xref rid="ref3" ref-type="bibr">3</xref>-<xref rid="ref5" ref-type="bibr">5</xref>,<xref rid="ref7" ref-type="bibr">7</xref>-<xref rid="ref9" ref-type="bibr">9</xref>] Among them, the first three ones play higher function and determine the amount of lip elevation and, therefore, should be the muscles affected by the injection of the toxin. The fibers of these muscles converge to the same area, and they form a triangle, what suggests that the point of adequate election comprehend the three muscles in a single injection. The toxin, when injected, can spread in an area of &#8203;&#8203;10 to 30 mm, what allows the effective extent.[<xref rid="ref3" ref-type="bibr">3</xref>-<xref rid="ref4" ref-type="bibr">4</xref>] The site indicated for the application of botulinum toxin was laterally to the wing of the nose.[<xref rid="ref3" ref-type="bibr">3</xref>,<xref rid="ref7" ref-type="bibr">7</xref>-<xref rid="ref9" ref-type="bibr">9</xref>] After application, the reduction of contraction of the muscles responsible for upper lip lift is expected, subsequently reducing the gingival exposure.[<xref rid="ref3" ref-type="bibr">3</xref>-<xref rid="ref10" ref-type="bibr">10</xref>]</p><p>The elevation of the upper lip is determined by a group of muscles that have specific functions during the activity of the smile. The gummy smile can be classified in anterior, posterior, mixed and asymmetrical, involving different muscle groups.[<xref rid="ref3" ref-type="bibr">3</xref>,<xref rid="ref9" ref-type="bibr">9</xref>] The anterior gummy smile is treated with the conventional technique, by the application laterally to the wing of the nose. In the posterior gummy smile, the applications should be made at the conventional point with half of the dose and the second point 2 cm laterally to the first, at the level of the tragus line. In the mixed gummy smile, the application should be performed by associating the previous two. However, the dose should be reduced to 50% in the lateral to the wing of the nose point.[<xref rid="ref4" ref-type="bibr">4</xref>] In cases of labial asymmetry, that occurs due to differences in muscle activity,[<xref rid="ref3" ref-type="bibr">3</xref>] the patients receive injections of different doses on either side of the face.[<xref rid="ref4" ref-type="bibr">4</xref>,<xref rid="ref9" ref-type="bibr">9</xref>]</p><p>Botulinum toxin type A is a hydrophilic powder, stored under vacuum, sterile and stable.[<xref rid="ref5" ref-type="bibr">5</xref>,<xref rid="ref7" ref-type="bibr">7</xref>] The reconstitution occurs from the smooth injection of the diluent (sodium chloride 0.9%) inside the bottle. The solution should be stored at 2 to 8&#176;C and used within 4 to 8 hours, in order to ensure its effectiveness.[<xref rid="ref8" ref-type="bibr">8</xref>]</p><p>At the beginning of the treatment, extraoral photographs, including the close-up of the smile, were performed. Some authors mentioned the importance of taking the picture of the smile before and after the application of the toxin.[<xref rid="ref5" ref-type="bibr">5</xref>,<xref rid="ref9" ref-type="bibr">9</xref>-<xref rid="ref1" ref-type="bibr">1</xref>] It has been suggested that the picture of the smile should be performed stimulating individually the muscles with electrical current, in order to ensure that muscle contraction be controlled, precise and repeatable, as the spontaneous smile is extremely difficult to be replicated. Patients understand that the treatment is carried out to produce a different smile, and, from this perspective, unconsciously, there is a tendency to smile differently in photographs after the treatment.[<xref rid="ref10" ref-type="bibr">10</xref>]</p><p>The clinical effects show up in 2-10 days after the injection, and the most visible effect occurs 14 days after the injection.[<xref rid="ref3" ref-type="bibr">3</xref>,<xref rid="ref5" ref-type="bibr">5</xref>] This first effect, scheduled to be progressive, is also reversible, lasting about 3 to 6 months.[<xref rid="ref4" ref-type="bibr">4</xref>-<xref rid="ref5" ref-type="bibr">5</xref>,<xref rid="ref8" ref-type="bibr">8</xref>]</p><p>The injection of botulinum toxin, despite being a simple and safe procedure, may be associated with some adverse events such as pain at the injection site, bruising, infection, edema, dysphonia, dysphagia, ptosis, or lengthening of the upper lip and asymmetry of the smile. The dentist should be attentive in relation to dosage, precision of technique and location of the puncture.[<xref rid="ref4" ref-type="bibr">4</xref>-<xref rid="ref5" ref-type="bibr">5</xref>,<xref rid="ref8" ref-type="bibr">8</xref>,<xref rid="ref10" ref-type="bibr">10</xref>] In this report, claims or changes arising from the application were not reported.
</p><p>Contraindications to the use of botulinum toxin are pregnancy; lactation; hypersensitivity (allergy) to botulinum toxin itself; lactose and albumin; muscle and neurodegenerative diseases (myasthenia gravis and Charcot's disease), and concurrent use of aminoglycoside antibiotic that enhances the action of the toxin.[<xref rid="ref8" ref-type="bibr">8</xref>]</p><p>In this report, the result was satisfactory to the harmony of the smile of the patient by association of treatments - resective gingival surgery and application of botulinum toxin type A.
The institution of isolated treatments could not culminate in the excellence of the earned results. Initially, the creation of the new dental zenith during the course of resective gingival
surgery promoted the new dental architecture, favoring harmony gingival-dental-facial for the patient. Subsequently, the application of botulinum toxin type A softened the gummy smile, by the
uniform dehiscence itself of the upper lip, still promoting smoothness to facial lines of the smile, as can be seen in the nasolabial folds, adjacent to the nostrils,
comparing <xref ref-type="fig" rid="JDS-19-248-g001.tif">Figures 1</xref> and <xref ref-type="fig" rid="JDS-19-248-g009.tif">9</xref>. </p></sec><sec sec-type="Conclusion" id="sec1-4"><title>Conclusion</title><p>In summary, the application of botulinum toxin is an alternative less invasive, faster, safer, and more effective. Moreover, it produces harmonics and pleasing results when applied in target muscles, respecting the appropriate dose and type of smile. Therefore, the technique is a useful adjunct in the esthetic improvement of the smile and provides better results when combined with resective gingival surgery.
</p></sec></body><back><fn-group><fn fn-type="COI-statement"><p><bold>Conflict of Interest: </bold>The authors declare that they have no conflict of interest.</p></fn></fn-group><ref-list><title>References</title><ref id="ref1"><label>1</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Bashetty</surname><given-names>K</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Nadig</surname><given-names>G</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Kapoor</surname><given-names>S</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>Electrosurgery in aesthetic and restorative dentistry: A literature review and case reports</article-title><source> J Conserv Dent</source><year> 2009</year><volume> 12</volume><fpage> 139</fpage><lpage>144</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">20543922</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.4103/0972-0707.58332</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC2879725</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="ref2"><label>2</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Narayan</surname><given-names>S</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Narayan</surname><given-names>TV</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Jacob</surname><given-names>PC</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>Correction of gummy smile: A report of two cases</article-title><source> J Indian Soc Periodontol</source><year> 2011</year><volume> 15</volume><fpage> 421</fpage><lpage>424</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">22368373</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.4103/0972-124X.92585</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC3283946</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="ref3"><label>3</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Hwang</surname><given-names>WS</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Hur</surname><given-names>MS</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Hu</surname><given-names>KS</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Song</surname><given-names>WC</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Koh</surname><given-names>KS</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Baik</surname><given-names>HS</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>et</surname><given-names>al</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>Surface anatomy of the lip elevator muscles for the treatment of gummy smile using botulinum toxin</article-title><source> Angle Orthod</source><year> 2009</year><volume> 79</volume><fpage> 70</fpage><lpage>77</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">19123705</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.2319/091407-437.1</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="ref4"><label>4</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Mazzuco</surname><given-names>R</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Hexsel</surname><given-names>D</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>Gummy smile and botulinum toxin: a new approach based on the gingival exposure area</article-title><source> J Am Acad Dermatol</source><year> 2010</year><volume> 63</volume><fpage> 1042</fpage><lpage>10451</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">21093661</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1016/j.jaad.2010.02.053</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="ref5"><label>5</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Polo</surname><given-names>M</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>Botulinum toxin type A in the treatment of excessive gingivaldisplay</article-title><source> Am J Orthod Dentofacial Orthop</source><year> 2005</year><volume> 127</volume><fpage> 214</fpage><lpage>218</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">15750541</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1016/j.ajodo.2004.09.013</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="ref6"><label>6</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Mangano</surname><given-names>A</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Mangano</surname><given-names>A</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>Current strategies in the treatment of gummy smile using botulinum toxin type A</article-title><source> Plast Reconstr Surg</source><year> 2012</year><volume> 129</volume><fpage> 1015e</fpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1097/PRS.0b013e31824f00a6</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">22634680</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="ref7"><label>7</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Indra</surname><given-names>AS</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Biswas</surname><given-names>PP</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Vineet</surname><given-names>VT</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Yeshaswini</surname><given-names>T</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>Botox as an adjunct to orthognathic surgery for a case of severevertical maxillary excess</article-title><source> J Maxillofac Oral Surg</source><year> 2011</year><volume> 10</volume><fpage> 266</fpage><lpage>270</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">22942600</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1007/s12663-011-0178-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC3238547</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="ref8"><label>8</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Jaspers</surname><given-names>GW</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Pijpe</surname><given-names>J</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Jansma</surname><given-names>J</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>The use of botulinum toxin type A in cosmetic facial procedures</article-title><source> Int J Oral Maxillofac Surg</source><year> 2011</year><volume> 40</volume><fpage> 127</fpage><lpage>133</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">20965695</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1016/j.ijom.2010.09.014</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="ref9"><label>9</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Sucupira</surname><given-names>E</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Abramovitz</surname><given-names>A</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>A simplified method for smile enhancement: botulinum toxininjection for gummy smile</article-title><source> Plast Reconstr Surg</source><year> 2012</year><volume> 130</volume><fpage> 726</fpage><lpage>728</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">22929256</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1097/PRS.0b013e31825dc32f</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="ref10"><label>10</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Niamtu</surname><given-names>J</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>Botox injections for gummy smiles</article-title><source> Am J Orthod Dentofacial Orthop</source><year> 2008</year><volume> 133</volume><fpage> 782</fpage><lpage>783</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">18538226</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1016/j.ajodo.2008.04.007</pub-id></element-citation></ref></ref-list></back></article></pmc-articleset>