<?xml version="1.0"  ?><!DOCTYPE pmc-articleset PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD ARTICLE SET 2.0//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pmc/articleset/nlm-articleset-2.0.dtd"><pmc-articleset><article xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" xmlns:ali="http://www.niso.org/schemas/ali/1.0/" article-type="research-article" xml:lang="en" dtd-version="1.4"><front><journal-meta><journal-id journal-id-type="nlm-ta">Sci Rep</journal-id><journal-id journal-id-type="iso-abbrev">Sci Rep</journal-id><journal-id journal-id-type="pmc-domain-id">1579</journal-id><journal-id journal-id-type="pmc-domain">scirep</journal-id><journal-title-group><journal-title>Scientific Reports</journal-title></journal-title-group><issn pub-type="epub">2045-2322</issn><publisher><publisher-name>Nature Publishing Group</publisher-name></publisher></journal-meta><article-meta><article-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC6355906</article-id><article-id pub-id-type="pmcid-ver">PMC6355906.1</article-id><article-id pub-id-type="pmcaid">6355906</article-id><article-id pub-id-type="pmcaiid">6355906</article-id><article-id pub-id-type="pmid">30705293</article-id><article-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1038/s41598-018-36966-0</article-id><article-id pub-id-type="publisher-id">36966</article-id><article-version article-version-type="pmc-version">1</article-version><article-categories><subj-group subj-group-type="heading"><subject>Article</subject></subj-group></article-categories><title-group><article-title>Fractional laser ablation for the targeted cutaneous delivery of an anti-CD29 monoclonal antibody &#8211; OS2966</article-title></title-group><contrib-group><contrib contrib-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Lapteva</surname><given-names initials="M">Maria</given-names></name><xref ref-type="aff" rid="Aff1">1</xref></contrib><contrib contrib-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>del R&#237;o-Sancho</surname><given-names initials="S">Sergio</given-names></name><xref ref-type="aff" rid="Aff1">1</xref></contrib><contrib contrib-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Wu</surname><given-names initials="E">Eric</given-names></name><xref ref-type="aff" rid="Aff2">2</xref></contrib><contrib contrib-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Carbonell</surname><given-names initials="WS">W. Shawn</given-names></name><xref ref-type="aff" rid="Aff2">2</xref></contrib><contrib contrib-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>B&#246;hler</surname><given-names initials="C">Christof</given-names></name><xref ref-type="aff" rid="Aff3">3</xref></contrib><contrib contrib-type="author" corresp="yes"><contrib-id contrib-id-type="orcid" authenticated="false">http://orcid.org/0000-0001-9049-5489</contrib-id><name name-style="western"><surname>Kalia</surname><given-names initials="YN">Yogeshvar N.</given-names></name><address><email>yogi.kalia@unige.ch</email></address><xref ref-type="aff" rid="Aff1">1</xref></contrib><aff id="Aff1"><label>1</label><institution-wrap><institution-id institution-id-type="ISNI">0000 0001 2322 4988</institution-id><institution-id institution-id-type="GRID">grid.8591.5</institution-id><institution>School of Pharmaceutical Sciences, </institution><institution>University of Geneva &amp; University of Lausanne, </institution></institution-wrap>Geneva, Switzerland </aff><aff id="Aff2"><label>2</label>OncoSynergy, Inc., Greenwich, CT, USA </aff><aff id="Aff3"><label>3</label>Pantec Biosolutions, Ruggell, Liechtenstein </aff></contrib-group><pub-date pub-type="epub"><day>31</day><month>1</month><year>2019</year></pub-date><pub-date pub-type="collection"><year>2019</year></pub-date><volume>9</volume><issue-id pub-id-type="pmc-issue-id">327256</issue-id><elocation-id>1030</elocation-id><history><date date-type="received"><day>30</day><month>4</month><year>2018</year></date><date date-type="accepted"><day>27</day><month>11</month><year>2018</year></date></history><pub-history><event event-type="pmc-release"><date><day>31</day><month>01</month><year>2019</year></date></event><event event-type="pmc-live"><date><day>04</day><month>02</month><year>2019</year></date></event><event event-type="pmc-last-change"><date iso-8601-date="2019-02-05 00:20:57.207"><day>05</day><month>02</month><year>2019</year></date></event></pub-history><permissions><copyright-statement>&#169; The Author(s) 2019</copyright-statement><license license-type="OpenAccess"><ali:license_ref specific-use="textmining" content-type="ccbylicense">https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</ali:license_ref><license-p><bold>Open Access</bold> This article is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution 4.0 International License, which permits use, sharing, adaptation, distribution and reproduction in any medium or format, as long as you give appropriate credit to the original author(s) and the source, provide a link to the Creative Commons license, and indicate if changes were made. The images or other third party material in this article are included in the article&#8217;s Creative Commons license, unless indicated otherwise in a credit line to the material. If material is not included in the article&#8217;s Creative Commons license and your intended use is not permitted by statutory regulation or exceeds the permitted use, you will need to obtain permission directly from the copyright holder. To view a copy of this license, visit <ext-link xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" ext-link-type="uri" xlink:href="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/">http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</ext-link>.</license-p></license></permissions><self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" content-type="pmc-pdf" xlink:href="41598_2018_Article_36966.pdf"/><abstract id="Abs1"><p id="Par1">Monoclonal antibodies targeting cytokines are administered parenterally for the systemic treatment of severe psoriasis. However, systemic exposure to the biologic increases the risk of side-effects including immunosuppression, whereas only a small fraction of the active molecules actually reaches the target organ, the skin. This preclinical study examines the feasibility of delivering a humanized anti-CD29 monoclonal antibody (OS2966) topically to skin using minimally-invasive fractional laser ablation. This approach would enable the targeted use of a biologic for the treatment of recalcitrant psoriatic plaques in patients with less widespread disease while minimizing the risk of systemic exposure. First, the effect of a wide range of laser poration conditions on skin permeation and deposition of OS2966 was tested <italic toggle="yes">in vitro</italic> to determine optimal microporation parameters. Subsequently, confocal laser scanning microscopy was employed to visualize the distribution of fluorescently-labelled OS2966 in skin. The results demonstrated that delivery of OS2966 into and across skin was feasible. Above fluences of 35.1&#8201;J/cm<sup>2</sup>, skin deposition and permeation were statistically superior to passive delivery reaching values up to 3.7&#8201;&#177;&#8201;1.2&#8201;&#181;g/cm<sup>2</sup> at the most aggressive condition. Selective targeting of the skin was also possible since &#8805;70% of the OS2966 was delivered locally to the skin. Although nanogramme quantities were able to permeate across skin, these amounts were orders of magnitude lower than levels seen following subcutaneous or intravenous injection and would result in minimal systemic exposure <italic toggle="yes">in vivo</italic>. The diffusion of fluorescently-labelled OS2966 into the skin surrounding the pores was clearly higher than in intact skin and demonstrated the feasibility of delivering the antibody at least as deep as the dermo-epithelial junction, a critical border region where inflammatory cells cross to promote disease progression. These preliminary results confirm that fractional laser ablation can be used for the cutaneous delivery of OS2966 and now preclinical/clinical studies are required to demonstrate therapeutic efficacy.</p></abstract><funding-group><award-group><funding-source><institution>Swiss Commission for Technology and Innovation: Grant - 13933.2</institution></funding-source></award-group></funding-group><custom-meta-group><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-status-qastatus</meta-name><meta-value>0</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-status-live</meta-name><meta-value>yes</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-status-embargo</meta-name><meta-value>no</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-status-released</meta-name><meta-value>yes</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-open-access</meta-name><meta-value>yes</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-olf</meta-name><meta-value>no</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-manuscript</meta-name><meta-value>no</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-legally-suppressed</meta-name><meta-value>no</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-has-pdf</meta-name><meta-value>yes</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-has-supplement</meta-name><meta-value>yes</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-pdf-only</meta-name><meta-value>no</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-suppress-copyright</meta-name><meta-value>no</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-is-real-version</meta-name><meta-value>no</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-is-scanned-article</meta-name><meta-value>no</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-preprint</meta-name><meta-value>no</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-in-epmc</meta-name><meta-value>yes</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-license-ref</meta-name><meta-value>CC BY</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>issue-copyright-statement</meta-name><meta-value>&#169; The Author(s) 2019</meta-value></custom-meta></custom-meta-group></article-meta></front><body><sec id="Sec1" sec-type="introduction"><title>Introduction</title><p id="Par2">Plaque psoriasis is an autoimmune skin condition, affecting approximately 25 million people in North America and Europe<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR1">1</xref></sup>. The physiopathology of the disease is complex and balanced by both environmental and genetic factors<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR2">2</xref></sup>. The skin of a psoriatic patient is deregulated in terms of both innate and acquired immunity. Cytokines including a wide range of interleukins, interferon-&#947; and TNF-&#945; (tumour necrosis factor alpha) stimulate the proliferation of keratinocytes which in turn produce more antimicrobial peptides (&#946;-defensins and psoriasin) and chemokines attracting neutrophils and T-cells into the viable epidermis. Feedback loops are responsible for further keratinocyte, fibroblast and endothelial cell activation leading to increased collagen synthesis and angiogenesis<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR2">2</xref></sup>.</p><p id="Par3">Several therapies are available for the treatment of the disease<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR3">3</xref></sup>. Topical application of corticosteroids, vitamin D derivatives or their combination can lead to plaque clearance<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR4">4</xref></sup> in mild and moderate disease states. Phototherapies using narrowband and broadband UV-B radiation alone or UV-A radiation combined with psoralen photosensitization are effective in moderate to severe plaque type psoriasis<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR5">5</xref></sup>. In the case of severe psoriasis, treatments involving oral administration of immunosuppressants such as ciclosporin A or tacrolimus are needed<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR4">4</xref></sup>. A range of biopharmaceuticals such as monoclonal antibodies (mAbs) or fusion proteins targeting the chemokines implicated in psoriasis pathogenesis have reached the market<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR6">6</xref></sup>. TNF-&#945; was among the first cytokines to be targeted using infliximab, adalimumab and etanercept, followed by the anti-interleukin12&#8211;23 ustekinumab (mAb targeting the common p40 chain of these cytokines)<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR2">2</xref></sup>. More recently, secukinumab an anti-interleukin17A (IL17A) antibody was approved by the Food and Drug Administration (FDA)<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR7">7</xref></sup>. However, due to their proteic nature and associated physicochemical properties, these drugs are administered either by intravenous or subcutaneous injection and are only indicated for patients that are candidates for systemic therapy.</p><p id="Par4">An optimal therapeutic agent for psoriasis should be (i) effective in plaque clearing and improving PASI scores (PASI: Psoriasis Area and Severity Index, a diagnostic tool used for the measurement of severity of psoriasis), (ii) preferably administered by the topical route to minimize systemic side-effects and (iii) interact selectively with molecular targets implicated in the deregulated skin immune response. Topically applied corticosteroids meet the first and second criteria; however, the lack of selectivity leads to numerous side effects such as cutaneous atrophy, formation of telangiectasia, steroid rosacea, perioral dermatitis and increased risk of skin infections<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR8">8</xref></sup>. Similarly, psoralen and ultraviolet A (PUVA) therapy may lead to increased risk of skin cancer<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR9">9</xref></sup>. Orally administered agents meet only the first condition and can&#160;provoke a series of severe side effects due to systemic exposure: renal and cardiac toxicity can be mentioned as examples for ciclosporin A. Biopharmaceutical therapies are promising because of their selective binding to receptors implicated in the immune response; however, their invasive parenteral administration and therefore distribution throughout the whole organism may lead to serious side effects such as anaphylaxis<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR10">10</xref></sup> or even unpredictable life-threatening &#8220;cytokine storms&#8221;<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR11">11</xref></sup>. They are currently only indicated for severe disease states. In order to meet the three conditions of an ideal psoriasis therapy, and enable their more widespread use, selective biopharmaceuticals such as mAbs should be administered topically to treat more localized and less widespread disease conditions &#8211; targeted cutaneous delivery would increase efficacy, expand their potential use and avoid systemic exposure.</p><p id="Par5">Many efforts have been made to satisfy the requirements of such an ideal psoriasis therapy. For instance a recent Phase II clinical investigation by Tsianakas <italic toggle="yes">et al</italic>.<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR12">12</xref></sup>. tested the topical and intradermal administration of DLX105 (Cell Medica Ltd; developed by Delenex Therapeutics AG), a novel 26&#8201;kDa anti-TNF-&#945; humanized single-chain (scFv; single-chain variable fragment) monoclonal antibody, to patients with chronic plaque-type psoriasis. Intradermal injections of DLX105 into the psoriatic lesions led to a significant decrease in mean local PASI scores over baseline after treatment for 14 days, together with decreased K16, Ki67 biomarkers, epidermal thickness and mRNA levels of several proinflammatory cytokines. However, topical administration of 0.5% DLX 105 formulated in a hydrogel did not yield comparable results. Indeed, only the reduction of proinflammatory cytokine mRNA was observed without any response at the histological and clinical scales. Tape-stripping of the lesion did not bring any improvement. The authors suggested that DLX 105 could penetrate into the epidermis via the impaired barrier of the lesion, but could not reach the dermis in sufficient amounts to provoke a clinically meaningful result &#8211; thus, leading to the conclusion that: &#8220;increasing drug concentration in the dermis by biological, chemical or physical methods and, maybe, the development of a more potent follow-on TNF-&#945; blocker might result in improved clinical efficacy&#8221;<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR12">12</xref></sup>.</p><p id="Par6">It is well known that only small molecules with the appropriate physicochemical properties can diffuse passively across the <italic toggle="yes">stratum corneum</italic>, the uppermost skin layer which is the principal barrier to transport<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR13">13</xref></sup>: a physical or chemical enhancement technique is needed to transiently breach the <italic toggle="yes">stratum corneum</italic> barrier to enable delivery of drugs with &#8220;less ideal&#8221; properties. It has been shown that minimally-invasive erbium-doped yttrium aluminium garnet (Erbium:YAG) fractional laser ablation can be used to deliver functional proteins to skin, e.g. cytochrome C (12.4&#8201;kDa)<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR14">14</xref></sup>, recombinant human growth hormone (hGH; 22&#8201;kDa)<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR14">14</xref>,<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR15">15</xref></sup>, urinary follicle stimulating hormone (FSH; 30&#8201;kDa)<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR14">14</xref></sup>, FITC-labelled bovine serum albumin (FITC-BSA; 70&#8201;kDa)<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR14">14</xref></sup> and more interestingly anti-thymocyte globulin and basiliximab (155&#8201;kDa)<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR16">16</xref></sup>. Furthermore, it was also able to deliver macromolecular antigens such as Recombinant Phl p 5, a grass pollen allergen (38&#8201;kDa),ovalbumin (44&#8201;kDa), or betagalactosidase into the skin for transcutaneous immunization <italic toggle="yes">in vivo</italic><sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR17">17</xref></sup>.</p><p id="Par7">Lasers used for drug delivery are derived from devices used for skin resurfacing applications for the local treatment of medical conditions (e.g., keloids or warts) or aesthetic dermatology (e.g., wrinkle reduction or removal of age spots)<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR18">18</xref></sup>. Low intensity Erbium:YAG (solid state erbium-doped yttrium aluminium garnet) lasers emitting light at 2940&#8201;nm are routinely used for skin ablation<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR18">18</xref></sup>. This wavelength corresponds to an absorption band of water in the infrared spectrum. As the laser pulse imparts energy to the skin, water molecules vibrate and start heating-up. Depending on the temperature reached, four effects may occur: heating (37&#8211;60&#8201;&#176;C), coagulation (60&#8211;65&#8201;&#176;C), drying (90&#8211;100&#8201;&#176;C), and vaporization (&gt;100&#8201;&#176;C)<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR18">18</xref></sup>. Each pulse is able to ablate a reproducible amount of tissue and thus the pore depth can be controlled<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR19">19</xref></sup>. Using this technology, Pantec Biosolutions AG (Ruggell, Liechtenstein) developed the P.L.E.A.S.E.<sup>&#174;</sup> system (Precise Laser Epidermal System) for delivery of low and high molecular weight molecules. The device is able to create an array of 150&#8201;&#181;m diameter micropores on a small skin area. The pore depth is monitored by modulating i) the number of pulses per pore and ii) pulse energy or fluence (J/cm<sup>2</sup>). The latter depends on the pulse duration (&#181;s) and repetition rate (Hz). To obtain minimally-invasive painless ablation, the pore depth must be limited so as not to reach the sensitive nerve endings situated in the dermis. Finally, the number of pores created per unit area determines the fraction of skin that is ablated and this is defined as the fractional ablated area (%). Fig.&#160;<xref rid="Fig1" ref-type="fig">1a&#8211;c</xref> show the different pore distribution patterns obtained when using different fractional ablated areas and Fig.&#160;<xref rid="Fig1" ref-type="fig">1d,e</xref> show the skin aspect after fractional laser ablation with the pulsed P.L.E.A.S.E.<sup>&#174;</sup> Professional device: Fig.&#160;<xref rid="Fig1" ref-type="fig">1d</xref> shows an example of coagulated tissue and Fig.&#160;<xref rid="Fig1" ref-type="fig">1e</xref> shows pores where the borders have carbonized tissue (black perimeters) as the applied fluence increases. Moreover, the tolerability of the P.L.E.A.S.E.<sup>&#174;</sup> treatment has been demonstrated <italic toggle="yes">in vivo</italic><sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR20">20</xref>,<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR21">21</xref></sup>.<fig id="Fig1" position="float" orientation="portrait"><label>Figure 1</label><caption><p>Typical laser poration pattern (1&#8201;cm<sup>2</sup>) for different fractional ablated areas: (<bold>a</bold>) 5%, (<bold>b</bold>) 10%, (<bold>c</bold>) 15%, and magnification (20x) of porated skin at (<bold>d</bold>) a fluence of 23&#8201;J/cm<sup>2</sup> (pulse length 75&#8201;&#956;s, repetition rate 400&#8201;Hz, stack of 5 pulses per pore) and (<bold>e</bold>) at 39&#8201;J/cm<sup>2</sup> (pulse length 125&#8201;&#956;s, repetition rate 300&#8201;Hz, stack of 5 pulses per pore). Reproduced with permission from Gratieri <italic toggle="yes">et al</italic>.<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR13">13</xref></sup>.</p></caption><graphic xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" id="d29e465" position="float" orientation="portrait" xlink:href="41598_2018_36966_Fig1_HTML.jpg"/></fig></p><p id="Par8">OS2966 is a neutralizing anti-CD29 (Cluster of differentiation 29 or &#946;1-integrin subunit) mAb, developed for the treatment of glioblastoma by OncoSynergy, Inc. Integrins are proteins responsible for cell-matrix and cell-cell interactions. They assemble into &#945;-&#946; dimers. &#946;<sub>1</sub> integrins constitute the majority of integrins and bind to extra-cellular matrices (ECM), thus in healthy skin they are mostly expressed in the basal layer of keratinocytes where they are known to be implicated in cell adhesion to the basal lamina. The abnormal expression of integrins in upper epidermal layers is linked to psoriasis-like phenotype formation<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR22">22</xref></sup>.</p><p id="Par9">Alongside this aspect of psoriasis pathogenesis, and as already mentioned above, unlike in healthy skin, T cells can be found in the epidermis of psoriatic patients<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR1">1</xref></sup>, meaning that they need to cross the dermo-epithelial junction. Conrad <italic toggle="yes">et al</italic>. showed that epidermal but not dermal T-cells in psoriatic lesions express &#945;<sub>1</sub>&#946;<sub>1</sub> integrin known to bind to collagen IV (in CD3<sup>+</sup> T-cells)<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR23">23</xref></sup>. The xenotransplantation mouse model showed that the increase in the &#945;<sub>1</sub>&#946;<sub>1</sub><sup>+</sup>CD3<sup>+</sup> T-cells numbers in the epidermis of prepsoriatic skin led to the onset of a psoriatic phenotype. Most interestingly, when the &#945;<sub>1</sub> subunit was blocked by an anti-&#945;<sub>1</sub> mAb <italic toggle="yes">in vitro</italic>, the ability of &#945;<sub>1</sub>&#946;<sub>1</sub><sup>+</sup> T-cells to cross collagen IV was significantly inhibited. Those results were confirmed <italic toggle="yes">in vivo</italic> in the xenotransplantation mouse model: the xenografts injected (sub. cut.) with the anti-&#945;<sub>1</sub> mAb were characterized by a significant decrease in acanthosis and paillomathosis<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR23">23</xref></sup>.</p><p id="Par10">Although &#945;<sub>1</sub>&#946;<sub>1</sub> inhibition alone was efficacious in the above studies, the complexity of the psoriatic disease process will likely mean that modulation of more than one integrin heterodimer is required in the clinic. Indeed, there are twelve known CD29 integrin heterodimers mediating adhesion to myriad ECM including multiple collagen receptors (e.g., &#945;<sub>1</sub>&#946;<sub>1</sub>, &#945;<sub>2</sub>&#946;<sub>1</sub>, &#945;<sub>8</sub>&#946;<sub>1,</sub> &#945;<sub>10</sub>&#946;<sub>1</sub>) and fibronectin receptors (e.g., &#945;<sub>5</sub>&#946;<sub>1</sub>, &#945;<sub>8</sub>&#946;<sub>1</sub>, &#945;<sub>v</sub>&#946;<sub>1</sub>). All are implicated in dynamic tissue remodelling including the inflammation, fibrosis, and angiogenesis seen in psoriasis<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR24">24</xref></sup>. OS2966 is the first pan-CD29 inhibiting therapeutic candidate in development and is thus functionally equivalent to twelve separate antibodies for more effective modulation of the inflammatory process.</p><p id="Par11">Taking this data into consideration the local application of OS2966 and its binding to CD29 could be of therapeutic interest in the treatment of psoriasis and inhibition of T-cell migration to the epidermis. Consequently, the objective of this preclinical study was to investigate the effect of P.L.E.A.S.E.<sup>&#174;</sup> laser microporation conditions on the delivery of OS2966, a humanized IgG1 (immunoglobulin G1) monoclonal antibody, into and across skin and to visualize its biodistribution within the membrane. The <italic toggle="yes">in vitro</italic> evaluation of delivery was used to identify the optimal conditions for subsequent clinical studies and was also intended to help to determine the number and proximity of microporation sites necessary to enable delivery of therapeutic amounts of the drug candidate.</p></sec><sec id="Sec2" sec-type="results"><title>Results</title><sec id="Sec3"><title>Cutaneous delivery experiments</title><sec id="Sec4"><title>Effect of laser poration parameters on OS2966 delivery at fixed donor concentration and fractional ablated area</title><p id="Par12">Topical deposition in skin and transdermal permeation of OS2966 as a function of laser fluence (J/cm<sup>2</sup>) are presented in Fig.&#160;<xref rid="Fig2" ref-type="fig">2</xref>.<fig id="Fig2" position="float" orientation="portrait"><label>Figure 2</label><caption><p>Effect of laser fluence on (<bold>a</bold>) skin deposition and (<bold>b</bold>) transdermal permeation of OS2966 after formulation application on porated skin for 12&#8201;h (mean &#177; SD; *p&#8201;&lt;&#8201;0.05 when compared to non-porated; ppp: pulse per pore).</p></caption><graphic xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" id="d29e633" position="float" orientation="portrait" xlink:href="41598_2018_36966_Fig2_HTML.jpg"/></fig></p><p id="Par13">The results suggested that a fluence of 20&#8201;J/cm<sup>2</sup> represented a threshold to OS2966 delivery. When skin was porated at a fluence below 20&#8201;J/cm<sup>2</sup>, antibody deposition in the skin was not statistically different from the non-porated control conditions (Fig.&#160;<xref rid="Fig2" ref-type="fig">2a</xref>). However, for fluences of 20&#8201;J/cm<sup>2</sup> and above, skin deposition increased almost linearly starting at a fluence of 21.3&#8201;J/cm<sup>2</sup> with a deposition of 1.094&#8201;&#177;&#8201;0.491&#8201;&#181;g/cm<sup>2</sup> to reach 3.665&#8201;&#177;&#8201;1.224&#8201;&#181;g/cm<sup>2</sup> at the most aggressive conditions. Both skin deposition and transdermal permeation of the antibody became significantly higher than the control at a fluence of 35.3&#8201;J/cm<sup>2</sup>. At fluences &#8805;35.3&#8201;J/cm<sup>2</sup>, OS2966 permeated across skin (0.445&#8201;&#177;&#8201;0.131 &#956;g/cm<sup>2</sup>) and its permeation increased to 0.851&#8201;&#177;&#8201;0.397 &#956;g/cm<sup>2</sup> at the most aggressive condition.</p></sec><sec id="Sec5"><title>Effect of fractional ablated area on OS2966 delivery using fixed number of pulses per pore and donor concentration</title><p id="Par14">In order to study the influence of fractional ablated area (FAA) on OS2966 delivery, the skin was porated to remove increasing amounts of skin per unit area (5%&#8201;=&#8201;100 pores; 10%&#8201;=&#8201;200 pores; 15% &#8776; 300 pores per cm<sup>2</sup>)(Fig.&#160;<xref rid="Fig1" ref-type="fig">1</xref>), at a fixed donor concentration of 1&#8201;mg/ml and number of pulses per pore (3ppp).</p><p id="Par15">Figure&#160;<xref rid="Fig3" ref-type="fig">3a,b</xref> show the influence of FAA on OS2966 deposition and permeation as a function of applied fluence. Consistent with previous results, skin deposition was low for fluences below 20&#8201;J/cm<sup>2</sup> and was not influenced by the FAA. At fluences above 20&#8201;J/cm<sup>2</sup> the increase of FAA from 5 to 10% resulted in a significant increase in skin deposition (i) from 0.217 &#177; 0.091&#8201;&#181;g/cm<sup>2</sup> to 1.103 &#177; 0.491&#8201;&#181;g/cm<sup>2</sup>, (ii) from 0.188 &#177; 0.056&#8201;&#181;g/cm<sup>2</sup> to 2.131 &#177; 0.940&#8201;&#181;g/cm<sup>2</sup>, and (iii) from 0.351 &#177; 0.066&#8201;&#181;g/cm<sup>2</sup> to 2.863 &#177; 0.618&#8201;&#181;g/cm<sup>2</sup> for fluences of 23.7; 35.3 and 53.9&#8201;J/cm<sup>2</sup>, respectively. The further increase of FAA to 15% did not yield an increase in OS2966 delivery. Permeation of OS2966 was observed at 23.7&#8201;J/cm<sup>2</sup> with FAA of 10% and 15% and ranged from 0.032 &#177; 0.010&#8201;&#181;g/cm<sup>2</sup> to 0.513 &#177; 0.183&#8201;&#181;g/cm<sup>2</sup>.<fig id="Fig3" position="float" orientation="portrait"><label>Figure 3</label><caption><p>Effect of fractional ablated area (FAA; % of skin surface ablated by laser per cm<sup>2</sup>) on (<bold>a</bold>) skin deposition and (<bold>b</bold>) skin permeation of OS2966 and effect of increased antibody content on (<bold>c</bold>) skin deposition and (<bold>d</bold>) skin permeation of OS2966. (data expressed as mean &#177; SD; *p&#8201;&lt;&#8201;0.05 when compared to the initial condition: black circle; 1&#8201;mg/ml,10% FAA, 3ppp; ppp: pulse per pore).</p></caption><graphic xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" id="d29e747" position="float" orientation="portrait" xlink:href="41598_2018_36966_Fig3_HTML.jpg"/></fig></p></sec><sec id="Sec6"><title>Effect of donor concentration on OS2966 delivery using fixed number of pulses per pore and FAA</title><p id="Par16">Figure&#160;<xref rid="Fig3" ref-type="fig">3c,d</xref> compare skin deposition and skin permeation of OS2966 using two different donor concentrations: 1 and 5&#8201;mg/ml at 3 ppp and 10% FAA. Increasing the OS2966 concentration from 1 to 5&#8201;mg/ml in the formulation resulted in significantly increased skin deposition for groups treated with 9.4 and 12.8&#8201;J/cm<sup>2</sup> (from 0.138 &#177; 0.061&#8201;&#181;g/cm<sup>2</sup> to 1.036 &#177; 0.547&#8201;&#181;g/cm<sup>2</sup> and from 0.174 &#177; 0.055&#8201;&#181;g/cm<sup>2</sup> to 1.249 &#177; 0.325&#8201;&#181;g/cm<sup>2</sup> respectively). In contrast, the application of a 5&#8201;mg/ml formulation did not significantly increase skin deposition porated with 23.7; 35.3 and 53.9&#8201;J/cm<sup>2</sup>. It should be noted that these treatments led to an increased permeation, ranging from 0.544 &#177; 0.336&#8201;&#181;g/cm<sup>2</sup> to 1.246 &#177; 0.464&#8201;&#181;g/cm<sup>2</sup>.</p></sec></sec><sec id="Sec7"><title>Skin distribution of labelled OS2966</title><p id="Par17">The effect of laser poration could be observed at a macroscopic scale (Fig.&#160;<xref rid="Fig4" ref-type="fig">4a</xref>). The region of skin treated with 35.3&#8201;J/cm<sup>2</sup> and 58.5&#8201;J/cm<sup>2</sup> (at 175&#181;s/200&#8201;Hz) appeared increasingly brighter than the adjacent intact skin when placed under a UV lamp (366&#8201;nm) (Fig.&#160;<xref rid="Fig4" ref-type="fig">4a</xref>). The confocal laser scanning microscopy (CLSM) study enabled the visualization of pores created with the different laser treatments (Fig.&#160;<xref rid="Fig4" ref-type="fig">4b</xref>). Hoechst 33258 (blue) enabled visualization of the skin cells, whereas the green signal came from the Alexa 488-OS2966. The pore depths were 43&#8201;&#181;m, 137&#8201;&#181;m and 153&#8201;&#181;m for 1 ppp, 3 ppp and 5 ppp, respectively (at 175&#181;s/200&#8201;Hz). Consequently, the use of 5 ppp, 10%; 58.5&#8201;J/cm<sup>2</sup>, which was the second most aggressive condition enabled the creation of micropores that were most likely reaching the upper dermis (dermis being considered to be situated 150&#8211;160&#8201;&#181;m below skin surface<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR25">25</xref>,<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR26">26</xref></sup>).<fig id="Fig4" position="float" orientation="portrait"><label>Figure 4</label><caption><p>(<bold>a</bold>) UV (366&#8201;nm) illuminated skin samples following permeation experiment, (<bold>b</bold>) Alexa 488-OS2966 (green) and Hoechst 33258 / auto-fluorescence of skin (blue) signals in healthy porated porcine skin following permeation experiment. Scale bar&#8201;=&#8201;100&#8201;&#956;m. ppp: pulse per pore.</p></caption><graphic xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" id="d29e826" position="float" orientation="portrait" xlink:href="41598_2018_36966_Fig4_HTML.jpg"/></fig></p><p id="Par18">This was confirmed by the histological observation of porated skin samples (Fig.&#160;<xref rid="Fig5" ref-type="fig">5b&#8211;e</xref>; 5 ppp, 10%; 58.5&#8201;J/cm<sup>2</sup>) The average pore depth was found to be 154.6&#8201;&#177;&#8201;35&#8201;&#181;m; n&#8201;=&#8201;9 and was consistent with the CLSM observations.<fig id="Fig5" position="float" orientation="portrait"><label>Figure 5</label><caption><p>(<bold>a</bold>) CLSM Wide field (x5 objective) view on healthy porcine skin porated with 5 ppp, 10%; 58.5&#8201;J/cm<sup>2</sup>. ppp: pulse per pore Green signal: Alexa 488-OS2966; blue signal: Hoechst 33258 / skin auto-fluorescence. Scale bar&#8201;=&#8201;100&#8201;&#956;m. (<bold>b</bold>&#8211;<bold>e</bold>) optical microscopy Hematoxylin and eosin stain of porcine skin porated with 5 ppp, 10%; 58.5&#8201;J/cm<sup>2</sup>, (<bold>b</bold>) and (<bold>c</bold>) wide field view of porated skin (6.3x and 20x), (<bold>d</bold>) magnification of one pore from panel (<bold>b</bold>) (White square) (40x), (<bold>e</bold>) laser created pore adjacent to a pilosebaceous unit (PSU) (40x). Scale bar&#8201;=&#8201;100 or 500&#8201;&#956;m</p></caption><graphic xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" id="d29e874" position="float" orientation="portrait" xlink:href="41598_2018_36966_Fig5_HTML.jpg"/></fig></p><p id="Par19">Figure&#160;<xref rid="Fig5" ref-type="fig">5a</xref> shows a broad view of the porated skin surface (xy-plane) after application of the Alexa 488-OS2966 formulation. It appears that the green signal originating from the labelled antibody was mainly localized around and inside the pores as well as in the inter-cluster regions<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR27">27</xref></sup>. CLSM microscopy also enabled three dimensional reconstructions to be made by combining images of each confocal plane.</p><p id="Par20">Thus, Fig.&#160;<xref rid="Fig6" ref-type="fig">6a</xref> shows the three dimensional reconstruction of skin presenting a laser-created pore and a hair follicle. Each component &#8220;slice&#8221; making up the image can be looked at individually and thus Fig.&#160;<xref rid="Fig6" ref-type="fig">6b,c</xref> indicate that (i) the Alexa 488-OS2966 did not enter intact skin (slice 35), (ii) the diffusion of Alexa 488-OS2966 into the skin in the surroundings of the pores and beneath was clearly higher than in intact skin (slice 24), and (iii) hair follicles did not seem to be a preferential pathway (slice 17). Overall, the results suggested that the laser-created pores were the only penetration pathway for OS2966 into the skin.<fig id="Fig6" position="float" orientation="portrait"><label>Figure 6</label><caption><p>(<bold>a</bold>) Three-dimensional reconstruction of healthy porated porcine skin surface (treated with 5 ppp, 10%; 58.5&#8201;J/cm<sup>2</sup>), (<bold>b</bold>) and (<bold>c</bold>) selected slices showing cross-sections of skin with a hair shaft, a pore and an intact area of skin. Green signal: Alexa 488-OS2966; blue signal: Hoechst 33258 / skin auto-fluorescence. Scale bar&#8201;=&#8201;100&#8201;&#956;m. ppp: pulse per pore.</p></caption><graphic xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" id="d29e912" position="float" orientation="portrait" xlink:href="41598_2018_36966_Fig6_HTML.jpg"/></fig></p></sec></sec><sec id="Sec8" sec-type="discussion"><title>Discussion</title><p id="Par21">The variation of laser settings such as pulse duration, repetition frequency and number of pulses used to create the pores enabled the controlled cutaneous delivery of a 150&#8201;kDa monoclonal IgG1 therapeutic antibody. The results suggested that poration with fluences below 20&#8201;J/cm<sup>2</sup> did not enhance skin deposition or permeation of OS2966 in comparison to control. The CLSM images showed that when mild poration conditions were used (1 ppp, 11.7&#8201;J/cm<sup>2</sup>; Fig.&#160;<xref rid="Fig4" ref-type="fig">4b</xref>), the ablation depth was about 40&#8201;&#956;m, which corresponded to the superior layers of the viable epidermis. In contrast, when skin was porated at fluences above 20&#8201;J/cm<sup>2</sup>, OS2966 deposition and permeation increased linearly. CLSM microscopy confirmed the presence of pores deeper than 120&#8201;&#956;m (i.e. lower layers of viable epidermis and perhaps entering the upper dermis) in which the labelled OS2966 was able to accumulate (Figs&#160;<xref rid="Fig4" ref-type="fig">4b</xref> and <xref rid="Fig6" ref-type="fig">6c</xref>) and then diffuse to the deeper dermis. These observations suggest that <italic toggle="yes">stratum corneum</italic> is not the only barrier to the delivery of the OS2966 and this barrier to diffusion is situated in the viable epidermis. It is probable that for a molecule as large as OS2966 the <italic toggle="yes">stratum granulosum</italic> and <italic toggle="yes">spinosum</italic> with its desmosomes can also constitute a diffusional barrier<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR28">28</xref></sup>.</p><p id="Par22">There are few reports in the literature that describe topical delivery of antibodies and quantify the amount present in the skin. The results described here are comparable to those obtained previously with anti-thymocyte globulin (ATG; a polyclonal antibody) and basiliximab using a prototype of the P.L.E.A.S.E.<sup>&#174;</sup> laser<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR16">16</xref></sup>. Indeed Yu <italic toggle="yes">et al</italic>. obtained a total delivery of 1.18 &#177; 0.10&#8201;&#181;g/cm<sup>2</sup> and 1.92 &#177; 0.48&#8201;&#181;g/cm<sup>2</sup> for ATG and basiliximab respectively (Conditions: 300 pores over diffusion area, 45.3&#8201;J/cm<sup>2</sup> fluence), whereas the total delivery of OS2966 1.68 &#177; 0.53&#8201;&#181;g/cm<sup>2</sup> ((Conditions: 300 pores over diffusion area, 35.3&#8201;J/cm<sup>2</sup> fluence). However, it should be noted that there are technical and specification differences between the two laser devices. Another report by Cao <italic toggle="yes">et al</italic>. described the delivery of an anti-PD1 antibody against murine B16F10 melanoma after laser microporation with a CO<sub>2</sub> laser<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR29">29</xref></sup>. However, there was no direct quantification of anti-PD1 and the endpoint was the measurement of tumour size: a significant reduction in tumour size was reported. Nevertheless, it has to be noted that murine skin has major structural differences with human skin: its epidermis has a mean thickness of 9.6&#8201;&#181;m<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR30">30</xref></sup>, which is less than the thickness of human stratum corneum alone. The high follicle density is also a feature that is not representative of human skin<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR30">30</xref></sup>. Therefore, it is commonly accepted that mouse skin is not a representative surrogate for drug transport in human skin<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR30">30</xref>&#8211;<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR33">33</xref></sup>.</p><p id="Par23">In addition to confirming the feasibility of using fractional laser ablation to deliver OS2966, another key objective of the study was to determine the optimal poration conditions in order to move towards first-in-man experiments in the treatment of psoriasis (and other dermatological conditions). An optimal treatment would maximize selective delivery of the active into the skin, while minimizing transdermal permeation.</p><p id="Par24">Figure&#160;<xref rid="Fig7" ref-type="fig">7a</xref> shows the proportions of the OS2966 retained in the skin (i.e. delivered selectively into the skin) from a 1&#8201;mg/ml formulation at a FAA of 10% as a percentage of the total delivery, and it is worth noting that laser poration does allow selective targeting of the skin since even under the most aggressive conditions (89.9&#8201;J/cm<sup>2</sup>) as at least 83.2 &#177; 11.9% of the total active delivered, is delivered locally to the skin with upto 3.67&#8201;&#177;&#8201;1.22&#8201;&#181;g/cm<sup>2</sup> being recovered after formulation application for 12&#8201;h.<fig id="Fig7" position="float" orientation="portrait"><label>Figure 7</label><caption><p>(<bold>a</bold>) Proportion of OS2966 delivered locally to skin relative to total delivery (topical selectivity) at a fixed FAA of 10%, (<bold>b</bold>) proportion of OS2966 delivered locally to skin relative to total delivery (topical selectivity) at 3 ppp with variation of the FAA and OS2966 concentration in the donor, (<bold>c</bold>) OS2966 skin deposition as a function of topical selectivity &#8211; a tool to select the optimal laser parameters for targeted cutaneous delivery (FAA of 10%, 1&#8201;mg/ml). ppp: pulse per pore.</p></caption><graphic xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" id="d29e1034" position="float" orientation="portrait" xlink:href="41598_2018_36966_Fig7_HTML.jpg"/></fig></p><p id="Par25">In the discussion below, the ability of the laser poration parameters as well as the formulation characteristics to target the skin will be referred to as the &#8220;topical selectivity&#8221; and expressed as the ratio of <italic toggle="yes">skin deposition (&#181;g/cm</italic><sup>2</sup><italic toggle="yes">)/skin deposition</italic>&#8201;+&#8201;<italic toggle="yes">skin permeation (&#181;g/cm</italic><sup>2</sup><italic toggle="yes">)</italic>.</p><p id="Par26">Assuming that the volume of distribution for an antibody is approximately 4l as its distribution is limited to the blood compartment, as reported for infliximab<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR34">34</xref></sup>&#160;and&#160;knowing that at fluences &#8805;35.3&#8201;J/cm<sup>2</sup>, OS2966 also permeates across skin and that cumulative permeation reaches 0.85&#8201;&#177;&#8201;0.40&#160;&#956;g/cm<sup>2</sup> at the most aggressive condition, the blood concentration of OS2966 in this case would be 0.21&#8201;ng/ml after a 12&#8201;h application of a 1&#8201;mg/ml solution over a 1&#8201;cm<sup>2</sup> pore array. Infliximab is a widely used monoclonal antibody for the treatment of severe psoriasis and can be used as a reference. The recommended by the FDA dose of infliximab is 5&#8201;mg/kg administered as an intravenous injection at 0,&#160;2 and 6 weeks followed by a maintenance dose of 5&#8201;mg/kg every 8 weeks in case of chronic severe plaque psoriasis<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR35">35</xref></sup>. That means that for an average man of 70&#8201;kg, the single IV administered dose is 350&#8201;mg. Pharmacokinetic data in psoriatic patients shows that the first administration of a 5&#8201;mg/kg dose leads to infliximab blood levels reaching up to 100&#8201;&#181;g/ml<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR34">34</xref></sup>. Consequently, even the most aggressive laser poration condition would lead to a 4.7&#8201;&#215;&#8201;10<sup>5</sup> -fold decrease in systemic exposure to the antibody whilst ensuring that microgramme amounts were present in the lesion.</p><p id="Par27">When pore density and OS2966 content were varied (Fig.&#160;<xref rid="Fig7" ref-type="fig">7b</xref><bold>)</bold>, the proportion of OS2966 delivered locally to skin remained high (above 78.0&#177;20.1%); however, increasing the FAA to 15% neither significantly increased absolute delivery nor the topical selectivity of the treatment. Decreasing FAA to 5% yielded good topical selectivity, yet low skin deposition. Finally, increasing the formulation concentration increased absolute OS2966 delivery but at the cost of lower topical selectivity. The maximal skin permeation was obtained for the 5&#8201;mg/ml formulation (1.25&#8201;&#177;&#8201;0.46&#8201;&#181;g/cm<sup>2</sup>) using the 3 ppp, 53.9&#8201;J/cm<sup>2</sup> 10% FAA condition and is estimated to correspond to a plasma concentration of 0.31&#8201;ng/ml, which is still 5 orders of magnitude (10<sup>5</sup>) less than the maximal plasma levels in infliximab treated patients.</p><p id="Par28">In order to select the optimal laser poration conditions it is interesting to plot the deposited OS2966 amounts against the topical selectivity (Fig.&#160;<xref rid="Fig7" ref-type="fig">7c</xref><bold>)</bold>: the application of the 1&#8201;mg/ml formulation and poration at 10% FAA, 5 ppp, 58.8&#8201;J/cm<sup>2</sup> appears to be the optimal treatment with more than 90% selectivity and 3.41&#8201;&#177;&#8201;1.14&#8201;&#181;g/cm<sup>2</sup> deposition.</p><p id="Par29">OS2966 was successfully labelled with Alexa Fluor 488 dye in order to visualize the antibody penetration pathways. The diffusion of Alexa 488-OS2966 into the skin in the pore surroundings and beneath the pores was clearly higher than in intact skin. Increasing the fluence also resulted in stronger fluorescence in the pore regions, confirming the quantitative data. The optimal laser setting 10% FAA, 5 ppp, 58.8&#8201;J/cm<sup>2</sup> yielded pores with a depth of150&#8201;&#956;m, corresponding to the dermo-epithelial junction, meaning that OS2966 was able to reach its target and act on dermal T-cells about to cross the basal lamina. Finally, CLSM observation of hair follicles did not reveal significant involvement of the transfollicular pathway, meaning that diffusion through the experimentally-created pores was the preferential pathway for the mAb to enter the skin. In addition, the optimal laser condition of 5 ppp, 10%; 58.5&#8201;J/cm<sup>2</sup>, which was the second most aggressive condition, enabled the creation of micropores that nevertheless did not reach the dermis and its sensitive nerve endings.</p><p id="Par30">It remains difficult to comment about an optimal laser condition as the therapeutic levels of OS2966 that have to be reached in skin are not yet known; Conrad <italic toggle="yes">et al</italic>.<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR23">23</xref></sup>. obtained clinically significant results in a xenotransplanted mouse <italic toggle="yes">vivo</italic> using a 1&#8201;mg mAb subcutaneous injection (twice weekly), therefore it needs to be confirmed that the amounts of OS2966 delivered to skin using laser poration are therapeutically relevant. Furthermore, it should be noted that the studies described here were conducted using aqueous solution and that an optimized formulation such as a gel will need to be developed in order to allow the topical application of OS2966 <italic toggle="yes">in vivo</italic> and better compliance of the patient.</p><p id="Par31">Nevertheless, it has been clearly demonstrated that by tuning the laser settings, i.e. pore and pulse number and hence the applied energy, it is possible to control OS2966 delivery as well as to selectively target the skin. The antibody permeation yielded by laser treatment appears to be negligible since it was 10<sup>5</sup> times lower than the plasma levels of infliximab after a single dose intravenous administration. In practice, the physio-pathological changes in psoriatic skin such as keratinization and scaling might necessitate further optimization of the laser treatment parameters.</p></sec><sec id="Sec9" sec-type="conclusion"><title>Conclusions</title><p id="Par32">The results demonstrate the feasibility of delivering a 150,000&#8201;Da monoclonal antibody topically and selectively into the skin using the P.L.E.A.S.E.<sup>&#174;</sup> minimally-invasive laser assisted enhancement technique. These results are very promising for the treatment of psoriasis as a difficult-to-deliver, potent and selective biologic could be delivered to skin in a targeted way after topical application for 12&#8201;h, minimizing transdermal permeation and subsequent systemic exposure.</p></sec><sec id="Sec10" sec-type="materials|methods"><title>Materials and Methods</title><sec id="Sec11"><title>Materials</title><p id="Par33">The monoclonal humanized antibody (OS2966), (5.87&#8201;mg/ml solution in PBS + Tween 20 0.1%) was supplied by OncoSynergy (South San Francisco, California, USA). The ELISA (enzyme-linked immunosorbent assay) Costar&#8482; 96-well EIA/RIA plates were purchased from Fisher Scientific (Reinach, Switzerland). Tween 20 was purchased from Applichem Axon lab AG (Baden-D&#228;ttwil, Switzerland). HCl, NaCl, KCl, bovine serum albumin (BSA), Fab specific Anti-Human IgG, HRP (horseradish peroxidase) linked Fc specific Anti-Human IgG and 3,3&#8242;,5,5&#8242;-tetramethylbenzidine (TMB) liquid substrate were supplied by Sigma-Aldrich (Steinheim, Germany). Na<sub>2</sub>HPO<sub>4</sub> and KH<sub>2</sub>PO<sub>4</sub> were supplied by Acros Organics (Geel, Belgium). All other reagents were at least of reagent grade. All other solvents were HPLC grade (high performance liquid chromatography grade, HiPerSolv Chromatonorm; Darmstadt, Germany). Ultra-pure water (Millipore Milli-Q Gard 1 Purification Pack resistivity &gt; 18M&#937;cm; Zug, Switzerland) was used to prepare all solutions.</p></sec><sec id="Sec12"><title>OS2966 quantification by enzyme-linked immunosorbent assay (ELISA)</title><p id="Par34">OS2966 was quantified using enzyme-linked immunosorbent assay (ELISA). The coating Fab specific antibody (5&#8201;&#181;g/ml in PBS; 100&#8201;&#181;l) solution was introduced into each well of the Costar&#8482; 96-well EIA/RIA plate and was covered with sealplate film and incubated at 37&#8201;&#176;C for 60&#8201;min. The content of the plate was subsequently emptied and the plate was deposited upside down on absorbent paper for 1&#8201;min. The wells were washed once with 300&#8201;&#181;l of wash buffer (PBS&#8201;+&#8201;Tween 20 0.1%). 250&#8201;&#181;l of BSA 3% in wash buffer was used to block the non-specific binding sites. The plate was covered with sealplate film and incubated at 37&#8201;&#176;C for 60&#8201;min. The wash step was subsequently repeated three times. Samples or standard were then introduced in the wells and incubated at room temperature (RT) for 120&#8201;min. The wash step was repeated three times. 100&#8201;&#181;l of the solution of the HRP-linked antibody was introduced into each well and the plate was incubated at RT for 60&#8201;min. After a final wash step, TMB substrate was introduced into each well and the plate was incubated at RT in the dark for 5&#8201;min. The plate was read with the plate reader (BioTek Synergy Mx Multi-Mode microplate; BioTek, Luzern, Switzerland) at 620&#8201;nm. Finally, 100&#8201;&#181;l of 1&#8201;N HCl solution was added to each well to stop the reaction and the plate was read again at 450&#8201;nm.</p><p id="Par35">A standard curve was constructed using 0.1&#8211;1000&#8201;ng/ml concentrations of OS2966 in wash buffer. A five parameter logistic (5PL) function was used to perform the regression<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR36">36</xref></sup>. The fitting was performed using GraphPad Prism 6.03 software. R<sup>2</sup> was superior to 0.99 for all of the regressions. The ELISA quantification method was validated regarding the specificity, selectivity, precision and accuracy (Supplementary Information Section&#160;<xref rid="MOESM1" ref-type="media">1</xref>). The limit of detection (LOD) and limit of quantification (LOQ) were determined to be 1&#8201;ng/ml and 3&#8201;ng/ml respectively.</p></sec><sec id="Sec13"><title>Skin source</title><p id="Par36">Porcine ears were obtained from a local abattoir (CARRE; Rolle, Switzerland) within a few hours of sacrifice. Full thickness skin was harvested from the external side of the porcine ear. It was punched out to form discs with an area of 3&#8201;cm<sup>2</sup>, followed by trimming of any surface hair using clippers. The discs were stored at &#8722;20&#8201;&#176;C for a maximum period of 30 days.</p></sec><sec id="Sec14"><title>Skin pre-treatment</title><p id="Par37">Skin samples were equilibrated in 0.9% NaCl for 30&#8201;min prior to poration using the P.L.E.A.S.E.<sup>&#174;</sup> Professional device. After removing surface moisture, skin samples were placed at the focal length of the laser to create the micropores. Laser poration parameters, i.e., the fractional ablated area (FAA) and the fluence were fixed using the device software. The parameters were selected from the pre-programmed combinations set for dermatological applications to cover a range of fluences (Table&#160;<xref rid="Tab1" ref-type="table">1</xref><bold>)</bold><table-wrap id="Tab1" position="float" orientation="portrait"><label>Table 1</label><caption><p>Different OS2966 content and laser poration parameters used. <italic toggle="yes">FAA: Fractional ablated area; ppp: pulse per pore</italic>.</p></caption><table frame="hsides" rules="groups"><thead><tr><th align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">OS2966 content</th><th align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Stacking</th><th align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">FAA</th><th align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Control</th><th align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">50&#181;s/500&#8201;Hz</th><th align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">75&#181;s/500&#8201;Hz</th><th align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">125&#181;s/300&#8201;Hz</th><th align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">175&#181;s/200&#8201;Hz</th><th align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">225&#181;s/100&#8201;Hz</th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td colspan="1" rowspan="1">1&#8201;mg/ml</td><td colspan="1" rowspan="1">1 ppp</td><td colspan="1" rowspan="1">10%</td><td colspan="1" rowspan="1">0&#8201;J/cm<sup>2</sup></td><td colspan="1" rowspan="1">3&#8201;J/cm<sup>2</sup></td><td colspan="1" rowspan="1">4&#8201;J/cm<sup>2</sup></td><td colspan="1" rowspan="1">7.9&#8201;J/cm<sup>2</sup></td><td colspan="1" rowspan="1">11.7&#8201;J/cm<sup>2</sup></td><td colspan="1" rowspan="1">17.8&#8201;J/cm<sup>2</sup></td></tr><tr><td colspan="1" rowspan="1">1&#8201;mg/ml</td><td colspan="1" rowspan="1">3 ppp</td><td colspan="1" rowspan="1">10%</td><td colspan="1" rowspan="1"/><td colspan="1" rowspan="1">9&#8201;J/cm<sup>2</sup></td><td colspan="1" rowspan="1">12&#8201;J/cm<sup>2</sup></td><td colspan="1" rowspan="1">23.7&#8201;J/cm<sup>2</sup></td><td colspan="1" rowspan="1">35.3&#8201;J/cm<sup>2</sup></td><td colspan="1" rowspan="1">53.4&#8201;J/cm<sup>2</sup></td></tr><tr><td colspan="1" rowspan="1">1&#8201;mg/ml</td><td colspan="1" rowspan="1">5 ppp</td><td colspan="1" rowspan="1">10%</td><td colspan="1" rowspan="1"/><td colspan="1" rowspan="1">15&#8201;J/cm<sup>2</sup></td><td colspan="1" rowspan="1">20&#8201;J/cm<sup>2</sup></td><td colspan="1" rowspan="1">39.5&#8201;J/cm<sup>2</sup></td><td colspan="1" rowspan="1">58.5&#8201;J/cm<sup>2</sup></td><td colspan="1" rowspan="1">89&#8201;J/cm<sup>2</sup></td></tr><tr><td colspan="1" rowspan="1">1&#8201;mg/ml</td><td colspan="1" rowspan="1">3 ppp</td><td colspan="1" rowspan="1">5%</td><td colspan="1" rowspan="1"/><td colspan="1" rowspan="1">9&#8201;J/cm<sup>2</sup></td><td colspan="1" rowspan="1">12&#8201;J/cm<sup>2</sup></td><td colspan="1" rowspan="1">23.7&#8201;J/cm<sup>2</sup></td><td colspan="1" rowspan="1">35.3&#8201;J/cm<sup>2</sup></td><td colspan="1" rowspan="1">53.4&#8201;J/cm<sup>2</sup></td></tr><tr><td colspan="1" rowspan="1">1&#8201;mg/ml</td><td colspan="1" rowspan="1">3 ppp</td><td colspan="1" rowspan="1">15%</td><td colspan="1" rowspan="1"/><td colspan="1" rowspan="1">9&#8201;J/cm<sup>2</sup></td><td colspan="1" rowspan="1">12&#8201;J/cm<sup>2</sup></td><td colspan="1" rowspan="1">23.7&#8201;J/cm<sup>2</sup></td><td colspan="1" rowspan="1">35.3&#8201;J/cm<sup>2</sup></td><td colspan="1" rowspan="1">53.4&#8201;J/cm<sup>2</sup></td></tr><tr><td colspan="1" rowspan="1">5&#8201;mg/ml</td><td colspan="1" rowspan="1">3ppp</td><td colspan="1" rowspan="1">10%</td><td colspan="1" rowspan="1">0&#8201;J/cm<sup>2</sup></td><td colspan="1" rowspan="1">9&#8201;J/cm<sup>2</sup></td><td colspan="1" rowspan="1">12&#8201;J/cm<sup>2</sup></td><td colspan="1" rowspan="1">23.7&#8201;J/cm<sup>2</sup></td><td colspan="1" rowspan="1">35.3&#8201;J/cm<sup>2</sup></td><td colspan="1" rowspan="1">53.4&#8201;J/cm<sup>2</sup></td></tr></tbody></table></table-wrap></p></sec><sec id="Sec15"><title>Delivery experiments: experimental set-up</title><p id="Par38">Skin samples with or without laser pre-treatment were clamped in Franz-diffusion cells (diffusion area 2.0&#8201;cm<sup>2</sup>) and the receiver compartment was filled with 10&#8201;ml of PBS pH 7.4&#8201;+&#8201;Tween 20 0.1%. The diffusion cells were placed in a water bath at 33&#8201;&#176;C and the receiver solution was stirred at 250&#8201;rpm. 500&#8201;&#181;l of OS2966 solution (1&#8201;mg/ml or 5&#8201;mg/ml in PBS) were placed in the donor compartment and contact of the formulation with the skin surface was checked. Each group consisted of 5 replicates, a cell with PBS as donor solution was used as the negative control. The cells were finally covered with Parafilm&#8482;; the duration of the permeation experiments was 12&#8201;h. At the end of the experiment, 1&#8201;ml was collected from the receiver compartment to quantify OS2966 skin permeation. Then, the diffusion cells were dismantled, the excess formulation removed from the skin surface with a tissue and the skin washed twice with a water impregnated cotton bud. Finally, the skin surface was dried with a soft tissue. OS2966 deposited in the skin was extracted by cutting the tissue into small pieces and soaking them in 10&#8201;ml of PBS pH 7.4&#8201;+&#8201;Tween 20 0.1% for 4&#8201;hours under constant agitation at room temperature. The samples were centrifuged and appropriately diluted before undergoing ELISA analysis.</p></sec><sec id="Sec16"><title>Data analysis</title><p id="Par39">Skin delivery data were expressed as mean&#8201;&#177;&#8201;SD. Outliers were determined using the Dixon&#8217;s Q test (&#945;&#8201;=&#8201;0.05) and discarded. Results were evaluated statistically using SigmaPlot v.11.0. Groups were compared using either analysis of variance (ANOVA) or analysis of means by Student&#8217;s t-test. Student Newman Keuls test or Bonferroni T-test were used when necessary as post-hoc procedures. The level of significance was fixed at &#945;&#8201;=&#8201;0.05. (the detailed statistics are presented in Supplementary Information Section&#160;<xref rid="MOESM1" ref-type="media">3</xref>).</p></sec><sec id="Sec17"><title>Fluorescent labelling of OS2966</title><p id="Par40">The OS2966 was labelled using Alexa Fluor<sup>&#174;</sup> 488 Protein Labeling Kit (Molecular probes<sup>&#174;</sup>, life technologies A-10235).</p><p id="Par41">The labelled OS2966 was purified on Bio-Rad BioGel P-30 size exclusion purification resin provided in the kit. Fractions of ~200&#8201;&#956;l were collected in Eppendorf tubes. At the end of purification, all tubes were observed under a UV lamp at 366&#8201;nm to visualize the tubes containing fluorescent compounds. The labelled antibody (Alexa 488-OS2966) was well separated from the residual free dye and collected in fractions 8&#8211;12 (Supplementary Information Section&#160;<xref rid="MOESM1" ref-type="media">2</xref>). The calculated concentration of the Alexa 488-OS2966 in the pooled 8 to 12 fractions was 1.4&#8201;mg/ml. This concentration was subsequently adjusted to 1&#8201;mg/ml for skin delivery experiments.</p><p id="Par42">All factions were tested by HPLC-Fluo for the presence of the free dye. Free dye was quantified using an HPLC system (formerly Dionex AG, now Thermo Fisher Scientific AG; Reinach Switzerland) composed of a P680A LPG-4 pump, an ASI-100 autosampler, a thermostatted column compartment TCC-100, a UV170U detector and a RF 2000 fluorescence detector. Data collection and integration were achieved using Chromeleon&#174; (version 6.8) software.</p><p id="Par43">A Lichrospher RP-C8, 5&#8201;&#956;m column (4,6&#8201;&#215;&#8201;125&#8201;mm) thermostatted at 40&#8201;&#176;C was used for the separation. The mobile phase consisted of a 70:30 mixture of methanol:water. Analyses were performed using an injection volume of 25&#8201;&#956;l and a flow rate of 0.6&#8201;ml/min. The excitation wavelength was set at 494&#8201;nm and the emission wavelength at 519&#8201;nm. A peak for Alexa fluor 488 was obtained at 2.518&#8201;min. The Alexa 488-OS2966 in the pooled 8 to 12 fractions was found to be 99.4% pure (m/m) (Supplementary Information Section&#160;<xref rid="MOESM1" ref-type="media">2</xref>).</p></sec><sec id="Sec18"><title>Confocal laser scanning microscopy visualization (CLSM)</title><p id="Par44">The delivery experiments for the confocal microscopy study were performed using the same conditions as for the &#8220;conventional&#8221; quantitative delivery experiments. 1&#8201;mg/ml solution of Alexa 488-OS2966 in PBS was applied to the donor compartment. Only the stacking was varied from 1 ppp to 5 ppp leading to fluences ranging from 11.7&#8201;J/cm<sup>2</sup> to 58.5&#8201;J/cm<sup>2</sup>.</p><p id="Par45">After the permeation experiment, cells were dismantled and skin samples were deposited on cotton swabs impregnated with a Hoechst 33258 solution (100&#8201;&#181;g/ml). Hoechst 33258 was allowed to diffuse into the skin from the dermal side for 30&#8201;min in order to stain dermal and epidermal tissue.</p><p id="Par46">Finally, the skin was cut in lateral slices (approx. 1&#8201;mm thick) with a scalpel and mounted on a glass slide in two ways: either <italic toggle="yes">stratum corneum</italic> (xy-plane) facing the microscope objective (LSM 710, Zeiss, Germany), or the vertical cross-section (xz-plane) slice facing the microscope objective. (Supplementary Information Section&#160;<xref rid="MOESM1" ref-type="media">3</xref>).</p><p id="Par47">The confocal images were obtained using the settings mentioned in Table&#160;<xref rid="Tab2" ref-type="table">2</xref> with an Achroplan 20x air or a Fluar 5x objective and analyzed using Image J software. Each image was the average of 4 repeated scans.<table-wrap id="Tab2" position="float" orientation="portrait"><label>Table 2</label><caption><p>CLSM settings for both dyes.</p></caption><table frame="hsides" rules="groups"><thead><tr><th colspan="1" rowspan="1"/><th colspan="1" rowspan="1">Alexa fluor 488</th><th colspan="1" rowspan="1">Hoechst 33258</th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td colspan="1" rowspan="1">Excitation Laser</td><td colspan="1" rowspan="1">488&#8201;nm</td><td colspan="1" rowspan="1">405&#8201;nm</td></tr><tr><td colspan="1" rowspan="1">Emission filter</td><td colspan="1" rowspan="1">510&#8211;530&#8201;nm</td><td colspan="1" rowspan="1">431&#8211;460&#8201;nm</td></tr><tr><td colspan="1" rowspan="1">Laser power</td><td colspan="1" rowspan="1">20</td><td colspan="1" rowspan="1">60</td></tr><tr><td colspan="1" rowspan="1">Pinhole</td><td colspan="1" rowspan="1">100</td><td colspan="1" rowspan="1">300</td></tr><tr><td colspan="1" rowspan="1">Master gain</td><td colspan="1" rowspan="1">500</td><td colspan="1" rowspan="1">600</td></tr></tbody></table></table-wrap></p><p id="Par48">The morphology of the pores created with the optimal laser treatment was confirmed by optical microscopy after a standard Hematoxylin and eosin staining procedure.</p></sec></sec><sec sec-type="supplementary-material"><title>Supplementary information</title><sec id="Sec19"><p>
<supplementary-material content-type="local-data" id="MOESM1" position="float" orientation="portrait"><media xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xlink:href="41598_2018_36966_MOESM1_ESM.docx" position="float" orientation="portrait"><caption><p>Supplemenatary Information</p></caption></media></supplementary-material>
</p></sec></sec></body><back><fn-group><fn><p><bold>Publisher&#8217;s note:</bold> Springer Nature remains neutral with regard to jurisdictional claims in published maps and institutional affiliations.</p></fn></fn-group><sec><title>Electronic supplementary material</title><p><bold>Supplementary information</bold> accompanies this paper at 10.1038/s41598-018-36966-0.</p></sec><ack><title>Acknowledgements</title><p>The authors thank Dr. Remo Perozzo and Dr. Kiran Sonaje for assistance in the development of the immunoassay. Y.K. thanks the University of Geneva and the Swiss Commission for Technology Innovation for financial support (CTI 13933.2).</p></ack><notes notes-type="author-contribution"><title>Author Contributions</title><p>Y.K., C.B. and W.S.C. conceived the study. E.W. and W.S.C. developed the immunoassay. M.L. performed the experiments. M.L. and S.D.R. wrote the paper. All authors reviewed the manuscript.</p></notes><notes notes-type="COI-statement"><sec id="FPar1"><title>Competing Interests</title><p>The authors declare no competing interests.</p></sec></notes><ref-list id="Bib1"><title>References</title><ref id="CR1"><label>1.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Lowes</surname><given-names>MA</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Bowcock</surname><given-names>AM</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Krueger</surname><given-names>JG</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>Pathogenesis and therapy of psoriasis</article-title><source>Nature.</source><year>2007</year><volume>445</volume><fpage>866</fpage><lpage>873</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1038/nature05663</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">17314973</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR2"><label>2.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Nestle</surname><given-names>FO</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Kaplan</surname><given-names>DH</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Barker</surname><given-names>J</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>Psoriasis</article-title><source>N. Engl. J. Med.</source><year>2009</year><volume>361</volume><fpage>496</fpage><lpage>509</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1056/NEJMra0804595</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">19641206</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR3"><label>3.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Menter</surname><given-names>A</given-names></name><etal/></person-group><article-title>Guidelines of care for the management of psoriasis and psoriatic arthritis: Section 1. Overview of psoriasis and guidelines of care for the treatment of psoriasis with biologics</article-title><source>J. Am. Acad. Dermatol.</source><year>2008</year><volume>58</volume><fpage>826</fpage><lpage>850</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1016/j.jaad.2008.02.039</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">18423260</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR4"><label>4.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Mitra</surname><given-names>A</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Wu</surname><given-names>Y</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>Topical delivery for the treatment of psoriasis</article-title><source>Expert Opin. Drug Deliv.</source><year>2010</year><volume>7</volume><fpage>977</fpage><lpage>992</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1517/17425247.2010.503953</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">20645673</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR5"><label>5.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Almutawa</surname><given-names>F</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Alnomair</surname><given-names>N</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Wang</surname><given-names>Y</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Hamzavi</surname><given-names>I</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Lim</surname><given-names>HW</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>Systematic review of UV-based therapy for psoriasis</article-title><source>Am. J. Clin. Dermatol.</source><year>2013</year><volume>14</volume><fpage>87</fpage><lpage>109</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1007/s40257-013-0015-y</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">23572293</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR6"><label>6.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Chiricozzi</surname><given-names>A</given-names></name><etal/></person-group><article-title>New topical treatments for psoriasis</article-title><source>Expert Opin. Pharmacother.</source><year>2014</year><volume>15</volume><fpage>461</fpage><lpage>470</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1517/14656566.2014.875159</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">24392930</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR7"><label>7.</label><mixed-citation publication-type="other">FDA. Cosentyx prescribing information, (2016) Available at, <ext-link xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" ext-link-type="uri" xlink:href="https://www.accessdata.fda.gov/drugsatfda_docs/label/2016/125504s001s002lbl.pdf">https://www.accessdata.fda.gov/drugsatfda_docs/label/2016/125504s001s002lbl.pdf</ext-link> (Accessed: 31.01.2018).</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="CR8"><label>8.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Horn</surname><given-names>EJ</given-names></name><etal/></person-group><article-title>Topical corticosteroids in psoriasis: strategies for improving safety</article-title><source>J. Eur. Acad. Dermatol Venereol.</source><year>2010</year><volume>24</volume><fpage>119</fpage><lpage>124</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1111/j.1468-3083.2009.03358.x</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">20175860</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR9"><label>9.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Archier</surname><given-names>E</given-names></name><etal/></person-group><article-title>Carcinogenic risks of psoralen UV-A therapy and narrowband UV-B therapy in chronic plaque psoriasis: a systematic literature review</article-title><source>J. Eur. Acad. Dermatol. Venereol.</source><year>2012</year><volume>26</volume><issue>Suppl 3</issue><fpage>22</fpage><lpage>31</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1111/j.1468-3083.2012.04520.x</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">22512677</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR10"><label>10.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Hansel</surname><given-names>TT</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Kropshofer</surname><given-names>H</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Singer</surname><given-names>T</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Mitchell</surname><given-names>JA</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>George</surname><given-names>AJ</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>The safety and side effects of monoclonal antibodies</article-title><source>Nat. Rev. Drug. Discov.</source><year>2010</year><volume>9</volume><fpage>325</fpage><lpage>338</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1038/nrd3003</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">20305665</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR11"><label>11.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Stebbings</surname><given-names>R</given-names></name><etal/></person-group><article-title>&#8220;Cytokine storm&#8221; in the phase I trial of monoclonal antibody TGN1412: better understanding the causes to improve preclinical testing of immunotherapeutics</article-title><source>J. Immunol.</source><year>2007</year><volume>179</volume><fpage>3325</fpage><lpage>3331</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.4049/jimmunol.179.5.3325</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">17709549</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR12"><label>12.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Tsianakas</surname><given-names>A</given-names></name><etal/></person-group><article-title>The single-chain anti-TNF-alpha antibody DLX105 induces clinical and biomarker responses upon local administration in patients with chronic plaque-type psoriasis</article-title><source>Exp. Dermatol.</source><year>2016</year><volume>25</volume><fpage>428</fpage><lpage>433</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1111/exd.12927</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">26738450</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR13"><label>13.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Schuetz</surname><given-names>YB</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Naik</surname><given-names>A</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Guy</surname><given-names>RH</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Kalia</surname><given-names>YN</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>Emerging strategies for the transdermal delivery of peptide and protein drugs</article-title><source>Expert Opin. Drug Deliv.</source><year>2005</year><volume>2</volume><fpage>533</fpage><lpage>548</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1517/17425247.2.3.533</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">16296773</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR14"><label>14.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Bachhav</surname><given-names>YG</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Heinrich</surname><given-names>A</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Kalia</surname><given-names>YN</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>Controlled intra- and transdermal protein delivery using a minimally invasive Erbium:YAG fractional laser ablation technology</article-title><source>Eur. J. Pharm. Biopharm.</source><year>2013</year><volume>84</volume><fpage>355</fpage><lpage>364</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1016/j.ejpb.2012.11.018</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">23207321</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR15"><label>15.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Song</surname><given-names>Y</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Hemmady</surname><given-names>K</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Puri</surname><given-names>A</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Banga</surname><given-names>AK</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>Transdermal delivery of human growth hormone via laser-generated micropores</article-title><source>Drug Deliv. Trans. Res.</source><year>2018</year><volume>8</volume><fpage>450</fpage><lpage>460</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1007/s13346-017-0370-y</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">28321676</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR16"><label>16.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Yu</surname><given-names>J</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Kalaria</surname><given-names>DR</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Kalia</surname><given-names>YN</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>Erbium:YAG fractional laser ablation for the percutaneous delivery of intact functional therapeutic antibodies</article-title><source>J. Control. Release.</source><year>2011</year><volume>156</volume><fpage>53</fpage><lpage>59</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1016/j.jconrel.2011.07.024</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">21803083</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR17"><label>17.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Weiss</surname><given-names>R</given-names></name><etal/></person-group><article-title>Transcutaneous vaccination via laser microporation</article-title><source>J. Control. Release.</source><year>2012</year><volume>162</volume><fpage>391</fpage><lpage>399</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1016/j.jconrel.2012.06.031</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">22750193</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC3462999</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR18"><label>18.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Gratieri</surname><given-names>T</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Alberti</surname><given-names>I</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Lapteva</surname><given-names>M</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Kalia</surname><given-names>YN</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>Next generation intra- and transdermal therapeutic systems: using non- and minimally-invasive technologies to increase drug delivery into and across the skin</article-title><source>Eur. J. Pharm. Sci.</source><year>2013</year><volume>50</volume><fpage>609</fpage><lpage>622</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1016/j.ejps.2013.03.019</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">23567467</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR19"><label>19.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Nelson</surname><given-names>JS</given-names></name><etal/></person-group><article-title>Mid-Infrared Laser Ablation of Stratum Corneum Enhances <italic toggle="yes">In Vitro</italic> Percutaneous Transport of Drugs</article-title><source>J. Invest Dermatol.</source><year>1991</year><volume>97</volume><fpage>874</fpage><lpage>879</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1111/1523-1747.ep12491600</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">1919050</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR20"><label>20.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Kalia</surname><given-names>YN</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Bachhav</surname><given-names>YG</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Bragagna</surname><given-names>T</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>B&#246;hler</surname><given-names>C</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>Intraepidermal drug delivery: P.L.E.A.S.E.&#174; - A new laser microporation technology</article-title><source>Drug Delivery Technology.</source><year>2008</year><volume>8</volume><fpage>26</fpage><lpage>31</lpage></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR21"><label>21.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Zech</surname><given-names>NH</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Murtinger</surname><given-names>M</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Uher</surname><given-names>P</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>Pregnancy after ovarian superovulation by transdermal delivery of follicle-stimulating hormone</article-title><source>Fertil. Steril.</source><year>2011</year><volume>95</volume><fpage>2784</fpage><lpage>2785</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1016/j.fertnstert.2011.03.073</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">21497348</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR22"><label>22.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Rippa</surname><given-names>AL</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Vorotelyak</surname><given-names>EA</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Vasiliev</surname><given-names>AV</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Terskikh</surname><given-names>VV</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>The role of integrins in the development and homeostasis of the epidermis and skin appendages</article-title><source>Acta Naturae.</source><year>2013</year><volume>5</volume><fpage>22</fpage><lpage>33</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">24455180</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC3890986</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR23"><label>23.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Conrad</surname><given-names>C</given-names></name><etal/></person-group><article-title>alpha(1)beta(1) integrin is crucial for accumulation of epidermal T cells and the development of psoriasis</article-title><source>Nat. Med.</source><year>2007</year><volume>13</volume><fpage>836</fpage><lpage>842</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1038/nm1605</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">17603494</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR24"><label>24.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Al-Jamal</surname><given-names>R</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Harrison</surname><given-names>DJ</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>Beta1 integrin in tissue remodelling and repair: from phenomena to concepts</article-title><source>Pharmacol. Ther.</source><year>2008</year><volume>120</volume><fpage>81</fpage><lpage>101</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1016/j.pharmthera.2008.07.002</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">18708090</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR25"><label>25.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Jacobi</surname><given-names>U</given-names></name><etal/></person-group><article-title>Porcine ear skin: an <italic toggle="yes">in vitro</italic> model for human skin</article-title><source>Skin Res. Technol.</source><year>2007</year><volume>13</volume><fpage>19</fpage><lpage>24</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1111/j.1600-0846.2006.00179.x</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">17250528</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR26"><label>26.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Lapteva</surname><given-names>M</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Mondon</surname><given-names>K</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Moller</surname><given-names>M</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Gurny</surname><given-names>R</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Kalia</surname><given-names>YN</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>Polymeric micelle nanocarriers for the cutaneous delivery of tacrolimus: a targeted approach for the treatment of psoriasis</article-title><source>Mol. Pharm.</source><year>2014</year><volume>11</volume><fpage>2989</fpage><lpage>3001</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1021/mp400639e</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">25057896</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR27"><label>27.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Lapteva</surname><given-names>M</given-names></name><etal/></person-group><article-title>Targeted cutaneous delivery of ciclosporin A using micellar nanocarriers and the possible role of inter-cluster regions as molecular transport pathways</article-title><source>J Control. Release.</source><year>2014</year><volume>196</volume><fpage>9</fpage><lpage>18</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1016/j.jconrel.2014.09.021</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">25278258</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR28"><label>28.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Brandner</surname><given-names>JM</given-names></name><etal/></person-group><article-title>Epidermal tight junctions in health and disease</article-title><source>Tissue Barriers.</source><year>2015</year><volume>3</volume><fpage>e9744511</fpage><lpage>e97445113</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.4161/21688370.2014.974451</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC4372028</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">25838981</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR29"><label>29.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Cao</surname><given-names>Y</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Kakar</surname><given-names>P</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Hossen</surname><given-names>MN</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Wu</surname><given-names>MX</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Chen</surname><given-names>X</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>Sustained epidermal powder drug delivery via skin microchannels</article-title><source>J. Control. Release.</source><year>2017</year><volume>249</volume><fpage>94</fpage><lpage>102</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1016/j.jconrel.2017.01.030</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">28132934</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC5377446</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR30"><label>30.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Jung</surname><given-names>EC</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Maibach</surname><given-names>HI</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>Animal models for percutaneous absorption</article-title><source>J. Appl. Toxicol.</source><year>2015</year><volume>35</volume><fpage>1</fpage><lpage>10</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1002/jat.3004</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">25345378</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR31"><label>31.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Bond</surname><given-names>JR</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Barry</surname><given-names>BW</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>Hairless mouse skin is limited as a model for assessing the effects of penetration enhancers in human skin</article-title><source>J. Invest. Dermatol.</source><year>1988</year><volume>90</volume><fpage>810</fpage><lpage>813</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1111/1523-1747.ep12462031</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">3373011</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR32"><label>32.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Schmook</surname><given-names>FP</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Meingassner</surname><given-names>JG</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Billich</surname><given-names>A</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>Comparison of human skin or epidermis models with human and animal skin in <italic toggle="yes">in-vitro</italic> percutaneous absorption</article-title><source>Int. J. Pharm.</source><year>2001</year><volume>215</volume><fpage>51</fpage><lpage>56</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1016/S0378-5173(00)00665-7</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">11250091</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR33"><label>33.</label><mixed-citation publication-type="other">OECD. Series on Testing and Assessment, No. 156, GUIDANCE NOTES ON DERMAL ABSORPTION, (2011) Available at, <ext-link xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" ext-link-type="uri" xlink:href="https://www.oecd.org/chemicalsafety/testing/48532204.pdf">https://www.oecd.org/chemicalsafety/testing/48532204.pdf</ext-link> (Accessed: 24.09.2018).</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="CR34"><label>34.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Klotz</surname><given-names>U</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Teml</surname><given-names>A</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Schwab</surname><given-names>M</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>Clinical pharmacokinetics and use of infliximab</article-title><source>Clin. Pharmacokinet.</source><year>2007</year><volume>46</volume><fpage>645</fpage><lpage>660</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.2165/00003088-200746080-00002</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">17655372</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR35"><label>35.</label><mixed-citation publication-type="other">FDA. Remicade prescribing information. Available at, http://www.accessdata.fda.gov/drugsatfda_docs/label/2011/103772s5295lbl.pdf (Accessed: 31.01.2018) (2011).</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="CR36"><label>36.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Gottschalk</surname><given-names>PG</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Dunn</surname><given-names>JR</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>The five-parameter logistic: a characterization and comparison with the four-parameter logistic</article-title><source>Anal. Biochem.</source><year>2005</year><volume>343</volume><fpage>54</fpage><lpage>65</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1016/j.ab.2005.04.035</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">15953581</pub-id></element-citation></ref></ref-list></back></article></pmc-articleset>