<?xml version="1.0"  ?><!DOCTYPE pmc-articleset PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD ARTICLE SET 2.0//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pmc/articleset/nlm-articleset-2.0.dtd"><pmc-articleset><article xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" xmlns:ali="http://www.niso.org/schemas/ali/1.0/" article-type="research-article" xml:lang="en" dtd-version="1.4"><front><journal-meta><journal-id journal-id-type="nlm-ta">Dermatol Surg</journal-id><journal-id journal-id-type="iso-abbrev">Dermatol Surg</journal-id><journal-id journal-id-type="pmc-domain-id">2035</journal-id><journal-id journal-id-type="pmc-domain">lwwopen</journal-id><journal-id journal-id-type="publisher-id">ds</journal-id><journal-title-group><journal-title>Dermatologic Surgery</journal-title></journal-title-group><issn pub-type="ppub">1076-0512</issn><issn pub-type="epub">1524-4725</issn><custom-meta-group><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-is-collection-domain</meta-name><meta-value>yes</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-collection-title</meta-name><meta-value>Lippincott Open Access</meta-value></custom-meta></custom-meta-group></journal-meta><article-meta><article-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC8021234</article-id><article-id pub-id-type="pmcid-ver">PMC8021234.1</article-id><article-id pub-id-type="pmcaid">8021234</article-id><article-id pub-id-type="pmcaiid">8021234</article-id><article-id pub-id-type="pmid">33587369</article-id><article-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1097/DSS.0000000000002856</article-id><article-id pub-id-type="publisher-id">ds-00539-2020</article-id><article-version article-version-type="pmc-version">1</article-version><article-categories><subj-group subj-group-type="heading"><subject>Original Article</subject></subj-group></article-categories><title-group><article-title>A Randomized, Controlled, Evaluator-Blinded, Multi-Center Study of Hyaluronic Acid Filler Effectiveness and Safety in Lip Fullness Augmentation</article-title></title-group><contrib-group><contrib contrib-type="author" corresp="yes"><name name-style="western"><surname>Weiss</surname><given-names initials="R">Robert</given-names></name><degrees>MD</degrees><xref ref-type="aff" rid="aff1">*</xref></contrib><contrib contrib-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Beer</surname><given-names initials="K">Kenneth</given-names></name><degrees>MD</degrees><xref ref-type="aff" rid="aff2">&#8224;</xref></contrib><contrib contrib-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Cox</surname><given-names initials="SE">Sue E.</given-names></name><degrees>MD</degrees><xref ref-type="aff" rid="aff3">&#8225;</xref></contrib><contrib contrib-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Palm</surname><given-names initials="M">Melanie</given-names></name><degrees>MD, MBA</degrees><xref ref-type="aff" rid="aff4">&#167;</xref></contrib><contrib contrib-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Kaufman-Janette</surname><given-names initials="J">Joely</given-names></name><degrees>MD</degrees><xref ref-type="aff" rid="aff5">&#8214;</xref></contrib><contrib contrib-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Bassichis</surname><given-names initials="B">Benjamin</given-names></name><degrees>MD</degrees><xref ref-type="aff" rid="aff6">&#182;</xref></contrib><contrib contrib-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Biesman</surname><given-names initials="B">Brian</given-names></name><degrees>MD</degrees><xref ref-type="aff" rid="aff7">**</xref></contrib><contrib contrib-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Joseph</surname><given-names initials="J">John</given-names></name><degrees>MD</degrees><xref ref-type="aff" rid="aff8">&#8224;&#8224;</xref></contrib><contrib contrib-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Almeg&#229;rd</surname><given-names initials="B">Birgitta</given-names></name><degrees>PhD</degrees><xref ref-type="aff" rid="aff9">&#8225;&#8225;</xref></contrib><contrib contrib-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Nilsson</surname><given-names initials="A">Anna</given-names></name><degrees>MSc</degrees><xref ref-type="aff" rid="aff9">&#8225;&#8225;</xref></contrib><contrib contrib-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Edwartz</surname><given-names initials="C">Carolina</given-names></name><degrees>PhD</degrees><xref ref-type="aff" rid="aff10">&#167;&#167;</xref></contrib><aff id="aff1"><label>*</label>Maryland Dermatology, Laser, Skin and Vein Institute, Hunt Valley, Maryland;</aff><aff id="aff2"><label>&#8224;</label>Research Institute of SouthEast, West Palm Beach, Florida;</aff><aff id="aff3"><label>&#8225;</label>Aesthetic Solutions, Chapel Hill, North Carolina;</aff><aff id="aff4"><label>&#167;</label>Art of Skin Maryland, Solana Beach, California;</aff><aff id="aff5"><label>&#8214;</label>Skin Research Institute, LLC, Coral Gables, Florida;</aff><aff id="aff6"><label>&#182;</label>Center for Advanced Clinical Research, Dallas, Texas;</aff><aff id="aff7"><label>**</label>Brian S. Biesman, Nashville, Tennessee;</aff><aff id="aff8"><label>&#8224;&#8224;</label>Clinical Testing of Beverly Hills, Encino, California;</aff><aff id="aff9"><label>&#8225;&#8225;</label>Galderma Aesthetics, Clinical Development, Uppsala, <country>Sweden;</country></aff><aff id="aff10"><label>&#167;&#167;</label>Galderma Aesthetics, Global Medical Affairs, Uppsala, <country>Sweden</country></aff></contrib-group><author-notes><corresp id="cor1">Address correspondence and reprint requests to: Robert Weiss, MD, Maryland Dermatology, Laser, Skin and Vein Institute, 54 Scott Adam Road, Suite 301, Hunt Valley, MD 21030, or e-mail: <email>rweiss@mdlsv.com</email></corresp></author-notes><pub-date pub-type="ppub"><month>4</month><year>2021</year></pub-date><pub-date pub-type="epub"><day>10</day><month>2</month><year>2021</year></pub-date><volume>47</volume><issue>4</issue><issue-id pub-id-type="pmc-issue-id">378949</issue-id><fpage>527</fpage><lpage>532</lpage><pub-history><event event-type="pmc-release"><date><day>05</day><month>04</month><year>2021</year></date></event><event event-type="pmc-live"><date><day>09</day><month>04</month><year>2021</year></date></event><event event-type="pmc-last-change"><date iso-8601-date="2021-04-10 05:16:23.940"><day>10</day><month>04</month><year>2021</year></date></event></pub-history><permissions><copyright-statement>Copyright &#169; 2021 The Author(s). Published by Wolters Kluwer Health, Inc. on behalf of the American Society for Dermatologic Surgery, Inc.</copyright-statement><copyright-year>2021</copyright-year><license license-type="open-access" specific-use="CCBY-NC-ND"><ali:license_ref specific-use="textmining" content-type="ccbyncndlicense">https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/4.0/</ali:license_ref><license-p>This is an open-access article distributed under the terms of the <ext-link xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" ext-link-type="uri" xlink:href="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/4.0/">Creative Commons Attribution-Non Commercial-No Derivatives License 4.0 (CCBY-NC-ND)</ext-link>, where it is permissible to download and share the work provided it is properly cited. The work cannot be changed in any way or used commercially without permission from the journal.</license-p></license></permissions><self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" content-type="pmc-pdf" xlink:href="ds-47-527.pdf"/><self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xlink:href="ds-47-527.pdf"/><abstract abstract-type="toc"><p>Supplemental Digital Content is Available in the Text.</p></abstract><abstract><title>BACKGROUND</title><p>HA<sub>RK</sub> was recently approved in the US for lip augmentation and correction of upper perioral rhytids.</p><sec><title>OBJECTIVE</title><p>To demonstrate noninferiority of HA<sub>RK</sub> versus a control (HA<sub>JV</sub>) in lip fullness augmentation at Week 8 after last injection (blinded evaluation). Secondary objectives were to evaluate the effectiveness and safety of HA<sub>RK</sub> in lip fullness augmentation and correction of upper perioral rhytids.</p></sec><sec><title>METHODS AND MATERIALS</title><p>Treatment with HA<sub>RK</sub> or control (randomized 2:1) was administered on Day 1 in this 48-week, evaluator-blinded study with optional touch-up at Week 4. Primary endpoint was change from baseline to Week 8 in lip fullness. Secondary endpoints included lip fullness, wrinkle severity, aesthetic improvement, subject satisfaction, adverse events, and local tolerability (subject diary entries).</p></sec><sec><title>RESULTS</title><p>The primary objective was met; HA<sub>RK</sub> was noninferior to control in lip fullness augmentation at Week 8. Lip fullness and wrinkle severity improvement persisted at Week 48, and was accompanied by high aesthetic improvement and subject satisfaction scores. The mean volume of HA<sub>RK</sub> injected was approximately 20% lower than control. Treatment-related adverse events and local tolerability symptoms were predominantly mild and transient.</p></sec><sec><title>CONCLUSION</title><p>HA<sub>RK</sub> was noninferior to control in lip fullness augmentation at Week 8, well-tolerated, and effective throughout this 48-week study.</p></sec></abstract><custom-meta-group><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-status-qastatus</meta-name><meta-value>0</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-status-live</meta-name><meta-value>yes</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-status-embargo</meta-name><meta-value>no</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-status-released</meta-name><meta-value>yes</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-open-access</meta-name><meta-value>yes</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-olf</meta-name><meta-value>no</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-manuscript</meta-name><meta-value>no</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-legally-suppressed</meta-name><meta-value>no</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-has-pdf</meta-name><meta-value>yes</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-has-supplement</meta-name><meta-value>no</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-pdf-only</meta-name><meta-value>no</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-suppress-copyright</meta-name><meta-value>no</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-is-real-version</meta-name><meta-value>no</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-is-scanned-article</meta-name><meta-value>no</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-preprint</meta-name><meta-value>no</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-in-epmc</meta-name><meta-value>yes</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-license-ref</meta-name><meta-value>CC BY-NC-ND</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>OPEN-ACCESS</meta-name><meta-value>TRUE</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>SDC</meta-name><meta-value>T</meta-value></custom-meta></custom-meta-group></article-meta></front><body><p>Injectable hyaluronic acid (HA) gel fillers are commonly used for minimally invasive lip augmentation and correction of perioral rhytids.<sup><xref rid="R1" ref-type="bibr">1</xref>&#8211;<xref rid="R7" ref-type="bibr">7</xref></sup> Restylane Kysse (HA<sub>RK</sub>; Galderma, Sweden) is an HA gel filler produced with XPresHAn technology (also known as the Optimal Balance Technology). It was first approved in the EU in 2010 for restoration or augmentation of lip volume. Clinical data supporting its intended use are described in published literature.<sup><xref rid="R6" ref-type="bibr">6</xref>,<xref rid="R8" ref-type="bibr">8</xref>&#8211;<xref rid="R10" ref-type="bibr">10</xref></sup> HA<sub>RK</sub> is also approved in many other countries worldwide, and was recently approved in the US for lip augmentation and correction of upper perioral rhytids.</p><p>Here, the authors present data from the first randomized, controlled, evaluator-blinded study performed with HA<sub>RK</sub> in the US to evaluate effectiveness and safety of HA<sub>RK</sub> versus a control (Juv&#233;derm Volbella XC [HA<sub>JV</sub>], Allergan, CA) in lip fullness augmentation and correction of upper perioral rhytids.</p><sec sec-type="materials|methods" id="s1"><title>Materials and Methods</title><sec id="s1-1"><title>Study Design</title><p>This was a randomized, controlled, evaluator-blinded 48-week pivotal study (<ext-link xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" ext-link-type="pmc:clinical-trial" xlink:href="NCT03320824">NCT03320824</ext-link>) performed at 14 centers in the US to evaluate the effectiveness and safety of HA<sub>RK</sub> in lip fullness augmentation and correction of upper perioral rhytids. The primary objective was to demonstrate noninferiority of HA<sub>RK</sub> versus a control in lip fullness augmentation 8 weeks after last injection. Secondary objectives were to evaluate the effectiveness and safety of HA<sub>RK</sub> in lip fullness augmentation and correction of upper perioral rhytids. Follow-up was done at 72 hours and Weeks 2, 4, 8, 16, 24, 32, 40 and 48 after last injection (baseline or touch-up).</p><p>The study started after obtaining approval from the US FDA and Independent Review Board and was performed in accordance with the Declaration of Helsinki, Good Clinical Practice, and International Organization for Standardization (ISO) guidelines for clinical studies of medical devices in humans (ISO 14155:2011).</p></sec><sec id="s1-2"><title>Main Eligibility Criteria</title><p>Healthy subjects aged &#8805;22 years with &#8220;very thin&#8221; or &#8220;thin&#8221; <sup><xref rid="R11" ref-type="bibr">11</xref></sup> upper and lower lips, and who provided written informed consent were eligible to participate in this study. At least 42 subjects with Fitzpatrick skin Types IV&#8211;VI were to be included; of these, 21 subjects with skin Types V or VI were exempted from the requirement to have &#8220;very thin&#8221; or &#8220;thin&#8221; lips. For treatment of upper perioral rhytids, subjects had to have &#8220;moderately deep&#8221; to &#8220;very deep&#8221; wrinkles.<sup><xref rid="R12" ref-type="bibr">12</xref></sup></p><p>Main exclusion criteria were allergy/hypersensitivity to any injectable HA gel, gram positive bacterial proteins, lidocaine, or other amide-type anesthetics; disease/lesions on or near the area to be treated (e.g., herpes labialis outbreak within 4 weeks before injection or &#8805;4 outbreaks within 12 months before baseline visit); facial treatment below the lower orbital rim (such as tissue augmentation with any HA- or collagen-based biodegradable product within 12 months before the baseline visit, or permanent or semi-permanent tissue augmentation, lifting threads, permanent implants or autologous fat); lip surgery, piercing or tattoo, or trauma to any area of the face; dental, oral or facial condition/treatment which could interfere with study injections/assessments; use of lip plumper within 10 days before any study visit; use of concomitant medication that potentially could prolong bleeding times (e.g., anticoagulants or inhibitors of platelet aggregation) within 14 days before injection.</p></sec><sec id="s1-3"><title>Treatment</title><p>HA<sub>RK</sub> or control (HA<sub>JV</sub>), randomized 2:1, was injected into lips and upper perioral rhytids at baseline to achieve optimal correction. Injection into upper perioral rhytids, vermillion, vermillion border, philtral columns, cupid's bow, and/or oral commissures was optional. For lips, optimal correction was typically &#8805;1-grade improvement on the Medicis Lip Fullness Scale (MLFS). Treatment was stratified by Fitzpatrick skin type (I&#8211;III, IV or V&#8211;VI) and center (only for skin Type I-&#8211;III). It was recommended to not inject more than 3 mL in lips (i.e., 1.5 mL per lip, including vermillion, vermillion border and cupid's bow) and not more than 3 mL in the perioral area (upper perioral rhytids, philtral columns and/or oral commissures) per treatment. Optional touch-up was offered at Week 4 after baseline if optimal correction was not achieved after baseline injection. Optional re-treatment with HA<sub>RK</sub> was offered at Week 48 after last injection.</p><p>HA<sub>RK</sub> was to be injected in the submucosal layer of the lips, or in the mid-dermis to subcutaneous layer of upper perioral rhytids, using the co-packed needles and an aseptic injection technique. Investigators were recommended to use linear antegrade/retrograde threading, serial puncture, fanning or fern pattern for lip injections, and linear retrograde threading, fanning or fern pattern for upper perioral rhytids. HA<sub>JV</sub> was injected in line with manufacturer recommendations.</p><p>The treated area could be gently massaged to correct slight irregularities, and ice packs could be applied to minimize post-treatment swelling.</p></sec><sec id="s1-4"><title>Effectiveness Assessments</title><p>Assessments were done at baseline and Weeks 8, 16, 24, 32, 40, and 48 after last injection, unless otherwise stated.</p><sec id="s1-4-1"><title>By Blinded Evaluator</title><sec id="s1-4-1-1"><title>Lip Fullness</title><p>Lip fullness was evaluated using live scoring against the validated MLFS,<sup><xref rid="R11" ref-type="bibr">11</xref></sup> ranging from 1 (very thin) to 5 (very full). The primary endpoint was change from baseline in MLFS score, assessed at Week 8 (separately for the upper and lower lip).</p></sec><sec id="s1-4-1-2"><title>Wrinkle Severity of Upper Perioral Rhytids/Oral Commissures</title><p>Wrinkle severity was evaluated using live scoring against the validated Wrinkle Assessment Scale,<sup><xref rid="R12" ref-type="bibr">12</xref></sup> ranging from 0 (no wrinkles) to 5 (very deep wrinkle/redundant fold).</p></sec><sec id="s1-4-1-3"><title>Independent Photographic Reviewer Assessment</title><p>A central independent photographic reviewer assessed improvement in lip fullness by comparison of random, blinded pairings of subjects' baseline and post-treatment photos (Weeks 8, 24, 40 and 48).</p></sec></sec><sec id="s1-4-2"><title>By Treating Investigator or Subjects</title><sec id="s1-4-2-1"><title>Aesthetic Improvement of Lips</title><p>Aesthetic improvement was evaluated using live scoring against the Global Aesthetic Improvement Scale, ranging from 3 (very much improved) to &#8722;3 (very much worse), by comparison to the subjects' baseline photo.</p></sec><sec id="s1-4-2-2"><title>Subject Satisfaction</title><p>Satisfaction with lips and appraisal of lip lines was evaluated using FACE-Q questionnaires.<sup><xref rid="R13" ref-type="bibr">13</xref></sup></p></sec></sec></sec><sec id="s1-5"><title>Safety Assessments</title><p>Safety assessments included adverse events, entries of predefined local tolerability symptoms in 30-day subject diaries, and lip assessments (palpation, texture, symmetry, movement, function, and sensation).</p></sec><sec id="s1-6"><title>Statistics</title><sec id="s1-6-1"><title>Sample Size</title><p>Approximately 280 subjects were to be included to ensure 234 evaluable subjects, with an overall power of 85% to test upper and lower lips separately using a noninferiority margin of 0.5% and 95% 2-sided confidence intervals (CIs).</p></sec><sec id="s1-6-2"><title>Analysis Populations</title><p>The safety population included all subjects who received HA<sub>RK</sub> or control, based on the as-treated principle. The intention-to-treat (ITT) population was used for all effectiveness analyses and included all randomized subjects who had a baseline upper and lower lip MLFS score &lt;5, based on the as-randomized principle. The per protocol population was used for the primary effectiveness analysis and included all subjects in the ITT population who completed the Week 8 visit without any deviations considered to substantially affect the primary effectiveness outcome.</p></sec><sec id="s1-6-3"><title>Analyses</title><p>Analyses were done using SAS version 9.4. Formal statistical testing was done at a significance level of 5% (2-sided). No correction for multiplicity was done. For the primary effectiveness analysis, noninferiority was only demonstrated if the CIs for both the upper and lower lip were entirely below the predetermined noninferiority margin of 0.5 in both the ITT and PP populations. Difference between treatments means (control&#8212;HA<sub>RK</sub>), and the corresponding 2-sided 95% CI, were calculated for both the upper and lower lip using the Student's <italic toggle="yes">t</italic>-statistic. Difference in injection volume between treatment groups was analyzed using a post-hoc 2-sample <italic toggle="yes">t</italic>-test. Other data were presented descriptively. For the primary endpoint, missing data were primarily handled using the hot deck imputation method. Missing values were not imputed for other effectiveness endpoints.</p></sec></sec></sec><sec sec-type="results" id="s2"><title>Results</title><sec id="s2-1"><title>Subject Disposition and Demographics</title><p>The first subject was enrolled November 13, 2017; the last subject completed the study April 23, 2019. Subject disposition is shown in <bold>Supplemental Digital Content 1</bold>, Figure, <ext-link xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" ext-link-type="uri" xlink:href="http://links.lww.com/DSS/A607">http://links.lww.com/DSS/A607</ext-link>; demographics are shown in <bold>Supplemental Digital Content 2</bold>, Table, <ext-link xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" ext-link-type="uri" xlink:href="http://links.lww.com/DSS/A608">http://links.lww.com/DSS/A608</ext-link>.</p></sec><sec id="s2-2"><title>Injection Details</title><p>In all treatment areas, the volume of HA<sub>RK</sub> injected was approximately 20% lower than control (Figure <xref ref-type="fig" rid="F1">1</xref>). The mean volume injected in lips was 1.82 mL (HA<sub>RK</sub>) and 2.24 mL (control); <italic toggle="yes">p</italic> &lt; .001. Overall, the mean total volume injected in all treatment areas was 2.65 mL (HA<sub>RK</sub>) and 3.33 mL (control); <italic toggle="yes">p</italic> &lt; .001.</p><fig id="F1" orientation="portrait" position="float"><label>Figure 1.</label><caption><p>Volume injected (baseline + touch-up; safety population). ***<italic toggle="yes">p</italic> &lt; .001.</p></caption><graphic xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" position="float" orientation="portrait" xlink:href="ds-47-527-g001.jpg"/></fig></sec><sec id="s2-3"><title>Effectiveness</title><sec id="s2-3-1"><title>Blinded Evaluator Assessments</title><sec id="s2-3-1-1"><title>Lip fullness</title><p>The primary objective was met. As CIs for both ITT and PP populations were below the predetermined noninferiority margin of 0.5 for both upper and lower lips, HA<sub>RK</sub> was noninferior to control in lip fullness augmentation at 8 weeks after last injection (Table <xref rid="T1" ref-type="table">1</xref>).</p><table-wrap id="T1" orientation="portrait" position="float"><label>TABLE 1.</label><caption><p>Change From Baseline in Lip Fullness<xref ref-type="table-fn" rid="tblfn1">*</xref> at 8 Weeks After Last Injection</p></caption><table frame="hsides" rules="groups"><thead><tr><td rowspan="1" colspan="1"/><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">HA<sub>RK</sub> (<italic toggle="yes">N</italic> = 183<xref ref-type="table-fn" rid="tblfn2">&#8224;</xref>/176<xref ref-type="table-fn" rid="tblfn3">&#8225;</xref>)</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Control (<italic toggle="yes">N</italic> = 87<xref ref-type="table-fn" rid="tblfn2">&#8224;</xref>/85<xref ref-type="table-fn" rid="tblfn3">&#8225;</xref>)</td></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Upper lip</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1"/><td rowspan="1" colspan="1"/></tr><tr><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">&#8195;Mean (SD)</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">1.8 (0.98)<xref ref-type="table-fn" rid="tblfn2">&#8224;</xref></td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">1.7 (0.90)<xref ref-type="table-fn" rid="tblfn2">&#8224;</xref></td></tr><tr><td rowspan="1" colspan="1"/><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">1.8 (0.96)<xref ref-type="table-fn" rid="tblfn3">&#8225;</xref></td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">1.7 (0.91)<xref ref-type="table-fn" rid="tblfn3">&#8225;</xref></td></tr><tr><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">&#8195;95% CI mean of (control&#8212;HA<sub>RK</sub>)</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1"><bold>(&#8722;0.31, 0.18)</bold><xref ref-type="table-fn" rid="tblfn2">&#8224;</xref></td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1"/></tr><tr><td rowspan="1" colspan="1"/><td rowspan="1" colspan="1"><bold>(&#8722;0.32, 0.17)</bold><xref ref-type="table-fn" rid="tblfn3">&#8225;</xref></td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1"/></tr><tr><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Lower lip</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1"/><td rowspan="1" colspan="1"/></tr><tr><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">&#8195;Mean (SD)</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">1.8 (0.98)<xref ref-type="table-fn" rid="tblfn2">&#8224;</xref></td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">1.8 (0.85)<xref ref-type="table-fn" rid="tblfn2">&#8224;</xref></td></tr><tr><td rowspan="1" colspan="1"/><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">1.8 (0.98)<xref ref-type="table-fn" rid="tblfn3">&#8225;</xref></td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">1.8 (0.86)<xref ref-type="table-fn" rid="tblfn3">&#8225;</xref></td></tr><tr><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">&#8195;95% CI mean of (control&#8212;HA<sub>RK</sub>)</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1"><bold>(&#8722;0.32, 0.16)</bold><xref ref-type="table-fn" rid="tblfn2">&#8224;</xref></td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1"/></tr><tr><td rowspan="1" colspan="1"/><td rowspan="1" colspan="1"><bold>(&#8722;0.30, 0.19)</bold><xref ref-type="table-fn" rid="tblfn3">&#8225;</xref></td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1"/></tr></tbody></table><table-wrap-foot><fn fn-type="other" id="tblfn1"><label>*</label><p>Blinded Evaluator live assessment of upper and lower lip MLFS score.</p></fn><fn fn-type="other" id="tblfn2"><label>&#8224;</label><p>ITT.</p></fn><fn fn-type="other" id="tblfn3"><label>&#8225;</label><p>PP.</p></fn><fn fn-type="other"><p>CI, confidence interval; ITT, intention-to-treat population; MLFS, medicis lip fullness scale; PP, per protocol population.</p></fn></table-wrap-foot></table-wrap><p>HA<sub>RK</sub> responder rates (&#8805;1-point improvement from baseline in MLFS score for both upper and lower lips) over time ranged between 88% (Week 8) and 60% (Week 48; Figure <xref ref-type="fig" rid="F2">2</xref>).</p><fig id="F2" orientation="portrait" position="float"><label>Figure 2.</label><caption><p>HA<sub>RK</sub> responder rates. Responder rates were defined as &#8805;1-point improvement from baseline. MLFS, Medicis lip fullness scale; N, number of analysed subjects.</p></caption><graphic xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" position="float" orientation="portrait" xlink:href="ds-47-527-g002.jpg"/></fig></sec><sec id="s2-3-1-2"><title>Wrinkle severity</title><p>HA<sub>RK</sub> responder rates (&#8805;1-point improvement from baseline in Wrinkle Assessment Scale score) for upper perioral rhytids ranged between 94% (Week 8) and 83% (Week 48; Figure <xref ref-type="fig" rid="F2">2</xref>).</p><p>HA<sub>RK</sub> responder rates (&#8805;1-point improvement from baseline in Wrinkle Assessment Scale score) for left and right oral commissures were 74% at Week 8% and 58% at Week 48 (Figure <xref ref-type="fig" rid="F2">2</xref>).</p></sec><sec id="s2-3-1-3"><title>Independent Photographic Reviewer assessment</title><p>According to the independent photographic reviewer, upper and lower lip fullness improved from baseline with HA<sub>RK</sub> treatment (See Figure, <bold>Supplemental Digital Content 3</bold>, <ext-link xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" ext-link-type="uri" xlink:href="http://links.lww.com/DSS/A609">http://links.lww.com/DSS/A609</ext-link>). At Week 8, &#8805;95% of subjects were improved. Lip fullness improvement remained high (&#8805;88%) at Week 48.</p></sec></sec><sec id="s2-3-2"><title>Treating Investigator or Subjects' Assessments</title><sec id="s2-3-2-1"><title>Aesthetic improvement of lips</title><p>Treating investigators and subjects assessed that HA<sub>RK</sub> responder rates ranged between 96% and 98% (Week 8) and 67% and 78% (Week 48; See Figure, <bold>Supplemental Digital Content 4</bold>, <ext-link xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" ext-link-type="uri" xlink:href="http://links.lww.com/DSS/A610">http://links.lww.com/DSS/A610</ext-link>).</p><p>Figure <xref ref-type="fig" rid="F3">3</xref> and Figure <xref ref-type="fig" rid="F4">4</xref> illustrate aesthetic improvement of lips after HA<sub>RK</sub> injection. For the subject in Figure <xref ref-type="fig" rid="F3">3</xref>, blinded evaluator-assigned MLFS scores for both lips were 1 (Baseline), 4 (Week 8), and 3 (Week 48). For the subject in Figure <xref ref-type="fig" rid="F4">4</xref>, blinded evaluator-assigned MLFS scores for upper/lower lips were 2/2 (Baseline), 4/3 (Week 8), and 3/3 (Week 48).</p><fig id="F3" orientation="portrait" position="float"><label>Figure 3.</label><caption><p>Subject photographs. Lip appearance of a 31-year-old woman at (A) baseline, and at (B) Week 8 and (C) Week 48 after injection of HA<sub>RK</sub> (total volume: 1.0 mL in upper lip; 1.5 mL in lower lip).</p></caption><graphic xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" position="float" orientation="portrait" xlink:href="ds-47-527-g003.jpg"/></fig><fig id="F4" orientation="portrait" position="float"><label>Figure 4.</label><caption><p>Subject photographs. Lip appearance of a 29-year old woman at (A) baseline, and at (B) Week 8 and (C) Week 48 after injection of HA<sub>RK</sub> (total volume: 0.85 mL in upper lip; 0.6 mL in lower lip).</p></caption><graphic xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" position="float" orientation="portrait" xlink:href="ds-47-527-g004.jpg"/></fig></sec><sec id="s2-3-2-2"><title>Subject satisfaction</title><p>The sum of the subjects' FACE-Q scores were converted to Rasch-transformed total scores according the FACE-Q manual; higher total scores indicated greater subject satisfaction.</p><p>After treatment with HA<sub>RK</sub>, subjects' satisfaction with their lips increased and subjects' appraisal of their lip lines indicated that the lines were less bothersome, as assessed by FACE-Q Rasch mean total scores, which peaked at Week 8 after treatment with HA<sub>RK</sub> and remained higher than the baseline score through Week 48.</p><p>Satisfaction with specific FACE-Q questionnaire items is shown in <bold>Supplemental Digital Content 5</bold>, Figure, <ext-link xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" ext-link-type="uri" xlink:href="http://links.lww.com/DSS/A611">http://links.lww.com/DSS/A611</ext-link> and <bold>Supplemental Digital Content 6</bold>, Figure, <ext-link xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" ext-link-type="uri" xlink:href="http://links.lww.com/DSS/A612">http://links.lww.com/DSS/A612</ext-link>.</p></sec></sec></sec><sec id="s2-4"><title>Safety</title><sec id="s2-4-1"><title>Adverse Events</title><p>No treatment-emergent adverse events (TEAEs) were reported for most subjects in either group (HA<sub>RK</sub>: 61%, control: 65%) throughout Week 48. Treatment-related TEAEs were predominantly mild (HA<sub>RK</sub>: 96%, control: 91%), none were severe, and most resolved spontaneously (median duration approx. 2 weeks).</p><p>The most commonly reported treatment-related TEAEs (occurring in &#8805;5% of subjects) were injection-site mass (HA<sub>RK</sub>: 10%; control: 11%), injection-site bruising (HA<sub>RK</sub>: 8%; control: 10%), and injection-site nodule (HA<sub>RK</sub>: 5%; control: 7%). All of the most commonly reported treatment-related TEAEs were mild, except one event of moderate injection-site bruising.</p><p>The reporting frequency of late-onset events (occurring &#8805;21 days after treatment) was similar between groups (HA<sub>RK</sub>: 5%; control: 6%). All late-onset events were mild (HA<sub>RK</sub>) or mild-to-moderate (control), and all resolved or were assessed as stable.</p></sec><sec id="s2-4-2"><title>Subject Diary Entries of Pre-defined Local Tolerability Symptoms</title><p>Events typically lasted &#8804;7 days; most (&#8805;67% in both groups) were rated as &#8220;tolerable.&#8221; The most commonly reported events in lips and oral commissures were tenderness, swelling and lumps/bumps. The most commonly reported events in upper perioral rhytids were tenderness and swelling, and for HA<sub>RK</sub> also redness.</p></sec><sec id="s2-4-3"><title>Lip Assessments</title><p>None of the lip assessments were remarkable or presented any safety concerns.</p></sec></sec></sec><sec sec-type="discussion" id="s3"><title>Discussion</title><p>This was the first study with HA<sub>RK</sub> conducted in the US. Subjects with all Fitzpatrick skin types were included, although most had light skin types. The primary objective was met; HA<sub>RK</sub> was noninferior to control in lip fullness augmentation at 8 weeks after last injection as assessed by blinded evaluation of change from baseline in MLFS score.</p><p>The total mean volume of HA<sub>RK</sub> used in this study was approximately 20% lower than control, and was significantly lower than control for lips and all treatment areas, which supports previous findings.<sup><xref rid="R6" ref-type="bibr">6</xref></sup> Effectiveness in terms of improvement of lip fullness, upper perioral rhytids, and oral commissures was maintained at Week 48 in most subjects injected with HA<sub>RK</sub> as assessed by a blinded evaluator. HA<sub>RK</sub> effectiveness was also corroborated by an independent photographic reviewer, who assessed that lip fullness improvement was maintained in most subjects at Week 48. Thus, at study end, most subjects still had a clinically relevant result that was visible in photographs. Treatment with HA<sub>RK</sub> was also associated with a high degree of aesthetic improvement and subject satisfaction, which is in line with previous findings for HA<sub>RK</sub>.<sup><xref rid="R6" ref-type="bibr">6</xref></sup></p><p>The postmarket safety experience collected during the first 5 years of commercial use of XPresHAn fillers (including HA<sub>RK</sub>) worldwide indicated that the frequency of potentially related AEs is low and stable, and did not identify any new, unexpected AEs compared with what has been reported for other HA filler products on the market.<sup><xref rid="R14" ref-type="bibr">14</xref></sup> In our study, HA<sub>RK</sub> was well-tolerated, with treatment-related TEAEs and subject diary entries of local tolerability reactions predominantly being mild and transient. Most commonly reported treatment-related TEAEs were injection-site reactions, which is in line with previous findings.<sup><xref rid="R6" ref-type="bibr">6</xref></sup> The reporting frequency of late-onset events was similar between treatment groups, and all such events were mild or moderate and resolved or were assessed as stable.</p><p>In summary, these data show that HA<sub>RK</sub> is well suited for lip fullness augmentation and correction of upper perioral rhytids.</p></sec><sec sec-type="conclusion" id="s4"><title>Conclusion</title><p>HA<sub>RK</sub> was noninferior to the control in lip fullness augmentation at 8 weeks after last injection. Also, HA<sub>RK</sub> was well-tolerated and achieved lip fullness improvement and correction of upper perioral rhytids that persisted in &#8805;60% of subjects at Week 48 after the last injection. HA<sub>RK</sub> effectiveness was supported by a high degree of aesthetic improvement and subject satisfaction.</p></sec></body><back><ack><title>Acknowledgments</title><p>The authors acknowledge the contributions of Drs. Kimberly Butterwick (Cosmetic Laser Dermatology, San Diego, CA), Lisa Grunebaum (University of Miami, Miami, FL), Michael S. Kaminer (SkinCare Physicians, Chestnut Hill, MA), Charles Boyd (BOYD, Birmingham, MI), Tiffani Hamilton (Hamilton Research, LLC, Alpharetta, GA), and Roy Geronemous (Laser and Skin Surgery Center, New York, NY), who served as Principal Investigators in the study.</p></ack><fn-group><fn fn-type="supplementary-material"><p>Supplemental digital content is available for this article. Direct URL citations appear in the printed text and are provided in the HTML and PDF versions of this article on the journal's Web site (<ext-link xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" ext-link-type="uri" xlink:href="http://www.dermatologicsurgery.org">www.dermatologicsurgery.org</ext-link>).</p></fn><fn fn-type="other"><p>Galderma R&amp;D, LLC funded the study described herein, provided materials and study products, are all consultants and investigators for Galderma B. Almeg&#229;rd, A. Nilsson and C. Edwartz are employed by Galderma Aesthetics.</p></fn></fn-group><ref-list><title>References</title><ref id="R1"><label>1.</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Beer</surname><given-names>K</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Glogau</surname><given-names>RG</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Dover</surname><given-names>JS</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Shamban</surname><given-names>A</given-names></name><etal/></person-group>. <article-title>A randomized, evaluator-blinded, controlled study of effectiveness and safety of small particle hyaluronic acid plus lidocaine for lip augmentation and perioral rhytides</article-title>. <source>Dermatol Surg</source><year>2015</year>;<volume>41</volume>(<issue>Suppl 1</issue>):<fpage>S127</fpage>&#8211;<lpage>36</lpage>.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">25828037</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1097/DSS.0000000000000199</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="R2"><label>2.</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Chiu</surname><given-names>A</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Fabi</surname><given-names>S</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Dayan</surname><given-names>S</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Nogueira</surname><given-names>A</given-names></name></person-group>. <article-title>Lip injection techniques using small-particle hyaluronic acid dermal filler</article-title>. <source>J Drugs Dermatol</source><year>2016</year>;<volume>15</volume>:<fpage>1076</fpage>&#8211;<lpage>82</lpage>.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">27602969</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="R3"><label>3.</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Chopra</surname><given-names>R</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Graivier</surname><given-names>M</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Fabi</surname><given-names>S</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Nestor</surname><given-names>M</given-names></name><etal/></person-group>. <article-title>A multi-center, open-label, prospective study of cannula injection of small-particle hyaluronic acid plus lidocaine (SPHAL) for lip augmentation</article-title>. <source>J Drugs Dermatol</source><year>2018</year>;<volume>17</volume>:<fpage>10</fpage>&#8211;<lpage>6</lpage>.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">29320583</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="R4"><label>4.</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Duranti</surname><given-names>F</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Salti</surname><given-names>G</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Bovani</surname><given-names>B</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Calandra</surname><given-names>M</given-names></name><etal/></person-group>. <article-title>Injectable hyaluronic acid gel for soft tissue augmentation. A clinical and histological study</article-title>. <source>Dermatol Surg</source><year>1998</year>;<volume>24</volume>:<fpage>1317</fpage>&#8211;<lpage>25</lpage>.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">9865196</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1111/j.1524-4725.1998.tb00007.x</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="R5"><label>5.</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Glogau</surname><given-names>RG</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Bank</surname><given-names>D</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Brandt</surname><given-names>F</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Cox</surname><given-names>SE</given-names></name><etal/></person-group>. <article-title>A randomized, evaluator-blinded, controlled study of the effectiveness and safety of small gel particle hyaluronic acid for lip augmentation</article-title>. <source>Dermatol Surg</source><year>2012</year>;<volume>38</volume>(<issue>Pt 2</issue>):<fpage>1180</fpage>&#8211;<lpage>92</lpage>.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">22759255</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1111/j.1524-4725.2012.02473.x</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="R6"><label>6.</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Hilton</surname><given-names>S</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Sattler</surname><given-names>G</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Berg</surname><given-names>AK</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Samuelson</surname><given-names>U</given-names></name><etal/></person-group>. <article-title>Randomized, evaluator-blinded study comparing safety and effect of two hyaluronic acid gels for lips enhancement</article-title>. <source>Dermatol Surg</source><year>2018</year>;<volume>44</volume>:<fpage>261</fpage>&#8211;<lpage>9</lpage>.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">29059146</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1097/DSS.0000000000001282</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC5821480</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="R7"><label>7.</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Solish</surname><given-names>N</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Swift</surname><given-names>A</given-names></name></person-group>. <article-title>An open-label, pilot study to assess the effectiveness and safety of hyaluronic acid gel in the restoration of soft tissue fullness of the lips</article-title>. <source>J Drugs Dermatol</source><year>2011</year>;<volume>10</volume>:<fpage>145</fpage>&#8211;<lpage>9</lpage>.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">21283918</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="R8"><label>8.</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Cartier</surname><given-names>H</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Trevidic</surname><given-names>P</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Rzany</surname><given-names>B</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Sattler</surname><given-names>G</given-names></name><etal/></person-group>. <article-title>Perioral rejuvenation with a range of customized hyaluronic acid fillers: efficacy and safety over six months with a specific focus on the lips</article-title>. <source>J Drugs Dermatol</source><year>2012</year>;<volume>11</volume>(<issue>Suppl 1</issue>):<fpage>s17</fpage>&#8211;<lpage>26</lpage>.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">22497040</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="R9"><label>9.</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Farhi</surname><given-names>D</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Trevidic</surname><given-names>P</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Kestemont</surname><given-names>P</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Boineau</surname><given-names>D</given-names></name><etal/></person-group>. <article-title>The emervel french survey: a prospective real-practice descriptive study of 1,822 patients treated for facial rejuvenation with a new hyaluronic acid filler</article-title>. <source>J Drugs Dermatol</source><year>2013</year>;<volume>12</volume>:<fpage>e88</fpage>&#8211;<lpage>93</lpage>.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">23652965</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="R10"><label>10.</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Rzany</surname><given-names>B</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Cartier</surname><given-names>H</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Kestemont</surname><given-names>P</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Trevidic</surname><given-names>P</given-names></name><etal/></person-group>. <article-title>Full-face rejuvenation using a range of hyaluronic acid fillers: efficacy, safety, and patient satisfaction over 6 months</article-title>. <source>Dermatol Surg</source><year>2012</year>;<volume>38</volume>(<issue>Pt 2</issue>):<fpage>1153</fpage>&#8211;<lpage>61</lpage>.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">22759252</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1111/j.1524-4725.2012.02470.x</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="R11"><label>11.</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Kane</surname><given-names>MA</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Lorenc</surname><given-names>ZP</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Lin</surname><given-names>X</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Smith</surname><given-names>SR</given-names></name></person-group>. <article-title>Validation of a lip fullness scale for assessment of lip augmentation</article-title>. <source>Plast Reconstr Surg</source><year>2012</year>;<volume>129</volume>:<fpage>822e</fpage>&#8211;<lpage>28e</lpage>.<pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1097/PRS.0b013e31824a2df0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">22544112</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="R12"><label>12.</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Lemperle</surname><given-names>G</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Holmes</surname><given-names>RE</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Cohen</surname><given-names>SR</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Lemperle</surname><given-names>SM</given-names></name></person-group>. <article-title>A classification of facial wrinkles</article-title>. <source>Plast Reconstr Surg</source><year>2001</year>;<volume>108</volume>:<fpage>1735</fpage>&#8211;<lpage>50</lpage>.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">11711957</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1097/00006534-200111000-00048</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="R13"><label>13.</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Klassen</surname><given-names>AF</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Cano</surname><given-names>SJ</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Schwitzer</surname><given-names>JA</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Baker</surname><given-names>SB</given-names></name><etal/></person-group>. <article-title>Development and psychometric validation of the FACE-Q skin, lips, and facial rhytids appearance scales and adverse effects checklists for cosmetic procedures</article-title>. <source>JAMA Dermatol</source><year>2016</year>;<volume>152</volume>:<fpage>443</fpage>&#8211;<lpage>51</lpage>.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">26934294</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1001/jamadermatol.2016.0018</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC4833666</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="R14"><label>14.</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Jones</surname><given-names>DH</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Bank</surname><given-names>D</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Jacobsson</surname><given-names>J</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Koltowska-Haggstrom</surname><given-names>M</given-names></name><etal/></person-group>. <article-title>Five-year postmarket safety experience with the optimal balance technology range of hyaluronic acid fillers</article-title>. <source>Dermatol Surg</source><year>2020</year>;<volume>46</volume>:<fpage>145</fpage>&#8211;<lpage>7</lpage>.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">30789520</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1097/DSS.0000000000001836</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref></ref-list></back></article></pmc-articleset>