<?xml version="1.0"  ?><!DOCTYPE pmc-articleset PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD ARTICLE SET 2.0//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pmc/articleset/nlm-articleset-2.0.dtd"><pmc-articleset><article xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" xmlns:ali="http://www.niso.org/schemas/ali/1.0/" article-type="case-report" xml:lang="en" dtd-version="1.4"><processing-meta base-tagset="archiving" mathml-version="3.0" table-model="xhtml" tagset-family="jats"><restricted-by>pmc</restricted-by></processing-meta><front><journal-meta><journal-id journal-id-type="nlm-ta">JAAD Case Rep</journal-id><journal-id journal-id-type="iso-abbrev">JAAD Case Rep</journal-id><journal-id journal-id-type="pmc-domain-id">2969</journal-id><journal-id journal-id-type="pmc-domain">jaadcr</journal-id><journal-title-group><journal-title>JAAD Case Reports</journal-title></journal-title-group><issn pub-type="epub">2352-5126</issn><publisher><publisher-name>Elsevier</publisher-name></publisher></journal-meta><article-meta><article-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC9039873</article-id><article-id pub-id-type="pmcid-ver">PMC9039873.1</article-id><article-id pub-id-type="pmcaid">9039873</article-id><article-id pub-id-type="pmcaiid">9039873</article-id><article-id pub-id-type="pmid">35495971</article-id><article-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1016/j.jdcr.2022.03.024</article-id><article-id pub-id-type="pii">S2352-5126(22)00161-8</article-id><article-version article-version-type="pmc-version">1</article-version><article-categories><subj-group subj-group-type="heading"><subject>Case Report</subject></subj-group></article-categories><title-group><article-title>Extensive facial scarring after ablative laser resurfacing in a patient with frontal fibrosing alopecia</article-title></title-group><contrib-group><contrib contrib-type="author" id="au1"><name name-style="western"><surname>Sun</surname><given-names initials="C">Cong</given-names></name><degrees>BSc, MD, MMed</degrees><email>tom.cong.sun@gmail.com</email><xref rid="aff1" ref-type="aff">a</xref><xref rid="cor1" ref-type="corresp">&#8727;</xref></contrib><contrib contrib-type="author" id="au2"><name name-style="western"><surname>Lim</surname><given-names initials="D">Davin</given-names></name><degrees>BSc, MBBS</degrees><xref rid="aff1" ref-type="aff">a</xref></contrib><contrib contrib-type="author" id="au3"><name name-style="western"><surname>Bekhor</surname><given-names initials="P">Philip</given-names></name><degrees>MBBS</degrees><xref rid="aff2" ref-type="aff">b</xref></contrib><aff id="aff1"><label>a</label>Princess Alexandra Hospital, Brisbane, Queensland, Australia</aff><aff id="aff2"><label>b</label>Cutis Clinic, Brisbane, Queensland, Australia</aff></contrib-group><author-notes><corresp id="cor1"><label>&#8727;</label>Correspondence to: Cong Sun, BSc, MD, MMed, 199 Ipswich Rd, Woolloongabba, Queensland, Australia 4102. <email>tom.cong.sun@gmail.com</email></corresp></author-notes><pub-date pub-type="collection"><month>5</month><year>2022</year></pub-date><pub-date pub-type="epub"><day>26</day><month>3</month><year>2022</year></pub-date><volume>23</volume><issue-id pub-id-type="pmc-issue-id">404651</issue-id><fpage>123</fpage><lpage>127</lpage><pub-history><event event-type="pmc-release"><date><day>26</day><month>03</month><year>2022</year></date></event><event event-type="pmc-live"><date><day>27</day><month>04</month><year>2022</year></date></event><event event-type="pmc-last-change"><date iso-8601-date="2022-06-10 05:16:41.777"><day>10</day><month>06</month><year>2022</year></date></event></pub-history><permissions><copyright-statement>&#169; 2022 by the American Academy of Dermatology, Inc. Published by Elsevier, Inc.</copyright-statement><copyright-year>2022</copyright-year><copyright-holder>American Academy of Dermatology, Inc.</copyright-holder><license><ali:license_ref specific-use="textmining" content-type="ccbylicense">https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</ali:license_ref><license-p>This is an open access article under the CC BY license (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/).</license-p></license></permissions><self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" content-type="pmc-pdf" xlink:href="main.pdf"/><kwd-group id="kwrds0010"><title>Key words</title><kwd>alopecia</kwd><kwd>cosmetics</kwd><kwd>laser</kwd></kwd-group><kwd-group id="kwrds0015"><title>Abbreviation used</title><kwd>FFA, frontal fibrosing alopecia</kwd></kwd-group><custom-meta-group><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-status-qastatus</meta-name><meta-value>0</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-status-live</meta-name><meta-value>yes</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-status-embargo</meta-name><meta-value>no</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-status-released</meta-name><meta-value>yes</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-open-access</meta-name><meta-value>yes</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-olf</meta-name><meta-value>no</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-manuscript</meta-name><meta-value>no</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-legally-suppressed</meta-name><meta-value>no</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-has-pdf</meta-name><meta-value>yes</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-has-supplement</meta-name><meta-value>no</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-pdf-only</meta-name><meta-value>no</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-suppress-copyright</meta-name><meta-value>no</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-is-real-version</meta-name><meta-value>no</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-is-scanned-article</meta-name><meta-value>no</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-preprint</meta-name><meta-value>no</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-in-epmc</meta-name><meta-value>yes</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-license-ref</meta-name><meta-value>CC BY</meta-value></custom-meta></custom-meta-group></article-meta></front><body><sec id="sec1"><title>Introduction</title><p id="p0010">Frontal fibrosing alopecia (FFA) is a primary cicatricial alopecia with an unknown incidence in the general population. A single-center study in New York estimated the rate of FFA to be 5.41 in 100,000.<xref rid="bib1" ref-type="bibr"><sup>1</sup></xref> It is a clinical subvariant of lichen planopilaris, which is the cause of 1.25% of all alopecia and up to 25% of cases of scarring alopecia.<xref rid="bib2" ref-type="bibr"><sup>2</sup></xref> The fractional erbium laser is among the most frequently used resources in dermatology for facial rejuvenation.<xref rid="bib3" ref-type="bibr"><sup>3</sup></xref> Laser resurfacing is regarded as a useful modality of&#160;treatment for acen scarring with a low risk for serious complications.<xref rid="bib3" ref-type="bibr"><sup>3</sup></xref><sup>,</sup><xref rid="bib4" ref-type="bibr"><sup>4</sup></xref> We hereby present a case of extensive scarring after ablative laser resurfacing in a patient with undiagnosed FFA. This article aims to illustrate the likely mechanism of extensive scarring after ablative laser resurfacing in patients with FFA and thereby convey the importance of recognizing this condition in the daily practice of laser dermatology.</p></sec><sec id="sec2"><title>Clinical record</title><p id="p0015">A 63-year-old woman presented with pigmentation and rhytides (<xref rid="fig1" ref-type="fig">Fig 1</xref>). The patient was otherwise&#160;medically unremarkable, with no previous history of viral or bacterial cutaneous infections or isotretinoin use, which are potential predisposing factors for postprocedural scarring and infection. Conservative fully ablative laser resurfacing was conducted for pigmentation and rhytides uneventfully, with an erbium 2940-nm laser with the following settings: 100-micron pass followed by 50-micron pass to the cheeks, single 80-micron pass to the eyelids, and 100-micron pass followed by 60-micron pass to the perioral area.<fig id="fig1" position="float" orientation="portrait"><label>Fig 1</label><caption><p><italic toggle="yes">Top left and right:</italic> appreciable hyperpigmentation and rhytides; <italic toggle="yes">Bottom Left:</italic> day 2 post resurfacing procedure; <italic toggle="yes">Bottom Right</italic>: day 7 post treatment with complete re-</p></caption><graphic xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" position="float" orientation="portrait" xlink:href="gr1.jpg"/></fig></p><p id="p0020">The aftercare routine consisted of 7&#160;days of topical white soft paraffin and Cetaphil cleanser along with dressing and wound checks every 48&#160;hours. On day 6, areas of erosion developed on the superior forehead, bilateral infraorbital areas, and superior lip and were extensively swabbed for bacteria and viruses, the results of which were all negative. Complete re-epithelialization was achieved by day 12, with residual erythema settling in the next 5&#160;weeks (<xref rid="fig1" ref-type="fig">Fig 1</xref>).</p><p id="p0025">Extensive global scarring over the treatment fields was noted at 7&#160;weeks, with the most extensive involvement in the forehead and perioral area. Scar revision protocols were commenced, involving 3 weekly nonablative low-density CO<sub>2</sub> laser (60-mj 3%&#160;density; 1 pass) treatments followed by topical triamcinolone suspension (40&#160;mg/mL) under 3-hour occlusion. Methylprednisolone aceponate ointment was prescribed for pulse regimen twice daily for 3 consecutive days with 4 rest days. Silicone gel was applied to the perioral area for the thickest scars 3 times a day.</p><p id="p0030">Sixteen weeks after the initial resurfacing procedure, the complete resolution of scarring was achieved (<xref rid="fig2" ref-type="fig">Fig 2</xref>), with no recurrence at the 12-month follow-up. It was at this appointment that the clinical features of FFA (<xref rid="fig3" ref-type="fig">Fig 3</xref>)&#8212;namely, the loss of bilateral eyebrow, frontal band-like recession of hairline, and complete loss of facial vellus hair&#8212;were noted by the treating dermatologist, who performed resurfacing and scar revision. Biopsies of the preauricular area showed the complete absence of hair follicles and adnexal structure, consistent with end-stage scarring alopecia (<xref rid="fig4" ref-type="fig">Fig 4</xref>).<fig id="fig2" position="float" orientation="portrait"><label>Fig 2</label><caption><p>Extensive hypertrophic scarring of the forehead and perioral area at 7 weeks check-up post initial resurfacing procedure in the treatment field.</p></caption><graphic xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" position="float" orientation="portrait" xlink:href="gr2.jpg"/></fig><fig id="fig3" position="float" orientation="portrait"><label>Fig 3</label><caption><p><italic toggle="yes">Top</italic><italic toggle="yes">l</italic><italic toggle="yes">eft and</italic><italic toggle="yes">r</italic><italic toggle="yes">ight:</italic> complete resolution of hypertrophic scarring with the regimen of low density carbon dioxide laser, topical triamcinolone under occlusion, and topical silicone gel. <italic toggle="yes">Bottom:</italic> bilateral loss of eyebrow hair and loss of facial vellus hair.</p></caption><graphic xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" position="float" orientation="portrait" xlink:href="gr3.jpg"/></fig><fig id="fig4" position="float" orientation="portrait"><label>Fig 4</label><caption><p><italic toggle="yes">Top left and right</italic>: horizontal sections of 4mm punch biopsy from left preauricular superior. <italic toggle="yes">Bottom</italic>: vertical sections of 4 mm punch biopsy from right preauricular inferior. Both specimens show complete absence of hair follicle, eccrine and sebaceous glands with mild perivascular lymphocytic infiltrate consistent with end-stage scarring alopecia.</p></caption><graphic xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" position="float" orientation="portrait" xlink:href="gr4.jpg"/></fig></p></sec><sec id="sec3"><title>Discussion</title><p id="p0035">FFA is a challenging entity, with a marked increase in incidence in the past years.<xref rid="bib5" ref-type="bibr"><sup>5</sup></xref><sup>,</sup><xref rid="bib6" ref-type="bibr"><sup>6</sup></xref> Epidemiologically, postmenopausal women constitute the majority of patients with FFA. FFA is often asymptomatic but may present with pruritus and, less frequently, trichodynia. The clinical features of FFA consist of band-like scarring alopecia of the frontal hairline, the loss of eyebrows, perifollicular hyperkeratosis, and erythema as well as the loss of facial vellus hair.<xref rid="bib5" ref-type="bibr">5</xref>, <xref rid="bib6" ref-type="bibr">6</xref>, <xref rid="bib7" ref-type="bibr">7</xref> One of the most frequent findings in FFA is eyebrow loss, which has been reported in up to 95% of the cases.<xref rid="bib8" ref-type="bibr"><sup>8</sup></xref> The histology of FFA is identical to that of lichen planopilarus, with a perifollicular lymphohistiocytic inflammatory reaction with progressive follicular fibrosis and the irreversible destruction of stem cells in the bulge area.<xref rid="bib2" ref-type="bibr"><sup>2</sup></xref></p><p id="p0040">The pathogenesis of FFA remains complex and not fully understood.<xref rid="bib8" ref-type="bibr"><sup>8</sup></xref> Currently, the immune-mediated inflammatory mechanism provides the most convincing level of evidence.<xref rid="bib5" ref-type="bibr"><sup>5</sup></xref><sup>,</sup><xref rid="bib8" ref-type="bibr"><sup>8</sup></xref> The immune-mediated mechanisms involve T cell&#8211;mediated attacks and, subsequently, the loss of follicular stem cells. This leads to permanent fibrosis through the inability of hair to regenerate and the epithelial-mesenchymal transition of the follicular stem cell, leading to a fibrotic phenotype. The immune-mediated reaction affects the hair of growth cycle, leading to the loss of vellus, intermediate, and terminal hair. Genetic, hormonal, and environmental factors have also been implicated in the pathogenesis of FFA.<xref rid="bib8" ref-type="bibr"><sup>8</sup></xref></p><p id="p0045">Ablative laser therapy achieves its effect through the ablation of the full-thickness dermis and the subsequent re-epithelialization.<xref rid="bib3" ref-type="bibr"><sup>3</sup></xref> Ablative lasers in skin rejuvenation therapy are well established treatment modalities.<xref rid="bib3" ref-type="bibr"><sup>3</sup></xref><sup>,</sup><xref rid="bib4" ref-type="bibr"><sup>4</sup></xref> Postprocedural erythema and edema are the most common complications from ablative laser therapy, followed by pain and peeling.<xref rid="bib3" ref-type="bibr"><sup>3</sup></xref> Hypertrophic scarring can occur as a rare complication, with limited cases reported in the literature.<xref rid="bib4" ref-type="bibr"><sup>4</sup></xref> The likelihood that this patient experienced iatrogenic scarring secondary to the laser is low, as the settings were conservative and the patient did not experience postprocedural complications that would increase the risk of scarring, such as infection. Additionally, the patient was compliant with postprocedure care and follow-ups.</p><p id="p0050">The pathogenesis of FFA and the biology of re-epithelialization in wound healing offers a potential explanation for the extensive facial scarring after ablative laser therapy. The re-epithelialization process requires new cells to replace the lost keratinocytes from the initial injury; lineage tracing studies on both human and animal skins have demonstrated the role of hair follicle stem cells in optimal wound healing.<xref rid="bib9" ref-type="bibr"><sup>9</sup></xref><sup>,</sup><xref rid="bib10" ref-type="bibr"><sup>10</sup></xref> Bulge follicular stem cells are activated upon full-thickness wounding and produce progeny in the interfollicular epidermis for re-epithelialization.<xref rid="bib3" ref-type="bibr"><sup>3</sup></xref> FFA results in the loss or malfunction of the follicular stem cell through a progressive immune reaction and fibrosis. The loss of facial vellus hair observed in this patient, along with the classical features of FFA, suggests the involvement of the facial follicles in the disease process. As the epidermis is ablated by an erbium laser, the optimal re-epithelialization process, which involves the migration and proliferation of follicular stem cells, is impaired due to the lack of pilosebaceous units as a result of the progressive immunological attack and fibrosis of the follicles. The lack of sufficient follicular stem cells leads to extensive scarring. The use of a nonablative laser involves a nonwounding process that creates zones of thermal injury without the obliteration of epidermal or dermal structures. This creates an inflammatory response, leading to increases in matrix metalloproteinase, collagen I, collagen III, and procollagen I, which promote tissue remodeling.<xref rid="bib11" ref-type="bibr"><sup>11</sup></xref> This may explain the excellent response that this patient had with scar revision using a nonablative CO<sub>2</sub> laser, as the healing process did not require follicular stem cells.</p></sec><sec id="sec4"><title>Summary</title><p id="p0055">FFA is a condition of scarring hair loss, with an increasing incidence being reported in the current literature. It is often a clinical diagnosis and has several distinct clinical features to guide the clinician toward a diagnosis. Laser procedures are increasingly common, with evidence-based efficacy and safety. In this article, we have presented the first known case, to our knowledge, of extensive facial scarring in a patient with undiagnosed FFA after an ablative erbium laser resurfacing procedure. We hope to illustrate the importance of recognizing FFA, or scarring alopecia in general, in patients presenting for laser therapy and avoiding ablative procedures to avoid potentially serious complications that may lead to potentially serious scarring.</p></sec><sec sec-type="COI-statement"><title>Conflicts of interest</title><p id="p0065">None disclosed.</p></sec></body><back><ref-list id="cebib0010"><title>References</title><ref id="bib1"><label>1</label><element-citation publication-type="journal" id="sref1"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Lavian</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Trager</surname><given-names>M.H.</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Lee</surname><given-names>E.Y.</given-names></name><etal/></person-group><article-title>Incidence estimates for lichen planopilaris and frontal fibrosing alopecia in a New York City health care system</article-title><source>Dermatol Online J</source><volume>27</volume><issue>8</issue><year>2021</year><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.5070/d327854687</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">34755956</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="bib2"><label>2</label><element-citation publication-type="journal" id="sref2"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Meinhard</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Stroux</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>L&#252;nnemann</surname><given-names>L.</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Vogt</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Blume-Peytavi</surname><given-names>U.</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>Lichen planopilaris: epidemiology and prevalence of subtypes - a retrospective analysis in 104 patients</article-title><source>J Dtsch Dermatol Ges</source><volume>12</volume><issue>3</issue><year>2014</year><fpage>229</fpage><lpage>235</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1111/ddg.12264</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">24533855</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="bib3"><label>3</label><element-citation publication-type="journal" id="sref3"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Modena</surname><given-names>D.A.O.</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Miranda</surname><given-names>A.C.G.</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Grecco</surname><given-names>C.</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Liebano</surname><given-names>R.E.</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Cordeiro</surname><given-names>R.C.T.</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Guidi</surname><given-names>R.M.</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>Efficacy, safety, and guidelines of application of the fractional ablative laser erbium YAG 2940 nm and non-ablative laser erbium glass in rejuvenation, skin spots, and acne in different skin phototypes: a systematic review</article-title><source>Lasers Med Sci</source><volume>35</volume><issue>9</issue><year>2020</year><fpage>1877</fpage><lpage>1888</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1007/s10103-020-03046-7</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">32472427</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="bib4"><label>4</label><element-citation publication-type="journal" id="sref4"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Metelitsa</surname><given-names>A.I.</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Alster</surname><given-names>T.S.</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>Fractionated laser skin resurfacing treatment complications: a review</article-title><source>Dermatol Surg</source><volume>36</volume><issue>3</issue><year>2010</year><fpage>299</fpage><lpage>306</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">20100273</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1111/j.1524-4725.2009.01434.x</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="bib5"><label>5</label><element-citation publication-type="journal" id="sref5"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Tavakolpour</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Mahmoudi</surname><given-names>H.</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Abedini</surname><given-names>R.</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Kamyab Hesari</surname><given-names>K.</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Kiani</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Daneshpazhooh</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>Frontal fibrosing alopecia: an update on the hypothesis of pathogenesis and treatment</article-title><source>Int J Womens Dermatol</source><volume>5</volume><issue>2</issue><year>2019</year><fpage>116</fpage><lpage>123</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1111/j.1524-4725.2009.01434.x</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">30997385</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC6451751</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="bib6"><label>6</label><element-citation publication-type="journal" id="sref6"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Va&#241;&#243;-Galv&#225;n</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Molina-Ruiz</surname><given-names>A.M.</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Serrano-Falc&#243;n</surname><given-names>C.</given-names></name><etal/></person-group><article-title>Frontal fibrosing alopecia: a multicenter review of 355 patients</article-title><source>J Am Acad Dermatol</source><volume>70</volume><issue>4</issue><year>2014</year><fpage>670</fpage><lpage>678</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1016/j.jaad.2014.01.376</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">24508293</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="bib7"><label>7</label><element-citation publication-type="journal" id="sref7"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Kanti</surname><given-names>V.</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Constantinou</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Reygagne</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Vogt</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Kottner</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Blume-Peytavi</surname><given-names>U.</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>Frontal fibrosing alopecia: demographic and clinical characteristics of 490 cases</article-title><source>J Eur Acad Dermatol Venereol</source><volume>33</volume><issue>10</issue><year>2019</year><fpage>1976</fpage><lpage>1983</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1111/jdv.15735</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">31179579</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="bib8"><label>8</label><element-citation publication-type="journal" id="sref8"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Photiou</surname><given-names>L.</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Nixon</surname><given-names>R.L.</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Tam</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Green</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Yip</surname><given-names>L.</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>An update of the pathogenesis of frontal fibrosing alopecia: what does the current evidence tell us?</article-title><source>Australas J Dermatol</source><volume>60</volume><issue>2</issue><year>2019</year><fpage>99</fpage><lpage>104</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1111/ajd.12945</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">30362109</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="bib9"><label>9</label><element-citation publication-type="journal" id="sref9"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Plikus</surname><given-names>M.V.</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Gay</surname><given-names>D.L.</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Treffeisen</surname><given-names>E.</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Wang</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Supapannachart</surname><given-names>R.J.</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Cotsarelis</surname><given-names>G.</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>Epithelial stem cells and implications for wound repair</article-title><source>Semin Cell Dev Biol</source><volume>23</volume><issue>9</issue><year>2012</year><fpage>946</fpage><lpage>953</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1016/j.semcdb.2012.10.001</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">23085626</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC3518754</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="bib10"><label>10</label><element-citation publication-type="journal" id="sref10"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Ritti&#233;</surname><given-names>L.</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>Cellular mechanisms of skin repair in humans and other mammals</article-title><source>J Cell Commun Signal</source><volume>10</volume><issue>2</issue><year>2016</year><fpage>103</fpage><lpage>120</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1007/s12079-016-0330-1</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">27170326</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC4882309</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="bib11"><label>11</label><element-citation publication-type="journal" id="sref11"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Orringer</surname><given-names>J.S.</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Ritti&#233;</surname><given-names>L.</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Baker</surname><given-names>D.</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Voorhees</surname><given-names>J.J.</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Fisher</surname><given-names>G.</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>Molecular mechanisms of nonablative fractionated laser resurfacing</article-title><source>Br J Dermatol</source><volume>163</volume><issue>4</issue><year>2010</year><fpage>757</fpage><lpage>768</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1111/j.1365-2133.2010.09998.x</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">20854401</pub-id></element-citation></ref></ref-list><fn-group><fn id="d35e69"><p id="ntpara0010">Funding sources: None.</p></fn></fn-group></back></article></pmc-articleset>