<?xml version="1.0"  ?><!DOCTYPE pmc-articleset PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD ARTICLE SET 2.0//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pmc/articleset/nlm-articleset-2.0.dtd"><pmc-articleset><article xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" xmlns:ali="http://www.niso.org/schemas/ali/1.0/" xml:lang="en" article-type="research-article" dtd-version="1.4"><processing-meta base-tagset="archiving" mathml-version="3.0" table-model="xhtml" tagset-family="jats"><restricted-by>pmc</restricted-by></processing-meta><front><journal-meta><journal-id journal-id-type="nlm-ta">Plast Reconstr Surg Glob Open</journal-id><journal-id journal-id-type="iso-abbrev">Plast Reconstr Surg Glob Open</journal-id><journal-id journal-id-type="pmc-domain-id">2522</journal-id><journal-id journal-id-type="pmc-domain">prsgo</journal-id><journal-id journal-id-type="publisher-id">GOX</journal-id><journal-title-group><journal-title>Plastic and Reconstructive Surgery Global Open</journal-title></journal-title-group><issn pub-type="epub">2169-7574</issn><publisher><publisher-name>Wolters Kluwer Health</publisher-name></publisher></journal-meta><article-meta><article-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC9988291</article-id><article-id pub-id-type="pmcid-ver">PMC9988291.1</article-id><article-id pub-id-type="pmcaid">9988291</article-id><article-id pub-id-type="pmcaiid">9988291</article-id><article-id pub-id-type="pmid">36891570</article-id><article-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1097/GOX.0000000000004838</article-id><article-version-alternatives><article-version article-version-type="pmc-version">1</article-version><article-version vocab="JAV" vocab-identifier="http://www.niso.org/publications/rp/RP-8-2008.pdf" article-version-type="Version of Record">3</article-version></article-version-alternatives><article-categories><subj-group subj-group-type="heading"><subject>Cosmetic</subject></subj-group><subj-group subj-group-type="heading"><subject>Original Article</subject></subj-group></article-categories><title-group><article-title>Algorithmic Approach to Management of Complications of Permanent Facial Filler: A Saudi Experience</article-title></title-group><contrib-group><contrib contrib-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Alarfaj</surname><given-names initials="S">Seham</given-names></name><degrees>MD</degrees><xref rid="aff1" ref-type="aff">1</xref></contrib><contrib contrib-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Zino Alarki</surname><given-names initials="SMK">Subhi M.K.</given-names></name><degrees>MD</degrees><xref rid="aff1" ref-type="aff">1</xref></contrib><contrib contrib-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Habib</surname><given-names initials="O">Ovais</given-names></name><degrees>MD, MS, Mch</degrees><xref rid="aff1" ref-type="aff">1</xref></contrib><contrib contrib-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Wani</surname><given-names initials="SA">Shabeer Ahmad</given-names></name><degrees>MD, MS, Mch, MRCS</degrees><xref rid="aff1" ref-type="aff">1</xref></contrib><contrib contrib-type="author" corresp="yes"><name name-style="western"><surname>AlSalmi</surname><given-names initials="LA">Loai Abdullah</given-names></name><degrees>MD, FRCSC</degrees><xref rid="aff1" ref-type="aff">1</xref></contrib><aff id="aff1">From the Division of Plastic and Reconstructive Surgery, Department of Surgical Specialties, King Fahad Medical City, Riyadh, Saudi Arabia.</aff></contrib-group><author-notes><corresp id="c1">Loai Abdullah AlSalmi, MD, FRCSC, Plastic and Reconstructive Surgery, King Fahad Medical City, Riyadh, Saudi Arabia, E-mail: <email xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xlink:href="luay1977@gmail.com">luay1977@gmail.com</email>; <email xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xlink:href="dralsalmiresearch@gmail.com">dralsalmiresearch@gmail.com</email></corresp></author-notes><pub-date pub-type="collection"><month>3</month><year>2023</year></pub-date><pub-date pub-type="epub"><day>06</day><month>3</month><year>2023</year></pub-date><volume>11</volume><issue>3</issue><issue-id pub-id-type="pmc-issue-id">430411</issue-id><elocation-id>e4838</elocation-id><history><date date-type="received"><day>29</day><month>8</month><year>2022</year></date><date date-type="accepted"><day>4</day><month>1</month><year>2023</year></date></history><pub-history><event event-type="pmc-release"><date><day>06</day><month>03</month><year>2023</year></date></event><event event-type="pmc-live"><date><day>07</day><month>03</month><year>2023</year></date></event><event event-type="pmc-last-change"><date iso-8601-date="2023-03-09 12:10:11.487"><day>09</day><month>03</month><year>2023</year></date></event></pub-history><permissions><copyright-statement>Copyright &#169; 2023 The Authors. Published by Wolters Kluwer Health, Inc. on behalf of The American Society of Plastic Surgeons.</copyright-statement><copyright-year>2023</copyright-year><license><ali:license_ref specific-use="textmining" content-type="ccbyncndlicense">https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/4.0/</ali:license_ref><license-p>This is an open-access article distributed under the terms of the <ext-link xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" ext-link-type="uri" xlink:href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/4.0/">Creative Commons Attribution-Non Commercial-No Derivatives License 4.0 (CCBY-NC-ND)</ext-link>, where it is permissible to download and share the work provided it is properly cited. The work cannot be changed in any way or used commercially without permission from the journal.</license-p></license></permissions><self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" content-type="pmc-pdf" xlink:href="gox-11-e4838.pdf"/><self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xlink:href="gox-11-e4838.pdf"/><abstract><title>Background:</title><p>Facial filler is the most common type of cosmetic surgery next to Botox. Permanent filler is preferred nowadays due to low cost brought about by nonrecurring injection appointments. However, such fillers pose a higher risk for complications, with even greater adverse effects when the procedure is done using unknown dermal filler injections. This study aimed to establish an algorithm to categorize and manage patients that receive permanent fillers.</p><sec><title>Methods:</title><p>Twelve participants were presented to the service through emergency or as outpatient from November 2015 to May 2021. Demographic characteristics such as age, sex, date of injection, time of onset, and types of complications were collected. After examination, all cases were managed based on an algorithm established. FACE-Q was used to measure overall satisfaction and psychological well-being.</p></sec><sec><title>Results:</title><p>An algorithm to diagnose and manage these patients effectively with high satisfaction rate was established in this study. All participants were non-smoking women, with no known medical comorbidities. The algorithm determined the treatment plan when faced with complications. Results revealed high appearance-related psychosocial distress before surgery, which significantly dropped after surgery. FACE-Q was able to establish evidence of satisfactory rating among patients before and after surgery.</p></sec><sec><title>Conclusion:</title><p>This treatment algorithm can guide the surgeon in formulating a suitable plan with less complications and high satisfaction rate.</p></sec></abstract><custom-meta-group><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-status-qastatus</meta-name><meta-value>0</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-status-live</meta-name><meta-value>yes</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-status-embargo</meta-name><meta-value>no</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-status-released</meta-name><meta-value>yes</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-open-access</meta-name><meta-value>yes</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-olf</meta-name><meta-value>no</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-manuscript</meta-name><meta-value>no</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-legally-suppressed</meta-name><meta-value>no</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-has-pdf</meta-name><meta-value>yes</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-has-supplement</meta-name><meta-value>no</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-pdf-only</meta-name><meta-value>no</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-suppress-copyright</meta-name><meta-value>no</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-is-real-version</meta-name><meta-value>no</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-is-scanned-article</meta-name><meta-value>no</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-preprint</meta-name><meta-value>no</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-in-epmc</meta-name><meta-value>yes</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-license-ref</meta-name><meta-value>CC BY-NC-ND</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>OPEN-ACCESS</meta-name><meta-value>TRUE</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>COUNTRY</meta-name><meta-value>SAUDI ARABIA</meta-value></custom-meta></custom-meta-group></article-meta></front><body><boxed-text position="float" orientation="portrait"><sec><title>Takeaways</title><p><bold>Question:</bold> Unknown types of facial fillers used in cosmetic surgery pose a problem because they are risky and can cause a high risk of complications.</p><p><bold>Findings:</bold> This study was able to develop an algorithm that can simply explain and help surgeons innovate a suitable plan when conducting surgery on facial filler complications, allowing them get a high satisfaction rate with excellent results.</p><p><bold>Meaning:</bold> An algorithmic approach is available to manage facial filler complications at various stages.</p></sec></boxed-text><sec sec-type="intro"><title>INTRODUCTION</title><p>Facial volume loss and the appearance of aging face are two of the most frequently encountered problems leading to facial filler injections. Facial filler injection is the second most common procedure performed after Botox in the United States, with reported cases of around 3.5 million in 2020.<sup><xref rid="R1" ref-type="bibr">1</xref></sup> These changes can be caused by multiple factors such as genetics, endocrine-related factors, and sun exposure, leading to changes known as photoaging.<sup><xref rid="R2" ref-type="bibr">2</xref></sup></p><p>Injectable fillers vary depending on the composition, which can either be autologous or alloplastic. Alloplastic fillers came to use in 1970, originally composed of viscus fluid or polymers that have both functional and aesthetic purposes.<sup><xref rid="R3" ref-type="bibr">3</xref></sup></p><p>Injectable fillers can also be classified, based on their duration of action, into three types: temporary, semi-permanent, and permanent. Each type has a different chemical structure, leading to their various duration and complications such as pain at injection site, erythema, edema, ecchymosis, surface irregularity, intravascular injection, and granuloma formation.<sup><xref rid="R4" ref-type="bibr">4</xref>,<xref rid="R5" ref-type="bibr">5</xref></sup></p><p>Despite having many products available in the market to use, another category started to appear worldwide: unknown filler materials that are used by unlicensed practitioners and are not designed for human use. These procedures are usually performed in an unsterile manner and are associated with serious and fatal complications.<sup><xref rid="R6" ref-type="bibr">6</xref></sup> Sclafani and Fagien<sup><xref rid="R7" ref-type="bibr">7</xref></sup> categorized complications brought by unknown facial fillers, as immediate (for those that occur in the 24-hour period upon injection), early-onset (for those that start after 2 weeks), and delayed (for those that persist after 14-day period). Due to its cost and the possibility of having multiple injection sessions, most patients prefer the permanent types of facial fillers even if they are associated with a greater risk of complications.<sup><xref rid="R8" ref-type="bibr">8</xref></sup></p><p>A Thai study comparing the complication rates between illegal versus legal fillers over 10 years reported that 70% of patients had a history of illegal filler injections. This group was associated with higher complication rates in terms of foreign body reaction (78.6%) and infections (21.4%).<sup><xref rid="R9" ref-type="bibr">9</xref></sup></p><p>Unfortunately, there is no single available study yet to demonstrate the prevalence of patients receiving unknown dermal filler injections in Saudi Arabia. Furthermore, there is no clear treatment strategy designed to manage these cases. In this study, we aimed to establish an algorithm of categorizing and managing the patients receiving permanent fillers.</p></sec><sec sec-type="methods"><title>PATIENTS AND METHODS</title><p>Before the start of the research, informed consent (written and verbal) from participants was obtained, and we made sure that their collaboration was voluntary with no penalties for nonparticipation. Ethical approval was granted by the research ethics committee. Upon approval from the local ethical committee, this prospective study evaluated 12 patients who received permanent filler injection. They were either presented to the service through the emergency department or came as outpatient visit from November 2015 to May 2021.</p><p>Patient history guides the management as to which material was injected, which was supplemented by imaging studies. All our patients were injected by nonmedical personnel, and it is routine for such personnel to use permanent filler material. Detailed relevant history obtained includes the following: age, sex, date of injection, time of onset, and types of complications. After this, a comprehensive physical examination was performed for all the patients referred to our institute by the senior author (LAS). Computed tomography and magnetic resonance imaging of head and neck that was reported by a musculoskeletal radiologist was requested (<xref rid="F1" ref-type="fig">1</xref>&#8211;<xref rid="F4" ref-type="fig">4</xref>). Additionally, all cases were managed based on an algorithm that was established by the senior author, as shown in Figure <xref rid="F5" ref-type="fig">5</xref>. The algorithm divided the patients into three categories: F (frequent visitors), I (indolent: meaning symptoms were of less severity), and D (delayed) based on their duration of injection, emergency visits, and symptoms. All the cases were treated by the senior author, either by a form of face lift and neck lift or by a filler material removal, with or without SMAS plication, depending on the patient&#8217;s condition and need for incision and drainage of the abscess with filler removal (Figs. <xref rid="F6" ref-type="fig">6</xref> and <xref rid="F7" ref-type="fig">7</xref>). The patients&#8217; satisfaction was measured using the FACE-Q scale. The FACE-Q is a patient-reported outcome instrument composed of numerous independently functioning scales designed to measure outcomes among facial aesthetic patients. Patients were asked to complete the following FACE-Q scales after surgery and to recall their statuses before the intervention:</p><fig position="float" id="F1" orientation="portrait"><label>Fig. 1.</label><caption><p>Axial CT scan of a patient with facial filler with acute ongoing inflammation.</p></caption><graphic xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" position="float" orientation="portrait" xlink:href="gox-11-e4838-g001.jpg"/></fig><fig position="float" id="F2" orientation="portrait"><label>Fig. 2.</label><caption><p>Coronal CT scan of the same patient with facial filler with acute ongoing inflammation.</p></caption><graphic xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" position="float" orientation="portrait" xlink:href="gox-11-e4838-g002.jpg"/></fig><fig position="float" id="F3" orientation="portrait"><label>Fig. 3.</label><caption><p>Axial MRI scan of a patient with long-standing facial filler.</p></caption><graphic xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" position="float" orientation="portrait" xlink:href="gox-11-e4838-g003.jpg"/></fig><fig position="float" id="F4" orientation="portrait"><label>Fig. 4.</label><caption><p>Coronal MRI scan of the same patient with long-standing facial filler with associated facial drooping.</p></caption><graphic xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" position="float" orientation="portrait" xlink:href="gox-11-e4838-g004.jpg"/></fig><fig position="float" id="F5" orientation="portrait"><label>Fig. 5.</label><caption><p>Algorithm for management of facial fillers.</p></caption><graphic xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" position="float" orientation="portrait" xlink:href="gox-11-e4838-g005.jpg"/></fig><fig position="float" id="F6" orientation="portrait"><label>Fig. 6.</label><caption><p>Preoperative and postoperative photographs of representative cases of patients with facial fillers. Preoperative (A-C) and 6 months postoperative pictures (D-F) of patient after filler removal and face lift.</p></caption><graphic xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" position="float" orientation="portrait" xlink:href="gox-11-e4838-g006.jpg"/></fig><fig position="float" id="F7" orientation="portrait"><label>Fig. 7.</label><caption><p>Preoperative and postoperative photographs of representative cases of patients with facial fillers. Preoperative (A-C) and long-term postoperative pictures (D-F) of patient after filler removal and face lift.</p></caption><graphic xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" position="float" orientation="portrait" xlink:href="gox-11-e4838-g007.jpg"/></fig><list list-type="order"><list-item><p>Satisfaction with overall facial appearance: measures patient satisfaction with the overall appearance of their face.</p></list-item><list-item><p>Psychological well-being: measures psychological well-being in terms of a series of positively worded statements.</p></list-item></list><p>Patients were also asked directly whether they are happy with the surgery results or whether they would prefer to go back in time and would not proceed to the surgery. Simple descriptive statistics were used to define the characteristics of the study variables through a form of counts and percentages for the categorical and nominal variables, whereas continuous variables are presented by mean and standard deviations.</p></sec><sec sec-type="results"><title>RESULTS</title><p>Demographic data of the patients involved in this study are shown in Table <xref rid="T1" ref-type="table">1</xref>. The mean age of patients involved in this study is 43.66 years, with a range of 35 to 50 years. All the involved participants were nonsmoking women, with no known medical comorbidities. It was also noted that the duration of filler injection has a mean of 12.5 years with range of 8 to 18 years. On the other hand, the type of filler used according to the 11 patients (90%) was unknown, while one patient mentioned that it was bio-alcamide. The follow-up months by patients was 21.72 months with a range of 3 to 51 months. Nine patients had no complications, but one patient experienced marginal nerve neuropraxia, one patient experienced sialocele, and another patient experienced hyperpigmentation.</p><table-wrap position="float" id="T1" orientation="portrait"><label>Table 1.</label><caption><p>Demographics of the Patients Involved in the Study</p></caption><table frame="hsides" rules="groups"><thead><tr><th align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">FACE-Q Scale</th><th align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">No. (%)</th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">No. patients</td><td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">12</td></tr><tr><td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Age (y)</td><td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Mean: 43.66<break/>Range: 35&#8211;50</td></tr><tr><td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Gender</td><td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Women: 12 (100%)<break/>Men: 0</td></tr><tr><td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Smoking status</td><td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">None: 12 (100)<break/>Smokers: 0</td></tr><tr><td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Medical comorbidities</td><td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">None: 12 (100)</td></tr><tr><td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Duration of filler injection (y)</td><td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">12.5 (8&#8211;18)</td></tr><tr><td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Type of filler</td><td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Unknown: 11 (90%)<break/>Bio alcamid: 1 (10%)</td></tr><tr><td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Follow-up (mo)</td><td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Mean: 21.72<break/>Range: 3&#8211;51</td></tr></tbody></table></table-wrap><p>The satisfaction rate of patients was measured using the FACE-Q questionnaire of facial appearance and psychosocial distress. A total of seven patients answered the questionnaire, with five patients (four who underwent facelift with SMAS plication and one who obtained postoperation of I and D) reporting a very satisfied score in terms of appearance, which was also reflected on their psychosocial distress score. Meanwhile, two patients who underwent facelift were unsatisfied with their result, although they did not have any postoperative complications.</p><p>Table <xref rid="T2" ref-type="table">2</xref> shows cases of different groups, their symptoms, and treatment. The majority of patients who underwent facelift had uneventful procedures, except the two cases where one had a marginal mandibular nerve neuropraxia and the other had sialocele. The total number of those in group F was four patients, all of whom were admitted through emergency department for facial abscess and were managed later by surgical incision and drainage with filler removal. Symptoms such as unilateral cheek, swelling, erythema, and fluctuation were experienced 11 years (mean) after filler injection with a range of 8&#8211;15 years.</p><table-wrap position="float" id="T2" orientation="portrait"><label>Table 2.</label><caption><p>Cases Identified per Group, Their Signs and Symptoms, and Treatment</p></caption><table frame="hsides" rules="groups"><thead><tr><th align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Group</th><th align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">No.<break/>Cases</th><th align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Years after Filler Injection when Presenting</th><th align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Signs and Symptoms</th><th align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Treatment</th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">F</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">4</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Mean: 11 y<break/>Range: 8&#8211;15 y</td><td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Unilateral cheek swelling, erythema, fluctuation increasing in size<break/>No orbital symptoms<break/>No trismus</td><td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Incision and drainage + filler removal if found</td></tr><tr><td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">I</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">1</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">8</td><td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Presented as group F</td><td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Treated as group D</td></tr><tr><td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">D</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">7</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Mean: 13.83 y<break/>Average: 10&#8211;18 y</td><td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Facial disfigurement<break/>Asymmetry<break/>Skin changes: telangiectasia, hyper/hypopigmentation<break/>No Hx of recent abscess formation</td><td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Facelift + SMAS addressing surgeries</td></tr></tbody></table></table-wrap><p>One patient was categorized in group I. This patient did not receive any intervention such as group F until 8 years after injection, when she received staged procedures in the form of lipofilling and facelift. In group D, a total of seven patients managed to recover by the removal of filler and a surgical correction in the form of facelift with or without SMAS adjustment, removal of filler, and lipofilling. Symptoms such as facial disfigurement, asymmetry, and skin changes such as telangiectasia, hyper/hypopigmentation, with no history of recent abscess formation were experienced 13.83 years (mean) after filler injection, with a range of 10 to 18 years.</p><p>The algorithm delineated the treatment plan when faced with such cases. In group F, the only treatment option available was incision and drainage, in order to remove the filler material. In the indolent group (I), this subset can be presented as group F, which will be managed just the same. Otherwise, the senior author preferred to wait at least till they reach 10 years after the material injection and then treated as group D, which was usually managed with rhytidectomy and SMAS plication. This protocol was adapted because by 10 years, most patients have developed both disfiguring deformity of the face and psychological impact of the deformity and are willing to get material removed and to accept any secondary deformities. Psychological impact requires a time period to develop until a patient seeks surgical intervention.</p><p>Table <xref rid="T3" ref-type="table">3</xref> shows Face-Q Overall Satisfaction Question-naire for the facelift group. Before surgery, overall satisfaction rating among patients was 4.3 with SD of 10.61, which increased to 63.3 with SD of 28.33 after surgery (lower the number means less satisfaction). However, ratings on appearance-related psychosocial distress was 81.33 with SD of 14.39 before surgery. On the other hand, after surgery, appearance-related psychosocial distress was 38.33 with standard deviation of 40.21% (higher number means more psychological impact).</p><table-wrap position="float" id="T3" orientation="portrait"><label>Table 3.</label><caption><p>FACE-Q Overall Satisfaction Questionnaire for the Facelift Group</p></caption><table frame="hsides" rules="groups"><thead><tr><th align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Question</th><th align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Before Surgery</th><th align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">After Surgery</th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Overall satisfaction rate (mean &#177; SD)</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">4.3&#8201;&#177;&#8201;10.61</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">63.3&#8201;&#177;&#8201;28.33</td></tr><tr><td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Appearance-related psychosocial distress (mean &#177; SD)</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">81.33&#8201;&#177;&#8201;14.39</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">38.33&#8201;&#177;&#8201;40.21</td></tr></tbody></table></table-wrap></sec><sec sec-type="discussion"><title>DISCUSSION</title><p>In Saudi Arabia, numbers of cosmetic surgery supporters have drastically shot up over the past few years. Plastic surgery has become a new trend not only for women but to some extent for men as well. In Saudi culture, one study mentioned that the 20- to 40-year-old age-group has the greatest number of individuals that have engaged in plastic surgery.<sup><xref rid="R10" ref-type="bibr">10</xref></sup> This study involving patients ranging 35 to 50 years old with a mean of 43.66 years was not able to fully cover the one that was previously investigated. This research was able to provide new data in this specific age bracket.</p><p>FACE-Q was able to provide sufficient data to measure the impact and effectiveness of the facial aesthetic procedure from the patients&#8217; point of view. Before surgery, there was a notably low overall satisfaction rate that eventually rose after surgery. On the other hand, high appearance-related psychosocial distress was observed before surgery, whereas it significantly dropped after surgery. A study mentioned that expectations play a major role in psychosocial stress and overall satisfaction in patients.<sup><xref rid="R11" ref-type="bibr">11</xref></sup> The treatments received by patients were satisfactory, which resulted in positive feedback from patients, as displayed by lowered psychosocial stress and increased overall satisfaction rating after surgery.</p><p>Soft tissue augmentation by using various types of fillers dates back over hundreds of years already. The majorityof these procedures are being used in the face by using small volumes of temporary fillers approved by the US Food and Drug Administration.</p><p>Other groups of patients received large amounts of permanent filler, some with which were not designed for human use. However, there have been a growing number of these unsafe procedures performed by nonmedical personnel. These injections frequently involve nonmedical grade products and equipment in nonsterile and nonprofessional environments. Due to sanitary issues and inappropriate materials used, such unprofessionally done injections could lead to chronic complications, of which some could also be fatal.</p><p>Due to lack of strict laws, it is often unregulated that unlicensed individuals are able to practice unlawful and unsafe cosmetic procedures to people eager to receive such injections at the expense of their health. These are also commonly done by anonymous people who rarely disclose the name of the product, the sterility of the instruments used, and the orientation of possible complications. In some instances, there would be a few satisfied individuals who would be able to encourage others as well, until serious complications start to occur.</p><p>Peer pressure, convenience, and cost-effectiveness have become the main appeal of these unsafe and unlawful procedures to the willing patients. Among the most encountered complications of such procedures is long-lasting inflammatory reaction. Unfortunately, these complications are also not usually self-limiting. The lesions caused by such procedures are also challenging to treat. Moreover, patients would often report to the care of plastic surgeons only after having exhausted all medical management provided by other specialists, such as dermatologists and internists.</p><p>This study was conducted to establish an algorithm to diagnose and manage these patients effectively with high satisfaction rate. This was made, as there was already a growing population of such cases and there were still no clear guidelines that could be found in relation to this.</p><p>However, one of the limiting factors of this study was the number of cases included in the study. Therefore, some other adjuncts can be added to the facelift procedure to augment its result, which might lead to a higher satisfaction rate. Other limitations involved in this study are that (1) it only covered women, as all the patients who participated were women, and (2) the sampling size for this prospective study was only 12, with age bracket of 35 to 50 years. Although this study presented new data, it suggests conducting investigation among larger groups to confirm validity.</p></sec><sec sec-type="conclusions"><title>CONCLUSIONS</title><p>Filler injection is considered one of the most common procedures worldwide. Treating unknown filler material can be challenging due to the lack of knowledge about the substances injected and the unpredictable pattern of complications associated with it. FACE-Q was able to provide sufficient data to measure the impact and effectiveness of the facial aesthetic procedure from the patients&#8217; point of view. An algorithm was developed in this study that assessed patients who received facial fillers. Using this treatment algorithm can guide the surgeon in formulating a suitable plan with fewer complications and a high satisfaction rate.</p></sec><sec><title>ACKNOWLEDGMENTS</title><p>The study was approved and followed the guidelines for ethical scientific research by the institutional review board. This research was carried out in accordance with the Code of Ethics of the World Medical Association (Declaration of Helsinki 2013) for experiments involving humans.</p></sec><sec sec-type="subjects"><title>PATIENT CONSENT</title><p>The patients provided written consent for the use of their images.</p></sec></body><back><fn-group><fn fn-type="other"><p>Published online 6 March 2023.</p></fn><fn fn-type="financial-disclosure"><p><bold>Disclosure:</bold>
<italic toggle="yes">The authors have no financial interest to declare in relation to the content of this article.</italic></p></fn></fn-group><ref-list><title>REFERENCES</title><ref id="R1"><label>1.</label><mixed-citation publication-type="webpage"><collab>American Society of Plastic Surgeons</collab>. <article-title>Plastic surgery statistics report: ASPS National Clearinghouse of Plastic Surgery Procedural Statistics.</article-title><comment>Available at <ext-link xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xlink:href="https://www.plasticsurgery.org/documents/News/Statistics/2020/plastic-surgery-statistics-full-report-2020.pdf" ext-link-type="uri">https://www.plasticsurgery.org/documents/News/Statistics/2020/plastic-surgery-statistics-full-report-2020.pdf</ext-link>. Accessed February 19, 2022</comment>.</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="R2"><label>2.</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Pellacani</surname><given-names>G</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Seidenari</surname><given-names>S</given-names></name></person-group>. <article-title>Variations in facial skin thickness and echogenicity with site and age.</article-title><source>Acta Derm Venereol</source>. <year>1999</year>;<volume>79</volume>:<fpage>366</fpage>&#8211;<lpage>369</lpage>.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">10494713</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1080/000155599750010283</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="R3"><label>3.</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Murray</surname><given-names>CA</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Zloty</surname><given-names>D</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Warshawski</surname><given-names>L</given-names></name></person-group>. <article-title>The evolution of soft tissue fillers in clinical practice.</article-title><source>Dermatol Clin</source>. <year>2005</year>;<volume>23</volume>:<fpage>343</fpage>&#8211;<lpage>363</lpage>.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">15837160</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1016/j.det.2004.09.009</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="R4"><label>4.</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Broder</surname><given-names>KW</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Cohen</surname><given-names>SR</given-names></name></person-group>. <article-title>An overview of permanent and semipermanent fillers.</article-title><source>Plast Reconstr Surg</source>. <year>2006</year>;<volume>118</volume>:<fpage>7S</fpage>&#8211;<lpage>14S</lpage>.<pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1097/01.prs.0000234900.26676.0b</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">16936539</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="R5"><label>5.</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Christensen</surname><given-names>L</given-names></name></person-group>. <article-title>Normal and pathologic tissue reactions to soft tissue gel fillers.</article-title><source>Dermatol Surg</source>. <year>2007</year>;<volume>33</volume>:<fpage>S168</fpage>&#8211;<lpage>S175</lpage>.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">18086055</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1111/j.1524-4725.2007.33357.x</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="R6"><label>6.</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Klein</surname><given-names>AW</given-names></name></person-group>. <article-title>Techniques for soft tissue augmentation: an &#8220;a to z.&#8221;</article-title><source>Am J Clin Dermatol</source>. <year>2006</year>;<volume>7</volume>:<fpage>107</fpage>&#8211;<lpage>120</lpage>.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">16605291</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.2165/00128071-200607020-00004</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="R7"><label>7.</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Sclafani</surname><given-names>AP</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Fagien</surname><given-names>S</given-names></name></person-group>. <article-title>Treatment of injectable soft tissue filler complications.</article-title><source>Dermatol Surg</source>. <year>2009</year>;<volume>35</volume>:<fpage>1672</fpage>&#8211;<lpage>1680</lpage>.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">19807763</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1111/j.1524-4725.2009.01346.x</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="R8"><label>8.</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Alshaer</surname><given-names>Z</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Alsaadi</surname><given-names>Y</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Mrad</surname><given-names>MA</given-names></name></person-group>. <article-title>Successful management of infected facial filler with Brucella.</article-title><source>Aesthetic Plast Surg</source>. <year>2018</year>;<volume>42</volume>:<fpage>1388</fpage>&#8211;<lpage>1392</lpage>.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">29948096</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1007/s00266-018-1173-3</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="R9"><label>9.</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Chayangsu</surname><given-names>O</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Wanitphakdeedecha</surname><given-names>R</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Pattanaprichakul</surname><given-names>P</given-names></name><etal/></person-group>. <article-title>Legal vs. illegal injectable fillers: the adverse effects comparison study.</article-title><source>J Cosmet Dermatol</source>. <year>2020</year>;<volume>19</volume>:<fpage>1580</fpage>&#8211;<lpage>1586</lpage>.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">32418301</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1111/jocd.13492</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="R10"><label>10.</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Alharethy</surname><given-names>SE</given-names></name></person-group>. <article-title>Trends and demographic characteristics of Saudi cosmetic surgery patients.</article-title><source>Saudi Med J</source>. <year>2017</year>;<volume>38</volume>:<fpage>738</fpage>&#8211;<lpage>741</lpage>.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">28674720</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.15537/smj.2017.7.18528</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC5556282</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="R11"><label>11.</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Klassen</surname><given-names>AF</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Cano</surname><given-names>SJ</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Alderman</surname><given-names>A</given-names></name><etal/></person-group>. <article-title>Self-report scales to measure expectations and appearance-related psychosocial distress in patients seeking cosmetic treatments.</article-title><source>Aesthet Surg J</source>. <year>2016</year>;<volume>36</volume>:<fpage>1068</fpage>&#8211;<lpage>1078</lpage>.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">27222106</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1093/asj/sjw078</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC5029370</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref></ref-list></back></article></pmc-articleset>