<?xml version="1.0"  ?><!DOCTYPE pmc-articleset PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD ARTICLE SET 2.0//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pmc/articleset/nlm-articleset-2.0.dtd"><pmc-articleset><article xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" xmlns:ali="http://www.niso.org/schemas/ali/1.0/" xml:lang="en" article-type="research-article" dtd-version="1.4"><processing-meta base-tagset="archiving" mathml-version="3.0" table-model="xhtml" tagset-family="jats"><restricted-by>pmc</restricted-by></processing-meta><front><journal-meta><journal-id journal-id-type="nlm-ta">Clin Cosmet Investig Dermatol</journal-id><journal-id journal-id-type="iso-abbrev">Clin Cosmet Investig Dermatol</journal-id><journal-id journal-id-type="pmc-domain-id">1442</journal-id><journal-id journal-id-type="pmc-domain">ccid</journal-id><journal-id journal-id-type="publisher-id">ccid</journal-id><journal-title-group><journal-title>Clinical, Cosmetic and Investigational Dermatology</journal-title></journal-title-group><issn pub-type="epub">1178-7015</issn><publisher><publisher-name>Dove Press</publisher-name></publisher></journal-meta><article-meta><article-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC9788834</article-id><article-id pub-id-type="pmcid-ver">PMC9788834.1</article-id><article-id pub-id-type="pmcaid">9788834</article-id><article-id pub-id-type="pmcaiid">9788834</article-id><article-id pub-id-type="pmid">36569419</article-id><article-id pub-id-type="doi">10.2147/CCID.S382582</article-id><article-id pub-id-type="publisher-id">382582</article-id><article-version article-version-type="pmc-version">1</article-version><article-categories><subj-group subj-group-type="heading"><subject>Original Research</subject></subj-group></article-categories><title-group><article-title>The Efficacy of Noninvasive 1060-Nm Diode Lasers for Submental Lipolysis: A Pilot Study</article-title><alt-title alt-title-type="running-authors">Wanitphakdeedecha et al</alt-title><alt-title alt-title-type="running-title">Wanitphakdeedecha et al</alt-title></title-group><contrib-group><contrib contrib-type="author"><contrib-id contrib-id-type="orcid" authenticated="false">http://orcid.org/0000-0002-3926-2193</contrib-id><name name-style="western"><surname>Wanitphakdeedecha</surname><given-names initials="R">Rungsima</given-names></name><xref rid="aff0001" ref-type="aff">
<sup>1</sup>
</xref><xref rid="an0001" ref-type="corresp"/></contrib><contrib contrib-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Evangelista</surname><given-names initials="KER">Kristy Elleza R</given-names></name><xref rid="aff0001" ref-type="aff">
<sup>1</sup>
</xref><xref rid="aff0002" ref-type="aff">
<sup>2</sup>
</xref></contrib><contrib contrib-type="author"><contrib-id contrib-id-type="orcid" authenticated="false">http://orcid.org/0000-0002-5347-5822</contrib-id><name name-style="western"><surname>Yan</surname><given-names initials="C">Chadakan</given-names></name><xref rid="aff0001" ref-type="aff">
<sup>1</sup>
</xref></contrib><contrib contrib-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Apinuntham</surname><given-names initials="C">Chalermkwan</given-names></name><xref rid="aff0001" ref-type="aff">
<sup>1</sup>
</xref></contrib><contrib contrib-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Techapichetvanich</surname><given-names initials="T">Thanya</given-names></name><xref rid="aff0001" ref-type="aff">
<sup>1</sup>
</xref></contrib><contrib contrib-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Eimpunth</surname><given-names initials="S">Sasima</given-names></name><xref rid="aff0001" ref-type="aff">
<sup>1</sup>
</xref></contrib><contrib contrib-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Lektrakul</surname><given-names initials="N">Nittaya</given-names></name><xref rid="aff0003" ref-type="aff">
<sup>3</sup>
</xref></contrib><contrib contrib-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Manuskiatti</surname><given-names initials="W">Woraphong</given-names></name><xref rid="aff0001" ref-type="aff">
<sup>1</sup>
</xref></contrib><aff id="aff0001"><label>1</label><institution>Department of Dermatology, Faculty of Medicine Siriraj Hospital, Mahidol University</institution>, <addr-line>Bangkok</addr-line>, <country>Thailand</country></aff><aff id="aff0002"><label>2</label><institution>Department of Dermatology, Research Institute for Tropical Medicine</institution>, <addr-line>Manila</addr-line>, <country>Philippines</country></aff><aff id="aff0003"><label>3</label><institution>Department of Radiology, Faculty of Medicine Siriraj Hospital, Mahidol University</institution>, <addr-line>Bangkok</addr-line>, <country>Thailand</country></aff></contrib-group><author-notes><corresp id="an0001">Correspondence: Rungsima Wanitphakdeedecha, <institution>Department of Dermatology, Faculty of Medicine Siriraj Hospital, Mahidol University</institution>, <addr-line>2 Prannok Road</addr-line>, <addr-line>Bangkok Noi</addr-line>, <addr-line>10700</addr-line>, <country>Thailand</country>, <phone>Tel +66 2 419 4333</phone>, <fax>Fax +66 2 411 9922</fax>, Email rungsima.wan@mahidol.ac.th</corresp></author-notes><pub-date pub-type="epub"><day>19</day><month>12</month><year>2022</year></pub-date><pub-date pub-type="collection"><year>2022</year></pub-date><volume>15</volume><issue-id pub-id-type="pmc-issue-id">397943</issue-id><fpage>2775</fpage><lpage>2783</lpage><history><date date-type="received"><day>13</day><month>8</month><year>2022</year></date><date date-type="accepted"><day>08</day><month>11</month><year>2022</year></date></history><pub-history><event event-type="pmc-release"><date><day>19</day><month>12</month><year>2022</year></date></event><event event-type="pmc-live"><date><day>24</day><month>12</month><year>2022</year></date></event><event event-type="pmc-last-change"><date iso-8601-date="2022-12-27 13:10:14.033"><day>27</day><month>12</month><year>2022</year></date></event></pub-history><permissions><copyright-statement>&#169; 2022 Wanitphakdeedecha et al.</copyright-statement><copyright-year>2022</copyright-year><copyright-holder>Wanitphakdeedecha et al.</copyright-holder><license><ali:license_ref specific-use="textmining" content-type="ccbynclicense">https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/3.0/</ali:license_ref><license-p>This work is published and licensed by Dove Medical Press Limited. The full terms of this license are available at <ext-link xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" ext-link-type="uri" xlink:href="https://www.dovepress.com/terms.php">https://www.dovepress.com/terms.php</ext-link> and incorporate the Creative Commons Attribution &#8211; Non Commercial (unported, v3.0) License (<ext-link xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" ext-link-type="uri" xlink:href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/3.0/">http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/3.0/</ext-link>). By accessing the work you hereby accept the Terms. Non-commercial uses of the work are permitted without any further permission from Dove Medical Press Limited, provided the work is properly attributed. For permission for commercial use of this work, please see paragraphs 4.2 and 5 of our Terms (<ext-link xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" ext-link-type="uri" xlink:href="https://www.dovepress.com/terms.php">https://www.dovepress.com/terms.php</ext-link>).</license-p></license></permissions><self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" content-type="pmc-pdf" xlink:href="ccid-15-2775.pdf"/><abstract><sec><title>Background</title><p>Submental fat is a noticeable fat in the submental region that is of great concern aesthetically, especially to female patients. A 1060-nm diode laser is a clinically proven device for the laser lipolysis of subcutaneous fat cells. This study aimed to evaluate the safety and efficacy of a 1060-nm diode laser for submental fat reduction.</p></sec><sec><title>Methods</title><p>Twenty subjects with unwanted localized submental fat were treated with a single session of a 1060-nm diode laser with an energy setting between 0.95 and 1.40 W/cm<sup>2</sup>, depending on each patient&#8217;s tolerance. Submental fat thickness measurements were documented at baseline, and 1, 3, and 6 months after treatment. Clinical photographs, ultrasound images, and adverse events were evaluated at each follow-up visit. Subjects responded to a satisfaction questionnaire at the end of the study.</p></sec><sec><title>Results</title><p>The subjects had a mean age of 34.55&#160;&#177;&#160;6.19 years, a mean body weight of 70.66&#160;&#177;&#160;10.55 kilograms, and most (95%) were women. The average energy setting was 0.95&#8211;1.40 W/cm<sup>2</sup>, with a pain score of 3.90&#160;&#177;&#160;1.30 on a 0-to-10 scale. A significant reduction in submental fat thickness measured by ultrasound was noted at post-treatment month 3 (falling to 0.46&#160;&#177;&#160;0.13; <italic toggle="yes">P</italic> =&#160;0.013). However, there was a slight increase in the submental fat thickness at the 6-month follow-up (to 0.48&#160;&#177;&#160;0.12); the change in the thickness relative to the baseline was nonsignificant (<italic toggle="yes">P</italic> =&#160;0.121). Most subjects reported an improvement 6 months after the treatment. No severe adverse events were observed throughout the study period.</p></sec><sec><title>Conclusion</title><p>Our study demonstrated the potential role of 1060-nm Diode laser for the treatment of localized submental subcutaneous adiposities. It is a promising alternative treatment modality for patients seeking an in-office, nonsurgical procedure for fat reduction without severe complications.</p></sec></abstract><kwd-group kwd-group-type="author"><title>Keywords</title><kwd>1060-nm</kwd><kwd>diode laser</kwd><kwd>lipolysis</kwd><kwd>submental fat</kwd></kwd-group><funding-group><award-group><funding-source><institution-wrap><institution>Faculty of Medicine Siriraj Hospital, Mahidol University</institution></institution-wrap></funding-source></award-group><funding-statement>This research project was supported by the Faculty of Medicine Siriraj Hospital, Mahidol University.</funding-statement></funding-group><counts><fig-count count="3"/><table-count count="3"/><ref-count count="24"/><page-count count="9"/></counts><custom-meta-group><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-status-qastatus</meta-name><meta-value>0</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-status-live</meta-name><meta-value>yes</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-status-embargo</meta-name><meta-value>no</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-status-released</meta-name><meta-value>yes</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-open-access</meta-name><meta-value>yes</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-olf</meta-name><meta-value>no</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-manuscript</meta-name><meta-value>no</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-legally-suppressed</meta-name><meta-value>no</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-has-pdf</meta-name><meta-value>yes</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-has-supplement</meta-name><meta-value>no</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-pdf-only</meta-name><meta-value>no</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-suppress-copyright</meta-name><meta-value>no</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-is-real-version</meta-name><meta-value>no</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-is-scanned-article</meta-name><meta-value>no</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-preprint</meta-name><meta-value>no</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-in-epmc</meta-name><meta-value>yes</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-license-ref</meta-name><meta-value>CC BY-NC</meta-value></custom-meta></custom-meta-group></article-meta></front><body><sec sec-type="intro" id="s0001"><title>Introduction</title><p>Currently, people seek consultations to improve their facial appearance. Maintaining a good body physique increases individuals&#8217; self-esteem and improves their emotional and social well-being.<xref rid="cit0001" ref-type="bibr">1</xref> Facial features are considered indicators of the attractiveness of a person.<xref rid="cit0001" ref-type="bibr">1</xref> The appearance of the chin and jawline or the submental area is a common facial concern that can profoundly impact a person&#8217;s feelings.<xref rid="cit0001" ref-type="bibr">1</xref></p><p>According to the 2019 American Society for Dermatologic Surgery consumer survey, 73% of 3645 respondents were concerned about excess fat in their chin and neck.<xref rid="cit0002" ref-type="bibr">2</xref> Excessive submental fat is either due to genetics or lifestyle factors, such as an unhealthy diet or a sedentary lifestyle.<xref rid="cit0001" ref-type="bibr">1</xref> This excessive fat can be corrected through surgical procedures, including submental liposuction and submentoplasty.<xref rid="cit0003" ref-type="bibr">3</xref>,<xref rid="cit0004" ref-type="bibr">4</xref> However, the procedures have pitfalls that can be frustrating to patients. They include nerve injury, bleeding, hematoma, seroma, postinflammatory hyperpigmentation, infection, and scarring.<xref rid="cit0004" ref-type="bibr">4</xref>,<xref rid="cit0005" ref-type="bibr">5</xref></p><p>More and more people are actively seeking noninvasive fat reduction and rejuvenation procedures.<xref rid="cit0005" ref-type="bibr">5</xref> Noninvasive treatment modalities have emerged that address unwanted fat in the submental area with less downtime and complications than surgical procedures. Among them are injection adipolysis,<xref rid="cit0005" ref-type="bibr">5&#8211;8</xref> cryolipolysis,<xref rid="cit0009" ref-type="bibr">9&#8211;11</xref>,<xref rid="cit0020" ref-type="bibr">20&#8211;22</xref> radiofrequency,<xref rid="cit0012" ref-type="bibr">12</xref> high-intensity focus ultrasound,<xref rid="cit0013" ref-type="bibr">13</xref>,<xref rid="cit0014" ref-type="bibr">14</xref> laser lipolysis<xref rid="cit0015" ref-type="bibr">15&#8211;18</xref> and microwave technology.<xref rid="cit0023" ref-type="bibr">23</xref></p><p>A recent study done by Salsi et al used microwaves technology for unwanted fat reduction and submental skin tightening.<xref rid="cit0023" ref-type="bibr">23</xref> The technology utilizes selective microwave frequency producing localized heat and is absorbed by that fat through a biophysical process called &#8220;dielectric heating&#8221;.<xref rid="cit0023" ref-type="bibr">23</xref> A total of 48 subjects underwent submental treatment for 6 sessions and showed significant decrease in submental fat and laxity at 12 weeks follow-up.<xref rid="cit0023" ref-type="bibr">23</xref> No significant adverse effects were noted among the subjects.<xref rid="cit0023" ref-type="bibr">23</xref></p><p>Studies have demonstrated the efficacy of a 1060-nm diode laser for fat reduction in some areas of the body.<xref rid="cit0015" ref-type="bibr">15&#8211;18</xref> The laser has a high affinity for adipose tissue due to its long wavelength. It raises the temperature of adipose cells to between 42 &#8451; and 47 &#8451;, damaging their structural integrity. Inflammatory responses are stimulated. The body naturally eliminates disrupted fat cells and cellular debris by attracting macrophages and removing the cells and debris through phagocytosis. Several investigations have established the safety of the laser in patients with skin of color.<xref rid="cit0015" ref-type="bibr">15&#8211;18</xref></p><p>Decorato et al demonstrated that the optimal time for a 1060-nm diode laser to cause significant adipocyte injury is 20 to 25 minutes. Use for longer than 25 minutes can create palpable nodules in the subcutaneous fat.<xref rid="cit0015" ref-type="bibr">15</xref>,<xref rid="cit0017" ref-type="bibr">17</xref> Work by Bass and associates and by Katz et al demonstrated a significant fat reduction in the abdomen and flanks, respectively, 12 weeks after treatment, measured by ultrasound.<xref rid="cit0015" ref-type="bibr">15</xref>,<xref rid="cit0018" ref-type="bibr">18</xref> Neither study documented any severe complications.<xref rid="cit0015" ref-type="bibr">15</xref>,<xref rid="cit0018" ref-type="bibr">18</xref></p><p>There was also an increasing demand for leg contouring among Asian patients. A recent study done in Thailand by Yan et al showed efficacy of 1060 nm Diode laser in reducing medial knee fat thickness.<xref rid="cit0024" ref-type="bibr">24</xref> A total of 19 subjects with localized unwanted fat on the medial knees were enrolled into this study. Significant reduction in knee circumferences at 1-, 3-, and 6-month follow-up visits compared with baseline, and knee fat thickness measured by ultrasound in both axial and sagittal plane at 1 and 6 months after treatment were recorded.<xref rid="cit0024" ref-type="bibr">24</xref> Minimal and transient side effects were noted among patients.<xref rid="cit0024" ref-type="bibr">24</xref></p><p>In view of these scientific findings, our investigation aimed to evaluate the safety and efficacy of a 1060-nm diode laser for submental fat reduction.</p></sec><sec id="s0002"><title>Methods</title><p>This single-site, prospective, clinical pilot study was conducted at the Skin Laser Center of Siriraj Hospital, Mahidol University in Bangkok, Thailand. We enrolled 20 healthy women and men aged between 20 and 65 and weighing 60 to 80 kilograms. Written informed consent was obtained from all subjects before prior the start of the study. The study was approved by the Human Research Ethics Committee of Siriraj Hospital (approval reference: Si420/2018). The procedures used in the research study adhered to the tenets of the 1975 Declaration of Helsinki.</p><p>The investigators gathered all demographic data, clinical histories, and physical examination findings related to the submental area prior to its treatment with a 1060-nm Diode laser.</p><p>The inclusion criteria consisted of healthy adult volunteers of both sexes. All subjects agreed to neither receive any kind of dermatologic/surgical procedures nor other body treatments aiming at reducing body fat during the entire study period. Subjects were excluded from the study if any of the following were met: pregnant or lactating women; a history of liposuction, surgical procedures, laser procedures, gold therapy, neuropathic disorders, skin malignancies, hypertrophic scar or keloid formation, skin infections, skin hypersensitivity, photosensitivity reactions, or herpes virus infection; evidence of compromised healing; an immunodeficiency disorder (including HIV infection or AIDS); the use of immunosuppressive medications; impaired skin sensation; diabetic neuropathy; or underlying psychological conditions.</p><p>The investigators evaluated each subject&#8217;s unwanted localized fat in the submental area. The baseline fat thickness was measured in a supine position using an ultrasound imaging device (iU 22 xMatrix, Philips Healthcare, Eindhoven, the Netherlands). The primary endpoint of the study was a statistically significant reduction in submental fat layer thickness compared with the baseline at follow-up visits held 1, 3, and 6 months after treatment. The secondary endpoint was a subject satisfaction score of 3 or higher after the treatment, measured by improvement scale surveys conducted at the follow-ups.</p><p>A 1060-nm Diode laser device, Sculpsure (Cynosure, Westford, MA, USA), was used in the study. The investigator and all the subjects wore protective eyewear goggles specific to protect against the 1060-nm wavelength during the laser treatment. The submental treatment was performed using one applicator with head gear. The flat non-suction applicator was placed on the subject&#8217;s submental area. The applicator was inserted into the appropriate frame and was placed in contact with the skin.</p><p>The subject was treated with a single laser session of 1060-nm Diode laser. For each patient, the optimal power setting was identified to maximize treatment efficacy and at the same time, guarantee safety and patient comfort. The power setting was in the range between 0.95 and 1.40 W/cm<sup>2</sup>, depending on an individual subject&#8217;s pain tolerance. The spot size was 14.2cm<sup>2</sup>. The exposure time for all subjects was 25 minutes,<xref rid="cit0015" ref-type="bibr">15</xref>,<xref rid="cit0018" ref-type="bibr">18</xref>. The treatment of fat in the submental area started from 1.5 cm below the lower border of the mandible up to the hyoid bone. This is to avoid treating the area of the arteries, veins and marginal mandibular nerve. The Diode laser at 1060 nm delivers heat below the surface of the skin to safely and permanently destroy fat cells. It also uses a constant cooling technology to keep subjects comfortable and safe without the risks of any burns. After the treatment, the subjects rated their pain using a 0-to-10 scale (0&#160;=&#160;none; 10&#160;=&#160;worst possible).<xref rid="cit0018" ref-type="bibr">18</xref></p><p>Clinical photographs and ultrasound images were taken at all follow-ups to assess the efficacy of the laser. All subjects answered an improvement scale survey, and adverse events were monitored at each follow-up visits. Submental fat thickness was also measured using ultrasound images, and the subjects&#8217; body weights (in kilograms) were documented. The submental fat thickness of subjects showing weight gain and no weight gain at 1, 3, and 6 months after their treatment were compared with baseline values.</p><p>Descriptive analysis was used for the demographic data. The data were analyzed using a paired <italic toggle="yes">t</italic>-test (normality) for parametric distribution. The statistical analysis was performed using the statistical software PASW Statistics for Windows, version 18.0 (SPSS Inc, Chicago, IL, USA), with a <italic toggle="yes">P</italic> value &lt;&#160;0.05 indicating statistical significance.</p></sec><sec id="s0003"><title>Results</title><p>Twenty healthy subjects completed the study. Their demographic data are detailed in <xref rid="t0001" ref-type="table">Table 1</xref>. The subjects&#8217; mean age was 34.55&#160;&#177;&#160;6.19 years, their mean body weight was 70.61&#160;&#177;&#160;10.56 kilograms, and 95% (19/20) were women. They received a single treatment with a 1060-nm diode laser, with an average energy setting of 0.95 to 1.40 W/cm<sup>2</sup> (<xref rid="t0001" ref-type="table">Table 1</xref>). The documented body weight changes of the subjects at the follow-ups were nonsignificant (<xref rid="t0002" ref-type="table">Table 2</xref>).<table-wrap position="float" id="t0001" orientation="portrait"><label>Table 1</label><caption><p>Demographic Data of Patients Enrolled in the Study</p></caption><table frame="hsides" rules="groups"><thead><tr><th rowspan="1" colspan="1">Characteristics</th><th rowspan="1" colspan="1">Mean &#177; SD*</th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td rowspan="1" colspan="1"><bold>Age (years)</bold></td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">34.55 &#177; 6.19</td></tr><tr><td rowspan="2" colspan="1"><bold>Sex (%)</bold></td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Female 19 (95%)</td></tr><tr><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Male 1 (5%)</td></tr><tr><td rowspan="1" colspan="1"><bold>Weight (kg)</bold></td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">70.61 &#177; 10.56</td></tr><tr><td rowspan="1" colspan="1"><bold>Energy setting (W/cm<sup>2</sup>)</bold></td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">0.95&#8211;1.40</td></tr><tr><td rowspan="1" colspan="1"><bold>Pain score</bold></td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">3.90 &#177; 1.30</td></tr></tbody></table><table-wrap-foot><fn id="tfn0001"><p><bold>Abbreviation</bold>: *SD, standard deviation.</p></fn></table-wrap-foot></table-wrap>
<table-wrap position="float" id="t0002" orientation="portrait"><label>Table 2</label><caption><p>Evaluation Parameters of Whole Study</p></caption><table frame="hsides" rules="groups"><thead><tr><th rowspan="1" colspan="1">Parameters</th><th rowspan="1" colspan="1">Baseline</th><th rowspan="1" colspan="1">1 Month After Treatment</th><th rowspan="1" colspan="1">3 Months After Treatment</th><th rowspan="1" colspan="1">6 Months After Treatment</th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td colspan="5" rowspan="1"><bold>Body weight (kg)</bold></td></tr><tr><td rowspan="1" colspan="1"><bold>Mean &#177; SD</bold></td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">70.61 &#177; 10.56</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">70.60 &#177; 10.58</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">69.90 &#177; 10.81</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">69.89 &#177; 10.66</td></tr><tr><td rowspan="1" colspan="1"><bold>Max&#8211;Min</bold></td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">53&#8211;91</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">53&#8211;91</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">53&#8211;91</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">53&#8211;91</td></tr><tr><td rowspan="1" colspan="1"><bold><italic toggle="yes">P</italic> value</bold></td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1"/><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">0.990</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">0.464</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">0.417</td></tr><tr><td colspan="5" rowspan="1"><bold>Fat thickness (cm)</bold></td></tr><tr><td rowspan="1" colspan="1"><bold>Mean &#177; SD</bold></td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">0.51 &#177; 0.09</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">0.50 &#177; 0.13</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">0.46 &#177; 0.13</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">0.48 &#177; 0.12</td></tr><tr><td rowspan="1" colspan="1"><bold>Mean difference</bold></td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1"/><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">&#8595; 0.01</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">&#8595; 0.05</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">&#8595; 0.03</td></tr><tr><td rowspan="1" colspan="1"><bold><italic toggle="yes">P</italic> value</bold></td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1"/><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">0.539</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">0.013*</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">0.121</td></tr></tbody></table><table-wrap-foot><fn id="tfn0002"><p><bold>Note</bold>: *Statistically significant at <italic toggle="yes">P</italic> &lt; 0.05.</p></fn></table-wrap-foot></table-wrap></p><p>The average submental fat thickness at baseline was 0.51&#160;&#177;&#160;0.09 cm (<xref rid="t0002" ref-type="table">Table 2</xref>). There was a significant reduction in the fat thickness at post-treatment month 3 compared with the baseline, with a decrease to 0.46&#160;&#177;&#160;0.13 cm (<italic toggle="yes">P</italic> =&#160;0.013). However, 6 months after the treatment, the submental thickness had increased (to 0.48&#160;&#177;&#160;0.12 cm). The change in the thickness relative to the baseline was nonsignificant (<italic toggle="yes">P</italic> =&#160;0.121; <xref rid="t0002" ref-type="table">Table 2</xref>).</p><p>Based on the dynamic subgroup analysis, the subjects who did not gain body weight responded better to treatment (<xref rid="t0003" ref-type="table">Table 3</xref>). The mean baseline fat thickness was 0.52&#160;&#177;&#160;0.11 (<xref rid="t0003" ref-type="table">Table 3</xref>). The fat thickness of the nonweight-gain group showed a significant reduction at post-treatment months 1 (0.46&#160;&#177;&#160;0.12 cm; <italic toggle="yes">P</italic> =&#160;0.014) and 3 (0.46&#160;&#177;&#160;0.15; <italic toggle="yes">P</italic> =&#160;0.042) compared with the baseline (<xref rid="t0003" ref-type="table">Table 3</xref>). On the other hand, the mean fat thickness of the weight-gain group did not show a significant reduction at either post-treatment months 1 or 3 (<italic toggle="yes">P</italic> =&#160;0.106 and 0.197, respectively; <xref rid="t0003" ref-type="table">Table 3</xref>).<table-wrap position="float" id="t0003" orientation="portrait"><label>Table 3</label><caption><p>Comparison of Evaluation Parameters of Weight-Gain and Nonweight-Gain Groups</p></caption><table frame="hsides" rules="groups"><thead><tr><th rowspan="2" colspan="1">Parameters</th><th colspan="2" rowspan="1">Weight-Gain Group (n = 7)</th><th colspan="2" rowspan="1">Nonweight-Gain Group (n = 13)</th><th rowspan="1" colspan="1">Comparison Between the 2 Groups</th></tr><tr><th rowspan="1" colspan="1">Mean &#177; SD</th><th rowspan="1" colspan="1"><italic toggle="yes">P</italic> value</th><th rowspan="1" colspan="1">Mean &#177; SD</th><th rowspan="1" colspan="1"><italic toggle="yes">P</italic> value</th><th rowspan="1" colspan="1"><italic toggle="yes">P</italic> value</th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td colspan="6" rowspan="1"><bold>Body weight (kg)</bold></td></tr><tr><td rowspan="1" colspan="1"><bold>Baseline</bold></td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">69.53 &#177; 7.34</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1"/><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">71.27 &#177; 12.17</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1"/><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">0.715</td></tr><tr><td rowspan="1" colspan="1"><bold>1 month after treatment</bold></td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">71.14 &#177; 7.43</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">0.307</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">70.31 &#177; 12.22</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">0.197</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">0.872</td></tr><tr><td rowspan="1" colspan="1"><bold>3 months after treatment</bold></td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">71.74 &#177; 8.36</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">0.178</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">68.85 &#177; 12.13</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">0.014*</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">0.563</td></tr><tr><td rowspan="1" colspan="1"><bold>6 months after treatment</bold></td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">71.69 &#177; 7.77</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">0.105</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">68.85 &#177; 12.13</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">0.014*</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">0.565</td></tr><tr><td colspan="6" rowspan="1"><bold>Fat thickness (cm)</bold></td></tr><tr><td rowspan="1" colspan="1"><bold>Baseline</bold></td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">0.49 &#177; 0.05</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1"/><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">0.52 &#177; 0.11</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1"/><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">0.477</td></tr><tr><td rowspan="1" colspan="1"><bold>1 month after treatment</bold></td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">0.56 &#177; 0.11</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">0.106</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">0.46 &#177; 0.12</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">0.014*</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">0.097</td></tr><tr><td rowspan="1" colspan="1"><bold>3 months after treatment</bold></td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">0.45 &#177; 0.09</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">0.197</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">0.46 &#177; 0.15</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">0.042*</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">0.881</td></tr><tr><td rowspan="1" colspan="1"><bold>6 months after treatment</bold></td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">0.50 &#177; 0.8</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">0.840</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">0.47 &#177; 0.14</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">0.051</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">0.658</td></tr></tbody></table><table-wrap-foot><fn id="tfn0003"><p><bold>Note</bold>: *Statistically significant at <italic toggle="yes">P</italic> &lt; 0.05.</p></fn></table-wrap-foot></table-wrap></p><p>Most subjects were satisfied with their treatment outcomes 1 and 6 months after their treatment (<xref rid="f0001" ref-type="fig">Figure 1</xref>). The mean pain score was 3.90&#160;&#177;&#160;1.30 on a 0-to-10 scale (<xref rid="t0001" ref-type="table">Table 1</xref>). All subjects reported mild erythema and mild tenderness immediately after treatment, but the side effects were transient. No severe side effects (hypopigmentation, hyperpigmentation, scarring, fat dystrophy, or infection) were found throughout the study period.
<fig position="float" id="f0001" fig-type="figure" orientation="portrait"><label>Figure 1</label><caption><p>Subjects&#8217; self-improvement scores for both groups at all follow-ups.</p></caption><graphic xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" content-type="print-only" position="float" orientation="portrait" xlink:href="CCID-15-2775-g0001.jpg"/></fig></p><p>Clinical photographs and ultrasound images of a representative subject are presented in <xref rid="f0002" ref-type="fig">Figures 2</xref> and <xref rid="f0003" ref-type="fig">3</xref>. They illustrate improvements 3 and 6 months after the treatment.
<fig position="float" id="f0002" fig-type="figure" orientation="portrait"><label>Figure 2</label><caption><p>Clinical photographs of a representative patient.</p></caption><graphic xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" content-type="print-only" position="float" orientation="portrait" xlink:href="CCID-15-2775-g0002.jpg"/></fig>
<fig position="float" id="f0003" fig-type="figure" orientation="portrait"><label>Figure 3</label><caption><p>Ultrasound images (2 dimensions) of the representative patient.</p></caption><graphic xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" content-type="print-only" position="float" orientation="portrait" xlink:href="CCID-15-2775-g0003.jpg"/></fig></p></sec><sec id="s0004"><title>Discussion</title><p>Excessive submental fat can substantially impact people&#8217;s feelings of attractiveness.<xref rid="cit0001" ref-type="bibr">1</xref> Work by Bauman et al validated that submental fat can negatively affect the psychological well-being of individuals. In their study analysis, the researchers documented that excessive submental fat can affect the emotional well-being of people. The data revealed that concerns about chin and neck appearance negatively impacted women&#8217;s feelings and emotional well-being more than men&#8217;s.<xref rid="cit0001" ref-type="bibr">1</xref> In the present study, majority of subjects included were women. Behavioral changes occurred in as many as 75% of people with a considerable amount of chin fat.<xref rid="cit0001" ref-type="bibr">1</xref> More female than male respondents avoided taking photographs (40% vs 31%). Additionally, more women than men (44% vs 34%) said posting photographs of themselves on social media sites was stressful due to their perception that their chin and neck area appeared unattractive.<xref rid="cit0001" ref-type="bibr">1</xref> Because of these emotional sequelae, physicians must evaluate the submental area during aesthetic consultations.</p><p>Laser lipolysis generates controlled hyperthermia using a specific wavelength and optimal energy in the subcutaneous layer. Hyperthermia then causes photomechanical and photothermal reactions that destroy adipocytes and stimulate an inflammatory response.<xref rid="cit0017" ref-type="bibr">17</xref>,<xref rid="cit0018" ref-type="bibr">18</xref></p><p>1060-nm Diode laser wavelength technology has a high affinity for adipose tissue. The laser raises the temperature of adipose cells between 42&#8451; and 47&#8451;, damaging their structural integrity.<xref rid="cit0024" ref-type="bibr">24</xref> After the treatment session, the body naturally eliminates the disrupted cells over the next few months.<xref rid="cit0024" ref-type="bibr">24</xref> Disrupted fat cells are permanently eliminated from the body and will not regenerate. Previous studies on 1060-nm diode lasers showed significant reductions in localized subcutaneous fat on the abdomen<xref rid="cit0015" ref-type="bibr">15</xref> and flanks.<xref rid="cit0018" ref-type="bibr">18</xref></p><p>In the study by Bass et al, significant mean reductions in the fat layer thickness of the abdomen from baseline were observed 6 and 12 weeks after treatment.<xref rid="cit0015" ref-type="bibr">15</xref> At 12 weeks, 91% (31/34) of the subjects were satisfied with the treatment.<xref rid="cit0015" ref-type="bibr">15</xref> Using the same laser device, an earlier pilot investigation on the flanks by Katz et al demonstrated a significant mean fat reduction based on ultrasound images.<xref rid="cit0018" ref-type="bibr">18</xref> Twelve weeks after the treatment, 96% (41/43) of the subjects reported being satisfied with their treatment outcomes.<xref rid="cit0018" ref-type="bibr">18</xref></p><p>A recent study done in Thailand by Yan et al, used the same device, 1060 nm Diode laser, to evaluate its efficacy for medial knee fat reduction. This showed significant reduction in knee circumferences (p&lt; 0.001) at 1-, 3-, and 6-month follow-up visits compared with baseline, and knee fat thickness measured by ultrasound in both axial and sagittal plane at 1 and 6 months after treatment (p = 0.036 and p &lt;0.001, respectively) were recorded.<xref rid="cit0024" ref-type="bibr">24</xref></p><p>In the present study on the submental area, we found a similar significant reduction in fat thickness at post-treatment month 3 (0.46&#160;&#177;&#160;0.13 cm) compared with the baseline (<italic toggle="yes">P</italic> =&#160;0.013). However, at the 6-month follow-up, there was a slight increase in the submental thickness (to 0.48&#160;&#177;&#160;0.12 cm). The change in the thickness relative to the baseline was nonsignificant (<italic toggle="yes">P</italic> =&#160;0.121; <xref rid="t0002" ref-type="table">Table 2</xref>). Most of our subjects expressed satisfaction with their treatment outcomes 1 and 6 months after the treatments (<xref rid="f0001" ref-type="fig">Figure 1</xref>). This study shows that the 1060-nm diode laser is helpful for subcutaneous fat reduction in the submental area for at least a short period after treatment. The authors believe additional treatment sessions must be undertaken to maintain the fat reduction in the submental area.</p><p>As with other investigations, no severe adverse events were reported by the subjects in our study.<xref rid="cit0009" ref-type="bibr">9</xref>,<xref rid="cit0015" ref-type="bibr">15</xref>,<xref rid="cit0017" ref-type="bibr">17</xref>,<xref rid="cit0018" ref-type="bibr">18</xref> In a Korean cryolipolysis study on the submental area, no serious adverse effects (eg, prolonged erythema and permanent hyperpigmentation) were reported.<xref rid="cit0009" ref-type="bibr">9</xref>,<xref rid="cit0010" ref-type="bibr">10</xref> In a laser lipolysis study by Katz and associates, the majority of reported events (83%) were mild and temporary. For instance, edema resolved within 4 to 6 days, pain and bruising within 9 to 11 days, and subcutaneous nodules within 32 to 78 days.<xref rid="cit0018" ref-type="bibr">18</xref> Bass et al documented posttreatment tenderness as the most frequent adverse event.<xref rid="cit0015" ref-type="bibr">15</xref> Seventy-four percent (74%) of the events were reported as mild, 26% as moderate, and none as severe.<xref rid="cit0015" ref-type="bibr">15</xref> In addition, Yan et al, all subjects reported mild tenderness and erythema immediately after the treatment for medial knee reduction. No hypopigmentation, hyperpigmentation, scarring, fat dystrophy, infection, or paradoxical adipose hyperplasia were documented.<xref rid="cit0024" ref-type="bibr">24</xref></p><p>The subjects in the current investigation reported an average pain score of 3.90&#160;&#177;&#160;1.30 on a 0-to-10 scale (<xref rid="t0001" ref-type="table">Table 1</xref>). Although all subjects reported mild erythema and mild tenderness immediately after treatment, these side effects were transient. No severe side effects (hypopigmentation, hyperpigmentation, scarring, fat dystrophy, or infection) were found throughout the study period. The patient satisfaction done in the present study is due to their observation of minimal complications. 1060-nm Diode laser has far fewer adverse effects than other treatment modalities, such as surgery, microneedling devices, and injections. Regarding the safety profile, submental laser lipolysis is comparable to submental cryolipolysis and has higher patient tolerability than the ATX-101 procedure, which is a form of injection adipolysis.<xref rid="cit0010" ref-type="bibr">10</xref> Considering that the submental area is a visible facial region, it is prudent to avoid any side effects that could cause emotional burden among patients, such as scarring or permanent dyspigmentation.</p><p>The fat thickness of the nonweight-gain group at baseline was 0.52&#160;&#177;&#160;0.11 (<xref rid="t0003" ref-type="table">Table 3</xref>). The fat thickness of this group showed significant reductions at post-treatment month 1 (0.46&#160;&#177;&#160;0.12 cm) and post-treatment month 3 (0.46&#160;&#177;&#160;0.15) compared with the baseline (<italic toggle="yes">P</italic> =&#160;0.014 and 0.042, respectively; <xref rid="t0003" ref-type="table">Table 3</xref>). On the other hand, the average fat thickness of the weight-gain group did not show a significant reduction at 1 or 3 months after treatment (<italic toggle="yes">P</italic> =&#160;0.106 and 0.197, respectively; <xref rid="t0003" ref-type="table">Table 3</xref>). Consequently, the authors believe that diet control and regular exercise must be undertaken by subjects to achieve and maintain satisfactory treatment results and patient satisfaction.</p><p>In conclusion, this study validated that using a 1060-nm diode laser safely and effectively reduces submental fat. This is the first study to report the clinical efficacy and safety of 1060-nm diode lasers for treating excessive subcutaneous fat in the submental areas of Asian subjects. The study&#8217;s limitations are a single treatment administration, a small sample size, the absence of a comparative group, and a short follow-up period. Further studies are encouraged to determine whether additional treatment sessions would yield more fat reduction and to identify if long-term complications arise from this treatment modality.</p></sec><sec id="s0005"><title>Conclusion</title><p>Our study demonstrated the potential role of 1060-nm Diode laser for the treatment of localized submental subcutaneous adiposities. 1060 nm Diode Lasers is a promising alternative treatment modality for patients seeking an in-office, nonsurgical procedure for fat reduction without severe complications.</p></sec></body><back><ack><title>Acknowledgments</title><p>The authors thank Ms. Phonsuk Yamlexnoi, Ms. Chutikan Kiatphansodsai, and Ms. Apichaya Jutaphonrakul for their assistance in recruiting subjects and managing the database. The authors are also indebted to Mr David Park for the English-language editing of this paper. In addition, the authors thank the patients who participated in the study.</p></ack><sec id="s0006"><title>Data Sharing Statement</title><p>The datasets generated during and/or analyzed during the current study are available from the corresponding author on reasonable request.</p></sec><sec id="s0007"><title>Compliance with Ethics Guidelines</title><p>The study was approved by the ethics committee of the Siriraj Institutional Review Board. Written informed consent was obtained for the publication and use of all patients&#8217; images prior to their enrollment in the study. This study was performed in accordance with the Helsinki Declaration of 1964 and its subsequent amendments.</p></sec><sec id="s0008"><title>Author Contributions</title><p>All authors made a significant contribution to the work reported, whether that is in the conception, study design, execution, acquisition of data, analysis and interpretation, or in all these areas; took part in drafting, revising or critically reviewing the article; gave final approval of the version to be published; have agreed on the journal to which the article has been submitted; and agree to be accountable for all aspects of the work. All authors read and approved the final manuscript.</p></sec><sec sec-type="COI-statement" id="s0009"><title>Disclosure</title><p>All authors declare that they have no conflicts of interest in this work.</p></sec><ref-list><title>References</title><ref id="cit0001"><label>1.</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><string-name name-style="western"><surname>Baumann</surname><given-names>L</given-names></string-name>, <string-name name-style="western"><surname>Shridharani</surname><given-names>SM</given-names></string-name>, <string-name name-style="western"><surname>Humphrey</surname><given-names>S</given-names></string-name>, <string-name name-style="western"><surname>Gallagher</surname><given-names>CJ</given-names></string-name>. <article-title>Personal (Self) perceptions of submental fat among adults in the United States</article-title>. <source><italic toggle="yes">Dermatol Surg</italic></source>. <year>2019</year>;<volume>45</volume>(<issue>1</issue>):<fpage>124</fpage>&#8211;<lpage>130</lpage>. doi:<pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1097/DSS.0000000000001648</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">30234657</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC6319576</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="cit0002"><label>2.</label><mixed-citation publication-type="webpage"><collab>American Society for Dermatologic Surgery</collab>. <article-title>2019 consumer survey on cosmetic dermatologic procedures</article-title>; <year>2019</year>. <comment>Available from</comment>: <ext-link xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xlink:href="https://www.asds.net/2019-consumer-survey/" ext-link-type="uri">https://www.asds.net/2019-consumer-survey/</ext-link>. <date-in-citation>Accessed <month>May</month><day>22</day>, 2020</date-in-citation>.</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="cit0003"><label>3.</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><string-name name-style="western"><surname>Ziccardi</surname><given-names>VB</given-names></string-name>, <string-name name-style="western"><surname>Newwark</surname><given-names>NJ</given-names></string-name>. <article-title>Basic technique of submental liposuction</article-title>. <source><italic toggle="yes">J Oral Maxillofac Surg</italic></source>. <year>2004</year>;<volume>62</volume>:<fpage>104</fpage>&#8211;<lpage>105</lpage>. doi:<pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1016/j.joms.2004.05.086</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="cit0004"><label>4.</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><string-name name-style="western"><surname>Koehler</surname><given-names>J</given-names></string-name>. <article-title>Complications of neck liposuction and submentoplasty</article-title>. <source><italic toggle="yes">Oral Maxillofac Surg Clin North Am</italic></source>. <year>2009</year>;<volume>21</volume>(<issue>1</issue>):<page-range>43&#8208;vi</page-range>. doi:<pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1016/j.coms.2008.10.008</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">19185794</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="cit0005"><label>5.</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><string-name name-style="western"><surname>Shamban</surname><given-names>AT</given-names></string-name>. <article-title>Noninvasive submental fat compartment treatment</article-title>. <source><italic toggle="yes">Plast Reconstr Surg Glob Open</italic></source>. <year>2016</year>;<volume>4</volume>(<issue>12Suppl</issue>):<fpage>e1155</fpage>. doi:<pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1097/GOX.0000000000001155</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">28018773</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC5172481</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="cit0006"><label>6.</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><string-name name-style="western"><surname>Dayan</surname><given-names>SH</given-names></string-name>, <string-name name-style="western"><surname>Humphrey</surname><given-names>S</given-names></string-name>, <string-name name-style="western"><surname>Jones</surname><given-names>DH</given-names></string-name>, et al. <article-title>Overview of ATX-101 (deoxycholic acid injection): a nonsurgical approach for reduction of submental fat</article-title>. <source><italic toggle="yes">Dermatol Surg</italic></source>. <year>2016</year>;<volume>42</volume>(<issue>Suppl 1</issue>):<page-range>S263&#8208;S270</page-range>. doi:<pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1097/DSS.0000000000000870</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">27787266</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="cit0007"><label>7.</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><string-name name-style="western"><surname>Ascher</surname><given-names>B</given-names></string-name>, <string-name name-style="western"><surname>Fellmann</surname><given-names>J</given-names></string-name>, <string-name name-style="western"><surname>Monheit</surname><given-names>G</given-names></string-name>. <article-title>ATX-101 (deoxycholic acid injection) for reduction of submental fat</article-title>. <source><italic toggle="yes">Expert Rev Clin Pharmacol</italic></source>. <year>2016</year>;<volume>9</volume>(<issue>9</issue>):<page-range>1131&#8208;1143</page-range>. doi:<pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1080/17512433.2016.1215911</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">27457304</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="cit0008"><label>8.</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><string-name name-style="western"><surname>Kamalpour</surname><given-names>S</given-names></string-name>, <string-name name-style="western"><surname>Leblanc</surname><given-names>K</given-names><suffix>Jr</suffix></string-name>. <article-title>Injection adipolysis: mechanisms, agents, and future directions</article-title>. <source><italic toggle="yes">J Clin Aesthet Dermatol</italic></source>. <year>2016</year>;<volume>9</volume>(<issue>12</issue>):<page-range>44&#8208;50</page-range>. doi:<pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1016/j.cps.2013.07.006</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC5300726</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">28210398</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="cit0009"><label>9.</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><string-name name-style="western"><surname>Suh</surname><given-names>DH</given-names></string-name>, <string-name name-style="western"><surname>Park</surname><given-names>JH</given-names></string-name>, <string-name name-style="western"><surname>Jung</surname><given-names>HK</given-names></string-name>, <string-name name-style="western"><surname>Lee</surname><given-names>SJ</given-names></string-name>, <string-name name-style="western"><surname>Kim</surname><given-names>HJ</given-names></string-name>, <string-name name-style="western"><surname>Ryu</surname><given-names>HJ</given-names></string-name>. <article-title>Cryolipolysis for submental fat reduction in Asians</article-title>. <source><italic toggle="yes">J Cosmet Laser Ther</italic></source>. <year>2018</year>;<volume>20</volume>(<issue>1</issue>):<page-range>24&#8208;27</page-range>. doi:<pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1080/14764172.2017.1368564</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">28850270</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="cit0010"><label>10.</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><string-name name-style="western"><surname>Kilmer</surname><given-names>SL</given-names></string-name>, <string-name name-style="western"><surname>Burns</surname><given-names>AJ</given-names></string-name>, <string-name name-style="western"><surname>Zelickson</surname><given-names>BD</given-names></string-name>. <article-title>Safety and efficacy of cryolipolysis for non-invasive reduction of submental fat</article-title>. <source><italic toggle="yes">Lasers Surg Med</italic></source>. <year>2016</year>;<volume>48</volume>(<issue>1</issue>):<page-range>3&#8208;13</page-range>. doi:<pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1002/lsm.22440</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC5396277</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">26607045</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="cit0011"><label>11.</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><string-name name-style="western"><surname>Avram</surname><given-names>MM</given-names></string-name>, <string-name name-style="western"><surname>Harry</surname><given-names>RS</given-names></string-name>. <article-title>Cryolipolysis for subcutaneous fat layer reduction</article-title>. <source><italic toggle="yes">Lasers Surg Med</italic></source>. <year>2009</year>;<volume>41</volume>(<issue>10</issue>):<fpage>7038</fpage>. doi:<pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1002/lsm.20864</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">20014262</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="cit0012"><label>12.</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><string-name name-style="western"><surname>Park</surname><given-names>JH</given-names></string-name>, <string-name name-style="western"><surname>Kim</surname><given-names>JI</given-names></string-name>, <string-name name-style="western"><surname>Park</surname><given-names>HJ</given-names></string-name>, et al. <article-title>Evaluation of safety and efficacy of noninvasive radiofrequency technology for submental rejuvenation</article-title>. <source><italic toggle="yes">Lasers Med Sci</italic></source>. <year>2016</year>;<volume>31</volume>:<fpage>1599</fpage>&#8211;<lpage>1605</lpage>. doi:<pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1007/s10103-016-2023-7</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">27402002</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="cit0013"><label>13.</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><string-name name-style="western"><surname>Fabi</surname><given-names>SG</given-names></string-name>. <article-title>Noninvasive skin tightening: focus on new ultrasound techniques</article-title>. <source><italic toggle="yes">Clin Cosmet Investig Dermatol</italic></source>. <year>2015</year>;<volume>8</volume>:<page-range>47&#8208;52</page-range>. doi:<pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.2147/CCID.S69118</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC4327394</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">25709486</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="cit0014"><label>14.</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><string-name name-style="western"><surname>Oni</surname><given-names>G</given-names></string-name>, <string-name name-style="western"><surname>Hoxworth</surname><given-names>R</given-names></string-name>, <string-name name-style="western"><surname>Teotia</surname><given-names>S</given-names></string-name>, <string-name name-style="western"><surname>Brown</surname><given-names>S</given-names></string-name>, <string-name name-style="western"><surname>Kenkel</surname><given-names>JM</given-names></string-name>. <article-title>Evaluation of a microfocused ultrasound system for improving skin laxity and tightening in the lower face</article-title>. <source><italic toggle="yes">Aesthet Surg J</italic></source>. <year>2014</year>;<volume>34</volume>(<issue>7</issue>):<page-range>1099&#8208;1110</page-range>. doi:<pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1177/1090820X14541956</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">24990884</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="cit0015"><label>15.</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><string-name name-style="western"><surname>Bass</surname><given-names>LS</given-names></string-name>, <string-name name-style="western"><surname>Doherty</surname><given-names>ST</given-names></string-name>. <article-title>Safety and efficacy of a noninvasive 1060-nm diode laser for fat reduction of the abdomen</article-title>. <source><italic toggle="yes">J Drugs Dermatol</italic></source>. <year>2018</year>;<volume>17</volume>(<issue>1</issue>):<fpage>106</fpage>&#8211;<lpage>112</lpage>.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">29320595</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="cit0016"><label>16.</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><string-name name-style="western"><surname>Schilling</surname><given-names>L</given-names></string-name>, <string-name name-style="western"><surname>Saedi</surname><given-names>N</given-names></string-name>, <string-name name-style="western"><surname>Weiss</surname><given-names>R</given-names></string-name>. <article-title>1060 nm diode hyperthermic laser lipolysis: the latest in noninvasive body contouring</article-title>. <source><italic toggle="yes">J Drugs Dermatol</italic></source>. <year>2017</year>;<volume>16</volume>(<issue>1</issue>):<fpage>48</fpage>&#8211;<lpage>52</lpage>.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">28095532</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="cit0017"><label>17.</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><string-name name-style="western"><surname>Decorato</surname><given-names>JW</given-names></string-name>, <string-name name-style="western"><surname>Chen</surname><given-names>B</given-names></string-name>, <string-name name-style="western"><surname>Sierra</surname><given-names>R</given-names></string-name>. <article-title>Subcutaneous adipose tissue response to a non-invasive hyperthermic treatment using a 1060 nm laser</article-title>. <source><italic toggle="yes">Lasers Surg Med</italic></source>. <year>2017</year>;<volume>49</volume>(<issue>5</issue>):<fpage>480</fpage>&#8211;<lpage>489</lpage>. doi:<pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1002/lsm.22625</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">28103642</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="cit0018"><label>18.</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><string-name name-style="western"><surname>Katz</surname><given-names>B</given-names></string-name>, <string-name name-style="western"><surname>Doherty</surname><given-names>ST</given-names></string-name>. <article-title>Safety and efficacy of a noninvasive 1060-nm diode laser for fat reduction of the flanks</article-title>. <source><italic toggle="yes">Dermatol Surg</italic></source>. <year>2018</year>;<volume>44</volume>:<fpage>388</fpage>&#8211;<lpage>396</lpage>. doi:<pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1097/DSS.0000000000001298</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">28902034</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="cit0019"><label>19.</label><mixed-citation publication-type="webpage"><article-title>ZELTIQ&#174; receives FDA clearance to treat submental fat with CoolSculpting&#174; procedure: introduction of new CoolMini&#8482; applicator uniquely designed non-invasively treat smaller pockets of fat</article-title>; <year>2015</year>. <comment>Available from</comment>: <ext-link xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xlink:href="http://www.biospace.com" ext-link-type="uri">http://www.biospace.com</ext-link>. <date-in-citation>Accessed <month>June</month><day>4</day>, 2020</date-in-citation>.</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="cit0020"><label>20.</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><string-name name-style="western"><surname>Wanitphakdeedecha</surname><given-names>R</given-names></string-name>, <string-name name-style="western"><surname>Sathaworawong</surname><given-names>A</given-names></string-name>, <string-name name-style="western"><surname>Manuskiatti</surname><given-names>W</given-names></string-name>. <article-title>The efficacy of cryolipolysis treatment on arms and inner thighs</article-title>. <source><italic toggle="yes">Lasers Med Sci</italic></source>. <year>2015</year>;<volume>30</volume>(<issue>8</issue>):<fpage>2165</fpage>&#8211;<lpage>2169</lpage>. doi:<pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1007/s10103-015-1781-y</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">26100004</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC4598345</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="cit0021"><label>21.</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><string-name name-style="western"><surname>Jalian</surname><given-names>HR</given-names></string-name>, <string-name name-style="western"><surname>Avram</surname><given-names>MM</given-names></string-name>. <article-title>Cryolipolysis: a historical perspective and current clinical practice</article-title>. <source><italic toggle="yes">Semin Cutan Med Surg</italic></source>. <year>2013</year>;<volume>32</volume>(<issue>1</issue>):<fpage>31</fpage>&#8211;<lpage>34</lpage>.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">24049927</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="cit0022"><label>22.</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><string-name name-style="western"><surname>Putra</surname><given-names>IB</given-names></string-name>, <string-name name-style="western"><surname>Jusuf</surname><given-names>NK</given-names></string-name>, <string-name name-style="western"><surname>Dewi</surname><given-names>NK</given-names></string-name>. <article-title>Utilisation of cryolipolysis among Asians: a review on efficacy and safety</article-title>. <source><italic toggle="yes">Open Access Maced J Med Sci</italic></source>. <year>2019</year>;<volume>7</volume>(<issue>9</issue>):<fpage>1548</fpage>&#8211;<lpage>1554</lpage>. doi:<pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.3889/oamjms.2019.318</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">31198471</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC6542401</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="cit0023"><label>23.</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><string-name name-style="western"><surname>Salsi</surname><given-names>B</given-names></string-name>, <string-name name-style="western"><surname>Fusco</surname><given-names>I</given-names></string-name>. <article-title>Non-invasive system delivering microwaves energy for unwanted fat reduction and submental skin tightening: clinical evidence</article-title>. <source><italic toggle="yes">J Cosmet Dermatol</italic></source>. <year>2022</year>;<volume>00</volume>:<fpage>1</fpage>&#8211;<lpage>8</lpage>.<pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1111/jocd.15205</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">35778895</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="cit0024"><label>24.</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><string-name name-style="western"><surname>Yan</surname><given-names>C</given-names></string-name>, <string-name name-style="western"><surname>Wanitphakdeedecha</surname><given-names>R</given-names></string-name>, <string-name name-style="western"><surname>Evangelista</surname><given-names>KER</given-names></string-name>, et al. <article-title>Efficacy of noninvasive 1060-nm diode laser for medial knee fat reduction</article-title>. <source><italic toggle="yes">Dermatol Ther</italic></source>. <year>2022</year>;<volume>12</volume>:<fpage>1253</fpage>&#8211;<lpage>1261</lpage>. doi:<pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1007/s13555-022-00730-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC9110628</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">35499741</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref></ref-list></back></article></pmc-articleset>